<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2018.13809</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Assessing landuse effect on soil properties in the Coastal plains sand, Imo State, Nigeria]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ukaegbu</surname>
            <given-names>E. P.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Nnawuihe</surname>
            <given-names>C. O.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">emekaprosper2@yahoo.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>13</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2018</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>17</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>850</fpage>
	  <lpage>859</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/8C2A1A163891">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/8C2A1A163891	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/8C2A1A163891">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/8C2A1A163891	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Impacts of landuses [old home garden (HG), oilpalm plantation (OP), fallow arable field (FA), grass lawn (GL)] on physico-chemical properties of an ultisol on a flat in the Coastal plains sand of Imo State, Nigeria were evaluated. Landuse significantly (at 5%) influenced the properties sand, organic matter (OM) content, soil reaction (pH), exchangeable cations Ca, Mg, K, exchangeable acidity (Al+H), effective cation exchange capacity (ECEC), base saturation (BS); while available phosphorous (av.P), Ca, Mg, K, Al+H, varied most within and among the management units. Properties varied least in HG, but most in FA and GL. Strong soil acidity and associated problems of nutrient (e.g. Ca, Mg, K) deficiencies, nutrient imbalance, low ECEC were the main limiting factors. The ratio Ca+Mg/Al+H, among other indices OM, Ca+Mg, Al+H, ESP, captured the soilsrsquo; degradation best. On its basis, the soilsrsquo; qualities were in the order, HG gt; OP gt; FA gt; GL. Management should aim at meeting the conditions of HG and that should include liming to correct nutrient imbalance as it had not been mitigated by long fallow. Indices identified should be considered in developing quantitative models for estimating soil quality in the location of study. Soil property variability as influenced by land fragmentation in the area needs further investigation using geostatistical technique.

	Key words: Management, Coastal plains sand, indices of soil quality, soil degradation, soil productivity.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adaikwu AO, Ali A (2013). Assessment of some soil quality indicators in Benue State. Nigeria Journal of Soil Science 23(2):66-75.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ahukaemere CM, Eshett ET, Ahiwe C (2014). Characterization and fertility status of wetland soils in Abia State agro-ecological zone of southeastern Nigeria. Nigerian Journal of Soil Science 24(1):147-157.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Akamigbo FOR (1986). Soil variability within map units in areas of low and undulating relief: A case study on Abakaliki/Okigwe anticlinorium, eastern Nigeria. Nigerian Agricultural Journal 21:81-29.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Akamigbo FOR (1999). Influence of Landuse on Soil Properties of the humid tropical agroecology of Southeastern Nigeria. Nigerian Agricultural Journal 30:59-76.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ano AO, Ubochi CI (2007). Neutralization of Soil acidity by animal manures: Mechanism of reaction. African Journal of Biotechnology 6(4):364-368.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Asadu CLA, Bosah CS (2003). A comparative study of the soils of the Upper coal-measure Residua under cropped-grass-forest land continuum in Eastern Nigeria. East African Agricultural and Forestry Journal 68(4):2005-2212.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Asadu CLA, Nweke FI, Enete AA (2008). Soil properties and intensification of traditional farming systems in sub-Saharan Africa. Agro-Science 7(3):186-192.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Beckett PHT, Webster B (1971). Soil Variability: A review. Soil and Fertilizers 34(1):1-15.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bouyoucos GJ (1951). A recalibration of the hydrometer method for making mechanical analysis of soils. Agronomy Journal 43:435-438.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bray RH, Kurtz LT (1998). Determination of total and available forms of phosphorus in soils. Soil Science 59:39-45.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Brevik EC, Calzolari C, Miller BA, Pereira P, Kabala C, Baumgarten A, Jordan A (2016). Soil Mapping, Classificaiton, and modeling: History and future directions. Geoderma 264:256-274.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chude VO, Malgwi WB, Amapu IY, Ano OA (2011). Manual on Soil Fertility Assessment. Federal Fertilizer Department in Collaboration with National Programme for Food Security, Abuja, Nigeria. P. 62.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dilkova R, Kerchev G, Kercheva M (1998). Evaluating and grouping of soils according to their susceptibility to anthropogenic degradation. Advances in GeoEcology 31:125-131.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ellerbrock RH, Gerke HH (2016). Analyzing Management-induced dynamics of soluble organic matter composition in soils from long-term field experiments. Verdose Zone Journal 15:4.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Enwezor WO, Udo EJ, Usoroh NJ, Ayotade KA, Adepeta JA, Chude VO, Udegbe CI (1989). Fertilizer use and Management Practices for Crops in Nigeria. Series No 2. Fertilizer Procurement and Distribution Division, Federal Ministry of Agriculture, Water Resources and Rural Development, Lagos, Nigeria P. 163.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Federal Department of Agricultural Land Resources (FDALR) (1999). Status of Agricultural Landuse in Nigeria. In: Evolving an Effective Agricultural Landuse Policy for Nigeria. Abuja, Federal Ministry of Agriculture and Natural Resources, P. 165.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fraser MA, Scott BJ (2011). Variability of acidity in agricultural soils - The impact of timber burning at Land clearing. Soil Research 49:223-230.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ghartey EO, Dowuona GNN, Nartey EK, Adjadeh TA (2012). Assessment of variability in the quality of an Acrisol under different landuse systems in Ghana. Open Journal of Soil Science 2:33-43.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Idowu OJ, Aduramigbo VO, Ande FT (2003). Variability in Surface Properties of an Alfisol as Function of Types of Landuse. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 34(1920):3045-3058.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Igbal I, Thomasson JA, Jenkins JN, Owens PR, Whisler FD (2005). Spatial variability analysis of soil physical properties of alluvial soils. Soil Science Society of America Journal 69(4):1338-1350.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Igbozurike MU (1975). Vegetation Types. In: Ofomata GEK (ed.). Nigeria in Maps: Eastern States. Benin City, Ethiope Pub. House P. 146.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Karlen DL, Mausbach MJ, Doran JW, Cline RG, Harris RF, Schuman GE (1997). Soil quality: A concept, definition and framework for evaluation. Soil Science Society of America Journal 61:4-10.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Komolafe MF, Adegbola AA, Are LA, Ashaye TI (1979). Agricultural science for West African Schools and Colleges (2nd edn). Ibadan, Univ. Press. Ltd. P. 228.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lageman J (1981). Problems of agricultural production in the humid tropical lowlands. In: Agroforestry, Proceedings of a Seminar held in CATIE Turrialba, Costa Rica, 23 February - 3 March, 1981.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lal R (1986). Soil Surface Management in the tropics for intensive landuse and high and sustained production. In: Advances in Soil Science, Springer Verlag, New York Inc., 5:1-108.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Landon JR (1984). Tropical Soil Manual. Booker Tate Ltd. P. 476.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Landon JR (1991). Booker Tropical Soil Manual: A handbook for Soil Survey and Agricultural Land Evaluation in the Tropics and Sub-tropics. New York, Longman Inc. P. 474.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mclean EO (1965). Aluminum. In: Black CA (9th edn). Methods of Soil Analysis. Part 2, Agronomy, Madison, Wisconsin, pp. 986-994.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Msanya BM, Kimaro DN, Kileo EP, Kimbi GG, Munisi AIM (2001). Land Resources Inventory and Suitability Assessment for the Production of the Major Crops in the Eastern Part of Morogoro Rural District, Tanzania. Soils and Land Resources of Morogoro Rural and Urban Districts, Department of Soil Science, Faculty of Agriculture, Sokoine University of Agriculture, Morogoro, Tanzania 3:69.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Msanya BM, Munishi JA, Amuri N, Semu E, Mhoro L, Malley Z (2016). Morphology, genesis, physico-chemical properties, classification and potential of soils derived from volcanic parent materials in selected Districts of Mbeya Region, Tanzania. International Journal of Plant Soil Science 10(4):1-19.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nelson DW, Sommers LE (1990). Total Carbon, Organic Carbon and Organic Matter. In: Miller RH, Keeney DR (Eds.). Methods of Soil Analysis. Chemical Method, ASA and SSA. Madison 39:1085-1121.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nnaji GU, Asadu CLA, Mbagwu JSC (2002). Evaluation of Physico-Chemical Properties of Soils under selected Agricultural Land Utilization Types. Agro-Science 3(1):27-33.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nottidge DO, Ojeniyi SO, Asawalam DO (2006). Effect of different levels of Woodash on Soil Chemical properties in an acid Ultisol of Southeast Nigeria. Nigerian Journal of Soil Science 16:109-114.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nye PH, Greenland DJ (1964). Changes in the soil after clearing tropical forest. Plant and Soil 21:101-112.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ogunkunle A (2015). Soil quality maintenance by sustainable landuse/management: an imperative for food security. Special edition of the Nigerian Journal of Soil Science 25:11-45.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Oti NN (2002). Discriminant Functions for Classifying erosion degraded lands at Otamiri, Southeastern Nigeria. Agro-Science 3(1):34-40.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rodrigo-Comino J, Keshavarzi A, Bagherzadeh A, Brevik EC (2019). The use of Multivariate Statistical analysis and soil quality indices as tools to be included in regional management plans. A case study from the Mashdad Plain, Iran. Geographical Research Letters 45.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Smalling CMA, Fresco LO, de Jager A (1996). Classifying, Monitoring and Improving Nutrient Stocks and flows in African Agriculture. AMBIO 25(8):492-496.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Udo EJ, Ibia TO, Ogunwale JA, Ano AO, Esu IE (2009). Manual of soil plant and water analyses. Lagos, Sibon Books Ltd, P. 183.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ukaegbu EP (2014). Soil Characterization and Land Evaluation of Owerri Agricultural Zone, Imo State, Nigeria. A Ph.D Thesis. Department of Soil Science, University of Nigeria, Nsukka.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Uwingabire S, Msanya BM, Mtakwa PW, Uwitonze P, Sirikare S (2016). Pedological Characterization of Soils developed on gneissic-granite in the Congo Nile Watershed Divide and Central Plateau Zones, Rwanda. International Journal of Current Research 89(9):39489-39501.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Uwitonze P, Msanya BM, Mtakwa PW, Uwingabire S, Sirikare S (2016). Pedological Characterization of Soils developed from volcanic parent materials of Northern Province of Rwanda. Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries 5(6):225-236.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Uzozie LC (1975). Food-crop combination and Agricultural Regions. In: Ofomata GEK (Ed). Nigeria in Maps: Eastern States. Benin City, Ethiope Publishing House P. 146.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wilding LP, Bouma J, Boss DW (1994). Impact of spatial variability on interpretative modeling. In: Bryant RB, Arnold RW. Quantitative modeling of soil forming process. SSSA Special Publication, No. 39:6175.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wuest SB, Reardon CL (2016). Surface and root inputs produce different carbon/phosphorus ratios in soil. Soil Science Society of America Journal 80:463-471.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Young A (1998). Land resources now and for the future. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press P. 319.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zheng H, Wu J, Zhang S (2009). Study on spatial variability of farmland soil nutrient based on the kriging interpolation. AICI, International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computational Intelligence, November 7-8, Shanghai, China 4:550-555.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>