<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2020.14723</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Promotion of rice growth and productivity as a result of seed inoculation with Azospirillum brasilense]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Vandeir</surname>
            <given-names>Francisco Guimares</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Jeferson</surname>
            <given-names>Klein</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Marcos</surname>
            <given-names>Barbosa Ferreira</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Dbora</surname>
            <given-names>Kestring Klein</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">vandeirfg@yahoo.com.br</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>15</day>
			<month>01</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>13</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>765</fpage>
	  <lpage>776</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D0AFA7163813">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D0AFA7163813	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/D0AFA7163813">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/D0AFA7163813	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The present study refers to the results obtained in four experiments carried out in the 2015/2016 crop: Toledo/PR; Palotina/PR; Cascavel/PR; and Satilde;o Miguel do Iguaccedil;u/PR. The objective of the present study was to evaluate the agronomic efficiency of Azospirillum brasilense (pest strains Ab-V5 and Ab-V6) in four distinct rice culture regions (Oryza sativa L.). The tests were performed to meet the requirements of the Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Supply regarding the registration of the product. The experiments were conducted in a randomized block design with seven treatments and four replications, totaling 28 plots each. Rice cultivar IAC 201 was used in all four experiments. At stage R7, 10 plants were collected to measure morphobiometric variables and nitrogen content in grains (N grains). The results showed that in all evaluated sites the use of liquid inoculation with A. brasilense increased rice crop development as well as productivity. Thus, inoculation of rice seeds with A. brasilense strains Ab-V5 and Ab-V6 based inoculant in the liquid formulations increased the yield and yield components of rice crop in different regions. The inoculant based on A. brasilense strains Ab-V5 and Ab-V6, using the liquid vehicle, presented higher agronomic efficiency for rice cultivation. The inoculant based on A. brasilense strains Ab-V5 and Ab-V6 using the peat medium has good agronomic efficiency similar to the standard inoculant. These results were satisfactory contributing also to the sustainability in the agriculture.

	Key words: Diazotrophic bacteria, plant growth promoting bacteria, nitrogen fertilization, seed inoculation, Oryza sativa L.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Areias RGBM, Paiva DM, Souza SR, Fernandes MS (2006). Similaridade gentica de variedades crioulas de arroz, em funo da morfologia, marcadores APD e acmulo de protena nos gros. Bragantia 65(1):19-28.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Babalola OO (2010). Beneficial bacteria of agricultural importance. Biotechnology Letters 32(1):1559-1570.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Barbosa Filho MP, Fageria NK, Silva OF (1999) Correo de deficincias de micronutrientes em arroz de terras altas. Santo Antnio de Gois: Embrapa Arroz e Feijo. P 21. (Embrapa Arroz e Feijo. Documentos 93).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Beutler AN, Burg GM, Deak EA, Schmidt MR, Galon L (2016). Effect of nitrogen-fixing bacteria on grain yield and development of flooded irrigated rice. Revista Caatinga 29(1):11-17.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cardoso ICM, Filho O K, Mariotto JR, Miquellutti DJ, Vicente D, Neves NA (2010). Ocorrncia de bactrias endofticas do gnero Azospirillum em arroz irrigado no estado de Santa Catarina. Revista de Cincias Agroveterinrias 9(2):178-186.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Companhia Nacional de Abastecimento (CONAB) (2017). Acompanhamento de safra brasileira: gros, stimo levantamento - Safra 2015/2016.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dobereiner J (1990). Avanos recentes na pesquisa em fixao biolgica de nitrognio no Brasil. Estudos Avanados. So Paulo 4(8):11.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dbereiner J, Baldani VLD, Baldani JI (1995). Como isolar e identificar bactrias diazotrficas de plantas no-leguminosas. Braslia: Embrapa-SPI P 60.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Embrapa (2013). Empresa Brasileira de Pesquisa Agropecuria - Embrapa. Sistema Brasileiro de Classificao de Solos. 3.ed. Braslia P 353.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ferreira DF (2011). Sisvar - Sistema de anlise de varincia. Cincia e Tecnologia, Lavras 35(6).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ferreira SF, Baldani JI, Baldani VLD (2010). Seleo de inoculantes  base de turfa contendo bactrias dizotrficas em duas varidades de arroz. Acta Scientiarum Agronomy 32(1):179-185.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gaibor JR, Navarrete EC, Arteaga CC, Vasquez GG, Velez, UM, Aragon DS (2017). Eficiencia agronmica del arroz INIAP-17 con niveles de fertilizacin qumica y biolgica em el Litoral Ecuatoriano. Jornal of Science and Research 2(6):10-15.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Garcia NFS, Orivaldo ARF, Portugal JR, Rodrigues M, Penteado MS (2015). Rendimento e qualidade de gros de arroz de terras altas em funo de doses e modos de inoculao com Azospirillum brasilense. Enciclopdia Biosfera 11(21):1653-1661.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gitti DDC, Orivaldo ARFO, Portugal JR, Corsini DCDC, Rodrigues RAF, Kaneko FH (2012). Coberturas vegetais, doses de nitrognio e inoculao de sementes com Azospirillum brasilense em arroz de terras altas no sistema plantio direto. Bragantia 71(4):509-517.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Goes RJ (2012). Inoculao de Sementes com Azospirillum brasilense e Doses de N Mineral em Arroz de Terras Altas Irrigado por Asperso. pp 30. Relatrio (Mestrado em Agronomia) - Faculdade de Engenharia, Universidade Estadual Paulista, Ilha Solteira P 151.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Guimares SG, Baldani VLD (2013). Produo de arroz inoculado com bactrias diazotrficas marcadas com resistncia induzida ao antibitico estreptomicina. Revista de Cincias Agrrias 56(2):125-132.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Guimares SL, Baldani JI, Baldani VLD, Jacob-Neto J (2007). Adio de molibdnio ao inoculante turfoso com bactrias diazotrficas usado em duas cultivares de arroz irrigado. Pesquisa Agropecuria Brasileira 42:393-398.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hernandes A Buzetti S, Andreotti M, S ME (2010). Doses, fontes e pocas de aplicao de nitrognio em cultivares de arroz. Cincia e Agrotecnologia 34(1):307-312.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kppen W, Geiger R (1928). Klimate der Erde. Gotha: Verlag Justus Perthes. Kuss AV, Kuss VV, Lovato T, Flres ML (2007) Fixao de nitrognio e produo de cido indolactico in vitro por bactrias diazotrficas endofticas. Pesquisa Agropecuria Brasileira 42(10):1459-1465.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Malavolta E, Moraes MF (2007). Fundamentos do nitrognio e do enxofre na nutrio mineral das plantas cultivadas. In: Yamada, T; Abdalla, SRS e; Vitti, GC (Ed.). Nitrognio e enxofre na agricultura brasileira. Piracicaba: IPNI Brasil pp 189-249.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ministrio da Agricultura, Pecuria e Abastaecimento (MAPA) (2010). Instruo Normativa n30, de 12 de novembro de 2010 (MAPA). Dirio Oficial da Unio Federativa do Brasil.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Moura RS (2011). Lminas de gua, inoculao de sementes com Azospirillum brasilense e doses de nitrognio em arroz terras altas. Dissertao (Mestrado em Agronomia) - Faculdade de Engenharia, Universidade Estadual Paulista, Ilha Solteira P 59.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Neves MB, Buzetti S, ARF O, S ME (2004). Doses e pocas de aplicao de nitrognio em dois cultivares de arroz com irrigao suplementar. Acta Scientiarum 26(1):429-435.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Perin L, Silva MF, Ferreira JS, Canuto EL, Medeiros AFA, Olivares FL, Reis VM (2003). Avaliao da capacidade de estabelecimento endoftico de estirpes de Azospirillum e Herbaspirillum em milho e arroz. Agronomia 37(2):47-53.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Perrig D, Boiero ML, Masciarelli AO, Penna C, Ruiz AO, Cassn FD, Luna MV (2007). Plant-growth-promoting compounds produced by two agronomically important strains of Azospirillum brasilense, and implications for inoculant formulation. Applied Microbiolog and Biotechnology 75(1):1143-1150.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rojas CAL, Bayer C, Fontoura SMV, Vieiro F (2012). Volatilizao de amnia da ureia alterada por sistemas de preparo do solo e plantas de cobertura invernais no centro-sul do Paran. Revista Brasileira de Cincia do Solo 36(1):261-270.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sabino DCC, Ferreira JS, Guimares SL, Baldani VLD (2012). Bactrias diazotrficas como promotoras do desenvolvimento inicial de plntulas de arroz ENCICLOPDIA BIOSFERA, Centro Cientfico Conhecer 8(15):12.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tedesco MJ, Gianello C, Bissani CA, Bohnen H, Volkweiss SJ (1995). Anlises de solo, plantas e outros materiais. 2.ed. Porto Alegre, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, pp 174p. (Boletim Tcnico, 5).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[USDA (2017). World agricultural supply and demand estimates. Washington D. C.: United States Department of Agriculture, P. 12.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vieira Neto AS, Pires FR, Menezes CCE, Menezes JFS, Silva AG, Silva GP, Assis RL (2008). Formas de aplicao de inoculante e seus efeitos sobre a nodulao da soja. Revista Brasileira de Cincias do Solo 32(1):861-870.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vogel GF, Martinkoski L, Martins PJ, Bichel A (2013). Desempenho agronmico de Azospirillum brasilense na cultura do arroz: uma reviso. Revista em Agronegcios e Meio Ambiente 6(3):567-578.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>