<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2019.14619</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Potential of reduced agricultural lime application rates to increase yield and profitability of maize through microdosing in central Malawi - A short note]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Martin</surname>
            <given-names>Lolani</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Vernon</surname>
            <given-names>H. Kabambe</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">kabambev@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>29</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>05</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>785</fpage>
	  <lpage>790</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/A317EA763817">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/A317EA763817	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/A317EA763817">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/A317EA763817	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Maize (Zea mays L.) is a staple food crop in Malawi, with average yields of 1.8 -2.2 t ha-1 compared to potential yields of 5 to 10 t ha-1. In some areas, soil acidity is a serious constraint in crop production. The current recommendation is to apply 2.0 t ha-1 of lime as pre-plant broadcast and incorporated into soils with pHW lt; 5.5. A pilot study was conducted during 2015/2016 season at Bunda Campus (14deg; 35 Srsquo;;  33deg; 50 Ersquo;) to evaluate the response of reduced lime application rates of 0, 100, 250 and 500 kg ha-1 applied by  point placement or dollop method (mirodosing) in comparison to recommendation pre-plant broadcast application. A uniform fertilizer application of 69:23:0+4S was made on all plots. Gross Margin (GM) analysis, Value Cost Ratio (VCR) and Benefit-Cost Ratio (BCR) were undertaken. A gross Margin analysis was done using prevailing input/out values of 2019 at exchange rate of Malawi Kwacha, MK 745 = 1USD. Results showed that the lsquo;no limersquo; control (4.01 t ha-1) gave the lowest grain yield and was significantly (Plt;0.05) out-yielded by the rest of the treatments. The highest yield of 5.75 t ha-1 was observed from the 500 kg ha-1 application, while the recommended control of 2t/ha yielded 4.90 t ha-1. The BCR was gt;1.0 for all treatments at two price scenarios of US$0.201 kg-1 and US$0.268 kg-1 grain, but gt;2.0 only for 100, 250 and 500 kg ha-1 lime application rates. VCR ranged from 4.4 to 10.4, except for 2 t ha-1 treatment which had 0.78 and 1.05 at US$0.201 and US$0.268 kg-1 grain price, respectively.  The results demonstrated that there is potential in reduced lime application rates to increase yield of maize by microdosing of agricultural lime. This study has provided a solid basis for wider evaluation of the concepts for subsequent rolling out to famers.

	Key words: Dolomitic lime, soil acidity, microdose applications, aglime profitability.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ajayi OC, Akinifesi FK, Sileshi G, Kanjipite W (2009). Labour inputs and financial profitability of conventional and agroforestry-based soil fertility management practices in Zambia. Agrekon 48(3):276-292.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Blackie MJ, Mann CK (2005). The origin and concept of the starter pack. In: Levey S (ed) Starter packs: A strategy to fight hunger in developing Countries? Lessons from the Malawi Experience. CABI Publishing, reading, UK. pp. 15-27.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chilimba AD, Nkosi D (2014). Malawi fertilizer recommendations for maize production based on soil fertility status. Department of Agricultural Research Services, Lilongwe, Malawi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chilimba ADC (2005). Liming Recommendations for Crop Production in Malawi. A Paper Presented to the Agricultural Technology Release Committee, Ministry of Agriculture, Irrigation and Food Security. Lilongwe, Malawi. .]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chilimba ADC, Kabambe VH, Chigowo MT, Nyirenda M, Botomani L, Tembo Y (2013). Agricultural Lime Application for Improved Soil and Cop Productivity in Malawi. Soil Health Consortium of Malawi technical Bulletin for field extension personnel. Lilongwe University of Agriculture and Natural Resources.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chilimba ADC, Saka AR (1998). Soil Degradation: An overview of the Management and Rehabilitation of Soils in Malawi. A Paper Presented at an Expert Consultation Meeting on the Management of Degraded Soils in Southern and Eastern Africa, Harare, Zimbabwe.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[De Pauw EF (1994). The management of acid soils in Africa. Outlook on Agriculture 23:11-16.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dzanja J (2008). Labour requirements for major crops of Malawi. Unpublished report. Bunda College of Agriculture, Lilongwe Malawi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fairhurst T (2012). Handbook of Integrated Soil fertility Management. Africa Soil Health Consortium, Nairobi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Goulding KWT (2016). Soil acidification and the importance of liming agricultural soils with particular reference to the United Kingdom. Soil Use and Management 32:390-399.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Government of Malawi (GoM) (2012). Annual Agricultural Statistical Bulletin. Ministry of Agriculture, Irrigation and Water Development, Department of Agricultural Planning Services. Lilongwe.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[ICRISAT/MAI (2000). Cost-effective soil fertility management options for smallholder farmers in Malawi. Bulawayo, Zimbabwe: ICRISAT; and Lilongwe, Malawi: Ministry of Agriculture and Irrigation.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jones MJ, Kanyama GY (1975). Some physical and chemical properties of the soils of bunda College farm. Research Bulletin, Bunda College of Agriculture, University of Malawi 6:1-14.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kabambe VH, Chilimba ADC, Ngwira AR, Kambauwa G, Mbawe M Mapfumo P (2012). Using innovation platforms to scale out soil acidity ameliorating technologies in Dedza district in in central Malawi. African Journal of Biotechnology 11(3):561-569.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kabambe VH, Nambuzi Sc, Kauwa AE (2008). Role or herbicide and fertilizer application in integrated management of Striga asiatica in maize in Malawi. African Journal of Agricultural Research 3(12):140-146.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kabambe VH, Ngwira AR, Aune JB, Sitaula BK, Chilongo T (2018). Productivity and profitability of groundnut and maize in a semi-arid area of southern Malawi. African Journal of Agricultural Research 113(43):2399-2407.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kihara J, Huising J, Nziguheba G, Waswa BS, Njoroge S, Iwuafor E, Kibunja C, Esilaba AO, Coulibaly A (2015). Maize response to macronutrients and potential for profitability in sub-Saharan Africa. Nutrient Cycling in Agroecosystems P. 11.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kisinyo OP, Opala PA, Palapala V, Gudu SO, Othieno CO, Ouma E (2015). Micro-dosing of lime, phosphorus and nitrogen fertilizers effect on maize performance on an acid soil in Kenya. Sustainable Agriculture Research 4(2):21-30.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumwenda, JDT, Waddington SR, Snapp SS, Jones RB, Blackie MJ (1997). Soil Fertility Management in Southern Africa. pp. 157-172. In: Byerlee D and Eicher CK (eds). Africas Emerging Maize Revolution. Lynne Reiner Publishers, Colorado.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maida JHA (1985). Some physical and chemical properties of selected Malawi soils. Luso Journal of Science and Technology (Malawi) 6(1):1-10.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Marschner H (2011). Mineral Nutrition of Higher Plants. Academic Press. eBook.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[McCauley A, Jones C, Jocobsen J (2009). Soil pH and Organic Matter. Nutrient Management Module No. 8. 12 pp. Montana State University.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[MoAFS (2012). Ministry of Agriculture, Irrigation and Water Development. Guide to Agricultural Production and Natural Resources Management. Agricultural Communications Branch, Lilongwe, Ministry of Agriculture and Food Security Malawi 366p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mtonga YPG (2013). Effects of combining selected bio and inorganic fertilizers with or without lime on soil nutrient availability and maize crop response on Malawi acid soils. MSc Thesis.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ngulube S, Subramanyam P, Freeman HA, van de Merwe PJA, Chiyembekeza AJ (2001). Economics of groundnut Production in Malawi. ICRISAT international poster. ICRISAT, Lilongwe, Malawi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ngwira AR, Kabambe VH, Kambauwa G, Mhango WG, Mwale CD, Chimphero L, Chimbizi A, Mapfumo P (2012). Scaling out best fit legume technologies for soil fertility enhancement among smallholder farmers in Malawi. African Journal of Agricultural Research 7(6):918-928.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ngwira AR, Kabambe VH, Simwaka P, Kakoko K, Kamoyo K (2020). Productivity and profitability of maize-legume cropping systems under conservation agriculture among smallholder farmers in Malawi. Acta Agriculture, Section B - Soil and Plant Science P. 11
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[One Acre Fund (2016). Managing soil acidity with lime. 2015 trial report.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Onwonga RN, Lelei JJ, Freyer B, Friedel JK, Mwonga SM, Wandhawa P (2008). Low Cost Technologies for Enhancing N and P Availability and Maize (Zea mays L.) performance on Acid Soils. World Journal of Agricultural Sciences 4:862-873.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Snapp SS (1998). Soil nutrient status of smallholder farms in Malawi. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 29:2571-2588.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Takane T (2008). Labour use in smallholder agriculture in Malawi. African Study Monographs 29(4):183-200.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[The C, Meka SS, Ngokeu ELM, Bell JM, Mafouasson HA, Menkir A, Calba H, Zonkeng C, Atemkeng M, Horst WJ (2012). Maize grain yield response to changes in acid soil characteristics with yearly leguminous crop rotation, fallow, slash, burn and liming practices. International Journal of Plant and Soil Science 1(1):1-15.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tully C, Sullivan C, Weil R, Sanchez P (2015). The State of Soil Degradation in Sub-Saharan Africa: Baselines, Trejectories and Solutions. Sustainability 7(6):6523-6552.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yamoah C, Ngueguim M, Ngong C, Dias DKW (1996). Reduction of P fertilizer requirement using lime and Mucuna on high P-sorption soils of NW Cameroon. African Crop Science Journal 4(4):441-451.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>