<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2019.14604</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Analysing chicken meat production comparative advantage of South Africa]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>K.</surname>
            <given-names>V. Pilusa</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>A.</surname>
            <given-names>Belete</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>V.</surname>
            <given-names>A. Baloi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">pilusa.victor@yahoo.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>14</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>843</fpage>
	  <lpage>849</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/5D6252463858">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/5D6252463858	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/5D6252463858">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/5D6252463858	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The study examined the relative efficiency of producing chicken meat in South Africa, in 2017, and its comparative advantage in chicken meat production in Southern African Development Community (SADC). The study used the Policy Analysis Matrix (PAM) to calculate the net financial and economic profitability, Nominal Protection Coefficient of output (NPCO), Nominal Protection Coefficient of input (NPCI), Effective Protection Co-efficient (EPC), Private Cost Ratio (PCR) and Domestic Resource Cost (DRC). Data used in this study was taken from the statistics collected by the Department of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries (DAFF) and South African Poultry Association (SAPA). The findings, based on the indicators of NPCI, EPC and PCR conclude that the existing government policy environment tends to protect the interest of the chicken meat producers at the production level. The DRC results indicated that South Africa had comparative advantage of producing chicken meat in 2017.

	Key words: Domestic resource cost, policy analysis matrix, private cost ratio.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bureau for Food and Agricultural Policy (BFAP) (2016). Evaluating the competitiveness of the South African broiler value chain: A collaborative report by the Bureau for Food and Agricultural Policy and the National Agricultural Marketing Council.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Davids T, Meyer FH, Louw M (2013). Evaluating the effect of proposed tariff protection for the South African broiler industry. Agrekon 54(1):70-95.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[DAFF (2016). Department of Agriculture Forestry and Fisheries. Abstract of Agricultural Statistics 2016. Directorate Statistics and Economic Analysis. The Republic of South Africa. Resource Centre. Directorate: Knowledge and Information Management.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[DAFF (2017). Department of Agriculture Forestry and Fisheries.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Joubert JCN (2017). A quantitative and qualitative analysis of the South African broiler industry. Doctoral dissertation, University of the Free State.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Louw A, Schoeman JJ, Geyser JM (2011). Pork and Broiler industry supply chain study with emphasis on feed and feed-related issues. National Agricultural Marketing Council, South Africa.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lubinga MH, Mazibuko N, Ngqangweni S, Potelwa YX, Nyhodo B (2018). Impact of export promotion and market development on social welfare in South Africa: Evidence from the agricultural sector. African Evaluation Journal 6:2.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mahlanza B, Mendez E, Vink N (2003). Comparative advantage of organic wheat production in the Western Cape. Agrekon 42(2):144-162.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Masters WA, Winter-Nelson A (1995). Measuring the comparative advantage of agricultural activities: domestic resource costs and the social cost-benefit ratio. American Journal of Agricultural Economics 77(2):243-250.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Monke EA, Pearson SR. (1989). The policy analysis matrix for agricultural development. Cornell University Press, Ithaca, NY, USA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Schmidhuber J (2008). Impact of an increased biomass use on agricultural markets, prices and food security: A longer-term perspective. In: Energy Security in Europe: Proceedings from the Conference Energy Security in Europe, pp. 133-170).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SAPA (2017). South African Poultry Association. Broiler and egg industry stats summary for 2017.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tsakok I (1990). Agricultural price policy and practitioners guide to partial equilibrium analysis. Ithaca, NY: Cornell University Press.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Van Rooyen CJ, Esterhuizen D, Doyer OT (1999). How competitive is agribusiness in the South African Food Commodity Chain? Working Paper: 1999-01. Department of Agricultural Economics, Extension and Rural Development.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yao S (1997). Comparative advantage and corp diversification: A PAM for Thai agriculture. Journal of Agricultural Economics 48(2):211-222.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>