<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2020.14695</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Production of liquid fertilizer by fermented livestock liquid and application on crops]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yong-Hong</surname>
            <given-names>Lin</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yi-Lang</surname>
            <given-names>Wei</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Juei-Yu</surname>
            <given-names>Chiu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Tai-Yuan</surname>
            <given-names>Chen</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Chih-Hang</surname>
            <given-names>Chang</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">yonghong@mail.npust.edu.tw</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>03</day>
			<month>01</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>29</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>752</fpage>
	  <lpage>757</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/0D0B67463809">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/0D0B67463809	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/0D0B67463809">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/0D0B67463809	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The livestock liquid commonly contains humic acid, amino acids and minerals; hence, it can be used for the fertilization of crops. These studies were conducted to examine the use of livestock fermented liquid in producing liquid fertilizers and irrigation application on two kinds of crops (tomato and wax apple). The experiments were designed as common liquid fertilizer and diluted by groundwater (CF), fermented livestock liquid fertilizer and diluted by groundwater (LF), fermented livestock liquid and diluted by groundwater (LL), fermented livestock liquid fertilizer and diluted by effluent (LFE), and the treatment of no liquid fertilizer (CK). The results showed that the highest values for fruit weight, width and length were obtained by the treatment of LF, and the sugar degree value was registered by the treatment of LFE. Hence, the treatment of LF was superior compared to CF. Analysis of microbiology in LF, CF and LL showed that the microorganismsrsquo; species were most abundant in the LF compared to the other two samples. The main microorganisms were Bacillus mycoides and Bacillus subtilis. Anthracnose of mango was inhibited in specific isolates of the B. subtilis in LF. The results provided the primary information on reusing of livestock waste for crops.

	Key words: Livestock liquid, effluent, tomato, wax apple]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Baker DE, Suhr NH (1992). Atomic absorption and flame emission spectrometry. In A.L. Page, R. H. Miller and D. R. Keeneys. (eds.) Methods of Soil Analysis, Part 2. Agronomy Monograph No. 9. 2nd edition. ASA-SSSA, WI. pp. 13-26.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bao W, Yang Y, Fu T, Xie GH (2019). Estimation of livestock excrement and its biogas production potential in China. Journal of Cleaner Production 229(5):1158-1166.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chang SH (1981). Current plant analysis in our province. Fertilizer demand diagnoses technology. Special Issue No. 13, Taiwan Agricultural Research Institute, pp. 53-59.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chen Y, Cheng JJ, Creamer KS (2008). Inhibition of anaerobic digestion process: a review. Bioresource Technology 99(10):4044-4064.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cope JT, Evans CE (1985). Soil testing. Advances in Soil Science 1:201-228.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Duan M, Zhang Y, Zhou B, Wang Q, Gu J, Liu G, Qin Z, Li Z (2019). Changes in antibiotic resistance genes and mobile genetic elements during cattle manure composting after inoculation with Bacillus Subtilis. Bioresource Technology 292:122011.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Holm-Nielsen JB, Al Seadi T, Oleskowicz-Popiel P (2009). The future of anaerobic digestion and biogas utilization. Bioresource Technology 100(12):5478-5484.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jiao GS, Kim S, Moayeri M, Thai A, Cregar-Hernandez L, McKasson L, OMalley S, Leppla SH, Johnson AT(2018). Small molecule inhibitors of anthrax edema factor. Bioorganic and Medicinal Chemistry Letters 28(1):134-139.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kanu PJ, Kanu JB, Sandy H, Kande BA, Mornya PMP, Huiming Z (2009). Optimization of enzymatic hydrolysis of defatted sesame flour by different proteases and their effect on the functional properties of the resulting protein hydrolysate. American Journal of Food Technology 4(6):226-240.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kelessidis A, Stasinakis AS (2012). Comparative study of the methods used for treatment and final disposal of sewage sludge in European countries. Waste Management 32(7):1186-1195.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kholmanskiy A, Smirnov A, Sokolov A, Proshkin Y (2019). Modeling of extraction mechanism of mineral elements by plants. Current Plant Biology, P. 9.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lin YH, Chiu JY (2019). Studies on the sod culture and the management of soil moisture for the improvement of wax apple quality. African Journal of Biotechnology 18(3):719-725.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Liu K, Wanga X, Young M (2014). Effect of bentonite/potassium sorbate coatings on the quality of mangos in storage at ambient temperature. Journal of Food Engineering 137(1):16-22.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[McLean EO (1982). Soil pH and lime requirement. In A.L. Pag, R.H. Miller and D.R. Keeneys.(eds.) Methods of Soil Analysis, Part 2. Agronomy Monograph No.9. 2nd edition.ASA-SSSA, WI. pp.199-224.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Murphy J, Riley JP (1962). A modified single solution method for determination of phosphate in natural waters. Analytica Chimica Acta 27(1):31-36.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nelson DW, Sommer LE (1982). Total carbon, organic carbon and organic matter. In: A.L. Page. Miller and D.R. Keeneys. (eds.) Method of Soil Analysis, Part 2. Agronomy Monograph No. 9. 2nd edition. ASA-SSSA, WI. pp. 383-411.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Richardson SD, Ternes TA (2011). Water analysis: emerging contaminants and current issues. Analytical Chemistry 83(9):4614-4648.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vijayakumar S, Durgadevi S, Arulmozhi P, Rajalakshmi S, Gopalakrishnan T, Parameswari N (2018). Effect of seaweed liquid fertilizer on yield and quality of Capsicum annum L. Acta Ecologica Sinica 39(5):406-410.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Weiland P (2010). Biogas production: current state and perspectives. Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology 85(6):849-860.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xu JC, Huang LM, Chen C, Wang J, Long XX (2019). Effective lead immobilization by phosphate rock solubilization mediated by phosphate rock amendment and phosphate solubilizing bacteria. Chemosphere 237(1):1-9.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhao Z, Liao D, Sun J, Tong Z, Huang K, Sun G, Wu Z (2012). Kinetic model of enzymatic hydrolysis of protein about the protein of silkworm pupae - Alcalase system. International Conference on Biomedical Engineering and Biotechnology pp. 356-359.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>