<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2020.14826</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Fertilizer-nitrogen use optimization for Tef in South Wollo Zone of Ethiopia]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Abebe</surname>
            <given-names>Getu Asfaw</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Samuel</surname>
            <given-names>Adissie Gedamu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Habtemariam</surname>
            <given-names>Teshome Abushe</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Tilahun</surname>
            <given-names>Taye Mekonen</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Seid</surname>
            <given-names>Belay Muhamed</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Tadesse</surname>
            <given-names>Hailu Shibeshi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">abegetu3@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>08</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>811</fpage>
	  <lpage>818</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/68FB5D363821">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/68FB5D363821	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/68FB5D363821">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/68FB5D363821	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Tef [Eragrotis tef] is a major staple cereal crop in Ethiopia but yields are low due to inadequate nutrient supply and other constraints. A field study was conducted in 2014 and 2015 in Jamma district of South Wollo Zone of Amhara Region to determine the economic optimum rate of fertilizer-N for tef. Fertilizer-N rates of 0, 23, 46, 69, 92, 115 and 138 kg ha-1 were evaluated. The randomized complete block design with three replications was used. The fertilizer-N rate means fit a quadratic yield response function with R2=0.25**. The maximum mean grain and straw yields were recorded with 138 kg N ha-1 which was not statistically different from the 92 and 115 kg ha-1 N rates. The net economic returns to N were optimized with the 115 and 92 kg ha-1 N rates with respective net benefits of Ethiopian Birr 30508 and 28971 ha-1 and with marginal rate returns of 236 and 288%, respectively. The highest value to cost ratio (VCR) and highest benefit to cost ratio (BCR) of 10.9 and 5.2, respectively were obtained with 46 kg N ha-1. Using the yield response function determined, the profit-maximizing optimal rate of N was found to be 117 kg N ha-1. Therefore, for financially constrained farmers 46 kg N ha-1 is recommended, while for farmers without financial constraints 92 to 117 kg N ha-1 can be recommended for economic optimum return from tef production on the Vertisols in Jamma District and similar agroecologies.

	Key words: Economic optimum, Jamma district, nitrogen fertilizer, yields response of tef.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abebe G, Heluf G, Tareke B (2013). Evaluation of Slow Release Urea Fertilizer on the yields of Wheat and Teff on Vertisols in Ethiopia, Haramaya University, Haramaya, Lap Lambert Academic Publishing. pp. 42-43.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abedenna D, Wakene N, Fite G, Birhanu D (2006). Response of tef to nitrogen and phosphorus fertilizers under farmers conditions. In: Asfaw Zeleke, Hailu Tefera, Gemechu Keneni, Amsalu Ayana, Tesfaye Tefera, Solomon Assefa, Desalegn Debelo and Belay Simane (eds.). Proceedings of the Eleventh Conference of the Crop Science Society of Ethiopia, 26-28 April 2004, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, pp 176-181.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Alemayehu A, Minale L, Tilahun T (2010). Yield response of tef (Eragrostis tef) to nitrogen application in relation to precursor crops on Nitosols of Adet area, northwestern Ethiopia. In: Ermias Abate (ed.). Proceedings of the Third Annual Regional Conference on Completed Crop Research Activities, 1-4 September, 2008. Amhara Region Agricultural Research Institute. Bahir Dar, Ethiopia, pp. 98-103.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Alemayehu A, Minale L, Tilahun T, Abrham M (2007). Determination of optimum rates of nitrogen and phosphorus fertilization for tef (Eragrostis tef) production in different agro-ecological areas of northwestern Ethiopia. In: Ermias Abate., Akalu Teshome, Alemayehu, Asefa, Melaku Wale, Tadesse Dessalegn, and Tilahun Tadesse (eds.). Proceedings of the First Annual Regional Conference on Completed Crop Research Activities, 14 - 17 August, 2006. Amhara Region Agricultural Research Institute. Bahir Dar, Ethiopia, pp 60-67.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Alkamper J (1973). The fertilization of teff. Journal of Association of Advance Agricultural Science in Africa 1:56- 65.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Asnakew W (1994). Soil fertility and management in the drylands. In: Development of Technologies for the Dry Land Farming Areas of Ethiopia. Reddy M.S. and Kidane G. (eds.), pp. 70-81. IAR. Addis Ababa.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cassman KG, Plant RE (1992). A model to predict crop response to applied fertilizer nutrients in heterogeneous fields. Fertilizer Research 31:151-163. International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center (CIMMYT) (1988). From Agronomic data to Farmers Recommendations: An economic training manual. Revised Edition. Mexico, D.F. 200p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cottenie A (1980). Soil and plant testing as a basis of fertilizer recommendations. FAO Soil Bulletin 38/2. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome, Italy.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Central Statistical Agency (CSA) (2015). Agricultural sample survey 2014/2015. Volume I. Report on area and production of major crops. Statistical Bulletin 578. Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dobermann A, Dawe D, Roetter RP, Cassman KG (1992). Reversal of rice yield decline in a long-term continuous cropping experiment. Agronomy Journal 92:633-643.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Doris P (2002). More about Ethiopian food: Teff. University of Washington, USA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ethiopian Soil Information System (EthioSIS) (2014). Soil fertility mapping and fertilizer blending. Agricultural Transformation Agency (ATA) Report. EthioSIS, Ministry of Agriculture, Addis Ababa.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) (2006). Plant nutrition for food security: A guide for integrated nutrient management. FAO, Fertilizer and Plant Nutrition Bulletin 16, Rome, Italy.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fassil K, Charles Y (2009). Soil fertility status and Numass fertilizer recommendation of Typic Hapluusterts in the Northern Highlands of Ethiopia. World Appllied Science Journal 6:1473-1480.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fissehaye M, Mitiku H, Fassil K, Alemteshay T, Charles Y (2009). Response of teff [Eragrostis (teff) Trotter] to phosphorus and nitrogen on a Vertisol at North Ethiopia. Journal of the Drylands 2(1):8-14.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Getachew A (1991). A study of the farming systems of some Ethiopian highland Vertisols areas (draft report). ILCA (International Livestock Centre for Africa), Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. 150p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gilles BL, John RW, John ER, Paul HM, Noura Z (2000). Comparison of three statistical models describing potato yield response to nitrogen fertilizer. Agronomy Journal 92:902-908.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hazelton P, Murphy B (2007). Interpreting soil test results: What do all the numbers mean? 2nd Edition. CSIRO Publishing 152p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jones JB (2003). Agronomic Handbook: Management of Crops, Soils, and Their Fertility. CRC Press LLC, Boca Raton, Florida, USA. 482p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kamara CS, Haque I (1988). Characteristics of Vertisols at ILCA research and outreach sites in Ethiopia. Revised version. Plant Science Division Working Document B5, ILCA (International Livestock Centre for Africa), Addis ababa, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumela B, Thomas A (2016). Performance of yield attributes, yield and economics of teff (Eragrostis tef) influenced by various row spacing, nitrogen and phosphorus fertilizers. African Journal of Plant Science 10(10):234-237.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Legesse A (2004). Response of teff [Eragrostis tef (Zucc) Trotter] to applied nitrogen and phosphorus in Sirinka, North eastern Ethiopia. M.Sc. Thesis, Haramaya University, pp. 1-68.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Miller D (2009). Teff grass crop overview and forage production guide, 2nd edition, A guide for producers, extension, educators and seed marketers.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Minale L, Alemayehu A, Tilahun T, Abrham M (2004). The response of tef to nitrogen and phosphorus applications at Bichena and Yilmana-Denssa areas, northwestern Ethiopia. In: Asfaw Zeleke, Getachew Belay, Belay Simane, Bulcha Weyessa and Nigussie Alemayehu (eds.). Proceedings of the Tenth Conference of the Crop Science Society of Ethiopia, 19-21 June 2001, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, pp.135-144.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[National Fertilizer and Inputs Unit (NFIU) (1992). Results of NPK fertilizer trials conducted on major cereal crops (1988-1991) Addis, Ababa Ethiopia. ADD/NFIU Joint Working Paper No. 43, FOA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[National Fertilizer and Inputs Unit (NFIU) (1993). Wheat results of the FTS, ITS and DSFT, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nosberg S, Roseberg R, Charlton B, Shock C (2009). A new warm seasonal annual grass for Oregon. Lost Crops of Africa, Grains 1:214-235.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Statistical Analysis System (SAS) (2004). Institute. SAS/STAT users guide. Proprietary software version 9.00. SAS Institute, Inc., Cary, NC.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Spaenij DL, Kooy WY, Koning F (2005). The Ethiopian cereal tef in celiac disease. New England Journal of Medicine 353:1748-1750.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Stoorvogel JJ, Smaling EMA (1990). Assessment of soil nutrient depletion in Sub-Saharan Africa: 1983-2000. Volume Il: Nutrient balances per crop and per Land Use Systems. Report 28 Wageningen (The Netherlands).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tekalign M, Haque I, Kamara CS (1988). Phosphorus status of Ethiopian Vertisols: management of Vertisols in Sub-Saharan Africa. In: Proceeding of the conference held at international livestock Centre for Africa (ILCA), 31 Aug-4 Sept 1987, 1988, pp. 232-252.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tekalign M, Selamyihun K, Mesfin A, Teklu E (1996). Review of soil fertility studies conducted on tef: Experience of Alemaya University of Agriculture. Alemaya University, Ethiopia 22p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tekalign T (1991). Soil, plant, water, fertilizer, animal manure and compost analysis. Working Document No. 13. International Livestock Research Center for Africa, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tekalign M, Teklu E, Balesh T (2001). Soil Fertility and Plant Nutrition Research on Tef in Ethiopia. In: Hailu Tefera, Getachew Belay and M. Sorrels (eds.). Narrowing the Rift: Tef Research and Development. Proceedings of the International Workshop on Tef Genetics and Improvement, 16-19 October 2000, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Ethiopia Agricultural Research Organization, Addis Ababa pp. 191-200.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tulema B, Zapta F, Aune JB, Sitaula B (2005). Nitrogen fertilization, soil type and cultivars effects on N use efficiency in tef (Eragrostis tef (Zucc.) Trotter). Nutrient Cycling in Agroecosystems 71:203-211.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wakene N, Yifru A (2013). Soil fertility management studies on tef. In: Kebebew Assefa, Solomon Chanyalew and Zerihun Tadele (eds.) 2013. Achievements and Prospects of Tef Improvement; Proceedings of the Second International Workshop, November 7-9, 2011, Debre Zeit, Ethiopia. Ethiopian Institute of Agricultural Research, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia; Institute of Plant Sciences, University of Bern, Switzerland. Printed at Stampfli AG, 3001 Bern, Switzerland. ISBN: 978-3-033-03818-9.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhejun L, Kevin FB, Kelly RT, Jarai M, Mohammad B, Guangyao W (2014). Cultivar and N fertilizer rate affect yield and N use efficiency in irrigated durum wheat. Crop Science 54:1175-1183.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>