<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2019.14670</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Severity and prevalence of the destructive fall armyworm on maize in Uganda: A case of 
Bulambuli District]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Buteme</surname>
            <given-names>Sharon</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Masanza</surname>
            <given-names>Michael</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Masika</surname>
            <given-names>Fred Bwayo</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">masikafred2012@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>12</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>24</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>777</fpage>
	  <lpage>784</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/E6D997463815">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/E6D997463815	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/E6D997463815">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/E6D997463815	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Maize kernel contains a large quantity of carbohydrates, proteins, vitamins, oils, fats and competes favorably with root and tuber crops as a rich energy source. In Uganda, the per capita consumption ranges from 28 to 125 kg per annum. However, the yields remain low, fluctuating around 1.5 tons per hectare. Although some losses to maize production occur through the post-harvest period, pre-harvest factors such as biotic and abiotic constraints significantly affect its production.  The most important biotic constraints include pests and diseases. Among the pests, Lepidopterans such as the fall armyworm (FAW) (Spodoptera frugiperda JE Smith) has become an important pest of maize during the early growing stages of the crop. Yet there is no information on the destructive levels of this pest in maize fields and this hinders management options for this pest. To determine the incidence, severity and prevalence of the FAW which may be responsible for low yields and poor maize quality, a survey was carried out in Bulambuli district in Uganda. Forty fields were sampled in Bwinkhonge Sub County to determine the level of damage caused by this pest. The severity of damage on leaves (df = 9, chi;2 = 87.66, P = 0.000*) ears (df = 9, chi;2 = 299.2, P = 0.000*) and kernels (df = 7, chi;2 = 19.9, P = 0.005*) was high and significantly different in two parishes surveyed.

	Key words: Larvae, incidence, pests, damage.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abdel-rhman MM (2015). Improvement the production of maize ( Zea mays L .) crop by using particle bombardment. International Conference on Biological, Civil and Environmental Engineering (BCEE-2015) Feb. 3-4, 2015 Bali (Indonesia).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agona A, Nabawanuka J, Muyinza H (1999). An overview of maize in Uganda. Postharvest programme, NARO Uganda.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aguirre AL, Hernndez-Jurez A, Flores M, Cerna E, Landeros J, Fras AG, Harris KM (2016). Evaluation of foliar damage by Spodoptera frugiperda (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae) to genetically modified corn (Poales: Poaceae) in Mexico. Florida Entomologist 99, 2.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Baudron F, Mainassara AZ, Chaipa I, Chari N, Chinwada P (2019). Understanding the factors influencing fall armyworm (Spodoptera frugiperda J.E. Smith) damage in African smallholder maize fields and quantifying its impact on yield. A case study in Eastern Zimbabwe, Crop Protection 120:141-150.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Daly J, Hamrick D, Gereffi G, Guinn A (2016). Maize value chains in East Africa F-38202-RWA-1. Center on globalization, governance  competitiveness, Duke University pp. 1-49.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Davis FM, Williams WP (1992). Visual rating scales for screening whorl-stage corn for resistance to fall armyworm. Mississippi Agricultural  Forestry Experiment Station, Technical Bulletin 186, Mississippi State University, MS39762, USA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) (2014). Analysis of price incentives for maize in Uganda. Technical notes series, MAFAP, by Ahmed, M. and Ojangole, S., Rome.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[FAO and CABI. (2019). Community-based fall armyworm (Spodoptera frugiperda) monitoring, early warning and management, training of trainers manual, first edition 112 p. Licence: cc by-nc-sa 3.0 igo]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Goergen G, Kumar PL, Sankung SB, Togola A, Tam M (2016). First report of outbreaks of the fall armyworm Spodoptera frugiperda (J E Smith) (Lepidoptera, Noctuidae), a new alien invasive pest in West and Central Africa. PLoS ONE 11(10):e0165632.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Grzywacz D, Stevenson PC, Mushobozi WL, Belmain S, Wilson K (2014). The use of indigenous ecological resources for pest control in Africa. Food Security 6:71-86.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hailu G, Saliou N, Khan RZ, Ochatum N, Sevgan S (2018). Maize-legume intercropping and push-pull for management of fall armyworm, stemborers, and Striga in Uganda pp. 2513-2522.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Harrison RD, Thierfelder C, Baudron F, Chinwadad P, Midegae C, Schaffner U, van den Berggg J (2019). Agro-ecological options for fall armyworm (Spodoptera frugiperda JE Smith) management: Providing low-cost, smallholder friendly solutions to an invasive pest, Journal of Environmental Management 243:318-330.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hijmans RJ, Cameron SE, Parra JL, Jones PG, Jarvis A (2005). Very high resolution interpolated climate surfaces for global land areas. International Journal of Climatology 25(15):1965-1978.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumar D, Jhariya A N (2013). Nutritional , medicinal and economical importance of corn : A Mini Review. Research Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences 2(7):7-8.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumela T, Simiyu J, Sisay B, Likhayo P, Mendesil E, Gohole L, Tefera T (2018). Farmers knowledge, perceptions, and management practices of the new invasive pest, fall armyworm (Spodoptera frugiperda) in Ethiopia and Kenya. International Journal of Pest Management,
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Liebig T, Jassogne L, Rahn E, Lderach P, Poehling H-M, Kucel P, Van Asten P, Avelino J (2016). Towards a collaborative research: A case study on linking science to farmers perceptions and knowledge on arabica coffee pests and diseases and its management. PLoS ONE 11(8):e0159392.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Masika FB, Masanza M, Aluana G, Barrigossi JAF, Kizito EB (2017a). Abundance , distribution and effects of temperature and humidity on arthropod fauna in different rice ecosystems in Uganda. Journal of Entomology and Zoology Studies. 5(5):964-973]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Masika FB, Kisekka R, Alicai T, Tugume AK (2017b). Incidence of viruses and virus-like diseases of watermelons and pumpkins in Uganda , a hitherto none-investigated pathosystem. African Journal of Agricultural Research 12(3):177-191
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Midega CAO, Pittchara OJ, Pickett AJ, Hailu WG, Khana RZ (2018). A climate-adapted push-pull system e ff ectively controls fall armyworm, Spodoptera frugiperda ( JE Smith ), in maize in East Africa, Crop Protection. Elsevier 105(2018):10-15.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nono-Womdim R, Swai IS, Green SK, Gebre-Selassie K, Laterrot H, Marchoux G, Opena RT (1996). Tomato viruses in Tanzania: identification, distribution and disease incidence. South African Society of Horticultural Scences pp. 41-44.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Otim MH, Tay WT, Walsh TK, Kanyesigye D, Adumo S, Abongosi J, Ochen S, Sserumaga J, Alibu S, Abalo G, Asea G, Agona A (2018). Detection of sister-species in invasive populations of the fall armyworm Spodoptera frugiperda (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae) from Uganda. PLoS ONE 13(4):e0194571.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pandey P, Irulappan V, Bagavathiannan MV, Senthil-Kumar M (2017). Impact of combined abiotic and biotic stresses on plant growth and avenues for crop improvement by exploiting physio-morphological traits. Frontiers in Plant Science 8:537.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Prasanna JE, Huesing RE, Virginia MP (2018). Fall Armyworm in Africa: A Guide for Integrated Pest Management, First Edition. Mexico, CDMX: CIMMYT.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rouf Shah T, Prasad K, Kumar P (2016). Maize- a potential source of human nutrition and health: A review. Cogent Food and Agriculture. Cogent 54(1):1-9.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sparks AN (1986). Fall armyworm ( Lepidoptera : Noctuidae ): Potential for area-wide management. Florida Entomological Society 69(3):603-614.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Stevens T, Madani K (2016). Future climate impacts on maize farming and food security in Malawi, Scientific Reports. Nature Publishing Group 6:1-14.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thierfelder C, Niassy S, Midega C, Sevgan S, van der Berg J, Prasanna BM, Baudron F, Harrison R (2018). Low-Cost Agronomic Practices and Landscape Management Approaches to Control FAW. In: Prasanna, B.M., Huesing, J.E., Eddy, R., Peschke, V.M. (Eds.), Fall Armyworm in Africa: A Guide for Integrated Pest Management. CIMMYT, Mexico CDMX pp. 89-96.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>