<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Agricultural Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1991-637X</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJAR2019.14620</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Role of leaf rolling on agronomic performances of durum wheat subjected to water stress]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Amal</surname>
            <given-names>Ben-Amar</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Anne-Alinor</surname>
            <given-names>Vry</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Herv</surname>
            <given-names>Sentenac</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Abdelaziz</surname>
            <given-names>Bouizgaren</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Said</surname>
            <given-names>Mahboub</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Nasser</surname>
            <given-names>Elhaq Nsarellah</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Keltoum</surname>
            <given-names>El Bouhmadi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">benamar2003@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>30</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>13</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>16</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>791</fpage>
	  <lpage>810</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/7FFC4FE63819">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/7FFC4FE63819	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/7FFC4FE63819">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-full-text-pdf/7FFC4FE63819	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[In arid and semi-arid climates characterized by low rainfall with a great annual and inter-annual irregularity, drought can occur at any time inducing large losses in crop yield. Leaf rolling is one of the adaptive morphological responses to the water deficit observed in a number of species including cereals. It reduces the leaf area exposed to sunlight and transpiration. The aim of the present work was to characterize the agronomical impact of water stress on a set of 16 Moroccan durum wheat varieties and to examine the possible correlations between leaf rolling and agronomic performances of these varieties. Experiments were conducted during three cropping seasons on a soil with a clay-loam texture at Tamellalet, in Marrakech region. The water stress was applied for one week to the studied varieties at tillering, and the degree of leaf rolling was determined at the end of the stress period. Strong differences between the varieties in the degree of leaf rolling upon water stress and in the ability to counteract drought were observed. Varieties displaying high leaf rolling showed less reduction in the yield components (number of ears per plant, number of grains per ear and weight of grains). The strong correlation observed between the degree of leaf rolling and maintaining of agronomic performance suggests that leaf rolling can be a criterion for water stress tolerance in durum wheat. This trait could thus be used as a morphological marker of tolerance to water stress.

	Key words: Durum wheat, water stress, leaf rolling, agronomic traits, grain yield, drought tolerance, Morocco.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amigues JP, Debaeke P, Itier B, Lemaire G, Seguin B, Tardieu F, Thomas A ( 2006). Scheresse et agriculture. Rduire la vulnrabilit de lagriculture  un risque accru de manque deau. Expertise scientifique collective, synthse du Rapport INRA (France). pp 72.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amokrane A, Bouzerzour H, Benmahammed A, Djekoun A (2002). Caractrisation des varits locales, syriennes et europennes de bl dur values en zone semi-aride daltitude. Sciences et Technologie C, Biotechnologies:pp. 33-38.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anderson WK (2010). Closing the gap between actual and potential yield of rainfed wheat. The impacts on environment, management and cultivar. Field Crops Research. pp.14-22.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Assem N, El Hafid L, Haloui B, El Atmani K (2006). Effets du stress hydrique appliqu au stade trois feuilles sur le rendement en grains de dix varits de bl cultives au Maroc oriental. Science et changements plantaires/Scheresse 17(4):499-505.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Begg JE (1980). Morphological adaptations of leaves to water stress. In Adaptation of plants to water and high temperature stress. pp.33-42.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Belaid A, Nsarellah N, Laamari A, Nachit M, Amri A (2003). Assessing the economic impact of durum wheat research in Morocco. International Center for Agricultural Research in the Dry Areas. pp. 51.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Belhassen E, This D, Monneveux P (1995). Ladaptation gntique aux contraintes de la scheresse. Cahiers Agricultures. pp. 251-261.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bogale A, Tesfaye K, Geleto T (2011). Morphological and physiological attributes associated to drought tolerance of Ethiopian durum wheat genotypes under water deficit condition. JBES: pp. 22-36.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bois JF, Dizes J, Lasceve G (1987). Rponse du riz  lapplication dacide abscissique exogne : Fermeture stomatique et enroulement foliaire. Comptes rendus de lAcadmie des sciences. Srie 3, Sciences de la vie 305(11) :449-452]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chennafi H, Aidaoui A, Bouzerzour H, Saci A (2006). Yield response of durum wheat (Triticum durum Desf.) cultivar Waha to deficit irrigation under semi-arid growth conditions. Asian J. Plant Sci. pp. 854-860.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Debaeke P, Puech J, Casal M (1996). Elaboration du rendement de bl dhiver en condition de dficit hydrique. Mise au point et test dun modle de stimulation de la culture de bl dhiver en conditions dalimentation hydriques et azote varies. Agron. pp. 25-46.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Duvick DN (2005). The contribution of breeding to yield advances in maize (Zea mays L.) Advances in agronomy 86:83-145.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fisher RA (1973). The effect of water stress at various stages of development in yield processes in wheat. In Plant Response to Climatic Factors Proceedings of theuppsala Symposium pp. 233- 241.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hamon, S. (2007). L amlioration de la rsistance  la scheresse]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[peut-elle tre base sur les mthodes de slection traditionnelle et/ou sur les mthodes biotechnologiques modernes. Possibilits et limites respectives. Acte des JSIRAUF, Hanoi 6-9.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hu N, Lu CG, Yao KM, Zou JS (2009). Simulation on distribution of photosynthetically active radiation in canopy and optimum leaf rolling index in rice with rolling leaves. Rice Sci. pp.217-225.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hsiao TC, OToole JC, Yambao EB, Turner NC (1984). Influence of osmotic adjustment on leaf rolling and tissue death in rice (Oryza sativa L.). Plant Physiology. pp. 338-341.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Itoh JI, Nonomura KI, Ikeda K, Yamaki S, Inukai Y, Yamagishi H, Kitano H, Nagato Y (2005). Rice plant development: from zygote to spikelet. Plant and cell physiology 46(1):23-47.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jane WN, Chiang SHT (1991). Morphology and development of bulliform cells in Arundo formosana Hack. Taiwania International Journal of Life Sciences 36(1)]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kantety R, Diab A, Sorrells M (2005). Comparative genetics of durum wheat and other triticeae. In: Royo C, Nachit M, di Fonzo N, Araus J, Pfeiffer W, Slafer G (Eds.), Durum Wheat Breeding: Current Approaches and Future Strategies. Haworth Press, New York, USA, pp. 209-223.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kadioglu A, Terzi R, Saruhan N, Saglam A (2012). Current advances in the investigation of leaf rolling caused by biotic and abiotic stress factors. Plant Science. 182 : 42-48.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Karrou M (2003). Conduite du bl au Maroc. Institut National de la recherche agronomique (INRA), Rabat :1-57.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kobata T, Palta JA, Turner NC (1992). Rate of development of post-anthesis water deﬁcit and grain ﬁlling of spring wheat. Crop science 32(5):1238-1242.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Laberche JC (2004). La nutrition de la plante. In Biologie Vgtale. Dunod. 2e (d). Paris. pp. 154-163.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Li C, Zou X, Zhang C, Shao Q, Liu J, Liu B, Li H, Zhao T, (2016a). OsLBD3-7 overexpression induced adaxially rolled leaves in rice. PLoS One 11(6):e0156413.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Li L, Shi ZY, Li L, Shen GZ, Wang XQ, An LS, Zhang JL (2010). Overexpression of ACL1 (abaxially curled leaf 1) increased bulliform cells and induced abaxial curling of leaf blades in rice. Molecular plant, 3(5):807-817.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Li YY, Shen A, Xiong W, Sun QL, Luo Q, Song T, Li Z.L, Luan WJ( 2016b). Overexpression of OsHox32 results in pleiotropic effects on plant type architecture and leaf development in rice. Rice 9(1): 46.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[MAPM Ministre de lAgriculture et de la Pche Maritime, 2014. Lagriculture marocaine en chiffres.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[MAPMDREF Ministre de lagriculture, de la pche maritime du Dveloppement Rural et des Eaux et Forts, 2016. Lagriculture en chiffres.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mongensen VO, Jensen HE, Abduerab MD (1985). Grain yield, yield components, drought sensitivity and water use efficiency of spring wheat subjected to water stress at various growth stages Irrigation Science 6(2):131-140
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Monneveux, P.,  Belhassen, E. (1996). The diversity of drought adaptation in the wide. In Drought Tolerance in Higher Plants: Genetical, Physiological and Molecular Biological Analysis (pp. 7-14). Springer, Dordrecht.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Monneveux P, Reynolds MP, Gonzalez-Santoyo H, Pena RJ, Mayr L, Zapata F (2004). Relationships between grain yield, flag leaf morphology, carbon isotope discrimination and ash content in irrigated wheat. Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science 190(6):395-401.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Moon J, Hake S (2011). How a leaf gets its shape. Current opinion in plant biology 14(1):24-30
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Moore R, Clarke WD (1998). Botany. 2nd edition. WCB/McGraw Hill, Dubuque, IA, USA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Moulia B (1994). The biomechanics of leaf rolling. Biomimetics, 267-281.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nachit MM, Picard E, Monneveux P, Labhilili M, Baum M, Rivoal R (1998). Prsentation dun programme international damlioration du bl dur pour le bassin mditerranen. Cahiers Agricultures 7(6):510-515]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nsarellah N, Amamou A, Taghouti M, Annicchiarico P (2011). Adaptation of Moroccan durum wheat varieties from different breeding eras. Journal of Plant Breeding and Crop Science 3(2):34-40]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ortiz Ferrara G, Mulitze D, Yau SK (1991). Bread wheat breeding for tolerance to thermal stresses occuring in West Asia and North Africa. In Improvement and Management of Winter Cereals under Temperature, Drought and Salinity Stresses, Acevedo, A., Fereres, E., Gimenez, C. and Srivastava, J.P. (eds). INIA, Madrid, pp. 267-282.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[OToole JC, Cruz RT (1979). Leaf rolling and transpiration. Plant Sci. Lett. 16(1):111-114.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[OToole JC, Cruz RT (1980). Response of leaf water potential, stomatal resistance, and leaf rolling to water stress. Plant Physiol, pp. 428-432.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Passioura JB (1996). Drought and drought tolerance. Plant Growth Regul, pp. 79-83.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Peleg Z, Fahima T, Krugman T, Abbo S, Yakir D, Korol AB, Saranga Y (2009). Genomic dissection of drought resistance in durum wheat x wild emmer wheat recombinant inbreed line population. Plant Cell and Environment 32(7):758-779.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Price AH, Young EM, Tomos AD (1997). Quantitative trait loci associated with stomatal conductance, leaf rolling and heading date mapped in upland rice (Oryza sativa). The New Phytologist 137(1): 83-91.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Riboldi LB, Oliveira RF, Angelocci LR (2016). Leaf turgor pressure in maize plants under water stress. Australian Journal of Crop Science 10(6):878
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Richards RA., Rebetzke GJ, Condon AG, van Herwaarden AF (2002). Breeding opportunities for increasing the efficiency of water use and crop yield in temperate cereals. Crop science 42(1):111-121
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Richard OC, Barnett T, Dwyer S, Chadwick K (2004). Cultural diversity in management, firm performance, and the moderating role of entrepreneurial orientation dimensions. Academy of management journal, 47(2):255-266.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ricroch AE, Berg JB, Kuntz M (2011). Evaluation of genetically engineered crops using transcriptomic, proteomic, and metabolomic profiling techniques. Plant physiology 155(4):1752-1761.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Royo C, Maccaferri M, lvaro F, Moragues M, Sanguineti MC, Tuberosa R, Maalouf F, Garca del Moral LF, Demontis A, Rhouma S, Nachit M, Nserallah N, Villegas D (2010). Understanding the relationships between genetic and phenotypic structures of a collection of elite durum wheat accessions. Field Crops Research 119(1):91-105.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Royo C, Nazco R, Villegas D (2014). The climate of the zone of origin of Mediterranean durum wheat (Triticum durum Desf.) landraces affects their agronomic performance. Genetic Resources and Crop Evolution 61(7):1345-1358.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref50">
				<label>50</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Singh BN, Mackill DJ (2008). Genetics of leaf rolling under drought stress. In Rice Genetics II. pp. 159-166.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref51">
				<label>51</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Taghouti M, Gaboun F, Nsarellah N, Rhrib R, El-Haila M, Kamar M, Abbad-Andaloussi F, Udupa SM (2010). Genotype x Environment interaction for quality traits in durum wheat cultivars adapted to different environments. African Journal of Biotechnology 9(21):3054-3062.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref52">
				<label>52</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tardieu F (2003). Virtual plants: modelling as a tool for the genomics of tolerance to water deficit. Trends Plant Sci. pp. 9-14.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref53">
				<label>53</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tardieu F (2005). Plant tolerance to water deficit: physical limits and possibilities for progress. Comptes Rendus Geoscience. pp. 57-67.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref54">
				<label>54</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tardieu F (2012). Any trait or trait-related allele can confer drought tolerance: just design the right drought scenario. J. Exp. Bot. pp. 25-31.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref55">
				<label>55</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tardieu F, Tuberosa R (2010). Dissection and modelling of abiotic stress tolerance in plants. Curr. Opin. Plant Biol. pp. 206-212.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref56">
				<label>56</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Taghouti M, Nsarellah N, Rhrib K, Benbrahim N, Amallah L, Rochdi A (2017). Evolution from durum wheat landraces to recent improved varieties in Morocco in terms of productivity increase to the detriment of grain quality. Revue Marocaine des Sciences Agronomiques et Vtrinaires 5(4): 351-358.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref57">
				<label>57</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Turner NC (1982). The role of shoot characteristics in drought resistance of crop plants. In Drought resistance in crops with emphasis on rice, pp115-134.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref58">
				<label>58</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wang YH, Li JY ( 2005). The plant architecture of rice (Oryza sativa). Plant molecular biology 59(1):75-84
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref59">
				<label>59</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Watts DG, El-Mourid M (1988). Rainfall patterns and probabilities in the semi-arid cereal production region of Morocco. USA I. D. project No. pp. 608-0136.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref60">
				<label>60</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Willmer CM (1983). In Stomata, Longman, London, p. 17.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref61">
				<label>61</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xiang JJ, Zhang GH, Qian Q, Xue HW (2012). SEMI-ROLLED LEAF1 encodes a putative glycosylphosphatidylinositol-anchored protein and modulates rice leaf rolling by regulating the formation of bulliform cells. Plant Physiol. pp. 1488-1500.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref62">
				<label>62</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yokota A, Takahara K, Akashi K (2006). Physiology and Molecular Biology of Stress Tolerance in Plants. Springer. pp. 15-39.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref63">
				<label>63</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yuan LP (1997). Super-high yield hybrid rice breeding. Hybrid Rice. pp. 1-6.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref64">
				<label>64</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zarkti H, Ouabbou H, Udupa SM, Gaboun F, Hilali A (2012). Agro-morphological variability in durum wheat landraces of Morocco. Australian Journal of Crop Science 6(7):1172-1178.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref65">
				<label>65</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhang GH, Xu Q, Zhu XD, Qian Q, Xue HW (2009). SHALLOT-LIKE1 is a KANADI transcription factor that modulates rice leaf rolling by regulating leaf abaxial cell development. Plant Cell .pp. 719-735.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref66">
				<label>66</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhang Q, Zheng T, Hoang L, Wang C, Nafisah Joseph C, Zhang W, Xu J, Li Z (2016). Joint mapping and allele mining of the rolled leaf Zou LP, Sun XH, Zhang ZG, Liu P, Wu JX, Tian CJ, Qiu JL, Lu TG (2011). Leaf rolling controlled by the homeodomain leucine zipper class IV gene Roc5 in rice. Plant Physiol. pp. 1589-1602.
				]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>