<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Biotechnology </journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1684-5315</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJB2020.17096</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Responses of soybeans (Glycine max (L.) Merrill) associated with variable plant density stress applied at different phenological stages: Plasticity or elasticity?]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Noah</surname>
            <given-names>Manda</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Mebelo</surname>
            <given-names>Mataa</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">mebelomataa@yahoo.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>14</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>04</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>19</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>307</fpage>
	  <lpage>319</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/75769A563860">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/75769A563860	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-full-text-pdf/75769A563860">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-full-text-pdf/75769A563860	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The study evaluated developmental responses associated with plant population density stress applied at different phenological phases and effects on grain yield in determinate and indeterminate soybean (Glycine max L.). A split-split plot design with four replications, with variety (main plot), plant density (sub plot) and thinning time (sub-subplot) was adopted. Two determinate genotypes (Lukanga and SC Semeki) and an indeterminate type (Mwembeshi) were used. Plant density stress was imposed by planting at supra optimal densities (700, 600 and 500 K plants ha-1) (K representing 1000) and stress was removed by thinning to the recommended density (400 K plants ha-1) at different phenological stages. Plant density had little effect on grain yield. Thinning time influenced root to shoot ratio, number of grains per pod, yield and harvest Index (HI). Lukanga had the highest grain yield (2.43 tons ha-1), followed by Mwembeshi (1.95 tons ha-1) and lastly SC Semeki (1.17 tons ha-1). Lukanga exhibited reproductive plasticity, while SC Semeki showed vegetative plasticity. Mwembeshi an indeterminate type suggested non-plastic or lsquo;elasticrsquo; response. The lack of effect on planting density exemplified by constant yield at different plant densities suggests that maintaining low seed rates is more economical given the high cost of seed.

	 

	Key words: Partitioning, determinate, indeterminate, reproductive plasticity, vegetative plasticity.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agalave HR (2017). Effect of environmental factors on productivity of crop. International Journal of Botany Studies 2:14-16.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agudamu Y, Yoshihira T, Shiraiwa T (2016). Branch development responses to planting density and yield stability in soybean cultivars. Plant Production Science 19:331-339.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bradshaw AD (1965). Evolutionary Significance of Phenotypic Plasticity in Plants. Advances in Genetics 13:115-155.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chigeza G, Boahen S, Gedil M, Agoyi E, Musholiwa H, Denwar N, Gondwe T, Tesfaye A, Kamara A, Alamu OE, Chikoye D (2019). Public sector soybean (Glycine max) breeding: Advances in cultivar development in the African tropics. Plant Breeding 138(4):455-464.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chileshe L, Chirwa B (1990). Soils of Mansa District-Soil Survey Report No. 186 D. Soil Survey Unit, Research Branch, Department of Agriculture. Ministry of Agriculture. Government of the Republic of Zambia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Craine JM, Dybzinski R (2013). Mechanisms of plant competition for nutrients, water and light. Functional Ecology 27:833-840.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Duncan WG (1986). Crop Ecology, Production and Management: Planting Patterns and Soybean Yields. Crop Science Journal 26:584-588.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) (2016). FAOSTAT. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome, Italy. Available online at:
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) (2001). World Soil Resource reports: Lecture notes on the major soils of the world. In Driessen P, Deckers J, Nachtergaele F (eds.) Rome: Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fehr WR, Caviness CE, Burmood DT, Pennington JS (1971). Stages of development descriptions for soybean, Glycine max (L.) Merril. Crop Science 11:929-931.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Grime JP (1977). Evidence for the existence of three primary strategies in plants and its relevance to ecological and evolutionary theory. American Naturalist 111:169-1194.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Grime JP, Mackey JML (2002). The role of plasticity in resource capture by plants. Evolutionary Ecology 16:299-307.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ibrahim HM (2012). Response of some sunflower hybrids to different levels of plant density. APCBEE Procedia 4:175-182.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Li J, Qu Z, Chen J, Yang B, Huang Y (2019). Effect of planting density on the growth and yield of sunflower under mulched drip irrigation. Water (Switzerland) 11:1-14.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maggio A, Bressan RA, Zhao Y, Park J, Yun D (2018). Its hard to avoid avoidance: Uncoupling the evolutionary connection between plant growth, productivity and stress tolerance. International Journal of Molecular Sciences 19:36-71.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mataa M, Sichilima I (2019). Phenotypic plasticity in soybean (Glycine max (Merrill)) genotypes with contrasting growth characteristics subjected to planting density stress at different developmental stages. African Journal of Agricultural Research 14:643-651.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mataa M, Tominaga S (1998a). Reproductive-vegetative shoot growth interactions and relationship to non-structural carbohydrates in immature ponkan mandarin. (Citrus reticulata Blanco). Journal of Horticultural Science and Biotechnology 73:189-194.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mataa M, Tominaga S (1998b). The effects of shading stage and level on fruit set and development, leaf carbohydrates and photosynthesis in ponkan (Citrus reticulata Blanco). Japanese Journal of Tropical Agriculture 42:103-110.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mellendorf NE (2011). Soybean growth and yield response to interplant competition relief in various plant density environments. MSc. Thesis (unpublished). University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, pp. 11-12. Available at:
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mhamdi A, Van Breusegem F (2018). Reactive oxygen species in plant development. Development (Cambridge). P. 145.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mitti JM (1995). Soybean (Glycine max (L.) Merr). In: Zambian Seed Technology Handbook. Muliokela SW. (ed.) Lusaka: Ministry o fAgriculture, Food and Fisheries. pp. 195-199.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Murren CJ, Auld JR, Ghalambor CK, Handelsman CA, Heskel MA, Kingsolver JG, Maclean HJ, Masel J, Maughan H, Pfenning DW, Relyea RA, Seiter S, Snell-Rood E, Steiner UK Schilichting CD (2015). Constraints on the evolution of phenotypic plasticity: Limits and costs of phenotype and plasticity. Heredity 115:293-301.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mooney HA, Gulman SL (1979). Environmental and evolutionary constraints on the photosynthetic characteristics of higher plants. In Topics in Plant Population Biology. Solbrig OT, Jain S, Johnson GB, Raven PH (eds,). Columbia University Press, New York. pp. 316-337.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Oyatokun OS, Oluwasemire KO (2014). Evaluating starter N application to Soybean with CROPGRO-Soybean model in the Southern Guinea Savanna Agro-Ecology of Nigeria. Journal of Agricultural Science 6:83-100.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pacala SW, Tilmant D (1994). Limiting similarity in mechanistic and spatial models of plant competition in heterogeneous environments. The American Naturalist 143(2):222-257.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Park SE, Benjamin LR, Watkinson AR (2003). The theory and application of plant competition models: An agronomic perspective. Annals of Botany 92:741-748.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Park Y, Runkle ES (2018). Far-red radiation and photosynthetic photon flux density independently regulate seedling growth but interactively regulate flowering. Environmental and Experimental Botany 155:206-216.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pereira-Flores ME, Justino BF (2019). Yield components and biomass partition in soybean: Climate change vision. (Unpublished) Intechopen.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rondanini DR, Menendez YC, Gomez NV, Miralles DJ, Botto JF (2017). Vegetative plasticity and floral branching compensate low plant density in modern spring rapeseed. Field Crop Research 210:104-113.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SeedCo (2015). Soybean growers guide. Available at:
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shamsi K, Kobraee S (2011). Soybean agronomic responses to plant density. Annals of Biological Research 2:168-173.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sichilima I, Mataa M, Mweetwa AM (2018). Morpho-physiological and Yield Responses Associated with Plant Density Variation in Soybean (Glycine max (L.) (Merrill)). International Journal of Environment, Agriculture and Biotechnology 3:274-285.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sultan SE (2003). Phenotypic plasticity in plants: A case study in ecological development. Evolution and Development 5:25-33.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sultan S (1992). Phenotypic plasticity and the Neo- Darwinian legacy. Evolutionary Trends in Plants 6:61-71]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sultan SE, Bazzaz FA (1993). Phenotypic Plasticity in Polygonum persicaria. II. Norms of Reaction to Soil Moisture and the Maintenance of Genetic Diversity. Evolution 47:1032-1049.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Takahashi F, Shinozaki K (2019). Long-distance signaling in plant stress response. Current Opinion in Plant Biology 47:106-111.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tekola T, Yoseph T, Worku W (2018). Biological and inorganic fertilizer applications improved growth, nodulation and yield of soybean (Glycine max L.) varieties. International Journal of Current Research 10:68855- 68862.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[VSN International (2015). Genstat for Windows 18th Edition. VSN International, Hemel Hempstead, UK. Available at:
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wahid A, Gelani S, Ashraf M, Foolad MR (2007). Heat tolerance in plants: An overview. Environmental and Experimental Botany 61:199-223.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wani SH, Kumar V, Shriram V, Sah SK (2016). Phytohormones and their metabolic engineering for abiotic stress tolerance in crop plants. Crop Science 4:162-176.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wright D, Lenssen AW (2013). Staging soybean development. Agriculture and Environment Extension Publications 191:1- 3.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yang X, Zhang W, He Q (2019). Effects of intraspecific competition on growth, architecture and biomass allocation of Quercus liaotungensis. Journal of Plant Interactions 14:284-294.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>