<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Biotechnology </journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1684-5315</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJB2019.16991</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Comparison and optimization for DNA extraction of okra (Abelmoschus esculentus L.  Moench)]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Letebrhan</surname>
            <given-names>Kidane</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Marie</surname>
            <given-names>Kalousova</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Hewan</surname>
            <given-names>Demissie</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">hewan.dd@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>21</day>
			<month>10</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>27</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>19</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>353</fpage>
	  <lpage>361</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/1B6190F63910">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/1B6190F63910	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-full-text-pdf/1B6190F63910">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-full-text-pdf/1B6190F63910	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The extraction of high-quality DNA from okra (Abelmoschus esculentus L. Moench) is notoriously troublesome due to the high contents of polysaccharides, polyphenols, and different secondary metabolites. We have tested seven extraction buffers on silica dried okra leaves. Here, we describe a simple, rapid and modified procedure for high-quality DNA extraction from okra, which is amenable for downstream analyses. In contrast to Cetyl-trimethyl-ammonium bromide (CTAB) methods, the described procedure is rapid, omits the use of liquid nitrogen, phenol, PVP-10, and chloroform. It also uses inexpensive and less hazardous reagents and requires only ordinary laboratory equipment. The procedure employed a high concentration of Sodium dodecyl sulphate (SDS) to rid the problems associated with polysaccharides and polyphenols. The average yield was between 36 and 45 mu;g of total DNA from 90 mg of dried leaf weight. The DNA is adequate for molecular analysis of okra, such as genetic mapping or marker-assisted plant breeding. This protocol can be performed in as little as 3 h and may be adapted to high-throughput DNA isolation.

	 

	Key words: PVP-10, polyvinylpyrrolidone, non cetyltrimethylammonium bromide, okra, genomic DNA, Sodium dodecyl sulphate (SDS).]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agrawal A, Sharma A, Shukla NP (2016). Genomic DNA Extraction Protocol for Artemisia Annua L. Without Using Liquid Nitrogen and Phenol. International Journal of Applied Sciences and Biotechnology 4:448-451.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Akotkar PK, De DK, Pal AK (2010). Genetic variability and diversity in okra (Abelmoschus esculentus L. Moench). Electronic Journal of Plant Breeding 1:393-398.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ali Q, Salisu IB, Raza A, Shahid AA, Rao AQ, Husnain T (2019). A modified protocol for rapid DNA isolation from cotton (Gossypium spp.). Methods X 6:259-264.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Allen GC, Flores-Vergara MA, Krasynanski S, Kumar S, Thompson WF (2006). A modified protocol for rapid DNA isolation from plant tissues using cetyltrimethylammonium bromide. Nature Protocols 1:2320-2325.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amani J, Kazemi R, Abbasi AR, Salmanian AH (2011). A simple and rapid leaf genomic DNA extraction method for polymerase chain reaction analysis. Iranian Journal of Biotechnology 9:69-71.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[De Mendiburu F (2020). agricolae: Statistical Procedures for Agricultural Research. R package version 1.3-2.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Diizyaman E (1997). Okra: botany and horticulture. Horticultural Reviews 21(7).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dubey P, Mishra S (2017). A review on: Diabetes and okra (Abelmoschus esculentus). The Journal of Medicinal Plants Studies 5:23-26.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Farrell RE (2011). RNA Methodologies. In Reviews in Cell Biology and Molecular Medicine, (American Cancer Society). P. 74.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fronda BX, Gamboa M, Zabala JD, Oasan R (2018). Development of Vegetable Marmalade Using Okras (Abelmoschus esculentus) Mucilage. In Abstract Proceedings International Scholars Conference pp. 91-91.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gemede HF, Ratta N, Haki GD, Woldegiorgis WZ, Beyene F (2015). Nutritional quality and health benefits of okra (Abelmoschu sesculentus): a review. Journal of Food Processing and Technology 25:16-25.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Harlan JR (1969). Ethiopia: A center of diversity. Economic Botany 23:309-314.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jeyaseelan TC, Jeyaseelan EC, De Costa DM, Shaw MW (2019). Selecting and optimizing a reliable DNA extraction method for isolating viral DNA in okra (Abelmoschus esculentus). Vingnanam Journal of Science 14.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kalbande BB, Patil AS, Chakrabarty PK (2016). An efficient, simple and high throughput protocol for cotton genomic DNA isolation. Journal of Plant Biochemistry and Biotechnology 25:437-441.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Khan GA, Yilmaz ND, Yilmaz K (2017). Okra Fibers: Potential Material for Green Biocomposites. In Green Biocomposites, (Springer), pp. 261-284.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumar DS, Tony DE, Kumar AP, Kumar KA, Rao DBS, Nadendla R (2013). A review on: Abelmoschus esculentus (okra). International Research Journal of Pharmaceutical and Applied Sciences 3:129-132.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumar V, Prasad A, Roy C, Chattopadhyay T (2018). Validation of a Simple and Rapid Method for Isolating Genomic DNA from Medicinal and Aromatic Plants for Subsequent Polymerase Chain Reaction. International Journal of Current Microbiology and Applied Sciences 7:2562-2566.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lamont WJ (1999). Okra-A versatile vegetable crop. HortTechnology 9:179-184.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lee CS, Chong MF, Binner E, Gomes R, Robinson J (2018). Techno-economic assessment of scale-up of bio-flocculant extraction and production by using okra as biomass feedstock. Chemical Engineering Research and Design 132:358-369.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mahuku GS (2004). A simple extraction method suitable for PCR-based analysis of plant, fungal, and bacterial DNA. Plant Molecular Biology Reporter 22:71-81.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Martin FW (1982). Okra, potential multiple-purpose crop for the temperate zones and tropics. Economic Botany 36:340-345.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Menu E, Mary C, Toga I, Raoult D, Ranque S, Bittar F (2018). Evaluation of two DNA extraction methods for the PCR-based detection of eukaryotic enteric pathogens in fecal samples. BMC Research Notes 11:206.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Paterson AH, Brubaker CL, Wendel JF (1993). A rapid method for extraction of cotton (Gossypium spp.) genomic DNA suitable for RFLP or PCR analysis. Plant Molecular Biology Reporter 11:122-127.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Porebski S, Bailey LG, Baum BR (1997). Modification of a CTAB DNA extraction protocol for plants containing high polysaccharide and polyphenol components. Plant Molecular Biology Reporter 15:8-15.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[R Core Team (2018). R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria. URL
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sambrook J, Fritsch EF, Maniatis T (1989). Molecular cloning: a laboratory manual. (Cold spring harbor laboratory press).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Seth T, Mishra GP, Singh B, Kashyap S, Mishra SK, Tiwari SK, Singh PM (2018). Optimization of quality DNA isolation protocol from various mucilage rich cultivated and wild Abelmoschus sp. and its validation through PCR amplification. Vegetable Science 45:1-6.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sharma S, Kumar A, Dobhal S, Rawat A (2018). Standardization of protocol for genomic DNA isolation in Melia composite Benth. (SM dubia Cav.).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Singh V, Kumar V (2012). An optimized method of DNA isolation from highly mucilage rich okra (Abelmoschus esculentus L.) for PCR analysis. Advances in Applied Science Research 3:1809-1813.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Valledor L, Hasbn R, Rodrguez R and Canal MJ (2009). RNA-free DNA Extraction Protocol from Pinus Tissues for Molecular Biology or HPCE/HPLC Analyses. Journal of Plant Biochemistry andBiotechnology 18(2):229-232.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Waghela M, Khan S (2018). Isolation, Characterization of Pigment Producing Bacteria from various food samples and testing of antimicrobial activity of bacterial Pigments. DAV International Journal of Science 7.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wei D, Guo S, Shulan SU, Qian D, Zhu Z, Shang E, Geng Z, Duan J (2017). Protective effect of okra seed oil on acute gastric ulcer in mice. Journal of China Pharmaceutical University 48:334-342.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wilson K, Walker J (2010). Principles and Techniques of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology (Cambridge University Press).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xia Y, Chen F, Du Y, Liu C, Bu G, Xin Y, Liu B (2019). A modified SDS-based DNA extraction method from raw soybean. Bioscience Reports 39.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhang T, Xiang J, Zheng G, Yan R, Min X (2018). Preliminary characterization and anti-hyperglycemic activity of a pectic polysaccharide from okra (Abelmoschus esculentus (L.) Moench). Journal of Functional Foods 41:19-24.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>