<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Biotechnology </journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1684-5315</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJB2020.17102</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Lactic acid bacteria fermentation of coconut milk and its effect on the nutritional, phytochemical, antibacterial and sensory properties of virgin coconut oil produced]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Olateru</surname>
            <given-names>Comfort T.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Popoola</surname>
            <given-names>Bukola M.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Alagbe</surname>
            <given-names>Gbolahan O.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ajao</surname>
            <given-names>Omobayonle</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">tosinola21@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>07</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>19</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>362</fpage>
	  <lpage>366</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/40EF7B663912">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/40EF7B663912	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-full-text-pdf/40EF7B663912">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-full-text-pdf/40EF7B663912	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Coconut oil has profound health benefits but the high content of fatty acids is a concern to many consumers, as several processing methods have failed to produce oil with considerable change in fatty acid content. In this study, selected lactic acid bacteria including Lactobacillus plantarum, Lactobacillus pentosus, Leuconostoc mesenteroides and Enterococcus faecium were used to ferment coconut milk for production of virgin coconut oil. Fermentation was carried out for 48 h, after which the milk was processed through heating to produce coconut oil. Phytochemical content, proximate composition, determination of steroids and free fatty acid content of the oil and antibacterial activity of the oil against Staphylococcus aureus and Pseudomonas aeruginosa were carried out using standard analytical and laboratory procedures. The results obtained in this study indicate that the control and LAB fermented oil had similar composition of phytochemicals; steroids, anthraquinone and glycosides were present in all the virgin coconut oil produced; however, reduced moisture content, lower levels of ester and free fatty acid was observed and higher quantity of protein and ash were obtained for coconut oil fermented with LAB compared to the control. The virgin coconut oil produced using the starter culture also had higher acceptability (Plt;0.05) compared to the spontaneously fermented oil, as the milk fermented with Lactobacillus plantarum had the highest acceptability value. There was no significant difference in the antibacterial activity of the virgin coconut oil produced against the test organisms. This study indicates that free fatty acid and other undesirable constituents in coconut oil can be reduced using lactic acid bacteria as starter culture, hence, increasing the acceptability of the product.

	 

	Key words: Lactic acid bacteria, coconut milk, fermentation, coconut oil.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abriouel H, Valdivia E, Martinez-Bueno M, Maqueda M, Galvez AN (2004). A simple method for semi-preparative-scale production and recovery of enterocin AS-48 derived from Enterococci faecalis subsp. LiquefaciensA-48-32. Journal of Biochemistry 76:947-953.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[AOAC (1984). Association of Official Analytical Chemists 14th Edition. Washington DC.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[De Vuyst L, Leroy F (2004). Fermented food in the context of a healthy diet: How to produce novel functional food? Journal of Current Opinion in Clinical Nutrition and Medical Care 17:574-581.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Divina DB (2002). Production, utilization and marketing of Virgin coconut oil. Coconut Info International 9(1):5-9.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ghosh PK, Bhattacharjee P, Mitra S, Poddar-Sarkar M (2014). Physicochemical and Phytochemical Analyses of Copra and Oil of Cocos nucifera L. (West Coast Tall Variety). International Journal of Food Science 2014(8):ID 310852
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hafidh RR, Abdulamir AS, Vern LS, Bakar FA (2010). The inhibition of human pathogens: Trichophyton rubrum and Trichoderma harzianum by a natural product. American Journal of Biochemistry and Biotechnology 6(1).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Manisha DM, Shyamapada M (2011). Coconut (Cocos nucifera L. Arecaceae): In health promotion and disease prevention. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Medicine 4(3):241-247.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Marina AM, Che Man YB, Nazimah SAH, Amin I (2009). Chemical properties of virgin coconut oil. Journal of the American Oil Chemists Society 86(4):301-307.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nguyen Van Thi A, Truong Dang L,HoaNgoc P,Lam Bich T(2017). Antibacterial Activity of free Fatty acids from hydrolyzed Virgin coconut oil using Lipase from Candida rugosa. Journal of Lipids 7p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nour AH, Mohammed FS, Yunus RM, Arman A (2009). Demulsification of virgin coconut oil by centrifugation method: A feasibility study. International Journal of Chemical Technology 1(2):59-64.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pearson D (1981). The Chemical Analysis of Food. Churchill Livingstone Edinburgh. Technology  Engineering pp. 504-530.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Satheesh N, Prasad NBL (2012). Induced fermentative production of virgin coconut oil. Asian Journal of Food and Agro-Industry 5(5):355-363.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thanuja TT, Sreekala GS, Meenakumari KS (2016). Isolation of microorganism from the fermented coconut milk and comparison of quality parameters of virgin coconut oil recovered by induced fermentation. International Journal of Advanced Research 4(6):1927-1934.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SAS (1999). Statistical Analysis System User Guide Statistics. SAS Institute Inc. Cary NC 27513 USA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>