<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Food Science</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0794</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJFS2019.1852</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Assessment of Arabusta coffee hybrids [Coffea arabica L. X Tetraploid Robusta (Coffea canephora )] for  green bean physical properties and cup quality]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Jane</surname>
            <given-names>Jerono Cheserek</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Kahiu</surname>
            <given-names>Ngugi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>James</surname>
            <given-names>Wanjohi Muthomi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Chrispine</surname>
            <given-names>Ogutu Omondi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">cheserekjerono@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>21</day>
			<month>08</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>02</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>5</issue>
	  	  <fpage>119</fpage>
	  <lpage>127</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/DBE061163916">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/DBE061163916	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-full-text-pdf/DBE061163916">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-full-text-pdf/DBE061163916	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Robusta coffee is known to be high yielding than Arabica coffee, since it is more vigorous in growth. However, it is limited by the inferior cup quality. The aim of the study was to evaluate the performance of the Arabusta hybrids and its backcross derivatives for bean physical characteristics and organoleptic properties including their interrelationship. Nineteen coffee genotypes were evaluated at Siaya ATC and KALRO-Alupe, using randomized complete block design with three replications. Data on the bean grades and sensory traits was carried out on beans harvested in the year 2018. The results indicated that there was a significant variation on both the sensory and bean grade traits from the two locations. On average, Arabusta hybrids showed better performance on bean traits when compared to its backcrosses and Robusta. There was a highly significant positive correlation between the sensory traits which had highly significant positive association with aftertaste (r=0.96), aroma (r=0.84), balance (r=0.85), flavor (r=0.96) and overall standard (r=0.96).  The positive significant correlation between the 100 bean weight and the AA bean size is an indication that weight of beans can be used in predicting the bean sizes. The interspecific hybridization enables the transfer of good cup quality attributes from Arabica coffee to Robusta coffee.

	 

	Key words: Flavor, Arabica, bean grade, quality, Arabica, Robusta, environment, variation.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abrar S, Ali M, Solomon E (2014). Processing method, variety and roasting duration effect on physical quality attributes of roasted Arabica coffee beans. Sky Journal of Agricultural Research 3(5): 082- 088.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adugnaw M, Nigussie D, Ali M (2015). Bean quality attributes of Arabica coffees grown in Ethiopia and the potential for discovering new specialty coffees. East African Journal of Sciences 9 (2):121-130.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agwanda CO, Baradat P, Eskes A, Cilas C, Charrier A (2003). Selection for bean and liquor qualities within related hybrids of Arabica coffee in multilocal field trials. Euphytica 131(1): 1-14.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ameyu MA (2016). Physical quality analysis of roasted Arabica coffee beans subjected to different harvesting and postharvest processing methods in eastern Ethiopia. Food Science and Quality Management Vol. 57.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Barbosa RM, Batista BL, Varrique RM, Coelho VA, Campiglia AD, Barbosa JF (2014). The use of advanced chemometric techniques and trace element levels for controlling the authenticity of organic coffee. Food Research International 61:246-251.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Batista L, Chalfoun S (2014). Quality of coffee beans In: Schwan RF, Fleet GH (Eds.), Cocoa and Coffee Fermentation, CRC Taylor  Francis, Boca Raton, FL (2014), p. 633.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Belay S, Mideksa D, Gebrezgiabher S, Seifu W (2016). Factors affecting coffee (Coffea arabica) quality in Ethiopia: A review. Journal of Multidisciplinary Scientific Research 4(1):27-33.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cheng B, Furtado A, Smyth HE, Henry RJ (2016). Influence of genotype and environment on coffee quality. Trends Food Science Technology 57: 20-30.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Curzi D, Raimondi V, Olper A (2014). Quality upgrading, competition and trade policy: Evidence from the Agri-food sector. European Review of Agricultural Economics 42(2):239-267.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Decasy F, Avelino J, Guyot B, Perriot JI, Pineda C, Cilas C (2003). Quality of different Honduran coffees in relation to several environments. Journal of Food Science 68:2356-2361.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dessalegn Y, Labuschagne MT, Osthoff G, Herselman L. (2008). Genetic diversity and correlation of bean caffeine content with cup quality and green bean physical characteristics in coffee (Coffea arabica L.). Journal of Science of Food and Agriculture 88:1726-1730.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dias RCE, Valderrama P, Marco PH, Scholz, dos Santos Scholz MB, Edelman M, Yeretzian C (2018). Quantitative assessment of specific defects in roasted ground coffee via infrared-photoacoustic spectroscopy. Food Chemistry 255:132-138.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Folmer B, Blank I, Hofmann T (2017). Crema-Formation, stabilization, and sensation. In: F. Britta (Ed.). The craft and science of coffee. Ch. 17. London: Academic Press. pp. 399-417.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fridell G (2014). Fair trade slippages and Vietnam gaps: the ideological fantasies of fair trade coffee. Third World Quarterly 35(7):1179-1194.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gichimu BM, Gichuru EK, Mamati GE, Nyende AB (2012). Selection within Coffea arabica cv. Ruiru 11 for high cup quality. African Journal of Food Science 6(18):456-464.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gichimu BM, Gichuru EK, Mamati GE, Nyende AB (2013). Yield selection within Coffea arabica cv. Ruiru 11. American Journal of Experimental Agriculture 3(1):76-88.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gichimu BM, Omondi CO (2010). Morphological characterization of five newly developed lines of arabica coffee as compared to commercial cultivars in Kenya. International Journal of Plant Breeding and Genetics 4(4):238-246.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gimase JM, Thagana WT, Kirubi DT, Gichuru EK, Kathurima CW (2014b). Beverage quality and biochemical attributes of Arabusta Coffee (C. arabica L. x C. Canephora Pierre) and their parental genotypes. African Journal of Food Science 8(9):456-464.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gonzlez AK, Lopez AM, Gaytn ORT, Ramos VM (2019). Cup quality attributes of Catimors as affected by size and shape of coffee bean (Coffea arabica L.). International Journal of Food Properties 22(1):758-767.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hameed A, Hussain SA, Ijaz HU, Ullah S, Pasha I, Suleria HAR (2018). Farm to consumer: Factors affecting the organoleptic characteristics of coffee. II: Postharvest processing factors. Comprehensive Reviews in Food Science and Food Safety 17(5):1184-1237.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hampson CR, Quamme HA, Hall JW, MacDonald RA, King MC, Cliff A (2000). Sensory evaluation as a selection tool in apple breeding. Euphytica 111(2):79-90.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hue J, Zhu J, Xu HM (2000). Methods of constructing core collections by stepwise clustering with three sampling strategies based on the genotypic values of crops. Theoretical and Applied Genetics 101:264-268.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[ICO (2019a). International Coffee Organization International coffee Council, 124th Session, country coffee profile, Kenya.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[ICO (2019b). International Coffee Organization Coffee market report August. Country coffee profile, Kenya.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jaetzold R, Schmidt H, Hornetz B, Shisanya D (2009). Farm management handbook of Kenya, Natural conditions and farm management information, West Kenya. Ministry of Agriculture, Kenya.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jansen J (1993). Generalized linear mixed models  their application in plant breeding research Eindhoven: Technische Universiteit Eindhoven.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kahiu N, Aluka P (2016). Sensory  organoleptic cup attributes of Robusta coffee (Coffea canephora Pierre ex A. Froehner). Journal of Agricultural Studies 4(1):101.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kathurima CW (2013). Characterization of coffee genotypes in Kenya by genetic, biochemical and beverage quality profiles. PhD. Thesis, Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology, Kenya.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kathurima CW, Gichimu BM, Kenji GM, Muhoho SM, Boulanger R (2009). Evaluation of beverage quality and green bean physical characteristics of selected Arabica coffee genotypes in Kenya. Africa. Journal Food Science 3(11): 365-371.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lattin J, Carroll D, Green P (2002). Analyzing Multivariate Data. 1st ed. Duxbury Press.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Leroy T, Ribeyre F, Bertrand B, Charmetant P, Dufour M, Montagnon C, Marraccini P, Pot D (2006). Genetics of coffee quality. Brazilian Journal of Plant Physiology 18(1):229-242.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lingle TR (2001). The Cuppers Handbook. Systematic Guide to the Sensory Evaluation of Coffees flavor. Third edition, p. 71.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Liu C, Yang Q, Linforth R, Fisk ID, Yang N (2019). Modifying Robusta coffee aroma by green bean chemical pre-treatment. Food Chemistry 272:251-257.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Marin K, Pozrl T, Zlatic E, Plestenjak A (2008). A new aroma index to determine the aroma quality of roasted and ground coffee during storage. Food Technology and Biotechnology 46 (4):442- 447.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Martin RP, Donald FB, Stanley W, Vincent AU (1978). A comparison of mean separation techniques. Journal of Statistical Computation and Simulation 7(1):33-54.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mburu JK. (2004). The current recommendations for the processing of high quality and safe coffee in Kenya. 20th International Conference on Coffee Science Bangalore, India.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mendes LC, Menezes HZ, Silva MAAP (2001). Optimization of the roasting of Robusta coffee (C. canephora conillon) using acceptability tests and RSM. Food Quality and Preference 12:153-162.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Michaela TL, Kreuml DM, Bettina P, Juergen K (2013). Changes in sensory quality characteristics of coffee during storage. Food Science and Nutrition 1(4):267- 272.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Muschler RG (2001). Shade improves quality in suboptimal coffee zone of Costa Rica. Agroforestry Systems 51:131-139.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nebesny E, Budryn G (2006). Evaluation of sensory attributes of coffee brews from Robusta coffee roasted under different conditions. European Food Resource Technology 224:159-165.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Noor-Aliah AM, Fareez-Edzuan AM, Noor-Diana AM (2015). A review of quality coffee roasting degree evaluation. Journal of Applied Science and Agriculture 10(7):18-23.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rachilo JR, Michieka DO (1991). Reconnaissance soil survey of the Busia area. Reconnaissance Soil Survey Report. No. R8. KARI/NARL. Kenya Soil Survey. Nairobi. Kenya.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Reyes GF, Escamilla PE, Prez PE, Almaguer VG, Curiel RA, Hernndez GJA (2016). Evaluacin de Productividad, Calidad Fsica y Sensorial Del Grano Del Caf (Coffea arabica L.), En Cafetos Injertados En El CRUO, Huatusco, Veracruz. Revista Geographic Agrcola 56:45-53.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sanz C, Czerny M, Cid C, Schieberle P (2002). Comparison of potent odorants in a filtered coffee brew and in an instant coffee beverage by aroma dilution analysis (AEDA). European Food Research and Technology, Berlin 214:299-302.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sureshkumar VB, George D, Prakash NS, Prakasan CB, Mohanan KV (2013). Study on the pattern of fruit development in Robusta coffee (Coffea canephora var. Robusta). International Journal of Plant, Animal and Environmental Sciences 3(2):248-257.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sunarharum W, Williams JD, Smyth H (2014). Complexity of coffee flavor: A compositional and sensory perspective. Food Research International 62: 315-325.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tefera F (2018). Variability and genotype by environment interaction for quantitative and qualitative traits of coffee (Coffea arabica l.) hybrids in south western Ethiopia. PhD dissertation. Jimma University, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tessema A, Sentayehu A, Taye K, Weyessa G (2011). Variability and association of quality and biochemical attributes in some promising Coffea arabica germplasm collection in Southwestern Ethiopia. International Journal of Plant Breeding and Genetics 5(4):302-316.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yigzaw D (2005). Assessment of cup quality, morphological, biochemical and molecular diversity of C. arabica L. genotypes of Ethiopia. PhD. Thesis, University Free State, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref50">
				<label>50</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yuwana Y, Silvia E, Sidebang B (2015). Engineering properties of coffee beans from various colors of coffee cherries. Agriculture and Agriculture Science Procedia 3:274-277.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>