<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Food Science</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0794</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJFS2020.1946</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Microbial quality of artisanal yoghurt and Dèguè products collected in schools of Cotonou and Abomey-Calavi (Benin)]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Majoie</surname>
            <given-names>Groxie TOHOYESSOU</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Wassiyath</surname>
            <given-names>MOUSSE</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Haziz</surname>
            <given-names>SINA</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Farid</surname>
            <given-names>BADE</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Chdrac</surname>
            <given-names>A. BOTON</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Oswald</surname>
            <given-names>R. AHOUISSOU</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Adolphe</surname>
            <given-names>ADJANOHOUN</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Lamine</surname>
            <given-names>BABA-MOUSSA</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">laminesaid@yahoo.fr</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>16</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>28</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>5</issue>
	  	  <fpage>112</fpage>
	  <lpage>118</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/BD7EF2263914">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/BD7EF2263914	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-full-text-pdf/BD7EF2263914">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-full-text-pdf/BD7EF2263914	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The main aim of this study is to evaluate the microbiological quality of yoghurt and two types of degrave;guegrave; (couscous and millet) sold in Cotonou and Abomey-Calavi. Samples of dairy products were collected in 15 schools of Abomey-Calavi and Cotonou from vendors located inside the schools. In this study, 180 samples (60 yoghurt, 60-degrave;guegrave; millet and 60-degrave;guegrave; couscous) were analysed. The microbial quality of collected samples was investigated using conventional methods for lactic acid bacteria, staphylococci, faecal and total coliforms and thermo-tolerant Gram-negative bacilli bacteria. The results of the microbiological analyses of the collected samples revealed a contamination of all the samples of yoghurt, degrave;guegrave; millet and degrave;guegrave; couscous. The microorganisms load varies according to not only the sampling sites, the sampling period but with the type of microorganisms. The presence of potentially pathogenic bacteria particularly the total coliforms (38%), faecal coliforms (21%), and thermo-tolerant Gram-negative bacilli bacteria (20%) and staphylococci (21%) were observed. In addition, it should be noted that the different samples of yoghurt, degrave;guegrave; millet and degrave;guegrave; couscous taken in the morning have a high microbial load compared to that of the evening with regard to faecal coliforms for the two sites. Dairy products sold to school children in Cotonou and Abomey-Calavi are potentially sources of food poisoning.

	 

	Key words: Yoghurt, degrave;guegrave;, microbiological quality, schools, South Benin.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Akouedegni CG, Adenile AD, Gbego IS, Hounzangbe-Adote MS (2013). Efficiency of Mombin L. spondias Leaves on Dairy Production and Sheep Weight Growth Djallonk in South Benin. Annales of Agricultural Sciences 17(2):137-148.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Angulo FJ, LeJeune JT, Rajala-Schultz PJ (2009). Unpasteurized milk: A continued public health threat. Clinical Infectious Diseases 48(1):93-100.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anihouvi EL, Salih H, Anihouvi VB, Kesenkaş H (2019). Milk and Dairy Products Production in Benin. Akademik Gıda 17(4):508-516.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[ANSES (2011). Foodborne biohazard description sheet/Staphylococcus aureus and staphylococcal enterotoxins.
				
					Viewaccessed July 13, 2019.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aspri M, Economou N, Papademas P (2017). Donkey milk: An overview on functionality, technology, and future prospects. Food Reviews International 33(3):316-333.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Baba-Moussa L, Bokossa YI, Baba-Moussa F, Ahissou H, Adeoti Z, Yehouenou B, Mamadou A, Toukourou F, Sanni A (2006). Study of the possibilities of contamination of street food in Benin: The case of the city of Cotonou. Journal de la Recherche Scientifique de lUniversit de Lom (Togo), 2006, Series A 8(2):149-156.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Baird‐Parker AC (1990). The staphylococci: An introduction. Journal of Applied Bacteriology 69:1S-8S.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bagr TS, Kagambga A, Bawa AI, Tchamba GT, Dembl R, Zongo C, Savadogo A, Aggad H, Traor AS, Barro N (2014). Antibiotic susceptibility of Escherichia coli and Salmonella strains isolated from raw and curds milk consumed in Ouagadougou and Ziniar, Burkina Faso. African Journal of Microbiology Research 8:1012-1016.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Becila A (2009). Prevention of spoilage and microbial contamination of food. Specialized post-graduation memory. University Mentouri - Constantine, Algeria 90p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bonfoh B, Wasem A, Traore A N, Fane A, Spillmann H, Simb CF, Zinsstag J (2003). Microbiological quality of cows milk taken at different intervals from the udder to the selling point in Bamako (Mali). Food Control 14(7):495-500.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bsadjo-Tchamba G, Ibrahim Bawa H, Nzouankeu Ngantcha AA, Bagr TS, Traor AS, Barro N (2015). Isolation, characterization and antibiotic susceptibility of Escherichia coli and Salmonella spp. Isolated from local beverages (bissap, gnamakoudji) sold in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso. International Journal of Biosciences 6:112-119.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Codex Alimentarius Commission (1975). Eleventh session-1976. Report on the Ninth Session of the Codex Committee on foods for special dietary uses. App. II. Draft standard for infant formula (Advanced to step 8). Bonn, 22-26.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[de Mesquita ARC, Costa CRR, Frutuoso J, Pinheiro IO, Mota A, Franchitti AA, Azevedo E (2017). Activity of metabolites produced by new strains of Lactobacillus in modified de Man, Rogosa and Sharpe (MRS) medium against multidrug-resistant bacteria. African Journal of Microbiology Research 11(8):345-355.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dror DK, Allen LH (2014). Dairy product intake in children and adolescents in developed countries: trends, nutritional contribution, and a review of association with health outcomes. Nutrition Reviews 72(2):68-81.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[FAO (2008). General view of the national dairy sector of the Republic of Benin. 23p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Haug A, Hstmark AT, Harstad OM (2007). Bovine milk in human nutrition-A review. Lipids in Health and Disease 6(1):25.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Havelaar AH, Kirk MD, Torgerson PR, Gibb HJ, HaldT, Lake RJ, Speybroeck N (2015). World Health Organization global estimates and regional comparisons of the burden of foodborne disease in 2010. PLoS Medicine 12(12):e1001923.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kassa SK, Salifou CFA, Dayo GK, Ahounou S, Dotch OI, Issifou TM, Houaga I, Koutinhouin GB, Mensah GA, Yapi-Gnaor V, Youssao AKI (2016). Assessment of milk production and resilience of Girolando cattle, reared in semi-improved breeding system in Benin. Journal of Veterinary Advances 6(6):1269-1281.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Milani E, Koocheki A, Moeenfard M, Mortazavi SA (2011). The distribution of some pathogenic microorganisms in Kurdish cheese during ripening. In IDF International Symposium on Sheep, Goat and other non-Cow Milk.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Millogo V, Sissao M, Ouedraogo GA (2018). Nutritional and bacteriological quality of samples of some local dairy products from the production chain in Burkina Faso. International Journal of Biological and Chemical Sciences 12(1):244-252.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Morou MA (2010). Evaluation of the microbiological quality of two drinking milks sold on the market in Niamey (Niger): Yoghurt and milk powder. Dissertation Masters Degree in Human Food Quality: Dakar (EISMV); 1.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mouss W, Baba-Moussa F, Adjanohoun A, Noumavo PA, Sina H, Assogba S, Baba-Moussa L (2016). Virulence profiles of pathogenic Escherichia coli strains isolated from street foods in Benin. International Journal of Biotechnology and Food Sciences. 4:52-64.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ndiaye M (2002). Contribution to the conformity study of the labelling and microbiological quality of yoghurts marketed in Dakar. DEA thesis: Animal Productions: Dakar (EISMV); 9.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pinheiro J, Bates D, DebRoy S, Sarkar D (2019). R Core Team (2019). nlme: Linear and nonlinear mixed effects models. R Package Version 3.1‐140.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pinstrup-Andersen P, Watson IIDD (2011). Food policy for developing countries: The role of government in global, national, and local food systems. Cornell University Press.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Riegel P, Archambaud M, Clav D, Vergnaud M (2006). Bacteria difficult to culture and identify. Ed. Biomerous. France, pp. 93-112.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Samapundo S, Thanh TC, Xhaferi R, Devlieghere F (2016). Food safety knowledge, attitudes and practices of street food vendors and consumers in Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam. Food Control 70:79-89.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sessou P, Farougou S, Azokpota P, Youssao I, Yehouenou B, Ahounou S, Sohounhloue DCK (2013). Inventory and analysis of endogenous conservation practices for wagashi, a traditional cheese produced in Benin. International Journal of Biological and Chemical Sciences 7(3):938-952.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tankoano A, Kabore D, Savadogo A, Soma A, Fanou-Fogny N, Compaore-Sereme D, Sawadogo-Lingani H (2016). Evaluation of microbiological quality of raw milk, sour milk and artisanal yoghurt from Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso. African Journal of Microbiology Research 10(16):535-541.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tchekessi CKC, Bokossa IY, Hounkpatin GJ, Banon J, Adigun N, Sachi P, Agbangla C (2014). Socio-economic and technological study of the manufacture of cereal pellets for the production of a fermented drink of probiotic type consumed in Benin. International Journal of Innovation and Applied Studies 9(3):1323-1335.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[UNESCO (2000). School Health and Nutrition. World Education Forum. 61p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[UNICEF (2013). WASH in Schools Evaluation Report in the West Department, Haiti. Quisqueya University. Report, Water and Environmental Quality Laboratory.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Van de Venter T (2000). Emerging food-borne diseases: A global responsibility. Food Nutrition and Agriculture (26):4-13.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yehia HM, Ismail EA, Hassan ZK, Al-Masoud AH, Al-Dagal MM (2019). Heat resistance and presence of genes encoding staphylococcal enterotoxins evaluated by multiplex-PCR of Staphylococcus aureus isolated from pasteurized camel milk. Bioscience Reports 39(11):12.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zagare MS, Deshmukh AM, Patil SS (2012). Analysis of dairy pack food for presence of bacterial pathogens. DAV International Journal of Science 1(1):2277-5641.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>