<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Microbiology Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0808</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJMR2019.9257</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Phenotypic detection of extended spectrum β-lactamase and Metallo β-lactamase production by Gram negative uropathogens after exposure to gamma radiation]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yehia</surname>
            <given-names>Ahmed El-Zawahry</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Lotfy</surname>
            <given-names>Abd-El-Rehem Mousa</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Eman</surname>
            <given-names>Araby</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Salma</surname>
            <given-names>Abd El Monsef-Elnahass</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">emansk2@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>13</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>13</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>225</fpage>
	  <lpage>236</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/5B812C163864">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/5B812C163864	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-full-text-pdf/5B812C163864">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-full-text-pdf/5B812C163864	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Eighty-five uropathogen isolates were collected and differentiated on the basis of their Gram stain reaction. Among the collected isolates, 25 (29.4%) were Gram positive cocci and 60 (70.6%) were Gram negative bacilli. Antibiotic susceptibility profile towards 15 different antibiotics concluded that impenime (IMP), amikacin (AK) and Pipperacillin/tazobactam (TZP) were the most effective against Gram negative; while linezolid (LZD), and vancomycin (VA) were the most potent against Gram positive. The highly drug resistant isolates were identified as Pseudomonas aeruginosa and Klebsiella pneumoniae using 16srRNA; the two strains were subjected to different doses of gamma-radiation and the sub lethal dose of both strains was 5.0 kGy. The D10 values were recorded (1.2 and 1.1 kGy) for P. aeruginosa and K. pneumoniae), respectively. In addition, gamma-irradiation technique decreases the resistance of K. pneumoniae towards IMP and the resistance of P. aeruginosa towards more than one antibiotic (TZP, AZM and CIP). The results also, revealed that both of the tested strains had the ability to produce Extended Spectrum beta;-lactamase (ESBL) before and after gamma-radiation but only P. aeruginosa had the ability to produce Metallo beta;-lactamase (MBL), that is, ESBL and MBL co-production was detected in P. aeruginosa. So, these findings must be supported by other studies on the level of genes to prove the possibility for using gamma-irradiation technique to overcome microbial drug resistance problem.

	 

	Key words: Urinary tract infection, antibiotic resistance, beta;-lactamases, gamma radiation.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abd El-Baky RM, Abd El-Azeim NH, Gad GFM (2013). Prevalence of Extended-Spectrum Beta-Lactamase, AmpC Beta- Lactamase and Metallo Beta-Lactamase among Clinical Isolates of Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Journal of Advanced Biotechnology and Bioengineering 1:22-29.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abujnah AA, Zorgani A, Zorgani AMM, El-Mohammady H, Khalek A R, Ghenghesh K (2015). Multidrug resistance and extended-spectrum b-lactamases genes among Escherichia coli from patients with urinary tract infections in Northwestern Libya. Libyan Journal of Medicine 10:26412.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adam SMA, Elhag WI (2018). Prevalence of metallo--lactamase acquired genes among carbapenems susceptible and resistant Gram-negative clinical isolates using multiplex PCR, Khartoum hospitals, Khartoum. BMC Infectious Diseases 18:668.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aggarwal R, Chaudhary U, Bala K (2008). Detection of extendeds pectrum - lactamase in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Indian Journal of Patholology and Microbiology 51:222-224.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amako K, Meno Y, Takade A (1988). Fine structures of the capsules of Klebsiella pneumonia and Escherichia coli K1. Journal of Bacteriology 170(10):4960-4962.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aquino KAS (2012). Sterilization by gamma irradiation. Gamma Radiation. Chapter 9. (R. F. Adrovic, Ed.), In Tech, ISBN: 978-953-51-0316-5.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Arora S, Bal M (2005). Amp C -lactamases producing bacterial isolates from Kolkata hospital. Indian Journal of Medical Research 122(3):224-233.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Atique BF, Ahmed TK, Asaduzzaman SM, Hasan NK (2013). Effects of Gamma Irradiation on Bacterial Microflora Associated with Human Amniotic Membrane BioMed Research International Volume 2013, Article ID 586561, 6 p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bauer AW, Kirby WMM, Sherris JC, Turck M (1966). Antibiotic susceptibility testing by a standardized single disk method. American Journal of Clinical Pathology 45(4):493-496.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Behera B, Mathur P, Das A, Kapil, A, Sharma V (2008). An evaluation of four different phenotypic techniques for detecting the metallo-- lactamases producing Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Indian Journal of Medical Microbiology 26(3):233-337.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Berrier C, Coulombe A, Houssin C, Ghazi A (1993). Voltage-dependent cationic channel of Escherichia coli. Journal of Membrane Biology 133:119-127.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bhatt P, Jagani R, Ranjan P, Namaji MAA, Rathi KR (2017). Antimicrobial Resistance Pattern of Bacterial Isolates from Urinary Tract Infections at a Tertiary Care Centre. International Journal of Current Microbiology and Applied Sciences 6(1):175-183.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bhattacharjee A, Anupurba S, Guar A, Sen MR (2008). The prevalence of inducible AmpC - lactamase producing Pseudomonas aeruginosa in a tertiary care hospital in northern India. Indian Journal of Medical Microbiology 26:89-98.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI) (2017). Performance standards for antimicrobial susceptibility testing. 27th edition, 282 p.View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Deshmukh DG, Damle AS, Bajaj JK, Bhakre JB, Patwardhan NS (2011). Metallo--lactamase-producing clinical isolates from patients of a tertiary care hospital. Journal of Laboratory Physicians 3(2):93-97.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dougnon V, Assogba P, Anago E, Dgunon E, Dapuliga C, Agbankp J, Bankol H (2020). Enterobacteria responsible for urinary infections: a review about pathogenicity, virulence factors and epidemiology. Journal of Applied Biology and Biotechnology 8(01):117-124.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dreier J, Ruggerone P (2015). Interaction of antibacterial compounds with RND efflux pumps in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Frontiers in Microbiology 6:600.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dutta H, Nath R, Saikia L (2014). Multi-drug resistance in clinical isolates of Gram-negative bacilli in a tertiary care hospital of Assam. Indian Journal of Medical Research 139:643-664.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Franklin RC, Matthew AW, Jef A, Michael ND, George ME, Mary JF (2012). Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Disk Susceptibility Tests, 11th edition, 2012.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Galvanoskis J, Sandblom J, Bergqvist B, Galt S, Hammerius (1999). Cytoplasmic Ca ++ oscillation in humain leukemia T-cells are reduced by 50 Hz magnetic field. Bio electromagnetic 20(5):269-276.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gashti CN, Baxi PV, Whittier WL, Korbet SM (2020). The Renal Biopsy in Chronic Kidney Disease. In Chronic Renal Disease (pp. 1207-1222). Academic Press.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ghafourian S, Sadeghifard N, Soheili S, Sekawi Z (2014). Extended Spectrum Beta-lactamases: Definition, classification and epidemiology. Current Issues in Molecular Biology 17:11-22.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gillard N, Coffinonat S, Bure C, Davidlova M, Maurizot J, Cadone M, Spothium M, Maunizot M (2007). Radiation induced oxidative oxidation to the DNA binding domain repressor of lactose. Chemistry Journal 31(1):3-8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gupta V (2008). Metallo beta lactamases in Pseudomonas aerugi-nosa and Acinetobacter species. Expert Opinion Investigational Drugs 17(2):131-143.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Giriyapur RS, Nandihal NW, Krishna BV, Patil AB, Chandrasekhar MR (2011). Comparison of disc diffusion methods for the detection of extended spectrum beta lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae. Journal of Laboratory Physicians 3(1):33-36.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hocquet D, Plesiat P, Dehecq B, Mariotte P, Talon D, Bertrand X (2010). Nationwide investigation of extended-spectrum beta-lactamases, metallo-beta-lactamases, and extended-spectrum oxacillinases produced by ceftazidime-resistant Pseudomonas aeruginosa strains in France. Antimicrobal Agents and Chemotherapy 54(8):3512-3515.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jacoby GA, Han P (1996). Detection of extended-spectrum Blactamases in clinical isolates of Klebsiella pneumoniae and Escherichia coli. Journal of Clinical Microbiology 34:908-911.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[James G (2010). In: M Schuller, TP Sloots, GS James, CL Halliday and IWJ Carter (eds) PCR for clinical microbiology, ISBN: 978-90-481-9038-6 (Netherlands: Springer) P. 209.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jarlier V, Nicolas MH, Fournier G, Philippon A (1988). Extended spectrum -lactamases conferring transferable resistance to newer - lactam agents in Enterobacteriaceae: Hospital prevalence and susceptibility patterns. Reviews of Infectious Diseases 10:867-878.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Joly-Guillou ML, Kempf M, Cavallo JD, Chomarat M, Dubreuil L, Maugein J (2010). Comparative in vitro activity of Meropenem, Imipenem and Piperacillin/tazobactam against 1071 clinical isolates using 2 different methods: a French multicentre study. BMC Infectious Diseases 10(72).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kim D, Ahn JU, Lee CH, Jang SJ, Lee H, Yong D, Jeong SH, Lee K (2017). Increasing Resistance to Extended-Spectrum Cephalosporins, Fluoroquinolone, and Carbapenem in Gram-Negative Bacilli and the Emergence of Carbapenem Non-Susceptibility in Klebsiella pneumoniae: Analysis of Korean Antimicrobial Resistance Monitoring System (KARMS) Data From 2013 to 2015. Annals of Laboratory Medicine 37:231-239.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Klein RD, Hultgren SJ (2020). Urinary tract infections: microbial pathogenesis, host-pathogen interactions and new treatment strategies. Nature Reviews Microbiology 18:211-226.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kuefner MA, Brand M, Engert C, Schwab SA, Uder M (2015). Radiation Induced DNA Double-Strand Breaks in Radiology. Fortschritte auf dem Gebiet der Rntgenstrahlen 187(10):872-878.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumar D, Singh AK, Ali MR, Chander Y (2014). Antimicrobial susceptibility profile of extended spectrum -lactamase (ESBL) producing Escherichia coli from various clinical samples. Infectious Diseases (Auckland) 7:1-8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lee SW, Kim YH (2015). Uropathogens based on Antibiotic Susceptibility. Urogenital Tract Infection 10:67-73.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Livermore DM (1995). B- lactamases in laboratory and clinical resistance. Clinical Microbiology Review 8:557-584.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Livermore DM (2009). Has the era of untreatable infections arrived? Journal of Antimicrobial Chemotherapy 64 Suppl (1):29-36.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lucena A, Libera M, Dalla Costab, da Silva Nogueirab K, Matosd PA, Galesd AC, Rabonia SM (2014). Comparison of phenotypic tests for the detection of metallo-beta-lactamases in clinical isolates of Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Enfermedades Infecciosas Microbiologia Clinica 32(10):625-630.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Meini MR, Llarrull LI, Vila AJ (2014). Evolution of Metallo- -lactamases: Trends Revealed by Natural Diversity and in vitro Evolution. Antibiotics 3(3):285-316.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mohammed MA, Alnour MST, Shakurfo1 OM, Aburass MM (2016). Prevalence and antimicrobial resistance pattern of bacterial strains isolated from patients with urinary tract infection in Messalata Central Hospital, Libya. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Medicine 9(8):771-776.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nakamura A, Miyake K, Misawa S, Kuno Y, Horii T, Kondo, S Tabe Y, Ohsaka A (2013). Meropenem as predictive risk factor for isolation of multidrug-resistant Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Journal of Hospital Infection 83:153-155.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nebras RM, Hanna SS, Mohammed F Al-Marjani, Khalid HM (2016). Effect of gamma and beta radiation on multi-drug resistant (MDR) pseudomonas aeruginosa resistance colistin isolated from skin, burn, wound infections and inhibition of MEXXY, MEXAB-OPRM efflux pumps. World Journal of Pharmaceutical Research 5(3).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Niemira BA, Kelly A, Lonczynski KA, Sommers CH (2006). Radiation sensitivity of Salmonella isolates relative to resistance to ampicillin, chloramphenicol or gentamicin. Radiation Physics and Chemistry 75:1080-1086.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ozyurt M, Haznedaroglu T, Sahiner F, Oncul O, Ceylan S, Ardic N, Erdemoğlu A (2008). Antimicrobial resistance profiles of community-acquired uropathogenic Escherichia coli isolates during 2004-2006 in a training hospital in Istanbul. Mikrobiyoloji Blteni 42(2):231-243.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Potron A, Poirel L, Nordmann P (2015). Emerging broad-spectrum resistance in Pseudomonas aeruginosa and Acinetobacter baumannii: Mechanisms and epidemiology. International Journal of Antimicrobial Agents 45(6):568-585.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pouget J-P, Frelon S, Ravanat J-L, Testard I, Odin F, Cadet J (2002). Formation of Modified DNA Bases in Cells Exposed Either to Gamma Radiation or to High-LET Particles. Radiation Research 157(5):589-595.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rajkowski KT, Boyd G, Thayer DW (2003). Irradiation D10 values for Escherishia coli O157:H7 and Salmonella sp. on inoculated broccoli seeds and effects of irradiation on broccoli sprout keeping quality and seed viability. Journal of Food Protection 66:760-766.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sage E, Shikazono N (2017). Radiation-induced clustered DNA lesions: Repair and mutagenesis. Free Radical Biology  Medicine 107:125-135.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Salleh MN, Azman SNL, Mulyadi HIA, Amba L (2017). Study for monitoring of antimicrobial resistance trends (smart): A Surveillance of Gram-negative Bacilli Causing Urinary Tract Infections in Inpatient. International Journal of Biomedical Laboratory Science 6(12):12-16.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref50">
				<label>50</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Salimi F, Eftekhar F (2013). Coexistence of AmpC and Extended-Spectrum -lactamases in Metallo -Lactamase Producing Pseudomonas aeruginosa Burn Isolates in Tehran Jundishapur. Journal of Microbiology 6(8):e7178.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref51">
				<label>51</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shahcheraghi F, Nikbin VS, Feizabadi MM (2010). Identification and genetic characterization of metallo-beta-lactamase- producing strains of Pseudomonas aeruginosa in Tehran, Iran. New Microbiology 33(3):243.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref52">
				<label>52</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shaikh S, Fatima J, Shakil S, Mohd S, Rizvi D, Kamal MA (2015). Risk factors for acquisition of extended spectrum beta lactamase producing Escherichia coli and Klebsiella pneumoniae in North-Indian hospitals. Saudi Journal of Biological Sciences 22:37-41.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref53">
				<label>53</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sedighi M, Hasanzadeh A, Safiri S, Syedi N, Mostafaei S, Faghri J (2015). Detection of blaSPM-1 Metallo--Lactamase Gene in Imipenem-Resistant Pseudomonas aeruginosa Strains Isolated From Hospitalized Patients in Isfahan Hospitals. Journal of Archive in Military Medicine 3(2):e26977.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref54">
				<label>54</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Seid J, Asrat D (2005). Occurrence of extended-spectrum beta-lactamase enzymes in clinical isolates of Klebsiella species from Harar region, eastern Ethiopia. Acta Tropica 95(2):143-148.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref55">
				<label>55</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sridhar Rao PN, Basavarajappa KG, Krishna GL (2008). Detection of extended spectrum beta-lactamase from clinical isolates in Davangere. Indian. Journal of Pathology and Microbiology 51(4):497-499.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref56">
				<label>56</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Talbot GH (2013). Beta-Lactam antimicrobials: what have you done for me lately? Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences 1277:76-83.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref57">
				<label>57</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thomson JM, Bonomo RA (2005). The threat of antibiotic resistance in Gram-negative pathogenic bacteria: beta-lactams in peril. Current Opinion in Microbiology 8(5):518-24.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref58">
				<label>58</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vandana KE, Honnavar P (2009). AmpC beta lactamases among ESBL producing Escherichia coli and Klebsiella pneumoniae. Journal of Clinical and Diagnostic Research 3(4):1653-1656.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref59">
				<label>59</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Woc-Colburn L, Godinez D (2020). Evlution and Globalization of Antimicrobial Resistance. In Highly Infectious Diseases in Critical Care (chapter 2 pp.15-22). Springer, Cham.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref60">
				<label>60</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[World Health Organization (WHO) (2014). Antimicrobial resistance. Global report on surveillance. Geneva.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>