<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Microbiology Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0808</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJMR2020.9325</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) associated with cotton (Gossypium hirsutum L.) growing in the Far-North region of Cameroon]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ismael</surname>
            <given-names>Haman Ramza</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Honore</surname>
            <given-names>Issa Koulagna</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Abaka</surname>
            <given-names>Abba Said</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Philippe</surname>
            <given-names>Kosma</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Clautilde</surname>
            <given-names>Megueni</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">ismaelramzah@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>19</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>01</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>211</fpage>
	  <lpage>224</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/A270AA963842">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/A270AA963842	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-full-text-pdf/A270AA963842">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-full-text-pdf/A270AA963842	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The present study was carried out with the aim of highlighting the diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) associated with the rhizosphere of cotton grown in the Far-North region of Cameroon. To achieve this, composite soil and root samples were taken in six fields, chosen according to edapho-climatic conditions and types of cultural practices. After entrapping the glomales in the greenhouse, the roots of the trap plants were thinned and stained to assess colonization. The spores were isolated by wet sieving and their identification was made after analysis of their morpho-anatomical structures; then the diversity was evaluated through the calculated index. The results obtained have revealed the presence of AMF in all sites surveyed with a maximum abundance of 432 spores per 100 g of soil. Despite the low diversity of AMF that exist, four genera have been identified: Acaulospora, Gigaspora, Glomus and Scutellospora. A significant dominance of Glomus spp. (42%) was found. A strong correlation was found between soil physico-chemical parameters and abundance, as well as between species richness. This study confirms the presence of AMF strains in the cotton rhizosphere cultivated in this zone. The exploitation of this AMF could lead to a controlled production of local fungal inoculum, adapted to the edaphic and climatic conditions of the region, for a sustainable agriculture in Cameroon.

	 

	Key words: Cotton, rhizosphere, arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF), diversity, Far-North, Cameroun.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abakar AS, Megueni C, Tchuenteu TL, Kosma P (2019). Response of two cotton varieties on mycorrizal inoculation at Soudano-Sahelian savannah of Cameroon. East African Scholars Journal of Agriculture and Life Sciences 2(3):145-154.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abbas Y (2014). Microorganismes de la rhizosphre des Ttraclinaies : un outil pour optimiser la rgnration assiste du Tetraclinis articulata Vahl. Master. Thses de Doctorat PhD, Universit Mohammed V, Rabat Maroc 157p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Balzergue C, Puech-Pages V, Bcard G, Soizic FR (2011). The regulation of arbuscular mycorrhizal symbiosis by phosphate in pea early and systemic signaling envents. Journal of Experimental Botany 62(3):1049-1049.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Barker KR (1985). Sampling nematode communities. In An advanced Treatise on Meloidogyne, Methodology (2) Barker R, Sasser JN (eds). North Carolina State University Graphics, Raleigh: USA 3-14.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Begoude BDA, Sarri PS, Mpon YLT, Owona AD, Kapeua NM, Araki S. (2016). Composition of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi associated with cassava (Manihot esculenta Crantz) cultivars as influenced by chemical fertilization and tillage in Cameroon. Journal of Applied Biosciences 98:9270-9283.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Belay Z, Vestberg M, Assefa F (2013). Diversity and abundance of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi associated xith Acacia tress from different land use system in Ethiopia. African Journal of Microbiological Research 7:5503-5515.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Blaszkowski J. Tadych M, Madej T (2002). Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (Glomales, Zygomycota) of the bledowska desert, Poland. Societastis Botanicorum Poloniae 71(1):71-85.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Borriello R, Lumini E, Girlanda M, Bonfante P, Bianciotto V (2012). Effects of different management practices on arbuscular mycorrhizal fungal diversity in maize fields by a molecular approach. Biology and Fertility of Soils 48:911-922.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bossou L-DR, Houngnandan HB, Adandonon A, Zoundji C, Houngnandan P (2019). Diversit des champignons mycorhiziens arbusculaires associs  la culture du mas (Zea mays L.) au Bnin. International Journal of Biological and Chemical Sciences 13(2):597-609.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Calvet G, Villemin P (l986). Interprtation des analyses de terre. France, SCP A. 24p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Caravaca F, Barea JM, Figueroa D, Roldn A (2002). Assessing the effectiveness of mycorrhizal inoculation and soil compost addition for enhancing reafforestation with Olea europaea subsp. sylvestris through changes in soil biological and physical parameters. Applied Soil Ecology 20:107-11.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dalp Y (2005). Les mycorhizes : outil de protection des plantes mais non une panace. Phytoprotection 865(1):53-59.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Diallo AT (1998). Contribution  ltude taxonomique et cologique des Glomales et de linfluence de la mycorhization avec Glomus mosseae et Glomus versiforme sur la croissance et la productivit du nib, Vigna ungutculata (L.) Walp. cultiv en condition de dficit hydrique. These De Doctorat De 3me Cycle, Universite Cheikh Anta Diop, Sngale 113p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dickson S, Smith FA, Smith SE (2007). Structural differences in arbuscular mycorrhizal symbioses: more than 100 years after Gallaud, where next? Mycorhiza 17:375-393.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Duchaufour PH (1977). Pdogense et classification pdologique (II). Masson Paris. 477 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Folefack DP, Ntsou Bakwowi J, Kpade PC (2014). Crise de la filire cotonnire et scurit alimentaire au Nord Cameroun. Journal of Applied Biosciences 75:6221-6231.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gerdeman JW, Nicolson TH (1963). Spore of mycorrhizal endogone species extracted from soil by wet sieving and decanting. Trans Britanique of Mycology Society 46:235-244.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gosling P, Hodge A, Goodlass G, Bending GD (2006). Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi and organic farming Agriculture. Ecosystems and Environment 113:17-35.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Haougui A, Souniabe PS, Doumma A, Adam T (2013). Evolution des populations des champignons endomycorhiziens sur les adventices de quatre sites marachers de la rgion de Maradi au Niger. International Journal of Biological and Chemical Sciences 7(2):554-565.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hassan SED, Boon E, St-Arnaud M, Hijri M (2011). Molecular biodiversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in trace metalpolluted soils. Molecular Ecology 20:3469-3483.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Husband R, Herre EA, Turner SL, Gallery R, Young JPW (2002). Molecular diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi and patterns of host association over time and space in a tropical forest. Molecular Ecology 11:2669-2678.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[INRA (1995). Rfrentiel pdologique. Association Franaise dtude des sols. INRA France 332 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[ISO (1991). Soil Quality - Terminology - Soil data structuration, AFNOR Paris. Jefwa JM, Mungatu J, Okoth P, Muya E, Roimen H, Njuguini S (2009). Influence of land use types on occurrence of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in the high altitude regions of MT. Kenya. Tropical and Subtropical Agroecosystems 11:277-290.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Johnson JM, Houngnandan P, Kane A, Sanon K, Neyra M (2013). Diversity patterns of indigenous arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi associated with rhizosphere of cowpea Vigna unguiculata L. Walp. in Benin, West Africa. Pedobiologia 56(3):121-128.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Juniper S, Abbott L (1993). Vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizas and soil salinity. Mycorrhiza 4:45-57.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Leake JR, Johnson D, Donnelly DP, Muckle GE, Boddy L, Read DJ (2004). Networks of power and influence: the role of mycorrhizal mycelium in controlling plant communities and agroecosystem functioning. Canadian Journal of Botany 82:1016-1045.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[MacDonald DC (1977). Methods of soil and tissue analysis used in the analytical laboratory. Ottawa, Canada: Canadian Forestry Service Information Report MM-X-78.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Marschner P, Kandeler E, Marschner B (2003). Structure and Function of the Soil Microbial Community in a Long-Term Fertilizer Experiment. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 35:453-461.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mbogne TJ, Temegne C, Hougnandan P, Youmbi E, Tonfack LB, Ntsomboh-Ntsefong G (2015). Biodiversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi of pumpkins Cucurbita spp. under the influence of fertilizers in ferralitic soils of Cameroon and Benin. Journal of Applied Biology and Biotechnology 3(05):001-010.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Megueni C, Awono ET, Ndjouenkeu R (2011). Effet simultan de la dilution et de la combinaison du Rhizobium et des mycorhizes sur la production foliaire et les proprits physico-chimiques des jeunes feuilles de Vigna unguiculata (L.) Walp. Journal of Applied Biosciences 40:2668-2676.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mekahlia MN (2014). Dpendance mycorhizienne de lolivier (Olea europea L.) dans lest algrien et mycorhization contrle de la varit Ferkeni. Thse de Doctorat, Universit Badji Mokhtar Annaba, Algrie, 160p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mohammad J, Rushdi Hamadw S, Issa Malkawi H (2003). Population of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungiin semi-arid environment of Jordan as influenced by biotic and abiotic factors. Journal of Arid Environment 53:409-417.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Morton JB (1992). Problems and solutions for the integration of Glomalean taxonomy,systematic, biology and the study of endomycorrhizal phenomena. Mycorrhiza 2:97-109.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Morton JB, Bentivenga SP, Wheeler WW (1993). Germ plasma in the International Collection of Arbuscular and Vesicular-arbuscular Mycorrhi-zal Fungi (INVAM) and procedures for culture development, documentation and storage. Mycotaxon 48:491-528.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Musoko M, Last FT, Mason PA (1994). Population of spores of vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in undisturbed soils of secondary semi-deciduous moist tropical forest in Cameroon. Forest Ecology and Management 63:359-377.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nandjui J (2015). Ecologie des champignons mycorhiziens aArbuscules dans trois zones de production digname (Dioscorea spp.) en Cte dIvoire. Thse de Doctorat, Universit de Nangui Abrogoua Cte dIvoire 172 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nehila A (2016). Symbiose tllurique: rle et mcanisme de tolrance aux stress biotiques. Thse de Doctorat LMD, Universit dOran 1, Algrie, 172 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ngonkeu MEL, Nwaga D, Adamou S, Fokom R, Tchameni NS, Onguene NA, Nana WL, Chaintreuil C, Amougou A, Moulin L, Prin Y, Lebrun M, Dreyfus B (2013). Diversit des champignons mycorhiziens arbusculaires du Cameroun. IRD Editions, Marseille pp. 141-154.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Oehl F, Sieverding E, Ineichen K, Mader P, Boller T, Wiemken A (2003). Impact of land use intensity on the species diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in agroecosystems of central Europe. Applied Environment and Microbiology 69:2816-2824.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Oehl F, Sieverding E, Palenzuela J, Ineichen K, Silva GA (2011). Advances in Glomeromycota taxonomy and classification. IMA Fungus 2(2):191-199.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Olina Bassala JP, MBiandoun M, Ekorong JA, Asfom P (2008). volution de la fertilit des sols dans un systme cotonnier crales au Nord Cameroun: diagnostic et perspectives. Tropicultura 26(4):240-245.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Olsen SR (1952). Measurement of surface phosphore on hydroxylapatite and phosphate rock with radiophosphorus. Journal of Physical Chemistry 56:630-632.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ongun NA, Tsimi JPM, Balla MJE (2002). Statut mycorhizien de lOkoum (Aucoumea klaineana Pierre) en rgnration artificielle au sud Cameroun. Tropicultura 20(3):104-108.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ouallal I, Abbas Y, Ech-cheddadi S, Ouajdi M, Ouhadach M, El Yacoubi H, Benaissa K, El Goumi Y, Rochdi A (2018). Diversit des champignons endomycorhiziens de larganier et potentiel mycorhizogne des sols rhizosphriques des arganeraies du Sud-Ouest marocain. Bois et Forts des Tropiques 338:73-86.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pansu M, Gautheyrou J (2003). Lanalyse du sol minralogique, organique et minrale. Montpellier, France: Springer-Verlag. 993 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Peyret-Guzzon M (2014). Etudes molculaires de la diversit des communauts et populations de champignons mycorhiziens  arbuscules (Glomeromycota). Thse de Doctorat, Universite De Bourgogne, France, 190p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Philips JM, Hayman DS (1970). Improved procedures for clearing roots and staining parasitic and vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi for rapid assessment of infection. Trans Britanic of Mycology Society 55:158-161.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Redecker D, Schler A, Stockinger H, Strmer S, Morton J, Walker C (2013). An evidence-based consensus for the classification of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (Glomeromycota). Mycorrhiza 23:515-531.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Schenk NC, Perez Y (1990). Manual for Identification of VA Mycorrhizal Fungi. Synergistic Publications, Gainesville, Florida, 250 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref50">
				<label>50</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Schler A, Walker C (2010). The Glomeromycota, a species list with new families and new genera. The Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh 19:58]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref51">
				<label>51</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sidhoum W (2011). Diversit des mycorhyses arbusculaires chez la varit sigoise dolivier (Olea europea L.): Etude de leurs efficacits sur la croissance des plantes. Mmoire de Master, Universit de dOran Es-Senia, Algrie, 192p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref52">
				<label>52</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sieverding E, Silva GA, Berndt R, Oehl F (2014). Rhizoglomus, a new genus of the Glomeracea. Mycotaxon 129(2):373-386.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref53">
				<label>53</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Smith SE, Facelli E, Pope S, Smith FA (2010). Plant performance in stressful environments: interpreting new and established knowledge of the roles of arbuscular mycorrhizas. Plant and Soil 326:3-20.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref54">
				<label>54</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Straker CJ, Hilditch AJ, Rey MEC (2010). Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi associated with cassava (Manihot esculenta Crantz) in South Africa. South African Journal of Botany 76:102-111.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref55">
				<label>55</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Talbi Z, Chliyeh M, Selmaoui K, Ouazzani Touhami A, Benkirane R, Douira A (2014). Mycorrhizal status of Populus alba and accompanying species of Riparian forest in the reserve of sidi boughaba (northwest of morocco). International Journal of Plant, Animal and Environmental Sciences 4(2):126-133.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref56">
				<label>56</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tchabi A, Coyne D, Hountondji F, Lawouin L,Wiemken A, Oehl F (2008). Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in the yam belt. West Africa African Journal of Biotechnology 56:256-268.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref57">
				<label>57</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tchinmegni FI, Tsobeng AC, Ngonkeu MEL, Tchoundjeu Z (2016). Evaluation du statutmycorhizien chez Allanblackia floribunda envue de sa domestication en zones forestires humides du Cameroun. Revue Scientifque, Technique Fort et Environnement du Bassin du Congo 6:81-83.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref58">
				<label>58</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Temegne NC, Wakem G-A, Taffouo VD, Mbogne TJ, Onguene AN, Youmbi E, Ntsombot-Ntsefong G (2017). Effect of phosphorus fertilization on arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in the Bambara groundnut rhizosphere. African Journal of Microbiology Research 11(37):1399-1410.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref59">
				<label>59</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tobolbai R, Adamou S, Ngakou A (2018). Morphological and structural diversities ofindigenous endomycorrhiza communitiesassociated to maize [Zea mays (L.)] in Northern Cameroonian soils. Journal of Animal and Plant Sciences 38(1):6057-6073.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref60">
				<label>60</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Trouvelot A, Kough JL, Gianinazzi-Pearson V (1986). Mesure du taux de mycorhization VA dun systme radiculaire. Recherche de mthodes destimation ayant une signification fonctionnelle. In: physiology and genetics aspects of mycorrhizae. Gianinazi-Pearson V et Gianinazzi S (Eds), 1st ESM, INRA Press, Paris, 217-221 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref61">
				<label>61</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tsozue D, Nghonda JP, Mekem DL (2015). Impact of land management system on crop yields and soil fertility in Cameroon. Journal of solid Earth 7:1761-1796.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref62">
				<label>62</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vestberg M, Saari K, Kukkonen S, Hurme T (2005). Mycotrophy of corps in rotation and soil amendment with peat influence the abundance and effectiveness of indigenous arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in field soil. Mycorrhiza 15(6):447-458.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref63">
				<label>63</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Voko D-RRB, Nandjui J, jean-marc drolet SeryJ-MD, Fotso B, Amoa JA, Kouadio M-SA, Coulibaly S, Niamke S, Zeze A (2013). Abundance and diversity of Arbuscular Mycorrhizal Fungal (AMF) communities associated with cassava (Manihot esculenta crantz) rhizospherein abengourou, east Cte dIvoire. Journal of Ecology and the Natural Environment 5(11):360-370.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref64">
				<label>64</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Walkley A, Black IA (1934). An examination of the Degtjareff method for determining soil organic matter and a proposed modification of the chromic acid titration method. Soil Sciences 37:29-38.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref65">
				<label>65</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zz A, Ouattara B, Brou CY, Van Tuinen D, Diallo-Attah H, Sangare A (2007). Distribution et abondance de spores de champignons endomycorhizognes  arbuscules dans diffrents types de forts de la Tn en Cte dIvoire. Agronomie Africaine 19(2):103-111.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>