<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0816</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJPP2020.5143</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Haematology, serum biochemistry and histopathological findings associated with sub-chronic administration of methanol leaf extract of Pterocarpus santalinoides DC in albino rats]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Thelma</surname>
            <given-names>Ebele Ihedioha</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Isaac</surname>
            <given-names>Uzoma Asuzu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Aruh</surname>
            <given-names>Ottah Anaga</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>John</surname>
            <given-names>Ikechukwu Ihedioha</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">thelma.ihedioha@unn.edu.ng</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>23</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>28</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>5</issue>
	  	  <fpage>136</fpage>
	  <lpage>146</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0CB8EF163899">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0CB8EF163899	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-full-text-pdf/0CB8EF163899">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-full-text-pdf/0CB8EF163899	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The effects of sub-chronic administration of Pterocarpus santalinoides methanol leaf extract (PSME) on haematology, serum biochemistry and histology of albino rats were evaluated. Twenty female albino rats, randomly assigned into four groups (A-D) of five rats each, were used for the study. Groups A-C were treated orally with 500, 250 and 50 mg/kg PSME, respectively, while Group D was given distilled water as placebo at the dose of 10 ml/kg (untreated control). Treatment was done daily for 3 months after which blood samples were collected for haematology and serum biochemistry.  After blood sample collection, the rats were weighed and humanely euthanized. The liver, kidneys, heart and spleen were eviscerated and weighed, and relative organ weights calculated. Thin slices of the liver and kidneys were processed for histopathology. Results showed no significant (p gt; 0.05) differences between the groups in all the haematological parameters assayed. The PSME (50 mg/kg) led to significantly (p lt; 0.05) higher serum albumin level, and at 250 and 50 mg/kg, it led to significantly (p lt; 0.05) lower serum creatinine level and mild random vacoulation of the hepatocytes. The PSME at all doses used in the study led to significantly (p lt; 0.05) higher body weights and significantly (p lt; 0.05) lower relative spleen and heart weights. It also caused moderate hyperaemia of the renal cortex at 500 mg/kg. It was concluded that oral sub-chronic administration of graded doses of methanol leaf extract of P. santalinoides to albino rats is non-toxic.

	Key words: Pterocarpus santalinoides, methanol extract, sub-chronic toxicity, haematology, serum biochemistry, histopathology.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Acary E, Anshu PS (2008). Herbal preparations. Traditional Medicine Preparations 61:142-170.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adeneye AA, Ajagbonna OP, Adeleke TI, Bello SO (2006). Preliminary toxicity and phytochemical studies of the stem bark aqueous extract of Musanga cecropioides in rats. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 105:374-379.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aderemi FA (2004). Effects of replacement of wheat bran with cassava root unsupplemented with enzyme on the haematology and serum biochemistry of pullet chicks. Tropical Journal of Animal Science 7:147-153.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adesina SK (1982). Studies on the Nigerian herbal medicinal plants. International Journal of Crude Drug Research 20(2):93-100.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adetunji JA (2007). Reviewing Pterocarpus species and their distribution. African Journal of Traditional, Complementary and Alternative Medicine 4(2):23-36.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Afolabi KD, Akinsoyinu AO, Olajide R, Akinleye SB (2010). Haematological parameters of the Nigerian local grower chickens fed varying dietary levels of palm kernel cake. Proceedings of the 35th Annual Conference of Nigerian Society for Animal Production, pp. 247.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amaechi NC (2009). Nutritive and Anti-Nutritive Evaluation of wonderful Kola Seeds. Pakistan Journal of Nutrition 8(8):1120-1122.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anowi CF, Okonkwo C, Agbata CA, Ezeokafor E (2012). Preliminary phytochemical screening, evaluation of acute toxicity and antipyretic activity of methanolic extract of Pterocarpus santalinoides (Fabaceae). International Journal of Pharmaceutical and Phytopharmacological Research 1(6):343-346.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Asante-Duah K (2002). Public health risk assessment for human exposure to chemicals (illustrated). Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands, pp. 234-258.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[AVMA (2013). AVMA guidelines for the euthanasia of animals: 2013 edition. American Veterinary Medical Association (AVMA), Illinois, USA, pp. 48-50.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ayman MM (2013). Hematological alterations in diabetic rats-role of adipocytokines and effects of citrus flavonoids. Experimental and Clinical Sciences Journal 12:647-657.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Babson AL, Greeley SJ, Coleman CM, Philips GE (1966). Phenolphthalein monophosphate as a substrate for serum alkaline phosphatase. Clinical Chemistry 12(18):482-490.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Blass KG, Thiebert RJ, Lam LK (1974). A study of the mechanism of the Jaffe reaction. Journal of Clinical Chemistry and Clinical Biochemistry 12:336-343.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bolliger AP, Everds NE (2010). Hematology of laboratory rodents: mouse (Mus musculus) and rat (Rattus norvegicus). In: Weiss DJ and Wardrop KJ (eds), Schalms Veterinary Hematology, 6th edn. Wiley-Blackwell, Iowa pp. 852-862.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Briejer MR, Bosmans JP, Van Dade P, Jurzaak M, Heylen L, Leysen JE, Prins NH, Schuurkes JA (2001). The in vitro pharmacological profile of procalopride, a novel enterokinetic compound. European Journal of Pharmacology 423(1):71-83.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Colville J (2002). Blood chemistry. In: Hendrix CM (ed), Laboratory procedures for Veterinary Technicians, 4th edn. Mosby, St Louis pp. 75-103.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Enemali MO, Udedi SC, Ubaoji KI, Haruna GS, Augustine E (2019). Modulatory effect of leaf extracts of Pterocarpus santalinoides Hook F. (red sandal wood) on acetamoniphen-induced hepatotoxicity in albino rats. FUW Trends in Science and Technology 4(2):366-371.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Eze SO, Cornelius C, Okereke HC (2012). Phytochemical and antimicrobial analyses of the stem bark of Pterocarpus santalinoides (Nturu ukpa). Asian Journal of Natural and Applied Sciences 1(3):26-32.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fawcett JK, Scott JE (1960). A rapid and precise method for the determination of urea. Journal of Clinical Pathology 13:156-159.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Higgins T, Beutler E., Doumas BT (2008b). Analytical methodology - Serum bilirubin. In: Burtis CA, Ashwood ER, Bruns DE (eds), Tietz Fundamentals of Clinical Chemistry, 6th edn. Saunders Elsevier, Missouri, pp. 524-525.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Higgins T, Beutler E, Doumas BT (2008a). Measurement of haemoglobin in blood. In: Burtis CA, Ashwood ER, Bruns DE (eds), Tietz Fundamentals of Clinical Chemistry, 6th edn. Sanders Elsevier, Missouri, pp. 524-525.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ihedioha TE, Onwuegbuka LU, Ihedioha JI (2017). Hepatoprotective effects of methanol leaf extract of Pterocarpus santalinoides DC on acetaminophen-induced liver damage in albino rats (Rattus norvegicus). Nigerian Journal of Animal Production 44(5):34-39.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ihedioha TE, Asuzu IU, Anaga AO, Ihedioha JI (2019). Hepatoprotective and antioxidant activities of Pterocarpus santalinoides methanol leaf extract. African Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology 13(18):359-373.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ihedioha TE, Okechukwu VN, Ihedioha JI (2018). Effects of aqueous leaf infusion of Pterocarpus santalinoides DC on serum lipid profile of guinea pigs (Carvia porcellus). Journal of Complementary Medicine Research 7(2):154-160.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Iwu MM (1993). Handbook of African medicinal plants, 1st edn. Chemical Rubber Company Press Incorporation, Boca Raton, U.S.A. pp. 133-135.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Johnson AM (2008). Amino acids and proteins. In: Burtis CA, Ashwood ER, Bruns DE (eds), Tietz Fundamentals of Clinical Chemistry, 6th edn. Saunders Elsevier, Missouri pp. 206-316.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Keay RWJ (1989). Trees of Nigeria. A revised version of Nigeria trees (1960 - 1964). Keay RWJ, Onochie CFA, Stanfied DP (eds). Claredon Press, Oxford, United Kingdom, p. 476.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Klein B, Read PA, Babson AL (1960). Rapid method for the quantitative determination of serum alkaline phosphatase. Clinical Chemistry 6:269-275.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kulkarni YA, Veeranjaneyulu A (2012). Toxicological evaluation of the methanol extract of Gmelina arborea Roxb. bark in mice and rats. Toxicology International 19:2.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lamb EJ, Price CP (2008). Creatinine, urea and uric acid. In: Burtis CA, Ashwood E R, Bruns DE (eds), Tietz Fundamentals of Clinical Chemistry, 6th edn. Saunders Elsevier, Missouri, pp. 363-372.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nowacek JM (2010). Fixation and tissue processing. In: Kumar GL and Kierman JA (eds), Pathology Education Guide: Special Stains and H  E, 2nd edn. Dako, California, North America pp. 141-152.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Obi CF, Nzeakor TA, Okpala MI, Ezeh IO, Nwobi LG, Omeje MO, Ezeokonkwo RC (2019). Evaluation of anti-trypanosomal activity of Pterocarpus santalinoides LHerit ex DC hydroethanol leaf extract in rats experimentally infected with Trypanosoma brucei. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 243, 112085.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Obidah N, Saad UA, Wurochekke AU (2009). Toxic effects of aqueous stem bark extract of Cassia sieberiana on some biochemical parameters in rats. African Journal of Biochemistry Research 3(5):229-231.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Odeh IC, Tor-Anyim A (2014). Phytochemical and antimicrobial evaluation of leaf-extracts of Pterocarpus santalinoides. European Journal of Medicinal Plants 4(1):105-110.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Offor CE, Ogbugo SO (2015). Effects of ethanol leaf extract of Pterocarpus santalinoides on haematological parameters in rats. Academic Journal of Oral and Dental Medicine 2(2):19-22.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Offor CE, Nwankwegu NJ, Ugwu-Okechukwu PC, Aja PM (2015). The effects of ethanol leaf extract of Pterocarpus santalinoides on liver enzymes of albino rats. American-Eurasian Journal of Agriculture and Environmental Sciences 15(5):920-922.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ogan MT (2004). Trees of Nigeria. Journal of Complementary and integrative medicine 123(1):125-129.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ojiako OA, Nwanjo HV (2006). Is Vernonia amygdalina hepatotoxic or hepatoprotective? Response from biochemical and toxicity studies in rats. Journal of African Biotechnology 5:1648-1659.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Okwu DE, Ekeke T (2003). Phytochemical screening and medicinal composition of chewing sticks in South Eastern Nigeria. Global Journal of Pure and Applied sciences 9 (1):235-238.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Olafedehan CO, Obun AM, Yusuf MK, Adewumi OO, Oladefedehan AO, Awofolaji AO, Adeniji AA (2010). Effects of residual cyanide in processed cassava peal meals on haematological and biochemical indices of growing rabbits. Proceedings of 35 Annual Conference of Nigerian Society for Animal Production, pp. 212-218.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Poppenga RH (2007). Herbal medicine: potential for intoxication and interactions with conventional drugs. In: Wynn S, Fougere B (eds.) Veterinary Herbal Medicine. Mosby Inc., Missouri USA pp. 183-207.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Reitman S, Frankel S (1957). A colorimetric method for determination of serum glutamic oxaloacetic and glutamic pyruvic transaminases. American Journal of Clinical Pathology 28:56-62.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rifai N, Warnick GR, Remaley AT (2008). Analysis of lipids, lipoproteins and apolipoproteins. In: Burtis CA, Ashwood ER, Bruns DE (eds), Tietz Fundamentals of Clinical Chemistry, 6th edn. Saunders Elsevier, Missouri, pp. 422-427.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sacks DB (2008). Measurement of glucose in body fluids. In: Burtis CA, Ashwood ER, Bruns DE (eds.), Tietz Fundamentals of Clinical Chemistry, 6th edn. Saunders Elsevier, Missouri, pp. 389-393.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Salawu OA, Aliyu M, Tijani AY (2008). Haematological studies on the ethanolic stem bark extract of Pterocarpus erinaceus poir (fabaceae). African Journal of Biotechnology 7(9):1212-1215.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sancho E, Cern JJ, Ferrando MD (2000). Cholinesterase activity and haematological parameters as biomarkers of sub-lethal molinate exposure in Anguilla anguilla. Ecotoxicology Environmental Safe 46:81-86.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Schalm OW, Jain NC, Carrol EJ (1975). Veterinary haematology, 3rd edn. Lea and Febieyer, Philadelphia pp. 55 - 77.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Searcy RL, Reardon JE, Foreman JA (1967). A new photometric method for serum urea nitrogen determination. American Journal of Medical Technology 33:15-20.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sofowora EA (1985). Medicinal plants and traditional remedies in Africa. University of Ife Press, Nigeria.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref50">
				<label>50</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Subramanion LJ, Zuraini YC, Yee LL, Lachimanan YL, Sreenivasan S (2011). Acute oral toxicity of methanolic seed extract of Cassia fistula in mice. Molecules 16.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref51">
				<label>51</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thapa BR, Walia A (2007). Liver function tests and their interpretation. Indian Journal of Pediatrics 74:663-671.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref52">
				<label>52</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thrall MA, Weiser MG (2002). Hematology. In: Hendrix CM (ed), Laboratory Procedures for Veterinary Technicians, 4th edn. Mosby, Missouri pp. 29-74.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref53">
				<label>53</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thrall MA, Weiser MG, Allison R, Campbell TW (2012). Veterinary Hematology and Clinical Chemistry, 2nd edn. John Wiley and Sons, Wiley-Blackwell, USA pp. 762.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref54">
				<label>54</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tiwari RH, Sinha M (2010). Veterinary Toxicology. Oxford Book Company, Jaipur, India, pp. 133-174.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref55">
				<label>55</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Uchino S, Bellomo R, Goldsmith D (2012). The meaning of the blood urea nitrogen/creatinine ratio in acute kidney injury. Clinical Kidney Journal 5(2):187-191.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref56">
				<label>56</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ward JW, Elsea JR (1997). Animal care and use in drug fate and metabolism. Methods and techniques Vol.1, Edward RG, Jean LH (eds), Marcel Dekker, New York pp. 372-390.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref57">
				<label>57</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Winsor L (1994). Tissue processing. In: Woods A and Ellis R (eds), Laboratory histopathology. Churchill Livingstone, New York pp. 4.2-1-4.2-39.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref58">
				<label>58</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zimmermann M (1983). Ethical guidelines for investigations of experimental pain in conscious animals. Pain 16(2):109-110.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>