<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0816</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJPP2020.5134</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Prevalence and the level of evidences supporting off-label prescribing of antidepressant, antipsychotic and antiepileptic drugs in Makkah Almukarramah: A case sectional study]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yosra</surname>
            <given-names>Al-Hindi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Amal</surname>
            <given-names>Al-sulami</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Aseel</surname>
            <given-names>Al-ghamdi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Nuha</surname>
            <given-names>Al-Harbi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Huda</surname>
            <given-names>Hamdi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Shooq</surname>
            <given-names>Al-moqati</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yara</surname>
            <given-names>Abualkair</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Arwa</surname>
            <given-names>Fairaq</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">yzhindi@uqu.edu.sa</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>21</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>5</issue>
	  	  <fpage>128</fpage>
	  <lpage>135</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/F0FC0BC63897">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/F0FC0BC63897	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-full-text-pdf/F0FC0BC63897">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-full-text-pdf/F0FC0BC63897	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Off-label prescribing is very common among physicians, particularly among psychiatrists and there is limited information regarding the extent of the unapproved drug use in Makkah city. The objective of this study was to assess the prevalence of off-label indications for antidepressant, antipsychotic and antiepileptic and the strength of evidence supporting use of the prescribed drug for the respective indication. A case sectional study was conducted on 15,955 prescriptions from 1 October 2018 to 6 January 2019 based on patient medication records obtained from an electronic medical record (EMRs) - health information system (HIS) from King Abdulaziz Hospital in Makkah city, Saudi Arabia. Two official databases (Micromedex and Lexicomp) were used to evaluate dual primary outcomes the determination off-label and on-label prescriptions and the level of evidence supporting the off-label indications. It showed that in 3 months there were 15,955 prescriptions concerning antipsychotics, antidepressants and antiepileptics drugs were issued to 5292 patients. Out of total 15,955 prescriptions, about 2218 (13.9%) prescriptions were off-label prescriptions for 29 drugs. The most frequently prescribed by class, were antidepressants 1025 (46.3%) followed by antipsychotics 1005 (45.3%) then antiepileptics 188 (8.5%). Off-label drugs use is common in psychiatric department and when physicians prescribed antidepressants, antipsychotics and antiepileptics for off-label indication, most of these prescribed indications were not supported by strong scientific evidences. The risks and benefits of off-label use should be carefully weighed up prior to prescribing these agents.

	Key words: Off-label, antipsychotics, antiepileptics, psychiatric, case sectional study.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anderson SL, Griend JP (2014). Quetiapine for insomnia: A review of the literature. American Journal of Health-System Pharmacy 71(5):394-402.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bashawri H (2013). Sleepless in Makkah City, Saudi Arabia: Prevalence and Risk Factors of Insomnia and the Variations in Sleep Quality among Visitors of Primary Health Care Centers. MPH. Emory University.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Botts SR, Raskind J (1999). Gabapentin and lamotrigine in bipolar disorder. American Journal of Health-System Pharmacy 56(19):1939-1944.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Calabrese JR, Bowden CL, Sachs GS, Ascher JA, Monaghan E, Rudd GD (1999). A Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Study of Lamotrigine Monotherapy in Outpatients With Bipolar I Depression. The Journal of Clinical Psychiatry 60(2):79-88.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Eguale T, Buckeridge DL, Verma A, Winslade NE, Benedetti A, Hanley JA, Tamblyn R (2016). Association of Off-label Drug Use and Adverse Drug Events in an Adult Population. JAMA Internal Medicine 176(1):55.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Eguale T, Buckeridge DL, Winslade NE, Benedetti A, Hanley JA, Tamblyn R (2012). Drug, Patient, and Physician Characteristics Associated With Off-label Prescribing in Primary Care. Archives of Internal Medicine 172(10):
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Franco V, Canevini MP, Capovilla G, Sarro GD, Galimberti CA, Gatti G, Perucca E (2014). Off-Label Prescribing of Antiepileptic Drugs in Pharmacoresistant Epilepsy: A Cross-Sectional Drug Utilization Study of Tertiary Care Centers in Italy. CNS Drugs 28(10):939-949.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fukada C, Kohler JC, Boon H, Austin Z, Krahn M (2012). Prescribing Gabapentin off Label: Perspectives from Psychiatry, Pain and Neurology Specialists. Canadian Pharmacists Journal / Revue Des Pharmaciens Du Canada 145(6).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kamath L (2017). Cost variation analysis study of oral anti-depressant drugs available in India. International Journal of Basic and Clinical Pharmacology 6(4):973.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maher AR, Maglione M, Bagley S, Suttorp M, Hu J, Ewing B, Shekelle PG (2011). Efficacy and Comparative Effectiveness of Atypical Antipsychotic Medications for Off-Label Uses in Adults. Jama 306(12):1359.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mercier A, Auger-Aubin I, Lebeau J, Schuers M, Boulet P, Hermil J, Peremans L (2013). Evidence of prescription of antidepressants for non-psychiatric conditions in primary care: An analysis of guidelines and systematic reviews. BMC Family Practice 14(1).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Onyenwenyi AJ (2008). Off-label prescribing of anticonvulsant drugs. (Order No. 3381471, University of Florida). ProQuest Dissertations and Theses, p. 184.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Park Susie H, Pharm D, BCPP, FCSHP (2013). Off-label use of atypical antipsychotics: Lack of evidence for their use in primary insomnia. Formulary 48(11):361-362,365-368,370-376.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rahajeng B, Ikawati Z, Andayani TM, Dwiprahasto I (2018). A Retrospective Study: The Off-Label Use Of Anticonvulsants At A Private Hospital In Indonesia. International Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences 10(5):119.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sartori SB, Singewald N (2019). Novel pharmacological targets in drug development for the treatment of anxiety and anxiety-related disorders. Pharmacology and Therapeutics 107402.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shrestha R, Prajapati S (2019). Assessment of prescription pattern and prescription error in outpatient Department at Tertiary Care District Hospital, Central Nepal. Journal of Pharmaceutical Policy and Practice 12(1):16.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Varghese D, Carroll N (2015). Resource Utilization and costs associated with off-label use of atypical Antipsychotics in a Community-Dwelling Adult Population: Findings from the Medical Expenditure Survey. Value in Health 18(3):
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Walton SM, Schumock GT, Lee K, Alexander GC, Meltzer D, Stafford RS (2008). Prioritizing Future Research on Off-Label Prescribing: Results of a Quantitative Evaluation. Pharmacotherapy. The Journal of Human Pharmacology and Drug Therapy 28(12):1443-1452.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wittich CM, Burkle CM, Lanier WL. (2012). Ten common questions (and theiranswers) about off-label drug use. Mayo Clinic Proceedings. 356:982-90.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wong J, Motulsky A, Abrahamowicz M, Eguale T, Buckeridge DL, Tamblyn R (2017). Off-label indications for antidepressants in primary care: Descriptive study of prescriptions from an indication based electronic prescribing system. BMJ 356, j603.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wong J, Motulsky A, Eguale T, Buckeridge DL, Abrahamowicz M, Tamblyn R (2016). Treatment Indications for Antidepressants Prescribed in Primary Care in Quebec, Canada, 2006-2015. Jama 315(20):2230.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>