<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>African Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0816</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/AJPP2020.5136</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Nutrients in Amazonian fruit pulps with functional and pharmacological interest]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Montero</surname>
            <given-names>I. F.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Saravia</surname>
            <given-names>S. A. M.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Santos</surname>
            <given-names>R. A.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>dos</surname>
            <given-names>Santos R. C.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Marca</surname>
            <given-names>J. A. F.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>da</surname>
            <given-names>Costa H. N. R.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">ismonterof@unex.es</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>27</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>5</issue>
	  	  <fpage>118</fpage>
	  <lpage>127</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/4461B8A63895">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/4461B8A63895	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-full-text-pdf/4461B8A63895">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-full-text-pdf/4461B8A63895	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[In this research, nine fruits cultivated in Northern Amazon were studied: Abiu, acerola, araccedil;aacute;, bacupari, biribaacute;, camu-camu, fruta-do-conde, graviola and taperebaacute;, with the objective of carrying out a proximate and nutritional study of the pulps of the Northern Amazon fruits. They were graviola (76.83 plusmn; 0.02 Kcal 100 g-1), bacupari (53.15 plusmn; 0.02 Kcal 100 g-1) and fruta-do-conde (46.66 plusmn; 0.02 Kcal 100 g-1). Among the macronutrients, potassium with high concentration stood out, especially in graviola (541.16 plusmn; 0.24 mg.100 g-1) and biribaacute; (468.21 plusmn; 0.13 mg 100 g-1). Among the micronutrients, iron concentrations was high in araccedil;aacute; pulp (3.04 plusmn; 0.02 mg 100 g-1), and abiu was abundant in zinc (3.71 plusmn; 0.02 mg 100 g-1) and manganese (6.61 plusmn; 0.11 mg 100 g-1). The presence of cobalt at the level of traces in some of the pulps studied stood out. The Pearson correlation coefficient was evaluated, as well as the statistical treatment by multivariate analysis Principal Component Analysis (PCA) to establish the correlation between the variables studied.

	Key words: Amazonian fruit, functional food, nutrients.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aguiar JPL (1996). Food composition tables of the Amazon. Acta Amaznica 26:121-126.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aletor VA, Adeogun OA (1995). Nutrient and antinutrient constituents of some tropical leafy vegetables. Food Chemistry 53:3775-3779.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Almeida MMA, de Souza PHM, Fonseca ML, Magalhes CEC, Lopes MFG, de Lemos TLG (2009). Evaluation of macro and micro-mineral content in fruits cultivated in the northeast of Brazil. Cincia e Tecnologia de Alimentos 23:581-589.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Arts IC, Hollman PC (2005). Polyphenols and disease risk in epidemiologic studies. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 81:371-375.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bairele M, Valentini J, Paniz G, Moro A, Junior FB, Garcia SC (2010). Possible effects of blood copper on hematological parameters in elderly. Jornal Brasileiro de Patologia e Medicina Laboratorial 46:463-470.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Berto A, Da Silva AF, Visentainer MM, de Souza NE (2015). Proximate compositions, mineral contents and fatty acid composition of native Amazon fruits. Food Research International 77:441-449.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Canuto GAB, Xavier AAO, Neves LC, Benassi MT (2010). Physical chemical characterization of fruit pulps from Amazonia and their correlation with free radical anti-free radicals. Revista Brasileira Frutic. Jaboticabal 32:1196-1205.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Carvalho MC, Baracat ECE, Sgarbieri VC (2010). Iron deficiency anemia and chronic disease anemia: disturbances of iron metabolism. Revista SAN 13:54-56.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cordeiro MHM, da Silva JM, Mizobutsi GP, Mizobutsi EH, da Mota WF (2015). Physical, chemical and nutritional characterization of red pulp pink pitahaya. Revista Brasileira Fruticultura Jaboticabal 37:20-26.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cozzolino SMF (2007). Bioavailability of nutrients. SP: Manile.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dantas ST, Saron ES, Dantas FBH, Yamashita DM, Kiyataka PHM (2007). Determining aluminuim dissolution when cooking food in aluminuim cans. Cincia e Tecnologia de Alimentos 27:291-297.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Darmon N, Briend A, Drewnowaki A (2004). Energy-dense are associated with lower diet costs: A community study of French adults. Public Health Nutrition 7:21-27.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dietary Reference Intakes (DRI) (2004).
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Douglas CR (2002). Necessidades minerais. In: Treatise on physiology applied to nutrition. Robe Editorial.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Caldeira SD, Hiane PA, Ramos MIL, Filho MMR (2004). Physical-chemical characterization of ara (Psidium guineense SW) and tucum (Vitez cymosa Bert.) Of the State of Mato Grosso do Sul Ceppa, Brazil. Boletim do Centro de Pesquisa e Processamento de Alimentos (Brazil).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Drewnowaki A, Fulgoni V (2008). Nutrient profiling of foods: Creating a nutrient-Rich. Food Index 66:23-29.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Empresa Brasileira de Pesquisa Agropecuria- EMBRAPA (2009). Manual of chemical analyzes of soils, plants and fertilizers. 2nd edition revised and extended, Brasilia, DF, 627 p,]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Nutrition Board (2013). Dietary reference intakes for vitamin A, vitamin K, arsenic, boron, chromium, copper, iodine, iron, manganese, molybdenum, nickel, silicon, vanadium and zinc. National Academy of Sciences, Washington.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Feitosa SD, Fabricante JR (2007). Potential fruit plant: Spondias mombin L., unexplored market. AREIA, PB.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Freitas CAS, Maia GA, da Costa JMC, Figueiredo RW, de Sousa HM (2014). Acerola: Production, composition nutritional aspects and products. Revista Brasileira Agrocincia, 12:395-400.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hardisson A, Rubio C, Baez A, Martin M, Alvarez R, Diaz E (2001). Mineral composition of the banana (Musa acuminate) from the island of Tenerife. Food Chemistry 73:153-161.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Herrera RP, Gabas AL, Yamashita F (2001). Osmotic dehydration of pineapple with edible coating-absorption isotherms. In: Latin American Symposium of Food (Abstracts), 4:190.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hubbell SP, He F, Condit R, Borda-de-gua L, Kellner J, Ter SH (2008). How many tree species are there in the Amazon and how many of them will go extinct? Proceedings of National Academy of Sciences, 105:11498-11504.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Instituto Adolfo Lutz (IAL) (2008). Physicochemical methods for food analysis (IV ed.) So Paulo.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Iseri LT, French JM (1984). Magnesium-natures physiologic calcium blocker. American Heart Journal, p. 108.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Krause MV, Mahan LK (2005). Minerals. In: food, nutrition and diet therapy. 11 ed. So Paulo, 2005.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Leterme P, Buldgen A, Estrada F, Londoo AM (2006). Mineral content of tropical fruits and unconventional foods of the Andes and the rain forest of Colombia. Food Chemistry 95:644-652.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maeda RN, Pantoja L, Yuyama LKO, Chaar JM (2006). Determination of the formulation and characterization of camu-camu nectar (Myrciaria dub McVaugh).Cincia e Tecnologia de Alimentos 26:70-74.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Macdle WD, Katch IF, Katch LV (2003). Exercise physiology: Energy, nutrition and human performance. 5 ed. Rio de Janeiro: Guanabara Koogan.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mahan LK, Escott-Stump S (2002). Food, nutrition and diet therapy. Roca, 1157p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Malavolta E (2006). Manual of mineral nutrition of plants. Piracicaba: ceres.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mariutti LRB, Rodrigues E, Chist RC, Fernandes E, Mercadate AZ Freitas SP (2014). The Amazonian fruit Byrsonima crassiflia effectively scavenges reactive oxygen and nitrogen species and protects human erythorocytes against oxidative demange. Food Research International 64:618-625.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Martyn CN, Coggan D, Inskip H, Lacey RF, Young WF (1997). Aluminium concentrations in drinking water and risk of Alzheimers disease. Epidemiology 8:281-286.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Medlicott AP, Thompson AK (1985). Analysis of sugars and organic acids in ripening mango fruits (Mangfera indica L. var Keitt) by high performance liquid chromatography. Journal of the Science of food and agriculture 36:561-566.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mendes-Filho NE, Carvalho MP, de Souza JMT (2014). Determination of macronutrients and minerals nutriente of the mango pulp (Mangifera indica L.). Perspectivas da Cincia e Tecnologia 6:22-36]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Moreto E (2008). Manual of mineral nutrition of plants, 2 ed Ampliada e revisada. Florianpolis. UFSC.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Norma de Procedimientos para muestreo de produtos vegetales. NTON 17002-02 (2002). Comision Nacional de Normalizacin Tcnica y Calidad del Ministerio de Fometo, industria y comercio. Norma tcnica Nicaraguense (NTN).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Panziera FB, Dorneles MM, Durgante PC, da Silva VL (2011). Evaluation of antioxidant minerals intake in elderly. Revista Brasileira de Geriatria e Gerontologia 14:49-58.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Penland JG (1994). Dietary boron, brain function and cognitive perfomance. Environmental Health Perspective 102:65-72.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pereira GAP, Genaro PS, Pinheiro MM, Szenjnfeld VL, Martini LA (2009). Diet Calcium-Strategies to Optimize Consumption. Revista Brasileira Reumatol, 49:164-180.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Powell SR (2000). The antioxidant properties of zinc. Journal of Nutrient 130:1447-1454.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ribeiro APB, Moura LMLN, Grimaldi R, Gonalves LAG (2007). Chemical Interesterification: alternative to obtain zero trans-fat. Quimica Nova, 5:1295-1300.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rienzo JA.di, Casanoves F, Balzarini MG, Gonzales L, Tablada M, Robledo CW (2016). InfoStat Release 2016. InfoStat Group FCA, Universidad Nacional de Crdoba, Argentina. Disponvel em URL]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SangHyun L, WolSoo K, TaeHo H (2009). Effects of post-harvest foliar boron and calcium applications on subsequent seasons pollen germination and pollen tube growth of pear (Pyrus pyrifolia). Scientie Horticulturae 122:77-82.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Silva DJ, Pereira JR, do Carmo MA, de Alburquerque JAS, Van Raji B, Silva CA (2004). Mineral nutrition and fertilization of the hose under irrigated conditions. Technical Circular, 77. Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Food Supply. EMBRAPA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tomassi G (2002). Phosphorus - An essential nutrient for human diet. Imphos 16:1-3.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vaitsman DS, Alonso JC, Dutra PB (2011). What are the chemical elements for? Editora Intercincia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Welti J, Vergara F (1997). Water activity: Concept and application in foods with high moisture content. In: AGUILERA, J.M. Topics in Food Technology 1:11-26.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vallee BL, Falchuk KH (1993). The biochemical basis of zinc physiology. Physiology Review 73:1.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref50">
				<label>50</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yuyama LKO, Rocha YR, Cozzolino SMP (1992). Chemical composition and percentage of adequacy of the regional diet of Manaus. Acta Amaznica 3:909-917.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref51">
				<label>51</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yuyama LKO, Aguiar JPL, Yuyama K, Lopes TM, Fvaro DIT, Bergl PCP, Vasconcellos MBA (2003). Content of mineral elements in some populations of camu-camu. Acta Amaznica 33:549-554.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>