<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>International Journal of Livestock Production</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-2448</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/IJLP2020.0695</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Effect of nutritional flushing on reproductive and body weight performance of Abergelle goat does]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Minister</surname>
            <given-names>Birhanie</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Mulalem</surname>
            <given-names>Zenebe</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Hailai</surname>
            <given-names>Hagos</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">msmini2001@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>29</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>19</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>11</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>68</fpage>
	  <lpage>71</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BB9723263804">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BB9723263804	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-full-text-pdf/BB9723263804">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-full-text-pdf/BB9723263804	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[This study was aimed to evaluate the effect of flushing on the reproductive and body weight change on Abergelle breed does. The study indicated that a mix of 300 or 450 g wheat bran (WB) with 50 g noug seed cake (NSC) flushed per day improved the doesrsquo; conception rate (70 to 80%) and kidding rate (70%); while does flushed with low concentrate level (150 g WB plus 50 g NSC) or those not flushed had poor and reduced conception and kidding rate almost by half from the flushed ones. However, the high concentrate level is not strategic to reduce abortion rate. Does flushed with high concentrate level (300 and 450 g WB mix with 50 g NSC) were significantly (plt;0.05) better in body weight at kidding (18.52 kg) and postpartum weight (19.48 kg) than does flushed with low concentrate level (16.44 and 17.70 kg, respectively). As the concentrate levels supplementation of their dam increased, birth weight of kids increased (1.73 to 2.36 kg). Therefore, the conception rate, postpartum weight, kid production of Abergelle goat can improve by flushing with 300 g WB and 50 g NSC concentrated feed. However, its effect on the reduction of abortion rate is not promising. Further study is needed on the abortion problem.

	Key words: Abortion rate, birth weight, body weight, conception rate, concentrated feed, goat, kidding rate, supplementation.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abay G, Zenebe M, Desta D, Hagos H, Berhanie M, Teame T (2017). Clinical survey on major ruminant diseases in Kola Tembein and Tanqua Abergelle Districts, Central Zone of Tigray, Northern Ethiopia. Journal of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Health 9(12):342-348.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Acero-Camelo A, Valencia E, Rodrguez A, Randel PF (2015). Effects of flushing with two energy levels on goat reproductive performance. Livestock Research for Rural Development 20(9).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Belay S, Gebru G, Godifey G, Brhane M, Zenebe M, Hagos H, Team T (2014). Reproductive performance of Abergelle goats their crosses. Livestock Research for Rural Development 26(1):1-5.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ben Salem H, Smith T (2008). Feeding strategies to increase small ruminant production in dry environments. Small Ruminant Research 77(2-3):174-194.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Berhane G, Eik LO (2006). Effect of vetch ( Vicia sativa ) hay supplementation to Begait and Abergelle goats in northern Ethiopia II Reproduction and growth rate. Small Ruminant Research 64(2006):233-240.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Blache D, Maloney SK, Revell DK (2008). Use and limitations of alternative feed resources to sustain and improve reproductive performance in sheep and goats. Animal Feed Science and Technology 147(2008):140-157.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chaturvedi OH, Bhatta R, Verma DL, Singh NP (2006). Effect of Flushing on Nutrient Utilization and Reproductive Performance of Ewes Grazing on Community Rangeland. Asian-Australasian Journal of Animal Sciences 19(4):521-525.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chemineau P, Daveau A, Cogni Y, Aumont G, Chesneau D (2004). Seasonal ovulatory activity exists in tropical Creole female goats and Black Belly ewes subjected to a temperate photoperiod. BMC Physiology 4(11):1-11.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[CSA (2017). Report on Livestock and Livestock Characteristics (Private Peasant Holdings). Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia (Vol. II). Addis Ababa.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[CSA (2018). Agricultural Sample Survey. Report on Livestock and Livestock Characteristics (Private Peasant Holdings). Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia (Vol. II) Addis Ababa.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[FAO (2011). Draft guidelines on phenotypic characterization of animal genetic resources, (April), 92.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[FAO (2019). Ethiopia. Availability and utilization of agroindustrial by-products as animal feed 2018. Rome.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fatet A, Pellicer-Rubio MT, Leboeuf B (2011). Reproductive cycle of goats. Animal Reproduction Science 124(3-4):211-219.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fazel AA, Daghigh H, Fazel A, Adv IJ, Biom B. (2014). Effect of Flushing Ration on the Sexual and Breeding Behaviors in Ghezel Sheep. International Journal of Advanced Biological and Biomedical Research 2(5):1700-1706.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Karikari PK, Blasu EY (2009). Influence of nutritional flushing prior to mating on the performance of West African Dwarf goats mated in the rainy season. Pakistan Journal of Nutrition 8(7):1068-1073.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Melesse A, Abebe G, Merkel R, Goetsch A, Dawson L, Gipson T, Tilahun S (2013). Effect of Body Condition Score and Nutritional Flushing on the Reproductive Performances of Spanish and Spanish x Boer Crossbred Does. Ethiopian Journal of Agricultural Science 153:141-153.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[OCallaghan D, Yaakub H, Hyttel P, Spicer LJ, Boland MP (2000). Effect of nutrition and superovulation on oocyte morphology, follicular fluid composition and systemic hormone concentrations in ewes. Journal of Reproduction and Fertility 118(2):303-313.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rekik M, Lassoued N, Salem HB Mahouachi M (2007). Interactions between nutrition and reproduction in sheep and goats with particular reference to the use of alternative feed sources. Options Mditerranennes 74:375-383.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sabra HA, Hassan SG (2008). Effect of New Regime of Nutritional Flushing on Reproduction Performance of Egyptian Barki Ewes. Global Veterinaria 2(1):28-31.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tesfay T, Tesfay Y (2013). Partial replacement of dried Leucaena leucocephala ( Lam .) de Wit leaves for noug ( Guizotia abyssinica ) ( L . f .) Cass . seed cake in the diet of highland sheep fed on wheat straw. Tropical Animal Health and Production 45:379-385.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[WOARD (2011). Woreda Office of Agriculture and Rural Development. Annual report tanqua abergele district.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>