<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>International Journal of Livestock Production</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-2448</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/IJLP2019.0646</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Comparative effects of Moringa oleifera powder and soybean meal on the zootechnical parameters of the ISA Brown pullet]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Jacques</surname>
            <given-names>S. Adouko</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Bienvenu</surname>
            <given-names>O. M. Koutonin</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Kvin</surname>
            <given-names>S. Kassa</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Arnaud</surname>
            <given-names>S. S. Soha</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Frjus</surname>
            <given-names>O. H. Ohouko</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Jacques</surname>
            <given-names>T. Dougnon</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">adoukojacques3@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>10</day>
			<month>10</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>12</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>11</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>60</fpage>
	  <lpage>67</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BA4280F63802">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BA4280F63802	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-full-text-pdf/BA4280F63802">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-full-text-pdf/BA4280F63802	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Poultry farming is an important sector of the Beninese agriculture. But this sector is facing economic difficulties. The aim of this study is to evaluate the effects of Moringa oleifera powder and soybean meal on zootechnical parameters in the ISA Brown pullet. For this purpose, the experiment was carried out on a total of 250 day-old chicks with an initial average weight of 40 plusmn; 1 g. Among these chicks, 25 subjects were used for the digestibility test and the rest were grouped into cinq (05) batches of 45 chicks fed with different rations. The test lasted 56 days. The apparent digestibility of the dry matter varied significantly from 50.0 plusmn; 9.18 to 50.42 plusmn; 16.11 at the 5% threshold between the different batches. Feed consumption of chicks of the different experimental batches did not show any significant variation, while for the feed conversion rate, weight gain and average daily gain, most averages vary significantly between batches and weeks. It brings out that M. oleifera powder improves the feed conversion and growth rates of ISA Brown pullets fed with a feed containing M. oleifera powder at different incorporation rates.

	Key words: Moringa oleifera, soybean, ISA Brown laying hens, zootechnical parameters.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aboh AB, Dahouda M, Adjolohoun S, Senou M, Toleba SS, Abou M, Vidjannagni DS, Kpodkon M (2002). Effets des aliments contenant des folioles de MoringaoleiferaLam et des aliments commerciaux sur les performances de croissances des lapins (Oryctolagus cuniculus). International Journal of Biological and Chemical Sciences 7(5):1838-1852.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Charoensin S (2014). Antioxidant and anticancer activities of Moringa oleifera leaves. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 8(7):318-325.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dougnon JT, Edorh AP, Bankole HS, Kpodekon M, Gbenou J (2011). Efficiency of ethanol extract of Moringa oleifera Lam. leaves for the treatment of Staphylococcus aureus infections in chicks. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 5(31):6704-6708.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) (2000). Guidelines for computing crop water requierements- FAO. Irrigation and drainage paper 56, FAO. Organisation of the United Nation, Rome.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) (2010). Gobal Fishing Effort (1950-2010): Trends, Gaps, and Implication 107(1-3):131-1365.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fuglie LJ (2001). Introduction to the multiple uses of Moringa (7-10) In: Fuglie LJ (editor). The miracle tree: the multiple attributes of Moringa. -Wageningen: CTA; Dakar: CWS. 177 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fuglie LJ (2002). Nutrition naturelle sous les tropiques (105-118). In: Larbre de la vie, Les multiples usages du Moringa.-Wageningen : CTA; Dakar: CWS. 177 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[INSAE (2008). Institut National de la Statistique et de lAnalyse Economique Rapport annuel dactivit15 p]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jaovelo FN (2007). Effet de la supplmentation en volihot sur les performances zootechniques de poulet de chair en priode de stress thermique. Thse de Mdecine Vtrinaire, E.I.S.M.V. Dakar 115 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kaijage JT, Sarwatt SV, Mutayoba SK (2003). Moringa oleifera leaf meal canim prove quality characteristics and consume preference of marketable eggs. Un publish eddicertation for award of Msc degree in animal science at Sokoine University of Agriculture, Morogoro, Tanzania. [En ligne]. Accs Internet:URL :]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kakengi AMV, Kaijage JT, Sarwatt SV, Mutayoba SK, Shem MN, Fujihara T (2007). Effect of Moringaoleiferaleafmeal as a substitute for sunflower seed meal on performance of layinghens in Tanzania. Livestock Research for Rural Development 19(8).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kavitha C, Ramesh M, Kumaran SS, Lakshmi SA (2012). Toxicity of moringaoleifera seed extract on some hematological and biochemical profiles in a freshwater fish, cyprinuscarpio. Experimental and Toxicologic Pathology 64:681-687.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Laurenson P (2002). Dtermination des paramtres zootechniques de la pintade locale dans la rgion du Borgou. Mmoire pour lobtention du diplme dIngnieur : Facult des Sciences Agronomiques de Gembloux, Universit de Gembloux 81 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Leclercq B, Beaumont C (2000). Etude par simulation de la rponse des troupeaux de volailles aux apports dacides amins et de protines, Station de recherche avicole de lINRA, Nouzilly (France). INRA Production Animal 13:47-59.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mbora A, Mundia G, Muasya S (2004). Combating nutrition with Moringa oleifera. Nairobi: World Agroforestry Centre. p. 43.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mufwaya PU, Kiatoko MH (2016). Effet de substitution de tourteau palmiste par le foin de Moringa oleifera dans la ration, sur la croissance de poulet de chair de souche ISA 715. International Journal of Innovation and Applied Studies 15(4):936-942.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ndong M, Wade S, Dossou N, Guiro AT, Gning RD (2007). Valeur nutritionnelle du Moringa oleifera, tude de la biodisponibilit du fer, effet de lenrichissement de divers plats traditionnels sngalais avec la poudre des feuilles. African Journal of Food, Agriculture, Nutrition and Development 7(3).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Olugbemi TS, Mutayoba SK, Lekule FP (2010). Effect of Moringa (Moringa oleifera) Inclusion in Cassava Based Diets Fed to Broiler Chickens. International Journal of Poultry Science 9(4):363-367.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Omole AJ (2006). Performance of snail fed graded levels of ripe and unripe pawpaw. Proc. 26th Annual Conference of Animal Production pp. 224-227.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pamok S, Saenphet S, Vinitketkumnuen U, Saenphet K (2012). Antiproliferative effect of Moringa oleifera Lam. and Pseuderanthemumpalatiferum (Nees) Radlk extracts on the colon cancer cells. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 6(1):139-145.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Price ML (2007). Le Moringa. In Note technique- ECHO (revue en 2000, en 2002 et en 2007). [En ligne] Accs Internet:]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Raphal KJ, Christian KT, Juliano RS, Lisita F, Soultan MY, Herv MK, Alexis T (2015). Effects of Substituting Soybean with Moringa oleifera Meal in Diets on Laying and Eggs Quality Characteristics of KABIR Chickens. Journal of Animal Ressources and Nutrition 1(4).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Richter N, Siddhuraju P, Becker K (2003). Evaluation of nutritional quality of Moringa (Moringa oleifera Lam.) leaves as an alternative protein source for Nile tilapia (OreochromisnibatchicusL.). Aquaculture 217:599-611.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tchigang C, Aissatou K (2004). Donnes ethnonutritionnelles et caractristiques physico-chimiques des lgumes-feuilles consomms dans la savane de lAdamaoua (Cameroun). Tropicultura 22(1):11-18.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tedonkeng PE, Niba AT, Fonteh FA, Tedonkeng F, Kana JR, Boukila B, Tsachoung J (2008). Effet de la supplmentation au Moringa oleifera ou aux blocs multi nutritionnels sur lvolution du poids post-partum et la croissance pr-sevrage des cobayes (Caviaporcellus L.). Livestock Research for Rural Development 17(46).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>