<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>International Journal of Livestock Production</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-2448</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/IJLP2019.0666</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[The performance of artificial insemination delivery system in Amhara, Oromia, SNNP and Tigray Regions of Ethiopia]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Kassahun</surname>
            <given-names>Melesse</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ashenafi</surname>
            <given-names>Mengistu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Driba</surname>
            <given-names>Geleti</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">kasishmele@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>19</day>
			<month>12</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>27</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>11</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>84</fpage>
	  <lpage>90</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/00B256663836">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/00B256663836	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-full-text-pdf/00B256663836">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-full-text-pdf/00B256663836	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The study was conducted in Amhara, Oromia, Southern Nations Nationalities and Peoples and Tigray regions of the country to provide information on the performance of Artificial Insemination (AI) service delivery system, its seasonality and effectiveness. Semi-structured questionnaire was prepared to interview AI technicians (on their performance and related issues) and farmers (about the outcome of AI services). Data on field performance were received directly from AI technicians using a pre-restructured reporting format. A follow-up calving survey for AI services were provided to farmers was conducted in March 2019 to know the outcome of insemination services provided to farmers. Peak season falls from August to December when AI technicians on average perform 6.7 inseminations per day. January, February, June, and July were categorized as regular season with daily average insemination of 3.8. March, April, and May are off-season with an average of only 2.2 inseminations per day. The seasonal variation is mainly associated with availability of feed. Field level actual performance data showed significant difference (Plt;0.05) in the number of inseminations provided per AI technician per month among regions and between male and female AI technicians with an overall average insemination of 39.3. The highest AI services reported in the month of October. The Service per Conception (SPC) reported by AI technicians was not significantly different among regions (Pgt;0.05) with mean SPC of 2.13. About 2.6 SPC obtained from a follow-up survey conducted with farmers who received AI service in a specified period. About 62% conception rate and 82% calving rates are obtained in this study.

	Key words:  Cattle, farmers, performance, technicians, semen.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ali T, Lemma A, Yilma T (2013). Reproductive performance of dairy cows under artificial insemination in south and northwest part of Ethiopia. Livestock Research for Rural Development 25 (12):191.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Camilla E (2013). The use of artificial insemination in dairy farms in urban/peri-urban Kampala, Uganda - a study of knowledge, attitude and practices. Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Science, Degree project, Veterinary Program, Uppsala 2013.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[CSA (2017). Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia Central Statistical Agency. Agricultural Sample Survey, 2016/17 [2009 E.C.], Volume II, Report on Livestock and Livestock Characteristics (Private Peasant Holdings). Statistical Bulletin 585. April 2017.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[CSA (2018). Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia Central Statistical Agency. Agricultural Sample Survey, 2017/18 [2010 E.C.], Volume II, Report on Livestock and Livestock Characteristics (Private Peasant Holdings). Statistical Bulletin 587. April 2018.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Daniel WW (1999). Biostatistics: A foundation for Analysis in the Health Sciences: 7th Edition. New York: John Wiley  Sons.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Desalegn G/M, Merga B, Azage T, Kelay B (2009). Status of artificial insemination service in Ethiopia. In: The 17th Annual Conference of the Ethiopian Society of Animal Production (ESAP), Sept 24-26, 2009 Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, pp.87-104.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dickson NK, Gideon O, John N (2018). Estimating pastoralists willingness to pay for artificial insemination in arid and semi-arid lands of Kenya. Journal of Development and Agricultural Economics 10(8):262-270.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Effa K, Hegde BP, Tesfaye K (2006). Lifetime production and reproduction performances of Bos taurus x Bos indicus crossbred cows in the central highlands of Ethiopia. Ethiopian Journal Animal Production 6(2):37-52.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[FAO (2002). World Agriculture 2030. Main findings.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gebregiorgis A, Alemselam B, Tadesse G (2016). Status of Artificial Insemination in Tigray Regional State, Constraints and Acceptability under Field Condition. Journal of Dairy Veterinary and Animal Research 3(3):00078.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hunde DGM, Tadelle D, Getnet A, Million T, Johan S (2015). Milk Yield and Reproductive Performance of Pure Jersey Dairy Cattle in the Central Highlands of Ethiopia. Livestock Research for Rural Development 27 (130).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kinyua J (2016). Evaluation of Artificial Insemination Services Performance in a Smallholder Dairy Herd Under Extensive Management: A Case Study of KALRO- Lanet Herd, Kenya. Weber Agricultural Research and Management 2(191):692-694.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mwambilwa K, Yambayamba KE, Joseph S (2013). Evaluation of the reproductive performance and effectiveness of artificial insemination on smallholder dairy farms in Zambia. Scholarly Journal of Agricultural Science 3(10):391-400.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nuraddis I, Reta H, Abidu M (2014). Assessment of Problems Associated with Artificial Insemination Service in Selected Districts of Jimma Zone. Journal of Reproduction and Infertility 5(2):37-44.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SAS (2004). Users Guide. Version 6.12. Statistical Analysis System (SAS) Institute, Inc. Carry, NC.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SPSS (2011). Statistical Procedures for Social Sciences (SPSS). IBM SPSS Statistics 20. IBM Corp. Chicago, USA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Suresh KP, Chandarashekara S (2012). Sample Size Estimation and Power Analysis for Clinical Studies. Journal of Human Reproductive Science 5(1):7-13.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tessema R, Atnaf A (2015). Assessment of Problems Associated with Artificial Insemination Services in and Around Gondar Town, North West Ethiopia. Journal of Reproduction and Infertility 6(2):22-26.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tatek W, Yoseph T, Aynalem H (2011). Factors affecting conception rate in artificially inseminated cattle under farmers condition in Ethiopia. Journal of Cell and Animal Biology 5(16):334-338.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wytze B, Dawit M, Binyam K, Mahlet Y, Jan van der L (2012). The Major Ethiopian Milk sheds. An assessment of development potential Milk value chain, stakeholders, production potential, market potential, and possible intervention areas. Wageningen University and SNV Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zerihun B, Malede B, Tewodros F (2013). Assessment on Problems Associated with Artificial Insemination Services in West Gojjam Zone, Ethiopia. Advances in Biological Research 7(2):59-66.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>