<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>International Journal of Physical Sciences</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1992-1950</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/IJPS2020.4870</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Determination and establishment of empirical relationship between magnetic susceptibility and mechanical properties of typical basement rocks in Southwestern Nigeria]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Akintorinwa,</surname>
            <given-names>O. James</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ajayi,</surname>
            <given-names>C. Ayodele</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Oyedele,</surname>
            <given-names>A. Akinola</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">ojakintorinwa@futa.edu.ng</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>17</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>11</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>15</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>70</fpage>
	  <lpage>89</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/28678DF63872">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/28678DF63872	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-full-text-pdf/28678DF63872">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-full-text-pdf/28678DF63872	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Magnetic susceptibility and mechanical properties of rocks in a typical basement complex Southwestern Nigeria were correlated with the aim of establishing empirical equations relating the two parameters and evaluate the parameters as related to its competency in hosting civil structures. A total of thirty rock samples were taken across the geology of the area and subjected to mechanical properties determinations. Magnetic susceptibility measurements were carried out on in-situ fresh rock outcrops and it ranges from 2.1 times; 10-4 to 9.5 times; 10-4. This signifies the amount of iron content in the rocks and its level of induration. The values of uniaxial compressive strength (UCS), Youngrsquo;s modulus (E), shear modulus ( ), bulk modulus (K) and Poissonrsquo;s ratio (ัด) ranges from 49 - 107 MPa, 1003 - 3321 MPa, 416 - 1310 MPa, 707 - 2728 MPa and 0.232 - 0.316, respectively. The cross plots of the mechanical parameters with the magnetic susceptibility exhibit a direct linear relationship. The relationship shows a good correlation with coefficient of correlation (R) ranging from 0.60 to 0.85 for uniaxial compressive strength, bulk modulus and Poissonrsquo;s ratio. The magnetic susceptibility relationship with shear and Youngrsquo;s Modulus are relatively weak with coeffecient of correlation (R) of 0.44 and 0.47, respectively. This implies that, magnetic susceptibility measurement may not be reliably applicable in determination of the stiffness of rocks and the rate of resistance of rocks to prevailing shearing loads. The validation results show that, reliable mechanical properties of rocks can be estimated from magnetic susceptibility measurements using the established empirical equations.

	Key words: Magnetic, susceptibility, mechanical, properties, rocks.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adelusi AO, Akinlalu AA, Nwanchukwu AI (2013). Integrated geophysical investigation for post-construction studies of buildings around school of science area, Federal University of Technology, Akure, southwestern, Nigeria. International Journal of Physical Science 8(15):657-669.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ajayi CA, Akintorinwa OJ, Ademilua OL, Adeoye AS (2019). Relationship between magnetic susceptibility and gravity of basement rocks in southwestern Nigeria. Journal of Applied Geology and Geophysics (IOSR-JAGG) 69(2):46-57.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ayodele OS, Ajayi CA (2016). Petrology, mineralogy and geochemistry of the Precambrian rocks around Ikere-ekiti, southwestern Nigeria. Journal of Chemical and Petrochemical Technology 2(1):1-24.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bayode S, Omosuyi GO, Abdullai HI (2009). Post-foundation engineering geophysical investigation in part of the Federal University of Technology, Akure, southwestern Nigeria. Journal of Emerging Trends in Engineering and Applied Sciences (JETEAS) 3(1):203-210.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chandong C, Mark DZ, Abbas K (2006). Empirical relations between rock strength and physical properties in sedimentary rocks. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 51:223-237.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chary KB, Sarma LP, Lakshmi KJP (2006). Evaluation of engineering properties of rock using ultrasonic pulse velocity and uniaxial compressive strength. National Geophysical Research Institute. 7:500.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fadamiro JA (2002). An assessment of building regulations and standards and the implication for building collapse in Nigeria. Nigeria Institute of Building, Ondo-State, Nigeria. pp. 28-39.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Frantisek H, Marta C, Martin C (2009). The use of magnetic susceptibility of rocks in geological exploration. Terraplus Geophysical Equipment Supplier, Georadis Publication.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hao Z, Wen Z, Runcheng X, Lina D, Christopher X, Yuming S, Haotian Z (2016). Characterization of Rock Mechanical Properties Using Lab Tests and Numerical Interpretation Model of Well Logs. Hindawi Publishing Corporation Mathematical Problems in Engineering. 1(10):1155.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mavko Mkerji GT, Dvorkin J (2003). The elastic properties of homogenous isotropic linear elastic materials. The Rock Physics Handbook, Cambridge University Press, pp. 223-235.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Morrow CA, Moore DE, Lockner DA (2001). Permeability reduction in granite under hydrothermal conditions. Journal of Geophysics Research and Solid Earth 106:30551-30560.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Olarewaju VO (1987). Charnockite-granite association in SW Nigeria: rapakivi granite type and charnockitic plutonism in Nigeria. Journal of African Earth Sciences 6(1):67-68.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Olusola KO, (2002). Structural stability of building structures. Nigerian Institute of Building, Ondo-State, Nigeria, pp. 50-73.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Oke A (2011). An examination of the causes and effects of building coollapse in Nigeria. Journal of Design and Built Environment 9:37-47]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Patrick B, Teng-fong W, Wei Z (2014). Effects of Porosity and Crack Density on the Compressive Strength of Rocks. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences 67:202-211.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rahaman MA (1979). Review of Basement Geology of Southwestern Nigeria, Department of Geology, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun-State Nigeria, pp. 44-67.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tarlingar DH, Hrouda F (1993). The magnetic anisotropy of rocks. Chapman and Hall, London, p. 217.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Telford WM, Geldart LP, Sheriff RE, Keys DS (1990). Applied Geophysics. Cambridge University Press.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>