<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>ISABB Journal of Health and Environmental Sciences</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1937-3236</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/ISAAB-JHE2019.0056 </article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Factors associated with irregular consumption of fruits and vegetables among health professionals in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yewayan</surname>
            <given-names>Larba Berenger KABORE</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Jean</surname>
            <given-names>TESTA</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Aristide</surname>
            <given-names>Romaric BADO</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Anyovi</surname>
            <given-names>FOLLY</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Souleymane</surname>
            <given-names>KABORE</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">arbado@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>26</day>
			<month>10</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>17</day>
			<month>01</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>7</volume>
      <issue>1</issue>
	  	  <fpage>1</fpage>
	  <lpage>10</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/419A12D62771">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/419A12D62771	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-full-text-pdf/419A12D62771">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-full-text-pdf/419A12D62771	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Fruits and vegetables (Famp;Vs) are an essential food group for humans and prevent non-communicable diseases (NCDs). The objective of this study is to know the level of consumption of Famp;Vs by health professionals in Ouagadougou and their determinants. This is a descriptive cross-sectional study conducted from May to August 2016 in the Central Region of Burkina Faso. It included 442 health workers according to cluster sampling. Data collection tools consisted of frequency of food consumption of fruits and vegetables.  The results showed that the level of Famp;Vs consumption among health professionals is very low. Only 11.5% of respondents consumed fruits every day and 21.8% did the same for vegetables and 1.4% of health professionals consumed more than five servings of Famp;Vs per day. Only 1.6% of health professionals surveyed had sufficient knowledge of the functions of Famp;Vs, and 85.8% were not aware of the recommendations of World Health Organizations regarding the consumption of Famp;Vs. Gender, distance from the fruit supply, and average monthly financial income were associated with the irregularity of the fruit consumption at the threshold of 5% in the univariate analysis. However, in the multivariate analysis, gender, profession, distance from fruit supply and average monthly financial income were predictive of irregular fruit consumption. The level of Famp;Vs consumption in health professionals is low, as is their level of knowledge of the functions of Famp;Vs.

	 

	Key words: Burkina Faso, consumption, determinants, fruits and vegetables, health professionals.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amo-Adje J, Kumi-Kyereme A (2015). Fruit and vegetable consumption by ecological zone and socioeconomic status in Ghana. Journal of Biosocial Science 47(5):613-631.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Becquey E, Savy M, Danel P, Dabir HB, Tapsoba S, Martin-Prvel Y (2010). Dietary patterns of adults living in Ouagadougou and their association with overweight. Nutrition Journal 9(1):13.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chisholm D, Abagunde D, Mendis S (2011). Scaling up action against noncommunicable diseases: how much will it cost? Geneva: World Health Organization.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dehghan M, Akhtar-Danesh N, Merchant AT (2011). Factors associated with fruit and vegetable consumption among adults. Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics 24(2):128-134.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Frank E, Wright EH, Serdula M K, Elon LK, Baldwin G (2002). Personal and professional nutrition-related practices of US female physicians. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 75(2):326-332
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Giaconi JA, Yu F, Stone KL, Pedula KL, Ensrud KE, Cauley JA, Coleman AL (2012). The Association of Consumption of Fruits/Vegetables with Decreased Risk of Glaucoma Among Older African-American Women in the Study of Osteoporotic Fractures. American Journal of Ophthalmology 154(4):635-644.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Glade MJ (1999). Food, nutrition, and the prevention of cancer: a global perspective. American Institute for Cancer Research/World Cancer Research Fund, American Institute for Cancer Research, 1997. Nutrition 15(6):523-526.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Greenwald P, Clifford C, Milner J (2001). Diet and cancer prevention. European Journal of Cancer 37(8):948-965.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Huijg JM, Gebhardt WA, Verheijden MW, van der Zouwe N, de Vries JD, Middelkoop BJC, Crone MR (2015). Factors Influencing Primary Health Care Professionals Physical Activity Promotion Behaviors: A Systematic Review. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine 22(1):32-50.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kamphuis CBM, Giskes K, de Bruijn G-J, Wendel-Vos W, Brug J, van Lenthe FJ (2006). Environmental determinants of fruit and vegetable consumption among adults: a systematic review. The British Journal of Nutrition 96(4):620-635.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Landais E, Bour A, Gartner A, McCullough F, Delpeuch F, Holdsworth M (2015). Socio-economic and behavioural determinants of fruit and vegetable intake in Moroccan women. Public Health Nutrition 18(5):809-816.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Leenders M, Sluijs I, Ros MM, Boshuizen HC, Siersema PD, Ferrari P, Bueno-de-Mesquita HB (2013). Fruit and Vegetable Consumption and Mortality. American Journal of Epidemiology 178(4):590-602.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maire B, Lioret S, Gartner A, Delpeuch F (2002). Transition nutritionnelle et maladies chroniques non transmissibles lies  lalimentation dans les pays en dveloppement. Cahiers dtudes et de Recherches Francophones/Sant 12(1):45-55.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maynard M, Gunnell D, Ness AR, Abraham L, Bates CJ, Blane D (2006). What influences diet in early old age? Prospective and cross-sectional analyses of the Boyd Orr cohort. European Journal of Public Health 16(3):315-323.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ministre de la sant Burkina-Faso (2014). Rapport de lenqute nationale sur la prvalence des principaux facteurs de risque communs aux maladies non transmissibles au Burkina-Faso, Enqute STEPS 2013.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ministre de la sant Burkina-Faso (2016). Plan Strategique Integre Lutte Contre Les Maladies Non Transmissibles 2016-2020. Retrieved from
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ministre de la sant Burkina-Faso (2017). Politique Nationale De Nutrition. Retrieved from
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Morland K, Diez Roux AV, Wing S (2006a). Supermarkets, Other Food Stores, and Obesity. American Journal of Preventive Medicine 30(4):333-339.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Morland K, Diez Roux AV, Wing S (2006b). Supermarkets, Other Food Stores, and Obesity. American Journal of Preventive Medicine 30(4):333-339.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Organisation Mondiale de la Sant (OMS) (2004). Stratgie mondiale pour lalimentation, lexercice physique et la sant. Organisation mondiale de la Sant.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pearson T Russell J, Campbell MJ, Barker ME (2005). Do food deserts influence fruit and vegetable consumption?-a cross-sectional study. Appetite 45(2):195-197.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ponza M, Devaney B, Ziegler P, Reidy K, Squatrito C (2004). Nutrient intakes and food choices of infants and toddlers participating in WIC. Journal of the American Dietetic Association 104:71-79.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ruel MT, Minot N, Smith L (2005). Patterns and determinants of fruit and vegetable consumption in sub-Saharan Africa: a multicountry comparison. WHO Geneva.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thompson RL, Margetts BM, Speller VM, McVey D (1999). The Health Education Authoritys health and lifestyle survey 1993: who are the low fruit and vegetable consumers? Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health 53(5):294-299.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thornton LE, Lamb KE, Tseng M, Crawford DA, Ball K (2015). Does food store access modify associations between intrapersonal factors and fruit and vegetable consumption? European Journal of Clinical Nutrition 69(8):902-906.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wells KB, Lewis CE, Leake B, Ware JE (1984). Do physicians preach what they practice? A study of physicians health habits and counseling practices. The Journal of the American Medical Association 252(20):2846-2848.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wolf RL, Lepore SJ, Vandergrift J, Wetmore-Arkader L, McGinty E, Pietrzak G, Yaroch AL (2008). Knowledge, Barriers, and Stage of Change as Correlates of Fruit and Vegetable Consumption among Urban and Mostly Immigrant Black Men. Journal of the American Dietetic Association 108(8):1315-1322.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zeba AN, Delisle HF, Renier G (2014). Dietary patterns and physical inactivity, two contributing factors to the double burden of malnutrition among adults in Burkina Faso, West Africa. Journal of Nutritional Science 3:e50.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>