<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of AIDS and HIV Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-2359</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JAHR2019.0492</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Immunological and clinical response to antiretroviral therapy according to baseline CD4+ T-cell count in Karamara General Hospital, Jigjiga, Ethiopia]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Adugna</surname>
            <given-names>Negussie</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Walid</surname>
            <given-names>Ali</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yerega</surname>
            <given-names>Belete</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Muktar</surname>
            <given-names>Shekabdulahi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">adugalab@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>31</day>
        <month>01</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>04</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>02</day>
			<month>08</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>12</volume>
      <issue>1</issue>
	  	  <fpage>1</fpage>
	  <lpage>8</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/1CCA6BB63927">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/1CCA6BB63927	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-full-text-pdf/1CCA6BB63927">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-full-text-pdf/1CCA6BB63927	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[In resource limited countries, there is scarcity of information regarding the degree of immunological and clinical recovery in remote communities with ART service. This study retrospectively assessed the degree of immune recovery by CD4 count after initiation of ART. A retrospective cohort study was conducted on adult HIV patients who have been on ART for more than one year at Karamara Hospital. All analyses were performed using SPSS software version 19.0 and findings were compared using the appropriate statistical tests. The median change from baseline to the most recent CD4 cell count was 141 cells/mu;l. By 5 years, the overall median CD4 cell count was 472 cells/mu;l while the median CD4 cell count was 401 cells/mu;l among patients with baseline CD4 cell counts le;100 cells/mu;l, 467 cells/mu;l among those with baseline CD4 cell counts of 100 to 199 cells/mu;l, and 586 cells/mu;l among those with baseline CD4 cell counts equal to greater 200 cells/mu;l. At the end of the study, patients with higher baseline CD4 cell stratum returned to normal CD4 cell counts compared to those with the least baseline CD4 cell stratum. The findings suggest that consideration be given to initiation of ART at a CD4 cell count gt;350 cells/mu;l to achieve better immune recovery.

	Key words: Antiretroviral therapy, CD4 cell count, HIV infection.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Actor JK (2007). Elseviers Integrated Immunology and Microbiology. Mosby Incorporated.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Asfaw A, Ali D, Eticha T, Alemayehu A, Alemayehu M, Kindeya F (2015) . CD4 Cell Count Trends after Commencement of Antiretroviral Therapy among HIV-Infected Patients in Tigray, Northern Ethiopia: A Retrospective Cross-Sectional Study. PLoS ONE 10(3): e0122583.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bastard M, Soulinphumy K, Phimmasone P, Saadani AH., Ciaffi L, Communier A, Phimphachanh C, Ecochard R, Etard JF (2013). Women experience a better long-term immune recovery and a better survival on HAART in Lao Peoples Democratic Republic. BMC Infectious Diseases 13(1):27.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Central Statistical Agency [Ethiopia] and ORC Macro (2012). Ethiopia Demographic and Health Survey 2011: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, and Calverton, Maryland, USA: Central Statistical Agency and ORC Macro.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gezie LD, Gelaye KA, Worku AG, Ayele TA, Teshome DF (2017). Time to immunologic recovery and determinant factors among adults who initiated ART in Felege Hiwot Referral Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Research Notes 10(1):277.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS): Report on the global AIDS epidemic, 2012, UNAIDS / JC2417E.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kelley CF, Kitchen CM, Hunt PW, Rodriguez B, Hecht FM, Kitahata M, Crane HM, Willig J, Mugavero M, Saag M, Martin JN (2009). Incomplete peripheral CD4+ cell count restoration in HIV-infected patients receiving long-term antiretroviral treatment. Clinical Infectious Diseases 48(6):787-794.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumar AM, Gupta D, Kumar A, Gupta RS, Kanchar A, Rao R, Shastri S, Suryakanth MD, Rangaraju C, Naik B, Guddemane DK., Bhat P, Nair AS, Harries AD, Dewan P (2017). HIV-infected presumptive tuberculosis patients without tuberculosis: How many are eligible for antiretroviral therapy in Karnataka, India? Journal of Epidemiology and Global Health 71:11-19.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lawn SD, Myer L, Bekker L, Wood R (2006). CD4 cell count recovery among HIV-infected patients with very advanced immunodeficiency commencing antiretroviral treatment in sub-Saharan Africa, BMC Infectious Diseases 6:59.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[MacLennan CA, Liu MK, White SA, van Oosterhout JJ, Simukonda F, Bwanali J, Moore MJ, Zijlstra EE, Drayson MT, Molyneux ME (2007). Diagnostic accuracy and clinical utility of a simplified low cost method of counting CD4 cells with flow cytometry in Malawi: Diagnostic accuracy study. British Medical Journal 335(7612):190-190.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Malaza A, Mossong J, Barnighausen T, Viljoen J, Newell M-L (2013). Population-Based CD4 Counts in a Rural Area in South Africa with High HIV Prevalence and High Antiretroviral Treatment Coverage. PLoS ONE 8(7):e70126.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Moges Derbe, Monga DP, Deresse Daka (2013). Immunological response among HIV/AIDS patients before and after ART therapy at Zewuditu Hospital Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. American Journal of Research Communication 1(1):103-115View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Molla AA, Gelagay AA, Mekonnen HS, Teshome DF (2018). Adherence to antiretroviral therapy and associated factors among HIV positive adults attending care and treatment in University of Gondar Referral Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Infectious Diseases 18(1):266. Published 2018 Jun 8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Moore DM, Harris R, Lima V, Hogg B, May M, Yip B, Justice A, Mocroft A, Reiss P, Lampe F, Chne G, Costagliola D, Elzi L, Mugavero MJ, Monforte AD, Sabin C, Podzamczer D, Ftkenheuer G, Staszewski S, Gill J, Sterne JA, Antiretroviral Therapy Cohort Collaboration (2009). Effect of baseline CD4 cell counts on the clinical significance of short-term immunologic response to antiretroviral therapy in individuals with virologic suppression. Journal of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndromes 52(3):357-63
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Reda AA, Biadgilign S, Deribew A, Gebre B, Deribe K (2013). Predictors of Change in CD4 Lymphocyte Count and Weight among HIV Infected Patients on Anti-Retroviral Treatment in Ethiopia: A Retrospective Longitudinal Study. PLoS ONE 8(4):e58595
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Seoane E, Resino S, Micheloud D, Moreno A, Juan CL, Lorente R, Rubio R, Gonzalez J, Pulido F, Arribas JR, Moreno S (2008). Lipid and apoprotein profile in HIV-1-infected patients after CD4-guided treatment interruption. Journal of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndromes 48(4):455-459.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Smith CJ, Sabin CA, Youle MS, Kinloch-de Loes S, Lampe FC, Madge S, Cropley I, Johnson MA, Phillips AN (2004). Factors influencing increases in CD4 cell counts of HIV-positive persons receiving long-term highly active antiretroviral therapy. The Journal of Infectious Diseases 190(10):1860-1868.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tiba F, Nauwelaers F, Traor S, Coulibaly B, Ouedraogo T, Compaor A, Krusslich HG, Bhler T (2012). Immune reconstitution during the first year of antiretroviral therapy of HIV-1-infected adults in rural Burkina Faso. The Open AIDS Journal 6:16.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhou J, Sirisanthana T, Kiertiburanakul S, Chen YMA, Han N, Lim P, Kumarasamy N, Choi JY, Merati TP, Yunihastuti E, Oka S (2010). Trends in CD4 counts in HIV-infected patients with HIV viral load monitoring while on combination antiretroviral treatment: Results from The TREAT Asia HIV Observational Database. BioMed Central Infectious Diseases 10(1):361.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>