<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Cereals and Oilseeds</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-6591</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JCO2020.0213</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Effect of germination on structural and physicochemical properties of starch in glutinous brown rice]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Liyezi</surname>
            <given-names>He</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Chuan</surname>
            <given-names>Cao</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Jingwei</surname>
            <given-names>Hu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Dongmei</surname>
            <given-names>Wei</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Li</surname>
            <given-names>Xu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Tang</surname>
            <given-names>Su</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yibin</surname>
            <given-names>Zhou</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">zhouyibin@ahau.edu.cn</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>31</day>
        <month>01</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>17</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>26</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>11</volume>
      <issue>1</issue>
	  	  <fpage>21</fpage>
	  <lpage>29</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/A25CDC863889">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/A25CDC863889	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-full-text-pdf/A25CDC863889">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-full-text-pdf/A25CDC863889	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[This study compared the structural and rheological properties of native (GB0), 12 h (GB12), 24 h (GB24), 36 h (GB36), 48 h (GB48) and 72 h (GB72) germinated glutinous brown rice starch to improve the market value of glutinous rice through germination. The proportion of A chains (DP 6-12) increases and the proportion of B1 chains (DP 13-24) decreased with germination time. Interestingly, we observed that the total proportion of B2 and B3 chains decreased, but was recovered after germination at 36 h. The effect of germination on the distribution of amylopectin length results in a decrease in relative crystallinity, gelatinisation temperature, gelatinisation enthalpy and pasting viscosities. In this study, we found that GB12 starch gel has the weakest thermal stability and its shear resistance is more difficult to retrogradation; while GB36 has the highest chain association (retrogradation) which is induced by cooling.

	Key words: Glutinous brown rice, germination, starch, structural properties, rheological properties.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Boluda-Aguilar M, Taboada-Rodrguez A, Lpez-Gmez A, Marn-Iniesta F,Barbosa-Cnovas GV(2013). Quick cooking rice by high hydrostatic pressure processing. LWT-Food Science and Technology 51(1):196-204.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cheetham NW, Tao L (1998).Variation in crystalline type with amylose content in maize starch granules: an X-ray powder diffraction study. Carbohydrate Polymers 36(4):277-284.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chen HH, Chang HC, Chen YK, Hung CL, Lin S Y, Chen YS (2016). An improved process for high nutrition of germinated brown rice production: Low-pressure plasma. Food Chemistry 191:120-127.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chung HJ, Liu Q, Lee L, Wei D (2011). Relationship between the structure, physicochemical properties and in vitro digestibility of rice starches with different amylose contents. Food Hydrocolloids 25(5):968-975.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chung JH, Han JA, Yoo B, Seib PA, Lim ST (2008). Effects of molecular size and chain profile of waxy cereal amylopectins on paste rheology during retrogradation. Carbohydrate Polymers 71(3):365-371.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cooke D,Gidley MJ (1992). Loss of crystalline and molecular order during starch gelatinisation: origin of the enthalpic transition. Carbohydrate Research 227:103-112.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cui L, Pan Z, Yue T, Atungulu GG, Berrios J (2010). Effect of ultrasonic treatment of brown rice at different temperatures on cooking properties and quality. Cereal Chemistry 87(5):403-408.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Das M, Banerjee R, Bal S (2008).Evaluation of physicochemical properties of enzyme treated brown rice (Part B). LWT-Food Science and Technology 41(10):2092-2096.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gidley MJ, Bulpin PV (1987). Crystallisation of malto-oligosaccharides as models of the crystalline forms of starch: minimum chain-length requirement for the formation of double helices. Carbohydrate Research 161(2):291-300.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hanashiro I, Abe JI, Hizukuri S (1996).A periodic distribution of the chain length of amylopectin as revealed by high-performance anion-exchange chromatography. Carbohydrate Research 283:151-159.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hizukuri S (1985).Relationship between the distribution of the chain length of amylopectin and the crystalline structure of starch granules. Carbohydrate Research 141(2):295-306.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jaisut D, Prachayawarakorn S, Varanyanond W, Tungtrakul P, Soponronnarit S.(2009). Accelerated aging of jasmine brown rice by high-temperature fluidization technique. Food Research International 42(5-6):674-681.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jane JL, Chen YY, Lee LF, McPherson AE, Wong KS, Radosavljevic M, Kasemsuwan T (1999). Effects of amylopectin branch chain length and amylose content on the gelatinization and pasting properties of starch. Cereal Chemistry 76(5):629-637.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kalita D, Sarma B, Srivastava B (2017). Influence of germination conditions on malting potential of low and normal amylose paddy and changes in enzymatic activity and physico chemical properties. Food Chemistry 220:67-75.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Khunae P, Tran T, Sirivongpaisal P (2007). Effect of heat‐moisture treatment on structural and thermal properties of rice starches differing in amylose content. Starch‐Strke 59(12):593-599.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Komatsuzaki N, Tsukahara K, Toyoshima H, Suzuki T, Shimizu N, Kimura T (2007). Effect of soaking and gaseous treatment on GABA content in germinated brown rice. Journal of food engineering 78(2):556-560.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Li C, Oh SG, Lee DH, Baik HW,Chung HJ (2017). Effect of germination on the structures and physicochemical properties of starches from brown rice, oat, sorghum, and millet. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules 105:931-939.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lim ST, Lee JH, Shin DH,Lim HS(1999). Comparison of protein extraction solutions for rice starch isolation and effects of residual protein content on starch pasting properties. Starch‐Strke 51(4):120-125.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Liu H, Corke H, Ramsden L (1999). Functional properties and enzymatic digestibility of cationic and cross-linked cationic ae, wx, and normal maize starch. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 47(7):2523-2528.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lopez‐Rubio A, Flanagan BM, Gilbert EP, Gidley MJ (2008).A novel approach for calculating starch crystallinity and its correlation with double helix content: A combined XRD and NMR study. Biopolymers: Original Research on Biomolecules 89(9):761-768.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mohan BH, Malleshi NG,Koseki T (2010). Physico-chemical characteristics and non-starch polysaccharide contents of Indica and Japonica brown rice and their malts. LWT-Food Science and Technology 43(5):784-791.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Musa AS, Umar M, Ismail M (2011). Physicochemical properties of germinated brown rice (Oryza sativa L.) starch. African Journal of Biotechnology 10(33):6281-6291.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Noda T, Nishiba Y, Sato T, Suda I (2003). Properties of starches from several low‐amylose rice cultivars. Cereal Chemistry 80(2):193-197.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pinkaew H, Thongngam M, Wang YJ, Naivikul O (2016). Isolated rice starch fine structures and pasting properties changes during pre-germination of three Thai paddy (Oryza sativa L.) cultivars. Journal of Cereal Science 70:116-122.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pinkaew H, Wang YJ, Naivikul O (2017). Impact of pre-germination on amylopectin molecular structures, crystallinity, and thermal properties of pre-germinated brown rice starches. Journal of Cereal Science 73:151-157.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tester RF, Karkalas J, Qi X (2004).Starch-composition, fine structure and architecture. Journal of cereal science 39(2):151-165. Journal of Cereal Science 39(2)151-165.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Subba Rao MVSST, Muralikrishna G (2002). Evaluation of the antioxidant properties of free and bound phenolic acids from native and malted finger millet (Ragi, Eleusine coracana Indaf-15). Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 50(4):889-892.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wang H, Hu F, Wang C, Ramaswamy HS, Yu Y, Zhu S, Wu J (2020). Effect of germination and high pressure treatments on brown rice flour rheological, pasting, textural, and structural properties. Journal of Food Processing and Preservation e14474.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wu F, Chen H, Yang N, Wang J, Duan X, Jin Z, Xu X (2013).Effect of germination time on physicochemical properties of brown rice flour and starch from different rice cultivars. Journal of Cereal Science 58(2): 263-271.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xia Q, Wang L, Xu C, Mei J, Li Y (2017). Effects of germination and high hydrostatic pressure processing on mineral elements, amino acids and antioxidants in vitro bioaccessibility, as well as starch digestibility in brown rice (Oryza sativa L.). Food Chemistry 214:533-542.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xu F, Zhang G, Tong C, Sun X, Corke H, Sun M, Bao J (2013).Association mapping of starch physicochemical properties with starch biosynthesizing genes in waxy rice (Oryza sativa L.). Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 61(42):10110-10117.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xu J, Zhang H, Guo X, Qian H (2012).The impact of germination on the characteristics of brown rice flour and starch. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture 92(2):380-387.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[You SY, Oh SG, Han HM, Jun W, Hong YS, Chung HJ (2016). Impact of germination on the structures and in vitro digestibility of starch from waxy brown rice. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules 82:863-870.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhu LJ, Liu QQ, Sang Y, Gu MH, Shi YC (2010). Underlying reasons for waxy rice flours having different pasting properties. Food Chemistry 120(1):94-100.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>