<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Development and Agricultural Economics</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2006-9774</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JDAE2020.1162</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Analysis of economic efficiency among smallholder sorghum producers in Kenya]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Backson</surname>
            <given-names>Mwangi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ibrahim</surname>
            <given-names>Macharia</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Eric</surname>
            <given-names>Bett</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">mbacksonmwangi@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>16</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>23</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>12</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>95</fpage>
	  <lpage>103</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/6B83ABB63823">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/6B83ABB63823	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-full-text-pdf/6B83ABB63823">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-full-text-pdf/6B83ABB63823	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[This study used Cobb-Douglas Stochastic Profit Frontier to analyze economic efficiency of sorghum farmers in Tharaka Nithi County, Kenya. Using a multi-stage stratified sample of 259 farmers, results depicted a wide range of profit efficiency between the best (0.96) and the worst (0.12) farmer with a mean of 0.17. The actual and potential profit was USD 164.88 ha-1 and USD 969.87 ha-1 respectively. This indicates that, sampled farmers incurred profit-loss of approximately USD 804.99 ha-1. Family labour and fixed capital base were the major contributing factors to sorghum profitability. Drivers of profit efficiency pointed out that, farmers who had more experience in sorghum farming, accessed agricultural credit, attended trainings, lived closer to the market and agro-dealers were likely to be more efficient. To increase profit efficiency, this study therefore advocates for policy strategies targeting these factors. Further, policy move targeting increase in uptake and correct application of fertilizer and other inputs should be reinforced.

	Key words: Improved sorghum varieties, economic efficiency, Cobb-Douglas stochastic profit frontier, Kenya.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abdullahi A (2012). Comparative economic analysis of rice production by adopter and non-adopter of improved varieties of rice among farmers in Paikoro LGA of Niger state. Nigeria. Journal of Basic and Applied Science 20(2):146-151.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abu O, Kirsten J (2009). Profit efficiency of small and medium scale maize milling enterprises in South Africa. Development Southern Africa 26(3):353-368.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aigner DJ, Lovell CAK, Schmidt P (1977). Formulation and estimation of stochastic frontier production function models. Journal of Econometrics 6:21-37.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ali M, Flinn JC (1989). Profit efficiency among Basmati rice producers in Pakistan Punjab. American Journal of Agricultural Economics 71:303-310.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ali F, Parikh A, Shah MK (1994). Measurement of profit efficiency using behavioural and Stochastic frontier approaches. Applied Economics 26:181-188.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Assa MM, Edriss A, Matchaya GC (2012). Unexploited profit among smallholder farmers in Central Malawi: What are the sources? International Journal of Applied Economics 9:83-95.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Battese GE (1992). Frontier production functions and technical efficiency: A survey of empirical applications in agricultural economics. Agricultural Economics 7:185-208.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Battese GE, Coelli TJ (1995). A model for technical inefficiency effects in a stochastic frontier production functions for panel data. Empirical Economics 20(2):325-332.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Biam C, Okorie A, Nwibo S (2015). Economic efficiency of small scale soyabean farmers in Central Agricultural Zone, Nigeria: A Cobb-Douglas stochastic frontier cost function approach. Journal of Development and Agricultural Economics 8(3):52-58.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bocher TF, Simtowe F (2017). Profit efficiency analysis among groundnut farmers from Malawi. Journal of Development and Agricultural Economics 9(10):278-288.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bravo-Ureta BE, Pinheiro AE (1993). Efficiency analysis of developing country agriculture: A review of the frontier function literature. Agriculture and Resource Economics Review 22:88-101.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[CBS (2016). Geographical dimensions of well-being in Kenya. Who and where are the poor. A constituency level profile (volume 2). The Legal Press Kenya Limited: Nairobi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chepngetich E, Bett E, Nyamwaro S, Kizito K (2014). Analysis of technical efficiency of sorghum production in Lower Eastern Kenya: A Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) approach. Journal of Economics and Sustainable Development 5(4):49-57.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chimai BC (2011). Determinants of technical efficiency in smallholder sorghum farming in Zambia.Unpublished MSc Thesis, Ohio State University, Ohio, USA.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Coelli TJ (1995). Recent developments in frontier modelling and efficiency measurement. Australian Journal of Agricultural Economics 39(3):219-245.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dang NH (2017). Profitability and profit efficiency of rice farming in TraVinh Province, Vietnam. Review of Integrative Business and Economics Research 6(1):191.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) (2005). Equivalence scales. Subjective methods. Easypol online resource materials for policy making. Rome, Italy.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Galawat F, Yabe M (2012). Profit efficiency in rice production in Brunei Darussalam: A Stochastic frontier Approach. Journal of the International Society for Southeast Asian Agricultural Sciences 18(1):100-112.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Government of Kenya (GoK) (2015). Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Fisheries. Economic review of agriculture. Government Printers: Nairobi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Government of Kenya (GoK) (2018). National crop variety list. Kenya Plant Health Inspectorate Service (KEPHIS).
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Government of Kenya (GoK) (2019a). Ministry of State for Planning, National Development and Vision 2030.2019 Kenya population and housing census. Government Printers: Nairobi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Government of Kenya (GoK) (2019b). Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Fisheries. Agricultural sector transformation and growth strategy towards sustainable agricultural transformation and food security in Kenya 2019-2029. Government Printers: Nairobi.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Joforullah M, Premachandra E (2003). Sensitivity of technical efficiency estimates to estimation approaches: An investigation using New Zealand dairy industry data. University of Otago. Economic Discussion Papers. No. 0306.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kenya Breweries Limited (KBL) (2018). Sorghum production in Kenya. Accessed in September 20.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Konja D, Mabe F, Oteng-Frimpong R (2019). Profitability and profit efficiency of certified groundnut seed and conventional groundnut production in Northern Ghana: A comparative analysis. Cogent Economics and Finance 7:1.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Meeusen W, Van den Broeck J (1977). Efficiency estimation from Cobb-Douglas production functions with composed error. International Economic Review 18(2):435-444.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tanko M, Alidu A (2017). Profit efficiency of small scale yam production yam production in Northern Ghana. International Journal of Development and Economic Sustainability 5(1):69-82.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Munir M, Hussain M, Imran M, Zia S, Anwar H, Ayub M, Rashid M, Jamil I, Ghaffar I (2015). Analysis of profit efficiency in sugarcane production in District Sargodha, Punjab, Pakistan. International Journal of Economics, Commerce and Management 9(3).
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ohen SB, Ajah EA (2015). Cost and return analysis in small scale rice production in Cross River State, Nigeria. International Research Journal Agriculture Soil Science 5(1):22-27.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Orr A, Mwema C, Gierend A, Nedumaran S (2016). Sorghum and Millets in Eastern and Southern Africa. Facts, Trends and Outlook. Working Paper Series No. 62. ICRISAT Research Program, Markets, Institutions and Policies. Patancheru 502 324, Telangana, India: International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics 76p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rahman S (2003). Profit efficiency among Bangladeshi rice farmers. Food Policy 28:483-503.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sadiq MS, Singh IP (2015). Application of Stochastic frontier function in measuring profit efficiency of small-scale maize farmers in Niger State, Nigeria. Journal of Agricultural Economics, Extension and Rural Development 3(1):229-239.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Saysay JL, Gabagambi DM, Mlay GI (2016). Profit efficiency among smallholder rice farmers in Central Liberia. Journal of Economics and Sustainable Development 7(14):94-103.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Trong P, Napasintuwong O (2015). Profit inefficiency among hybrid rice farmers in Central Vietnam, Agriculture and Agricultural Science Procedia 5:89-95.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wollie G, Zemedu L, Tegegn B (2018). Economic efficiency of smallholder farmers in barley production in Meket district, Ethiopia. Journal of Development and Agricultural Economics 10:328-338.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wongnaa CA, Awunyo-Vitor D, Mensah A (2018). Profit efficiency of Ghanas maize farmers. Conference paper presented at the International Association of Agricultural Economists (IAAE) in July-August, Vancouver, British Columbia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>