<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0875</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JMPR2020.6931</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Hydroethanolic stem bark extract of Vernonia amygdalina Del. (Asteraceae) suppresses yeast-induced pyrexia and Plasmodium berghei malaria in murine models]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Anna</surname>
            <given-names>Kwarley Quartey</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Yakubu</surname>
            <given-names>Jibira</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Arnold</surname>
            <given-names>Forkuo-Donkor</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Isaac</surname>
            <given-names>Ayensu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Adwoa</surname>
            <given-names>Agyakoma Oduro-Kwarteng</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Sussana</surname>
            <given-names>Emi-Reynolds Asuamah</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Patience</surname>
            <given-names>Noah</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">quarleyquartey@yahoo.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>21</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>258</fpage>
	  <lpage>264</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/447934F63538">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/447934F63538	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/447934F63538">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/447934F63538	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Vernonia amygdalina has been widely utilized in Ghana and other West African states for numerous parasitic infections, diabetes and some inflammatory conditions. In this study we evaluated the antipyretic and antimalarial properties as well as in vitro antioxidant activities of an ethanolic stem bark extract of V. amygdalina (VAE). The antipyretic effect of VAE was assessed using Bakerrsquo;s yeast-induced pyrexia and the antimalarial activities of plant extract against Plasmodium berghei-infected mice in the Peters 4-day suppressive test. The antioxidant activities of the stem bark extract were determined by DPPH radical scavenging and total phenol content assay. Phytochemical screening was carried out using standard methods. V. amygdalina (100-600 mg kg-1) dose related decreased the Bakerrsquo;s yeast-induced fever in young rats. Also, it exhibited a significant (F (5, 24) = 91.35, P lt; 0.0001) anti-plasmodial activity in the mouse model. It caused a percentage suppression of 81.80 plusmn; 3.76 at 600 mg kg-1and a relative antioxidant activity in the DPPH radical scavenging assay with an IC50 of 146.4 plusmn; 2.31  gml-1 and a total phenol content of 345.7 plusmn; 4.56 mg g-1 of gallic acid equivalence. Preliminary phytochemical screening showed that the extract contained tannins, reducing sugars, flavonoids, terpenoids and alkaloids. V. amygdalina hydroethanolic stem bark extract evoked promising antipyretic, anti-plasmodial and antioxidant effects.

	Key words: Vernonia amygdalina, pyrexia, malaria, antioxidants, Bakerrsquo;s Yeast, Plasmodium berghei.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adaramoye OA (2008). Lipid-lowering effects of methanolic extract of Vernonia amygdalina leaves in rats fed on high cholesterol diet. Vascular Health and Risk Management 4(1):235-241.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adesanoye OA, Farombi EO (2010). Hepatoprotective effects of Vernonia amygdalina (astereaceae) in rats treated with carbon tetrachloride. Experimental and Toxicologic Pathology 62(2):197-206.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Afolabi IS, Osikoya IO, Fajimi OD, Usoro PI, Ogunleye DO, Bisi-Adeniyi T, Adeyemi AO, Adekeye BT (2012). Solenostemon monostachyus, Ipomoea involucrata and Carica papaya seed oil versus Glutathione, or Vernonia amygdalina: Methanolic extracts of novel plants for the management of sickle cell anemia disease. BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine 12(1):262.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agbodeka K, Gbekley H, Karou S, Anani K, Agbonon A, Tchacondo T, Batawila K, Simpore J, Gbeassor M (2016). Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants used for the treatment of malaria in the plateau region, Togo. Pharmacognosy Research 8(5):12.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anochie IP (2013). Mechanisms of fever in humans. International Journal of Microbiology and Immunology Research 2(5):37-43.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aronoff DM, Neilson EG (2001). Antipyretics: mechanisms of action and clinical use in fever suppression. The American Journal of Medicine Elsevier 111(4):304-315.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Asnake S, Teklehaymanot T, Hymete A, Erko B, Giday M (2016). Survey of Medicinal Plants Used to Treat Malaria by Sidama People of Boricha District, Sidama Zone, South Region of Ethiopia. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine 2016:1-9.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Berendt AR, Tumer GD, Newbold CI (1994). Cerebral malaria: the sequestration hypothesis. Parasitology Today (Personal ed.)10(10):412-414.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Boadu AA, Asase A (2017). Documentation of herbal medicines used for the treatment and management of human diseases by some communities in southern Ghana. Evidence-based Complementary and Alternative Medicine 2017:1-12.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Erukainure OL, Chukwuma CI, Sanni O, Matsabisa MG, Islam MS (2019). Histochemistry, phenolic content, antioxidant, and anti-diabetic activities of Vernonia amygdalina leaf extract. Journal of Food Biochemistry. John Wiley  Sons, Ltd (10.1111) 43(2):e12737.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Evans WC (2009). Trease and Evans Pharmacognosy E-Book, Elsevier Health Sciences.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Eyong EU, Agiang MA, Atangwho IJ, Iwara IA, Odey MO, Ebong PE (2011). Phytochemicals and micronutrients composition of root and stem bark extracts of Vernonia amygdalina Del. Journal of Medicine and Medical Science 2 (June):900-903.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fabricant DS, Farnsworth NR (2001). The value of plants used in traditional medicine for drug discovery. Environmental Health Perspectives 109(suppl 1):69-75.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gross L (2006). Anatomy of a Fever. PLoS Biology 4(9):e305.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gl-stndağ , Mazza G (2007). Saponins: Properties, Applications and Processing. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition 47(3):231-258.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Han X, Shen T, Lou H (2007). Dietary Polyphenols and Their Biological Significance. International Journal of Molecular Sciences 8(9):950-988.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hunt NH, Grau GE (2003). Cytokines: accelerators and brakes in the pathogenesis of cerebral malaria. Trends in Immunology. Elsevier Current Trends 24(9):491-499.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ivanova D, Gerova D, Chervenkov T, Yankova T (2005). Polyphenols and antioxidant capacity of Bulgarian medicinal plants. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 96(1-2):145-150.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Iyiola O, Tijani A, Lateef K (2011). Antimalarial activity of ethanolic stem bark extract of Alstonia boonei in mice. Asian Journal of Biological Science 4:235-243.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Li S, Dou W, Tang Y, Goorha S, Ballou LR, Blatteis CM (2008). Acetaminophen: antipyretic or hypothermic in mice? In either case, PGHS-1b (COX-3) is irrelevant. Prostaglandins Other Lipid Mediat 85(3-4):89-99.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Njan AA, Adzu B, Agaba AG, Byarugaba D, Daz-Llera S, Bangsberg DR (2008). The Analgesic and Antiplasmodial Activities and Toxicology of Vernonia amygdalina. Journal of Medicinal Food 11(3):574-581.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Peng S, Zhao M, Mei S (2009). Preparation of -carboline-3-formyltryptophanyl amino acid benzyl esters as antitumor agents. Faming Zhuanli Shenqing, 17pp.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Penna-Coutinho J, Cortopassi WA, Oliveira AA, Frana TCC, Krettli AU (2011). Antimalarial Activity of Potential Inhibitors of Plasmodium falciparum Lactate Dehydrogenase Enzyme Selected by Docking Studies. PLoS ONE, Public Library of Science 6(7):e21237.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Prashant Tiwari B, Kumar MK, Gurpreet Kaur HK (2011). Phytochemical screening and extraction - A review. Internationale Pharmaceutica Sciencia 1(1):98-106.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Roginsky V (2003). Chain-breaking antioxidant activity of natural polyphenols as determined during the chain oxidation of methyl linoleate in Triton X-100 micelles. Archives of biochemistry and Biophysics 414(2):261-270.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ruth O, Hamid N, Kholijah S, Mudalip A (2017). Phytochemical and Pharmacological properties of Vernonia amygdalina : A review. 2(September):80-96.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shewo BS, Girma B (2017). Review on Nutritional and Medicinal Values of Vernonia amygdalina and its Uses in Human and Veterinary Medicines. Global Veterinaria 19(3): 562-568.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Simbo DJ (2010) An ethnobotanical survey of medicinal plants in Babungo, Northwest Region, Cameroon. Journal of Ethnobiology and Ethnomedicine. BioMed Central 6(1):8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sultana S, Asif HM, Akhtar N, Ahmad K (2015). Medicinal plants with potential antipyretic activity: A review. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Disease 5:S202-S208.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tomazetti J, vila DS, Ferreira APO, Martins JS, Souza FR, Royer C, Rubin MA, Oliveira MR, Bonacorso HG, Martins MAP, Zanatta N, Mello CF (2005). Baker yeast-induced fever in young rats: Characterization and validation of an animal model for antipyretics screening. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, Elsevier 147(1):29-35.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Velu G, Palanichamy V, Rajan AP (2018). Phytochemical and Pharmacological Importance of Plant Secondary Metabolites in Modern Medicine. Bioorganic Phase in Natural Food: An Overview. Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 135-156.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Victor VM, Rocha M, De La Fuente M (2004). Immune cells: Free radicals and antioxidants in sepsis. International Journal of Immunopharmacology 4 (3):327-347.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Walter EJ, Hanna-Jumma S, Carraretto M, Forni L (2016). The pathophysiological basis and consequences of fever. Critical care (London, England). BioMed Central 20(1):200.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xiao J (2015). Phytochemicals in medicine and food. Phytochemistry Reviews. Springer Netherlands 14(3):317-320.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yuan H, Ma Q, Ye L, Piao G (2016). The Traditional Medicine and Modern Medicine from Natural Products. Molecules 21(5):559.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zou Y, Lu Y, Wei D (2004). Antioxidant activity of a flavonoid-rich extract of Hypericum perforatum L. in vitro. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 52(16):5032-5039.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>