<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0875</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JMPR2020.6944</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Ultrasonic assisted extraction of bioactive compounds from different parts of Hancornia Speciosa Gomes]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Srgio</surname>
            <given-names>Prado Leite</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Tiago</surname>
            <given-names>Batista Adami</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Thiago</surname>
            <given-names>R. Bjerk</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Michel</surname>
            <given-names>Rubens dos Reis Souza</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Claudia</surname>
            <given-names>A. L. Cardoso</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Laza</surname>
            <given-names>Canielas Krause</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Elina</surname>
            <given-names>Bastos Caramo</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">elina@ufrgs.br</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>31</day>
        <month>07</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>17</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>23</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>7</issue>
	  	  <fpage>300</fpage>
	  <lpage>308</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/55E3DD363829">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/55E3DD363829	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/55E3DD363829">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/55E3DD363829	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The proper use of plants and their extracts, whether for medicine or as a food additive, requires the use of extraction and characterization methods that allow the identification and quantification of the active principles in each extract, associating them with the effect produced. With this objective, the present work was developed to  study the ultrasonic extracts of mangabeira (Hancornia speciosa Gomes), obtained from bark, leaves, and fruits of mangabeira in search of compounds with phytotherapeutic potential, particularly, anti-inflammatory activity. This plant is native to Brazil, belonging to the Apocinaceae family and is used in folk medicine to treat various diseases. The extracts were analyzed by gas chromatography and liquid chromatography, to test their antioxidant activity without toxicity. It was found that the extracts did not present toxicity as they have great antioxidant power. Identification of the compounds by GC/MS indicated the presence of Lupeol and Lupeol acetate as major compounds. The general characterization of extracts showed high contents of total phenolic compounds, flavonoids and flavonol in leaves and tannins (9 mg g-1) in the fruits. Some compounds such as Chlorogenic acid ( 35 mg g-1 in leaves and fruits), Catechin ( 35 mg g-1 in leaves, peels and fruits), Rutin ( 35 mg g-1 in leaves, peels and fruits) and Isoquercetin (35 mg g-1 only in the leaves) were also identified and quantified by HPLC/UV-DAD.

	Key words: Hancornia speciosa Gomes; medicinal plants; Gas chromatography; Lupeol; Antioxidants; flavonoids.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agostini-Costa TS, Garruti DS, Lima L, Freire S, Abreu FAP, Feitosa T (1999). Methodological evaluation for the determination of tannin in cashew juice. Boletim Centro de Pesquisa de Processamento de Alimentos 17:167-176.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Angelo PM, Jorge N (2007). Phenolic compounds in foods - A brief review. Revista do Instituto Adolfo Lutz 66:1-9.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Assumpo CF, Bachiega P, Morzelle MC, Nelson DL, Ndianye EA, Rios AO, Souza EC (2014). Characterization. antioxidant potential and cytotoxic study of mangaba fruit. Cincia Rural 44:1927-1303.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Azmir J, Zaidul ISM, Rahman MM, Sharif KM, Mohamed A, Sahna F, Jahurul MHA, Ghafoor K, Norulaini NAN, Omar AKM (2013). Techniques for extraction of bioactive compounds from plant materials: a review. Journal of Food Engineering 117:426-436.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bindes MMM, Reis MHM, Cardoso VL, Boffito DC (2019). Ultrasound-assisted extraction of bioactive compounds from green tea leaves and clarification with natural coagulants (chitosan and Moringa olefera seeds). Ultrasonic Sonochemistry 51:111-119.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chemat F, Rombaut N, Sicaire AG, Meullemiestre A, Fabiano-Tixier AS, Abert-Vian M (2017). Ultrasound assisted extraction of food and natural products. Mechanisms. techniques. combinations. protocols and applications A Review. Ultrasonic Sonochemistry 34:540-560.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Costa CF, Collevatti RG, Chaves LJ, Lima JS, Soares TN, Telles MPC (2017). Genetic diversity and fine-scale genetic structure in Hancornia speciosa Gomes (Apocynaceae). Biochemical System and Ecology 72:63-67.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Djeridane A, Yousfi M, Nadjemi B, Boutassouna D, Stocker P, Vidal N (2006). Antioxidant activity of some Algerian medicinal plants extracts containing phenolic compounds. Food Chemistry 97:654-660.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Formagio ASN, Volobuff CRF, Santiago M, Cardoso CAL, Vieira MC, Pereira ZV (2014). [Evaluation of antioxidant activity. total flavonoids. tannins and phenolic compounds in Psychotria leaf extracts. Antioxidants (Basel) 3:745-757.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ghorbani A (2017). Mechanisms of antidiabetic effects of flavonoid rutin. Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy 96:305-312.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Guardia T, Rotelli AE, Juarez AQ, Pelzer LE (2001). Anti-inflammatory properties of plant flavonoids. Effects of rutin. quercetin and hesperidin on adjuvant arthritis in rat. II. Pharmacology 56:683-687.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Huie CW (2002). A review of modern sample-preparation techniques for the extraction and analysis of medicinal plants. Analytical and Bioanalytical Chemistry 373:23-30.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jacques RA, Freitas LS, Peres VF, Dariva C, Oliveira JV, Caramao EB. (2006). Chemical composition of mate tea leaves (Ilex paraguariensis): A study of extraction methods. Journal of Separation Science 29:2780-2784.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Khoddami A, Wilkes MA, Robert TH (2013). Techniques for Analysis of Plants Phenolic Compounds. Molecules 18:2328-2375.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lacerda AM, Modolo AK, Matias RC, Pistori H, Yano M, Roel AR, Porto KRA (2011). Screening de plantas com potencial fitotxico. Revista Brasileira de Farmcia 92:352-355.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lucetti DL, Lucetti EPC, Bandeira MAM, Vera HNH, Silva AH, Leal LKAM, Lopes AA, Alves VCC, Silva GS, Brito GA, Viana GB (2010). Anti-inflammatory effects and possible mechanism of action of lupeol acetate isolated from Himatanthus drasticus (Mart.) Plumel. Journal of Inflammation 7:60-71.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maciel MAM, Pinto AV, Veiga Jr VF (2002). Medicinal plants: the need for multidisciplinary scientific studies. Quimica Nova 25:429-438.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Marinho DG, Alviano DS, Matheus, ME, Alviano CS, Fernandes PD (2011). The latex obtained from Hancornia speciosa Gomes possesses anti-inflammatory activity. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 135:530-537.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mason TJ, Paniwnyk L, Lorimer JP (1996). The uses of ultrasound in food technology. Ultrasonic Sonochemistry 3:5253-5360.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Melecchi MIS, Peres VF, Dariva C, Zini CA, Abad FC, Marttinez MM, Caramao EB (2006) Optimization of the sonication extraction method of Hibiscus tiliaceus L. flowers. Ultrasonic Sonochemistry 13:242-250.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Naveed M, Hejazi V, Abbas M, Kamboh AA, Khan GJ, Shumzaid M, Ahmad F, Babazadeh D, Fangfang X, Modarresi-Ghazani F, Wenhua L, Xiaohui L (2018). Chlorogenic acid (CGA): A pharmacological review and call for further research. Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy 97:67-74.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Okoye NN, Ajaghaku DL, Okeke HN, Ilodigwe EE, Nworu CS, Okoye FBC (2014). Beta-Amyrin and alpha-amyrin acetate isolated from the stem bark of Alstonia boonei display profound anti-inflammatory activity. Pharmceutical Biology 52:1-9.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Patil DM, Akamanchi KG (2017). Ultrasound-assisted rapid extraction and kinetic modelling of influential factors: extraction of camptothecin from Nothapodytes nimmoniana plant. Ultrasonic Sonochemistry 37:582-591.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pereira AC, Pereira ABD, Moreira CCL, Botion LM, Lemos VS, Braga FC, Cortes SF (2015). Hancornia speciosa Gomes (Apocynaceae) as a potential anti-diabetic drug. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 161:30-35.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Peres VF, Saffi J, Melecchi MIS, Abad FC, Jacques RA, Marttinez MM, Oliveira EC, Caramao EB (2006). Comparison of soxhlet, ultrasound-assisted and pressurized liquid extraction of terpenes, fatty acids and Vitamin E from Piper gaudichaudianum Kunth. Journal of Chromatography A 1105:115-118.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Perk AA, hatynska-Mytsyk I, Gercek YC, Boztaş K, Yazgan M, Fayyaz S, Farooqi AA (2014). Rutin mediated targeting of signaling machinery in cancer cells. Cancer Cell International 14:124-128.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rego MT, Furtado AA, Bitencourt MAO, Lima MCJS, Andrade RCLC, Azevedo EP, Soares TC, Tomaz JC, Lopes NP, Silva Jr. AA, Zucolotto SM, Pedrosa MFF (2016). Anti-inflamatory activity of aqueous extract and bioactive compounds identified from the fruits of Hancornia speciosa Gomes (apocynaceae). BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine 16:275.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Roohinejad S, Kouba M, Barba FJ, Greiner R, Orlien V, Lebovka N (2016). Negative pressure cavitation extraction: A novel method for extraction of food bioactive compounds from plant materials. Trends of Food Science and Technology 52:98-108.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Santos UP, Campos JF, Torquato HFV, Paredes-Gamero EJ, Carollo CA, Estevinho LM, Souza KP, Santos EL (2016). Antioxidant. antimicrobial. and cytotoxic properties as well as the phenolic content of the extract from Hancornia speciosa Gomes. PLOS ONE 11:1-19.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Siddique HR, Saleem M (2011). Beneficial health effects of lupeol: a review of preclinical studies. Life Sciences 88:285-293.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Silva AVC, Nascimento ALS, Soares ANR, Rabbani ARC, Silva Jr. JF, Ledo AS (2017). Identification and preliminary characterization of early fruiting mangabeira (Hancornia speciosa - Apocynaceae). Revista Agroambiente On-line 13:115-128.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Silva GC, Braga FC, Lemos VS, Cortes SF (2016). Potent antihypertensive effect of Hancornia speciosa leaves extract. Phytomedicine 23:214-219.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Stefanello MEA, Salvador MJ, Ito IY, Macar PAT (2006). Avaliao da atividade antimicrobiana e citotxica de extratos de Gochnatia polymorpha ssp floccose. Brazilian Journal of Pharmacognosy 16:525-530.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tao Y, Sun DW (2013). Enhancement of food processes by ultrasound: a review. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition 55:570-594.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tsai FS, Lin LW, Lin CRWU (2016). Lupeol and Its Role in Chronic Diseases. In: Gupta S, Prasad S, Aggarwal B, (eds) Drug Discovery from Mother Nature. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology 929:146-175.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Van Den Dool H, Kratz P (1963) A generalization of the retention index system including linear temperature programmed gas-liquid partition chromatography. Journal of Chromatography A 11:463-471.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Veiga Jr VF, Pinto AC (2005). Medicinal plants: Safe cure? Quimica Nova 28:519-528.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zhang H (2011). Bioactive Natural Products: Detection. Isolation. and Structural Determination. Phytomedicine 18:902-903.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>