<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0875</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JMPR2019.6890</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[The effects of aqueous extract of Bowdichia virgilioides Kunth in the immune functions of thymocytes and B-lymphocytes]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Maria</surname>
            <given-names>Danielma dos Santos Reis</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Larissa</surname>
            <given-names>Fernanda de Arajo Vieira</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Altair</surname>
            <given-names>Rogrio Alves Brando</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Emiliano</surname>
            <given-names>Barreto</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Salete</surname>
            <given-names>Smaniotto</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">danielma.reis@icbs.ufal.br</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>11</day>
			<month>12</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>27</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>247</fpage>
	  <lpage>257</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/086CB2463536">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/086CB2463536	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/086CB2463536">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/086CB2463536	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Bowdichia virgilioides Kunth (Fabaceae) is a tree species used in folk medicine against inflammatory disorders, and it is still unclear whether consumption of the B. virgilioides stem bark extract has any effect on immune cells. Thus, this study aimed to evaluate the effects of B. virgilioides stem bark extract (AEBv) on the functions of the thymus and B lymphocytes. The AEBv was obtained by decoction and administrated orally once a day in male mice for 7 days. After treatment, thymi were obtained for morphology analysis, relative weight, cellularity and deposition of laminin. Thymocytes obtained from control and treated animals were submitted to adhesion and migration assays followed by immunophenotyping. Also, mesenteric lymph nodes were removed, and the lymphoid cells were obtained to measure B cell proliferation and cytokine production. Mice treated with AEBv and their controls were also immunized with sheep red blood cells (SRBC), and 8 days post immunization the sera were collected to perform antibody titration using hemagglutination assays. AEBv administration decreased thymus weight and cellularity and increased the laminin deposition without any significant effect on the expression of the laminin receptor VLA-6 in the thymus microenvironment. Additionally, thymocytes of AEBv-treated mice showed reduced adhesion and migration on laminin substrates, and the B lymphocytes showed reduced proliferation, enhanced IL-10 secretion, decreased TNF-alpha; production, and attenuated anti-SRBC antibody production. These findings showed that AEBv intake might cause modulatory effects on the functions of thymocytes and B-lymphocytes, contributing to the treatment of immune diseases.

	Key words: Thymocytes, cell migration, cell adhesion, immunosuppression, B cell.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agra IKR, Pires LLS, Carvalho PSM, Silva-Filho EA, Smaniotto S, Barreto E (2013). Evaluation of wound healing and antimicrobial properties of aqueous extract from Bowdichia virgilioides stem barks in mice. Anais da Academia Brasileira de Cincias 85(3):945-954.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Alburquerque KA, Guimares RM, Almeida IF, Clemente ACS (2007). Mtodos para superao da dormncia em sementes de sucupira-preta (Bowdichia virgilioides Kunth). Cienc Agrotec 6:31.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Almeida SP, Proena CEB, Sano SM, Ribeiro JF (1998). Cerrado: espcies vegetais teis. Planaltina: Embrapa-CPAC.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Asadi-Samani M, Bagheri N, Rafieian-Kopaei M, Shirzad H (2017). Inhibition of Th1 and Th17 Cells by Medicinal Plants and Their Derivatives: A Systematic Review. Phytotherapy Research 31(8):1128-1139.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Azad R, Babu NK, Gupta AD, Reddanna P (2018). Evaluation of anti-inflammatory and immunomodulatory effects of Premna integrifolia extracts and assay-guided isolation of a COX-2/5-LOX dual inhibitor Fitoterapia 131:189-199.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Barros WM, Rao VS, Silva RM, Lima JC, Martins DT (2010). Anti-inflammatory effect of the ethanolic extract from Bowdichia virgilioides H.B.K stem bark. Anais da Academia Brasileira de Cincias 82(3):609-616.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bin-Hafeez B, Ahmad I, Haque R, Raisuddin S (2001). Protective effect of Cassia occidentalis L. on cyclophosphamide-induced suppression of humoral immunity in mice. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 75:13-18.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bin-Hafeez B, Haque R, Pandey S, Sayeed I, Raisuddin S (2003). Immunomodulatory effects of fenugreek (Trigonella foenum graecum L.) extract in mice. International Immunopharmacology 3:257-265.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bui TT, Kwon DA, Choi DW, Jung SY, Lee SY, Piao CH, Hyeon E, Fan Y, Yeon SH, Son RH, Shon DH, Song CH, Shin HS, Chai OH (2019). Rosae multiflorae fructus extract and its four active components alleviate ovalbumin-induced allergic inflammatory responses via regulation of Th1/Th2 imbalance in BALB/c rhinitis mice. Phytomedicine 55:238-248.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chen F, Ye X, Yang Y, Teng T, Li X, Xu S, Ye Y (2015). Proanthocyanidins from the bark of Metasequoia glyptostroboides ameliorate allergic contact dermatitis through directly inhibiting T cells activation and Th1/Th17 responses. Phytomedicine 22(4):510-5.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chen LX, Qi YL, Qi Z, Gao K, Gong RZ, Shao ZJ, Liu SX, Li SS, Sun YS (2019). A Comparative Study on the Effects of Different Parts of Panax ginseng on the Immune Activity of Cyclophosphamide-Induced Immunosuppressed Mice. Molecules 20:24(6).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cragg GM, Newman DJ (2013). Natural products: a continuing source of novel drug leads. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 1830(6):3670-95.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Deharo E, Bourdy G, Quenevo C, Munoz V, Ruiz G, Sauvain M (2001). A search for natural bioactive compounds in Bolivia through a multidisciplinary approach. Part V. Evaluation of the antimalarial activity of plants used by the Tacana indians. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 77:91-98.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fridlender M, Kapulnik Y, Koltai H (2015). Plant derived substances with anti-cancer activity: from folklore to practice. Frontiers in Plant Science 1(6):799.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gao S, Wang Y, Zhang P, Dong Y, Li B (2008). Subacute oral exposure to dibromoacetic acid induced immunotoxicity and apoptosis in the spleen and thymus of the mice. Toxicological Sciences105(2):331-341.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Garcilln B, Figgett WA, Infantino S, Lim EX, Mackay F (2018). Molecular control of B-cell homeostasis in health and malignancy. Immunology and Cell Biology 96(5):453-462.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Golbert DC, Correa-de-Santana E, Ribeiro-Alves M, de Vasconcelos AT, Savino W (2013). ITGA6 gene silencing by RNA interference modulates the expression of a large number of cell migration-related genes in human thymic epithelial cells. BMC Genomics 14(Suppl 6):S3.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hu Z, Lancaster JN, Ehrlich LI (2015). The Contribution of Chemokines and Migration to the Induction of Central Tolerance in the Thymus. Frontiers in Immunology 7(6):398.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hueza IM, Latorre AO, Raspantini PCF, Raspantini LER, Mariano-Souza DP, Guerra JL, Grniak SL (2007). Effect of Senna occidentalis seeds on immunity in broiler chickens. Journal of Veterinary Medicine 54:179-185.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kallifatidis G, Hoy JJ, Lokeshwar BL (2016). Bioactive natural products for chemoprevention and treatment of castration-resistant prostate cancer. Seminars in Cancer Biology 40-41:160-169.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Khan WN, Wright JA, Kleiman E, Boucher JC, Castro I, Clark ES (2013). B-lymphocyte tolerance and effector function in immunity and autoimmunity. Immunologic Research 57(1-3):335-353.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kim MG, Lee G, Lee SK, Lolkema M, Yim J, Hong SH, Schwartz RH (2000). Epithelial cell-specific laminin 5 is required for survival of early thymocytes. Journal of Immunology 165(1):192-201.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lannes-Vieira J, Dardenne M, Savino W (1991). Extracellular matrix componentes of the mouse thymus microenvironment Ontogenetic studies and modulation by glucocorticoids hormones. Journal of Histochemistry and Cytochemistry 39:1539-1546.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Le CF, Kailaivasan TH, Chow SC, Abdullah Z, Ling SK, Fang CM (2017). Phytosterols isolated from Clinacanthus nutans induce immunosuppressive activity in murine cells. International Immunopharmacology 44:203-210.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lima AC, Francelin C, Ferrucci DL, Stach-Machado DR, Verinaud L (2012). Thymic alterations induced by Plasmodium berghei: expression of matrix metalloproteinases and their tissue inhibitors. Cellular Immunology 279(1):53-59.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ma B, Kan WL, Zhu H, Li SL, Lin G (2017). Sulfur fumigation reducing systemic exposure of ginsenosides and weakening immunomodulatory activity of ginseng. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 195:222-230.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Macdo MJF, Ribeiro DA, Santos MO, Macdo DG, Macedo JGF, Almeida BV, Saraiva ME, Lacerda MNS, Souza MMA (2018). Fabaceae medicinal flora with therapeutic potential in Savanna areas in the Chapada do Araripe, Northeastern Brazil. Revista Brasileira de Farmacognosia 28:738-750.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mahajan SG, Mehta AA (2010). Immunosuppressive activity of ethanolic extract of seeds of Moringa oleifera Lam. in experimental immune inflammation. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 130:183-186.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Melo FN, Navarro VR, Silva MS, Da-Cunha EV, Barbosa-Filho JM, Braz-Filho R. (2001). Bowdenol, a new 2,3-dihydrobenzofuran constituent from Bowdichia virgilioides. Natural Product Letters 15(4):261-266.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mendes-da-Cruz DA, Brignier AC, Asnafi V, Baleydier F, Messias CV, Lepelletier Y, Bedjaoui N, Renand A, Smaniotto S, Canioni D, Milpied P, Balabanian K, Bousso P, Leprtre S, Bertrand Y, Dombret H, Ifrah N, Dardenne M, Macintyre E, Savino W, Hermine O (2014). Semaphorin 3F and neuropilin-2 control the migration of human T-cell precursors. PLoS ONE 9(7):e103405.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Meng Q, Niu Y, Roubin RH, Hanrahan JR (2009). Ethnobotany, phytochemistry and pharmacology of the genus Caragana used in traditional Chinese medicine. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 124:350-368.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Murdoch JR, Lloyd CM (2010). Chronic inflammation and asthma. Mutation Research 690(1-2):24-39.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nakamura K, Matsuoka H, Nakashima S, Kanda T, Nishimaki-Mogami T, Akiyama H (2015). Oral administration of apple condensed tannins delays rheumatoid arthritis development in mice via downregulation of T helper 17 (Th17) cell responses. Molecular Nutrition and Food Research 59(7):1406-1410.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ocampo JS, de Brito JM, Corra-de-Santana E, Borojevic R, Villa-Verde DM, Savino W (2008). Laminin-211 controls thymocyte--thymic epithelial cell interactions. Cellular Immunology 254(1):1-9.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Petrie HT (2003). Cell migration and the control of post-natal T-cell lymphopoiesis in the thymus. Nature Reviews Immunology, 3(11):859-866.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pezzi N, Assis AF, Cotrim-Sousa LC, Lopes GS, Mosella MS, Lima DS, Bombonato-Prado KF, Passos GA (2016). Aire knockdown in medullary thymic epithelial cells affects Aire protein, deregulates cell adhesion genes and decreases thymocyte interaction. Molecular Immunology 77:157-173.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Rathee P, Chaudhary H, Rathee S, Rathee D, Kumar V, Kohli K (2009). Mechanism of action of flavonoids as anti-inflammatory agents: a review. Inflammation and Allergy Drug Targets 8(3):229-235.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ribeiro-Carvalho MM, Lima-Quaresma KRF, Mouo T, Varvalho VF, Mello-Coelho V, Savino W (2007). Triiodothyronine modulates thymocyte migration. Scandinavian Journal of Immunoogy 66:17-25.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Saad B, Azaizeh H, Said O (2005). Tradition and perspectives of arab herbal medicine: a review. Evidence-based Complementary and Alternative Medicine 2(4):475-479.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Saha S, Tieng A, Pepeljugoski KP, Zandamn-Goddard G, Peeva E (2011). Prolactin, Systemic Lupus Erythematosus, and Autoreactive B Cells: Lessons learnt from murine models. Clinical Reviews in Allergy and Immunology 40:8-15.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Savino W, Mendes-da-Cruz DA, Golbert DC, Riederer I, Cotta-de-Almeida V (2015). Laminin-Mediated Interactions in Thymocyte Migration and Development. Frontiers in Immunology 6:579.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Savino W, Mendes-da-Cruz DA, Lepletier A, Dardenne M (2016). Hormonal control of T-cell development in health and disease. Nature Reviews Endocrinology 12(2):77-89.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Savino W, Mendes-da-Cruz DA, Silva JS, Dardenne M, Cotta-de-Almeida, V (2002). Intrathymic T cell migration: a combinatorial interplay of extracellular matrix and chemokines? Trends in Immunology 23:305-313.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Savino W, Mendes-da-Cruz DA, Smaniotto S, Silva-Monteiro E, Villa-Verde DMS (2004). Molecular mechanisms governing thymocyte migration: combined role of chemokines and extracellular matrix. Journal of Leukocyte Biology 75:1-11.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Schelleken GA, de Jong BAW, van den Hoogen FHJ, van de Putte LBA, van Venrooij WJ (1998). Citrulline is an essential constituent of antigenic determinants recognized by rheumatoid arthritis-specific autoantibodies. The Journal of Clinical Investigation 101:273-281.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Silva JP, Ferro JN, Filho HS, Silva LA, Souza TP, Matos HD, Carvalho VD, Rodarte RS, Barreto E (2016). Aqueous extract of Bowdichia virgilioides stem bark inhibition of allergic inflammation in mice. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 10:575-584.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Silva JP, Rodarte RS, Calheiros AS, Souza CZ, Amendoeira FC, Martins MA, Silva PMR, Frutuoso V, Barreto E (2010). Antinociceptive activity of aqueous extract of Bowdichia virgilioides in mice. Journal of Medicinal Food 13:348- 351.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Simon T, Bromberg JS (2017). Regulation of the Immune System by Laminins. Trends in Immunology 38(11):858-871.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Smaniotto S, Mello-Coelho V, Villa-Verde DM, Plau JM, Postel-Vinay MC, Darrdenne M, Savino W (2005). Growth hormone modulates thymocyte development in vivo through a combined action of laminin and CXC chemokine ligand 12. Endocrinology 146:3005-3017.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref50">
				<label>50</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thomazzi SM, Silva CB, Silveira DCR, Vasconcellos CLC, Lira AF, Cambui EVF, Estevam CS, Antoniolli AR (2010). Antinociceptive and anti-inflammatory activities of Bowdichia virgilioides (sucupira). Journal of Ethnopharmacology 127:451-456.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref51">
				<label>51</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Toro F, Benshimol AL, Gonzlez EM, Soyano A (1992). Spleen and thymus histology and proliferative response of splenic cells in rats fed raw and cooked Phaseolus vulgaris beans. Archivos Latinoamericanos de Nutricin 42:395-402.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref52">
				<label>52</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Velozo LSM, Silva BP, Bernardo RR, Parente JP (1999). Odoratin-7-O--D-glucopyranoside from Bowdichia virgilioides. Phytochemistry 52:1473-1477.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref53">
				<label>53</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vieira LFA, Reis MDS, Brando ARA, Viana IMMN, Silva JP, Barreto E, Smaniotto S (2013). Anxiolytic-like effect of the extract from Bowdichia virgilioides in mice. Revista Brasileira de Farmacognosia 23:680-686.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref54">
				<label>54</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Yellayi S, Naaz A, Szewczykowski MA, Sato T, Woods JA, Chang J, Segre M, Allred CD, Helferich WG, Cooke PS (2002). The phytoestrogen genistein induces thymic and immune changes: a human health concern? Proceeding of the National Academy of Science of the United States of America 99(11):7616-7621.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>