<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0875</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JMPR2019.6843</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Chemical composition and biological potentials of Lebanese Cupressus sempervirens L. leaves’ extracts]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Layal</surname>
            <given-names>Anka</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Hassan</surname>
            <given-names>Rammal</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ahmad</surname>
            <given-names>Kobeissi</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Hamid</surname>
            <given-names>Bou Saab</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">hamid_bou_saab@hotmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>15</day>
			<month>09</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>22</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>292</fpage>
	  <lpage>299</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/014F43E63709">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/014F43E63709	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/014F43E63709">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/014F43E63709	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The essential oils and defatted ethanolic extracts isolated from Cupressus sempervirens L. leaves collected from two geographically distinct regions in Lebanon; Beit El-Dein (mountain) and Jbeil (sea-side) were analysed for their chemical composition by GC/MS and qualitative phytochemical screening, respectively. These were then tested for their in-vitro antioxidant and antibacterial activities. Fourteen and eighteen compounds were identified in Beit El-Dein and Jbeil samples, respectively with alpha;-pinene (45.69-20.97%) and delta;-3-carene (24.55-16.7%) representing the major constituents. C. sempervirens L. ethanolic extracts were able to reduce the stable radical 1,1-Diphenyl-2-picrylhydrazyl (DPPH) reaching 50% reduction with IC50 values equal to 113.17 and 155.75 mu;g/ml, respectively. These results positively correlated with the high phenol (77.4-66.4 mg gallic acid equivalent/g dry weight) and flavonoid (3.8-2.8 mg rutin equivalent/g dry weight) contents in both samples, respectively. Regarding the in-vitro antibacterial activity, essential oils exhibited a stronger potential mainly towards the Gram-positive bacteria Staphylococcus aureus compared with the ethanolic extracts as this was revealed by higher diameters of inhibition zone ranging between 7 and 12.3 mm and minimal inhibitory concentrations equal to 15.62 mu;l/ml. The results obtained from this study show that the Lebanese Cypress may be used as a good source of natural food preservatives and as drugs for various ailments.

	Key words: Lebanese Cupressus sempervirens L., essential oil and ethanolic extract, antioxidant, antibacterial activities.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ahmad S, Asili J, Rahimizadeh M, Fazly-bazzaz BS (2006). Chemical and antimicrobial studies of Cupressus sempervirens L . and C . horizentalis Mill . essential oils. Iranian Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences 2(2):103-108.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Boukhris M, Regane G, Yangui T, Sayadi S, Bouaziz M, (2012). Chemical composition and biological potential of essential oil from Tunisian Cupressus sempervirens L. Journal of Arid Land Studies 332:329-332.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cowan MM (1999). Plant products as antimicrobial agents. Clinical Microbiology Reviews 12(4):564-582.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dāʾirat al-Arṣād al-Jawwīyah al-Lubnānīyah (1977). Atlas climatique du Liban. Publi par le service mtorologique du Liban avec laide de lobservatoire de Ksara. 2me Edition.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Deeb T, Knio K, Shinwari ZK, Kreydiyyeh S, Baydoun E (2013). Survey of medicinal plants currently used by herbalists in Lebanon. Pakistan Journal of Botany 45(2):543-555.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Elansary HO, Salem MZM, Ashmawy NA, Yacout MM (2012). Chemical composition ,antibacterial and antioxidant activities of leaves essential oils from Syzygium cumini L., Cupressus sempervirens L. and Lantana camara L. from Egypt. Journal of Agricultural Sciences 4(10):144-152.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Farhan H, Rammal H, Hijazi A, Badran B (2012). Preliminary phytochemical screening and extraction of polyphenol from stems and leaves of a Lebanese plant Malva parviflora L. International Journal of Current Pharmaceutical Research 4(1):1-5.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fayed SA (2015). Chemical composition, antioxidant, anticancer properties and toxicity evaluation of leaf essential oil of Cupressus sempervirens. Notulae Botanicae Horti Agrobotanici Cluj-Napoca 43(2):320-326.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gopinath SM, Rakesh CK, Murthy TPN, Dayananda KS (2012). Preliminary phytochemical evaluation of leaf extracts of Gymnema. International Journal of Pharmacognosy and Phytochemical Research 4(3):109-111.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ibrahim NA, Mohammed MMD, El-kom S (2009). Chloroform extract and essential oil of Cupressus sempervirens. Chemistry of Natural Compounds 45(3):265-268.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ibrahim NA, El-seedi HR (2007). Phytochemical investigation and hepatoprotective activity of Cupressus sempervirens L . leaves growing in Egypt. Natural Product Research: Formerly Natural Product Letters 21(10) 37-41.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jamshidi-Kia F, Lorigooini Z, Amini-Khoei H (2018). Medicinal plants: past history and future perspective. Journal of Herbmed Pharmacology 7(1):1-7.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kabera JN, Semana E, Mussa AR, He X (2014). Plant secondary metabolites: biosynthesis, classification, function and pharmacological properties. Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology 2:377-392.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kavit M, Patel BN, Jain BK (2013). Phytochemical analysis of leaf extract of Phyllanthus fraternus. Research Journal of Recent Sciences 2:12-15]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mazari K, Bendimerad N, Bekhechi C, Fernandez X (2010). Chemical composition and antimicrobial activity of essential oils isolated from Algerian Juniperus phoenicea L. and Cupressus sempervirens L. Journal of Medicinal Plant Research 4(10):959-964.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Miguel MG (2010). Antioxidant activity of medicinal and aromatic plants: A review. Flavour and Fragnance Journal, pp. 291-312.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nehdi IA (2013). Cupressus sempervirens var . horizentalis seed oil : Chemical composition, physicochemical characteristics and utilizations. Industrial Crops and Products 41:381-385.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nouri A, Dhifi W, Bellili S, Ghazghazi H, Aouadhi C, Chrif A, Hammami M, Mnif W (2015). Chemical composition, antioxidant potential, and antibacterial activity of essential oil cones of Tunisian Cupressus sempervirens. Hindawi Publishing Corporation. Journal of Chemistry Volume 2015, Article ID 538929, 8p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Preedy VR, Watson RR (2014). The Mediterranean diet: an evidence-based approach. 1st Edition. Academic Press.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sarikurkcu C, Arisoy K, Tepe B, Cakir A, Abali G, Mete E (2009). Studies on the antioxidant activity of essential oil and different solvent extracts of Vitex agnus castus L . fruits from Turkey. Food and Chemical Toxicology 47(10):2479-2483.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Selim SA, Adam ME, Hassan SM, Albalawi AR (2014). Chemical composition , antimicrobial and antibiofilm activity of the essential oil and methanol extract of the Mediterranean Cypress (Cupressus sempervirens L.). BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine 14(1):1-8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shah RK (2015). Qualitative phytochemical analysis and estimation of total phenols and flavonoids in leaf extract of Sarcochlamys Pulcherrima Wedd.. Global Journal of Bioscience and Biotechnology 4(1):81-84.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>