<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0875</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JMPR2020.6914</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Antibacterial, cytotoxic, and schistosomicidal activities of the methanolic extract from Cassia grandis L.f. (Fabaceae) stem bark and its fractions]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Lucimri</surname>
            <given-names>Paulino Machado Magalhes</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Brbara</surname>
            <given-names>Azevedo Ramos</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Mrcia</surname>
            <given-names>Vanusa da Silva</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Maria</surname>
            <given-names>Tereza dos Santos Correia</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ksia</surname>
            <given-names>Xisto Fonseca Ribeiro de Sena</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Tlio</surname>
            <given-names>Diego da Silva</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Andr</surname>
            <given-names>de Lima Aires</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Mnica</surname>
            <given-names>Camelo Pessa de Azevedo Albuquerque</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Gardnia</surname>
            <given-names>Carmen Gadelha Milito</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Teresinha</surname>
            <given-names>Gonalves da Silva</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Renata</surname>
            <given-names>Mendona Arajo</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Julianna</surname>
            <given-names>Ferreira Cavalcanti de Albuquerque</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Rafael</surname>
            <given-names>Matos Ximenes</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">mohtaram_a_m_e@yahoo.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>24</day>
			<month>01</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>24</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>265</fpage>
	  <lpage>282</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/74A5BA963542">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/74A5BA963542	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/74A5BA963542">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/74A5BA963542	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Cassia grandis L. (Fabaceae), a native tree from Amazon Forest, has been used in folk medicine against worms and intestinal parasites, and to treat stomach and respiratory problems, blood diseases, among others uses. This study aimed to evaluate the antioxidant, cytotoxic, antimicrobial, and schistosomicidal activities of the methanolic extract from C. grandis stem bark (CgME) and to elucidate the chemical profile of its active fractions. The antioxidant activity of C. grandis stem bark methanolic extract (CgME) and its fractions were determined by DPPH radical scavenging assay and by the total phenolics and flavonoid contents. The antimicrobial activity was performed by microdilution. The cytotoxicity against MCF-7 (breast), NCI-H292 (lung), and HL-60 (leukemia) cancer cell lines was evaluated by the MTT method. The schistosomicidal activity was investigated in vitro against adult Schistosoma mansoni couple worms. The phytochemical profile of the active fractions was determined by GC-MS and UPLC-MS. The hexane fraction from the CgME was cytotoxic to NCI-H292 and HL-60 cancer cell lines and both major compounds clionasterol and lupeol acetate, determined by GC-MS, are well known for their cytotoxicity against cancer cells. The ethyl acetate fraction (CgEF) exhibited both antibacterial, against multidrug-resistant S. aureus, and schistosomicidal activities, which could be attributed to the presence of flavonoids, such as catechin derivatives, quercetin, and luteolin in the CgEF. These results agree with the popular uses of C. grandis and should stimulate future research on this species.

	Key words: Antimicrobial activity, antioxidant, Staphylococcus aureus, clinical isolates, Schistosoma mansoni, cytotoxicity.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Andrade ALP, Miotto STS, Santos EPA (2009). Subfamlia Faboideae (Fabaceae Lindl.) no Parque Estadual do Guartel Paran, Brasil. Hoehnea 36(4):737-768.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adams RP (2001). Identification of essential oil components by gas chromatography/quadrupole mass spectroscopy. Allured Publishing Corporation, 3rd Ed, Carol Stream.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aires AL, Ximenes ECPA, Silva RAR, Barbosa VX, Ges AJS, Peixoto CA, Souza VMO, Albuquerque MCPA (2014). Ultrastructural Analysis of -lapachone-induce surface membrane damage in male adult Schistosoma mansoni BH strain worms. Experimental Parasitology 142:83-90.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amaral GP, Mizdal CR, Stefanello ST, Mendez ASL, Puntel RL, Campos MMA, Soares FAA, Fachinetto R (2019). Antibacterial and antioxidant effects of Rosmarinus officinalis L. extract and its fractions. Journal of Traditional Complementary Medicine 9(4):383-392.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bauer AW, Kirby WMM, Shevis JC, Turck M (1966). Antibiotic susceptibily testing by a standardized single disc method. American Journal of Clinical Pathology 45(4):493-496.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Blois MS (1958). Antioxidant determinations by the use of a stable free radical. Nature 181:1199-1200.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Braguine CG, Costa ES, Magalhes LG, Rodrigues V, da Silva Filho AA, Bastos JK, Silva ML, Cunha WR, Janurio AH, Pauletti PM (2009). Schistosomicidal evaluation of Zanthoxylum naranjillo and its isolated compounds against Schistosoma mansoni adult worms. Nature A Journal Biosciences 64(11-12):F793-F797.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Calixto JB (2019). The role of natural products in modern drug discovery. Anais da Academia Brasileira de Cincias 91(3).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Castro AT, Castro AP, Silva MS, Souza IMM, Martins-Souza RL, Chagas-Paula DA, Coelho LFL, Bolzani VS, Pivatto M, Junior CV, Marques MJ (2016). In vitro evaluation of the schistosomicidal effect of the extracts, fractions and major 3-hydroxy-2,6-dialkyl-substituted piperidine alkaloids from the flowers of Senna spectabilis (Fabaceae). Bioorganic and Medicinal Chemistry Letters 26(17):4197-4204.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chanda S, Kaneria M, Baravalia Y (2012). Antioxidant and antimicrobial properties of various polar solvent extracts of stem and leaves of four Cassia species. African Journal Biotechnology 11(10):2490-2503.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Clarke KA, Dew TP, Watson REB, Farrar MD, Bennett S, Nicolaou A, Rhodes LE, Williamson G (2014). High performance liquid chromatography tandem mass spectrometry dual extraction method for identification of green tea catechin metabolites excreted in human urine. Journal Chromatography B 972:29-37.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI) (2018). M100-S29 performance standards for antimicrobial susceptibility testing 29th informational supplement.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dave H, Ledwani L (2012). A review on anthraquinones isolated from Cassia species and their applications. Indian Journal of Natural Products and Resources 3(3):291-319.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[El-Hashash MM,  Abdel-Gawad MM,  El-Sayed MM (2010). Antioxidant properties of methanolic extracts of the leaves of seven Egyptian Cassia species. Acta Pharmaceutica 60(3):361-367.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Forzza RC, Leitman PM, Costa AF, Carvalho jr. AA, Peixoto A, Walter BMT, Bicudo C, Zappi D, Costa DP, Lleras E, Martinelli G, Lima HC, Prado J, Stehmann JR, Baumgratz JFA, Pirani JR, Sylvestre L, Maia LC, Lohmann LG, Queiroz LP, Silveira M, Coelho MN, Mamede MC, Bastos MNC, Morim MP, Barbosa MR, Menezes M, Hopkins M, Secco R, Cavalcanti TB, Souza VC (2010). Introduo. In: Lista de Espcies da Flora do Brasil. Jardim Botnico do Rio de Janeiro.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gallo MBC, Miranda B, Sarachine MJ (2009). Biological Activies of Lupeol. International Journal of Research in Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Sciences 3(1):46-66.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Guidoti DGG, Guidoti DT, Romero AL, Ruiz ALTG, Foglio MA, Carvalho JE, Rocha CLMSC (2019). Kaurenoic acid from Annona squamosa L. exhibits antiproliferative effect on human tumor cell lines and induces apoptosis in Aspergillus nidulans. Revista Fitos 13(2):122-136.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[ Hegazi NM, Hashim AN (2016). Grandisin, 2-methoxy 6,7,2,6-tetrahydroxy flavanone 6-O-glucoside, from Cassia grandis leaves - antioxidant and cytotoxic activities. Pharmazie 71(9):544-547.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Horiuchi A, Satou T, Akao N, Koik K (2005). The effect of free and polyethylene glycol-liposome-entrapped albendazole on larval mobility and number in Toxocara canis infected mice. Veterinary Parasitology 129(1-2):83-87.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jiang H, Li J, Chen A, .Li Y, Xia M, Guo P, Yao S, Chen S (2018). Fucosterol exhibits selective antitumor anticancer activity against HeLa human cervical cell line by inducing mitochondrial mediated apoptosis, cell cycle migration inhibition and downregulation of m-TOR/PI3K/Akt signalling pathway. Oncology Letters 15(3):3458-3463.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Joshi H, Kapoor VP (2003). Cassia grandis Linn. F. Seed galactomannan: structural and crystallographical studies. Carbohydrate Research 338(18):1907-1912.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lima HC, de Queiroz LP, Morim MP, Souza VC, Dutra VF, Bortoluzzi RLC, Iganci JRV, Fortunato RH, Vaz AMSF, Souza ER, de Filardi FLR, Valls JFM, Garcia FCP, Fernandes JM, Martins-da-Silva RCV, Perez APF, Mansano VF, Miotto STS, Tozzi AMGA, Meireles JE, Lima LCP, Oliveira MLAA, Flores AS, Torke BM, Pinto RB, Lewis GP, Barros MJF, Schtz R, Pennington T, Klitgaard BB, Rando JG, Scalon VR, Cardoso DBOS, Costa LC, da,Silva MJ, da,Moura TM, Barros LAV, de,Silva MCR, Queiroz RT, Sartori ALB, Camargo R.A, Lima IB, Costa J, Soares MVB, Snak C, So-Mateus W, Falco M, J.,Martins MV, Reis IP, Cordula E (2015). Fabaceae in Lista de Espcies da Flora do Brasil. Jardim Botnico do Rio de Janeiro. BFG. Growing knowledge: an overview of Seed Plant diversity in Brazil. Rodrigusia 66(4):1085-1113.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lodha SR, Joshi SV, Vyas BA, Bhavin AV, Mohini CU, Megha SK, Shweta SS, Sheetal KK, Manasi VR (2010). Assessment of the antidiabetic potential of Cassia grandis using an in vivo Model. Journal of Advanced Pharmaceutical Technololy Research 1(3):330-333.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lucetti DL, Lucetti ECP, Bandeira MAM, Helenicy NHV, Aline H Silva, Luzia Kalyne AML, Amanda AL, Victor CCA, Gabriela SS, Gerly AB, Glauce BV (2010). Anti-inflammatory effects and possible mechanism of action of lupeol acetate isolated from Himatanthus drasticus (Mart.) Plumel. Journal of Inflammation 7:60.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[McDonald S, Prenzler PD, Antolovich M, Robards K (2001). Phenolic content and antioxidant activity of olive extracts. Food Chemistry 73:73-84.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Meena M, Jain AK, Jain CP, Gaur K, Kori ML, Kakde A, Nema RK (2009). Screening of Anti-inflammatory and Analgesic Activity of Cassia grandis Linn. Acadademic Journal Plant Sciences 2(1):51-55.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Meena MK, Pal SC, Jain AK, Jain CP, Ashawat MS, Gaur K, Jain A (2010). Comparative study on physicochemical variation for different samples of Cassia grandis Linn. Leaves. African Journal Plant Science 4(7):261-267.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mosmann T (1983). Rapid colorimetric assay for cellular growth and survival: Aplication to proliferation and cytotoxicity assays. Journal of Immunological Methods 65(1-2):55-63.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Parra AL, Sardias MIG (2000). Toxicidadade aguda oral de 3 formas farmacuticas a partir de Cassia grandis L.. Revista Cubana Planat Medicinales 5(2):68-70.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pivatto M, Crotti AEM, Lopes NP, Castro-Gamboa I, Rezende A, Viegas Jr. C, Young MCM, Furlan M, Bolzani VS (2005). Electrospray Ionization Mass Spectrometry Screening of Piperidine Alkaloids from Senna spectabilis (Fabaceae) Extracts: Fast Identification of New Constituents and Co metabolites. Journal of the Brazilian Chemical Society 16(6B):1431-1438.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Prada AL, Amado JRR, Arranz JCE, Laurido FC (2014). State of the art in Cassia grandis L.f. (Caandonga). Revista Cubana Planat Medicinales 19(1):21-28.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Prada AL, Amado JRR, Keita H, Zapata EP, Carvalho H, Lima ES, De Sousa TP, Carvalho JCT (2018). Cassia grandis fruit extract reduces the blood glucose level in alloxan-induce diabetic rats. Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy 103:421-428.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Prieto P, Pineda M, Aguilar M (1999). Spectrophotometric quantitation of antioxidant capacity through the formation of a phosphomolybdenium complex: specific application to the determination of vitamin E. Analytical Biochemistry 269(2):337-341.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Proestos C, Chorianopoulos N, Nychas GJE, Komaitis M (2005). RP-CLAE Analysis of the phenolics compounds of plant extracts. Investigation of their antioxidant capacity and antimicrobial activity. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 53(4):1190-1195.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Regasini LO, Pivatto M, Scorzoni L, Benaducci T, Fusco-Almeida AM, Giannini MJ, Barreiro EJ, Siva DH, Bolzani VD (2010). Antimicrobial activity of Pterogyne nitens Tul., Fabaceae, against opportunistic fungi. Brazilian Journal Pharmacognosy 20(5):706-711.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Singh M, Pandey N, Agnihotri V, Singh KK, Pandey A (2017). Antioxidant, antimicrobial activity and bioactive compounds of Bergenia ciliata Sternb.: A valuable medicinal herb of Sikkim Himalaya. Journal of Traditional Complementary Medicine 7(2):152-157.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Stein S, Mallard G, Levitsky A (1997). NIST MS Library Database. National Institute of Standards and Technology.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sundarraj S, Thangama R, sreevani V, Kaveri K, Gunasekaran P, Achiraman S, Kannan S (2012). -Sitosterol from Acacia nilotica L. induces G2/M cell cycle arrest and apoptosis through c-Myc suppression in MCF-7 and A549 cells. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 141(3):803-809.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Viegas Junior C, Rezende A, Silva DHS, Castro-Gamboa I, Bolzani VS (2006). Ethnopharmacological, biological and chemical aspects of the Cassia genus. Qumica Nova 29(6):1279-1286.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Woisky RG, Salatino A (1998). Analysis of propolis: some parameters and procedures for chemical quality control. Journal of Apicultural Research 37(2):99-105.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wangchuk P, Pearson MS, Giacomin PR, Becker L, Sotillo J, Pickering D, Smout MJ, Loukas A (2016). Compounds Derived from the Bhutanese Daisy, Ajania nubigena, Demonstrate Dual Anthelmintic Activity against Schistosoma mansoni and Trichuris muris. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases 10 (8).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>