<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0875</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JMPR2019.6841</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Biological properties and therapeutic applications of cannabidiol]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Elanne</surname>
            <given-names>Costa Glria</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Adriana</surname>
            <given-names>Idalina Torcato de Oliveira</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Juliana</surname>
            <given-names>Fonseca Moreira da Silva</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Raphael</surname>
            <given-names>Sanzio Pimenta</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">ecgalimentos@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>14</day>
			<month>09</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>07</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>283</fpage>
	  <lpage>291</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/1690A3D63559">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/1690A3D63559	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/1690A3D63559">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/1690A3D63559	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Cannabis sp. has important pharmacological activities, so it has been the focus of attention of the scientific community. Through the search for new drugs, it was found that cannabinoids present in the plant can modulate transient potential receptors (TPR). Cannabidiol (CBD), also known as ldquo;medical marijuanardquo;, represents the second most abundant phytocannabinoid of the Cannabis plant and it is widely used in the management of pain, nausea and migraine in cancer patients. In fact, CBD exhibits various therapeutic effects and constitutes up to 40% of Cannabis extracts and it is devoid of the typical psychological effects of Cannabis used in social use as a psychoactive drug, and has low affinity for endocannabinoid receptors CB1 and CB2. Thus, this article aims to conduct an integrative review of CBD and its potential benefits for human health. The results of this research confirmed CBD therapeutic actions in diseases such as schizophrenia, anxiety, epilepsy and motor disorders such as Parkinson#39;s disease, Alzheimer#39;s disease, multiple sclerosis, neuropathic pain, childhood convulsive disorders, Lennox-Gastaut and Dravet syndromes. Thus, cannabidiol has an important relevance for medical applications and also has anti-inflammatory, antioxidant, anticonvulsant, anxiolytic, neuroprotective, antipsychotic, antiemetic, analgesic and antibiotic activities.

	Key words: Medical marijuana, cannabinoids, Cannabidiol (CBD), medicinal use.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Alledrone G, Pollastro F, Magagini G, Taglialatela-scafati O, Seegers J, Koeberle A, Werz O, Appendino G (2017). The bibenzyl canniprene inhibits the production of pro-inflammatory eicosanoids and selectively accumulates in some Cannabis sativa strains. Journal of Natural Products 80(3):731-734.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Andre CM, Hausman JF, Guerriero G (2016). Cannabis sativa: The plant of the Thousand and one molecules. Frontiers in Plant Science 7(19):1-17.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Basavarajappa BS (2017). Chapter 2 - Cannabinoid Receptors and their Signaling Mechanisms. In: Rodrguez EM, The Endocannabinoid System. Genetics, Biochemistry, Brain Disorders, and Therapy. pp. 25-62.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Beale C, Broyd SJ, Chye Y, Suo C, Schira M, Galettis P, Martin JH, Yuce M, Solowiji N (2018). Prolonged Cannabidiol Treatment Effects on Hippocampal Subfield Volumes in Current Cannabis Users. Cannabis and Cannabinoid Research 3(1):94-107.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Begg M, Pacher P, Batkai S, Osei-hyiaman D, Offertler L, Mo FM, Liu J, Kunos (2005). Evidence of new cannabinoid receptors. Pharmacology and Therapeutics 106(2):133-145.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Crippa JA, Guimares FS, Campos AC, Zuardi AW (2018). Translational investigation of the therapeutic potential of Cannabidiol (CBD): Toward a New Age. Frontiers of Immunology, 9:2009.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hua T, Vemuri K, Pu M, Qu L, Han GW, Wu Y, Zhao S, Shui W, Li S, Korde A, Laprairie RB, Stahl E, Ho JH, Zvonok N, Zhou H, Kufareva I, Wu B, Zhao Q, Hanson MA, Bohn LM, Makriyannis A, Stevens RC, Liu ZJ (2016). Crystal structure of the Human Cannabinoid Receptor CB1. Cell 167(3):750-762.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jiang R, Yamaori S, Okamoto Y, Yamamoto I, Watanabe K (2013). Cannabidiol is a potent inhibitor of the Catalytic Activity of Cytochrome P4502C19. Drug Metabolism and Pharmacokinetics 28(4):332-338.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumar KK, Shalev-benami M, Robertson M, Hu H, Banister SD, Hollingsworth SA, Latorraca NR, Kato HE, Hilger D, Maeda S, Weis WI, Farrens DL, Dror RO, Malhotra SV, Kobilka BK, Skiniotis G (2019). Structure of a Signaling Cannabinoid Receptor 1-G Protein Complex. Cell 176(3):448-458.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lorenzen E, Sakmar TP (2019). Receptor Structures for a Caldron of Cannabinoids. Cell 176(3):409-411.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maroon J, Bost J (2018). Review of the neurological benefits of phytocannabinoids. Surgical Neurology International 9:91.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Massi P, Solinas M, Cinquina V, Parolaro D (2013.) Cannabidiol as potential anticancer drug. British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology 75(2):303-312.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Matsuda LA, Lolait SJ, Brownsten M, Young AC, Bonner TI (1990). Structure of a cannabinoid receptor and functional expression of cloned cDNA. Nature 346:561-564.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Muller C, Morales P, Reggio PH (2019). Cannabinoid Ligands Targeting TRP Channels. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience 11:487.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Munro S, Thomas KL, Abu-shaar M (1993). Molecular characterization of a peripheral cannabinoid receptor. Nature 365(6441):61-65.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pertwee RG (2008). The diverse CB1 and CB2 receptor pharmacology of three plant cannabinoids: ∆9-tetrahydrocannabinol, cannabidiol and ∆9 -tetrahydrocannabivarin. British Journal of Pharmacology 153(2):199-215.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Perucca E (2017). Cannabinoids in the Treatment of Epilepsy: Hard Evidence at Last? Journal of Epilepsy Research 7(2):60-76.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pellati F, Brighenti V, Sperlea JI, Marchetti L, Bertelli D, Benvenutri S (2018). New Methods for the Comprehensive Analysis of Bioactive Compounds in Cannabis sativa L. (hemp). Molecules 23(10):2639.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Pollastro F, Minassi A, Fresu LG 2018. Cannabis phenolics and their bioactivities. Current Medicinal Chemistry 25(10):1160-1185.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Romero-Sandoval EA, Fincham JE, Kolano AL, Sharpe BN, Alvarado-Vzquez PA (2018). Cannabis for Chronic Pain: Challenges and Considerations. Pharmacotherapy: The Journal of Human Pharmacology and Drug Therapy 38(6):651-662.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wertz O, Seegers J, Schaible AM, Barz D, Koeberle A, Allegroned G, Pollastro F, Zampieri L, Grassi G, Appendino G (2014). Cannflavins from hemp sprouts, a novel cannabinoid-free hemp food product, target microsomal prostaglandin E2 synthase-1 and 5-lipoxygenase. Pharma Nutrition 2(3):53-60.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Whittermore R, Knafl K (2005). The integrative review: updated methodology. Journal of Clinical Nursing 52(5):546-553.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zendulka O, Dovrtelov G, Noskov K, Turjap M, Sulcov A, Hanus L, Jurica J. (2016). Cannabinoids and Cytochrome P450 Interactions. Current Drug Metabolism 17(3):206-226.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>