<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1996-0875</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JMPR2019.6838</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Control of papaya fruits anthracnose by essential oils of medicinal plants associated to different coatings]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Talita</surname>
            <given-names>Pereira de Souza Ferreira</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ped</surname>
            <given-names>ro Raym undo Argiielles Osorio</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Rosangela</surname>
            <given-names>Ribeiro de Sousa</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Felipe</surname>
            <given-names>Rocha Dias</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Dalmarcia</surname>
            <given-names>de Souza Carlos Mou rao</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Mateus</surname>
            <given-names>Sunti Dakin</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Priscila</surname>
            <given-names>Fonseca Costa</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Bruna</surname>
            <given-names>Leticia Dias</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Fabricio</surname>
            <given-names>Souza Campos</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Gil</surname>
            <given-names>Rod rigues Dos Santos</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">gilrsan@uft.edu.br</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>06</day>
			<month>09</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>31</day>
			<month>10</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>14</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
	  	  <fpage>239</fpage>
	  <lpage>246</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5BF161663528">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5BF161663528	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/5BF161663528">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-full-text-pdf/5BF161663528	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Chemical pesticides have been commonly used for the control of various plant diseases. Although pathogens can be controlled with the application of these products, there are hazardous impacts in human health and environment. In parallel, essential oils have been shown to be effective in plant diseases management and can be safely incorporated as suitable alternatives for synthetic fungicides. Therefore, the aim of this study was to evaluate the control of papaya fruits anthracnose by different essential oils associated with different coatings. In vitro evaluation of essential oils was carried out to conidial germination and mycelial growth of Colletotrichum gloeosporioides. Quantification of anthracnose and fruits fresh mass loss was also performed for all treatments. Rosemary pepper and Noni essential oils were the most effective in reducing conidia germination and mycelial growth of C. gloeosporioides. The application of essential oils associated with different coatings was as effective as the chemical control, in inhibiting the growth of the pathogen in 100%. Moreover, papaya fruits treated with the mixture of paraffin and essential oils reduced in 7% the fruits fresh mass loss infected with the fungus. These combinations are a promising alternative to chemicals to control anthracnose, a major postharvest disease on papaya during storage.

	Key words: Colletotrichum gloeosporioides, alternative control, post-harvest, weight loss.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adams RP (2007). Identification of Essential Oil Components by Gas Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry. CarolStream: Allured Publishing Corporation, p. 4.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aguiar RWS, Ootani MA, Ascencio S, Ferreira TPS, Santos MM, Santos GR (2014). Fumigant Antifungal Activity of Corymbia citriodora and Cymbopogon nardus Essential Oils and Citronellal against Three Fungal Species. The Scientific World Journal Volume 2014, Article ID 492138, pp. 1-8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amarante CVT, Steffens CA, Beninc TDT, Hackbarth C, Santos KL (2013). Fruit quality and postharvest conservation potential in Brazilian guava-serrana cultivars. Revista Brasileira de Fruticultura 35(4):990-999.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Barman K, Patel VB, Sharma S, Singh RR (2017). Effect of chitosan coating on postharvest diseases and fruit quality of mango (Mangifera indica). Indian Journal of Agricultural Sciences 87(5):618-23.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Campbell CL, Madden LV (1990). Introduction to plant disease epidemiology. 1. ed. New York: John Wiley  Sons. 532 p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Carnelossi PR, Schwan-Estrada KRF, Cruz MES, Itako AT, Mesquini RM (2009). ). Essential oils for postharvest control of Colletotrichum gloeosporioides in papaya. Brazilian Journal of Medicinal Plants 11(4):399-406.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Castro DM, Ming LC, Marques MOM (2002). Phytochemical composition of leaf essential oils of Lippia alba (Mill.) N.E.Br. at different harvest times and parts of the branch. Brazilian Journal of Medicinal Plants 4(2):75-79.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Costa JGM, Rodrigues FFG, Anglico EC, Silva MR, Mota ML, Santos NKA, Cardoso ALH, Lemos TLG (2005). Chemical-biological study of the essential oils of Hyptis martiusii, Lippia sidoides and Syzigium aromaticum against larvae of Aedes aegypti and Culex quinquefasciatus. Revista Brasileira de Farmacognosia 15(4):304-309.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cunico MM, Miguel OG, Miguel MD, Carvalho JLS, Peitz C, Auer CG, Grigoletti Jnior A (2003). Study of the antifungal activity of Ottonia martiana Miq., Piperaceae: an in vivo test. Academic Vision 4(2):77-82.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dalcin MS, Caf-Filho AC, Sarmento RA, Nascimento IR, Ferreira TPS, Aguiar WSS, Santos GR (2017). Evaluation of essential oils for preventive or curative management of melon gummy stem blight and plant toxicity. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 6(5):426-432.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dantas SAF, Oliveira SMA, Michereff SJ, Nascimento LC, Gurgel LMS, Pessoa WRLS (2003). Postharvest fungal diseases in papayas and oranges sold at the Recife Supply Center. Brazilian Plant Pathology 28(5):528-533.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Dunn LL, Harness ML, Smith DM, Gorman SJ, Zhong Q, Davidson P M, Critzer FJ (2019). Essential Oil Emulsions as Postharvest Sanitizers To Mitigate Salmonella Cross-Contamination on Peppers. Journal of Food Protection 82(1):159-163.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Evangelista RM, Gouveia MAS, Corra CV, Cardoso AII (2014). Use of edible films and gelatin in the preservation of Sweet grape mini organic tomato fruits. Iberoamerican Journal of Technology Postcosecha 15(2):168-176.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ferreira DF (2014). Sisvar: a Guide for its Bootstrap procedures in multiple comparisons. Cincia e Agrotecnologia 38(2):109-112.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gonalves AH, Pereira AS, Santos GRS, Guimares LGL (2015). Fungitoxicity in vitro of essential oils from Lippia sidoides Cham., Cymbopogon citratus (D.C.) Stapf. and their major constituents in the control of Rhizoctonia solani and Sclerotium rolfsii. Revista Brasileira de Plantas Medicinais 17(4):1007-1015.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Guanhyao H, Bincheng L, Chengyin L, Youjin Y, Bo X, XI C, Jianzhong Z (2019). Plant extracts inhibit postharvest pathogens on hot pepper and induces Rhizopus resistance. Shipin Kexue / Food Science 40(9):234-240.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Habashi RT, Zomorodi S, Talaie A, Jari SK (2019). Effects of chitosan coating enriched with thyme essential oil and packaging methods on a postharvest quality of Persian walnut under cold storage. Foods and Raw Materials 7(1):18-25.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hossain MS, Iqbal A (2016) Effect of shrimp chitosan coating on postharvest quality of banana (Musa sapientum L.) fruits. International Food Research Journal 23(1):277-283.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[IBGE. Instituto Brasileiro de Geografia e Estatstica (2016).
				
					View
			
		
		
			
				
		
		
			
				
					Junqueira NTV, Chaves RC, Nascimento AC, Ramos VHV, Peixoto JR, Junqueira LP (2004). Effect of soybean oil on anthracnose control and mango conservation cv. Palmer postharvest. Brazilian Journal of Fruit 26 (2):222-225.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jongsri P, Wangsomboondee T, Rojsitthisak P, Seraypheap K (2016). Effect of molecular weights of chitosan coating on postharvest quality and physicochemical characteristics of mango fruit. LWT 73:28-36.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kimati H, amorim L, Rezende JAM, Bergamin Filho A, Camargo LEA (2005). Manual de Fitopatologia: doenas das plantas cultivadas. 4. ed. So Paulo: Agronmica Ceres 2:663.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Liberato JR, Zambolim L. Control of diseases caused by fungi, phytonmathoid bacteria and papaya. In: Zambolim L, Vale FXR, Monteiro AJA, Costa H (2002) 1. ed. Fruit Plant Disease Control. Viosa, Federal University of Viosa 1:1023-1169.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maia FGM, Armesto C, Maia JB, Abreu MS (2011). Effect of temperature on mycelial growth, conidial production and germination of Colletotrichum spp. isolated from mango with anthracnose symptoms. Bioscience Journal 27(2):205-210.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Muazu SA, Channya FK, Chimbekujwo IB, Basiri B, Zakari BG, Tukur KU, Fauziya KM, Samuel KB (2018). Antifungal Activity of Garlic (Allium sativum) Essential Oil and Wood Ash against Post-harvest Fruit Rot of Banana (Musa acuminata L.) in Yola, Adamawa State, Nigeria. International Journal of Plant and Soil Science 24(6):1-10.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Oliveira KR, Conceio ML, Oliveira SPA, Lima MS, Sousa Galvo M, Madruga MS, Magnani M, Souza EL (2019). Postharvest quality improvements in mango cultivar Tommy Atkins by chitosan coating with Mentha piperita L. essential oil. The Journal of Horticultural Science and Biotechnology 2019:1-13.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Osorio PRA, Leo EU, Veloso RA, Mouro DSC, Santos GR (2018). Essential oils for alternative teak rust control. Floresta e Ambiente 25(2).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Palou L, Ali A, Fallik E, Romanazzi G (2016). GRAS, plant- and animal-derived compounds as alternatives to conventional fungicides for the control of postharvest diseases of fresh horticultural produce. Postharvest Biology and Technology 122:41-52.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Price CL, Parker JE, Warrilow AG, Kelly DE, Kelly SL (2015). Azole fungicides - understanding resistance mechanisms in agricultural fungal pathogens. Pest Management Science 71(8):1054-1058.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sahoo KS, Dhal NK, Sahoo SL, Lenka SS (2012). Comparative phytochemical and antimicrobial study of Morinda pubescens Sm. and Morinda citrifolia L. International Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences 4(3):425-429.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sarmento-Brum RBC, Castro HG, Silva ML, Sarmento RA, Nascimento IR, Santos GR (2014a). Effect of vegetable oils on mycelial growth inhibition of phytopathogenic fungi. Journal of Biotechnology and Biodiversity 5(1):63-70.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sarmento-Brum RBC, Castro HG, Cardon CH, Pereira AS, Cardoso DP, Santos GR (2014). Antifungal activity of essential oils on phytopathogenic fungi. Magistra 26(3):365-375.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Schwan-Estrada KRF, Stangarlin JR (2005). Extracts and essential oils of medicinal plants in resistance induction. In: Cavalcanti LS, Di Piero RM, Cia P, et al. Induction of resistance in plants to pathogens and insects. Piracicaba: Fealqp: 125-32.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Stangarlin JR, Schwan-Estrada KRF (2008). Control of plant diseases by plant extracts. Annual Plant Pathology Review 16:265-304.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Stangarlin JR, Schwan-Estrada KRF, Cruz MES, Nozaki MH (1999). Medicinal plants and alternative control of phytopathogens. Biotechnology Science and Development 2(11):16-24.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Zillo RR, Silva PPM, Oliveira J, Glria EM, Spoto MHF (2018). Carboxymethylcellulose coating associated with essential oil can increase papaya shelf life. Scientia Horticulturae 239:70-77.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>