<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Plant Breeding and Crop Science</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2006-9758</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JPBCS2019.0860</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Selection of drought tolerant genotypes in groundnut (Arachis hypogaea L.) using indices]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Ousmane</surname>
            <given-names>Sanogo</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Pangirayi</surname>
            <given-names>B. Tongoona</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Kwadwo</surname>
            <given-names>Ofori</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Haile</surname>
            <given-names>Desmae</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">ouzbi777@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>28</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>21</day>
			<month>04</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>12</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>146</fpage>
	  <lpage>155</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/65D45BD63825">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/65D45BD63825	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-full-text-pdf/65D45BD63825">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-full-text-pdf/65D45BD63825	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[A study was carried out to evaluate the effect of drought stress on pod yield and other traits of groundnut genotypes to select the ten best performing genotypes using indices. Ninety six genotypes including 90 F2:3 progenies, 4 parents and 2 checks were planted under well-watered (WW) and water-stressed (WS) conditions at the International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics ICRISAT, Mali. Six selection indices including mean productivity (MP), tolerance (TOL), geometric mean productivity (GMP), stress tolerance index (STI), drought tolerance index (DTI) and reduction (%) (RED) were used. The indices were adjusted based on pod yield under WW and WS conditions. High DTI, STI, MP, and GMP values under both well-watered and water-stressed conditions were more effective in identifying high yielding cultivars under water limited conditions. Based on these indices, the F2:3 progenies ICGV-IS 13012F2-B1-297, ICGV-IS 13012F2-B1-40, ICGV-IS 13005F2-B1-46, ICGV-IS 13005F2-B1-252, ICGV-IS 13012F2-B1-29, ICGV-IS 13005F2-B1-205, ICGV-IS 13005F2-B1-287, ICGV-IS 13012F2-B1-525, ICGV-IS 13012F2-B1-576 and ICGV-IS 13005F2-B1-91 were identified as the most drought tolerant genotypes with high yield stability in the well-watered and drought stress conditions. The indices STI, MP and GMP were positively correlated with pod yield under WW and WS conditions and breeding for drought tolerance.

	Key words: Groundnut, breeding, selection indices, drought stress.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Allahdou M (2012). Evaluation of resistance to drought in Tritipyrum lines using drought tolerance indices. International Research Journal for Applied and Basic Science 3(3):461-465.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anwar J, Subhani GM, Hussain M, Ahmad J, Hussain M, Munir M (2011). Drought tolerance indices and their correlation with yield in exotic wheat genotypes. Pakistan Journal of Botany 43(3):1527-1530.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Blum A (1996).Crop responses to drought and the interpretation of adaptation. Plant Growth Regulation 20:135-148.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Choukan R, Taherkhani T, Ghannadha MR, Khodarahmi M (2006). Evaluation of drought tolerance in grain maize inbred lines using drought tolerance indices. Iran Journal of Agricultural Science 8(1):79-89.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Debrah SK, Waliyar F (1998). Groundnut production and utilization in West Africa: Past trends, projections, and opportunities for increased production. In: Proceedings of the Fifth Regional Groundnut Workshop for Western and Central Africa, 18-21 Nov 1996, Accra, Ghana (in En, Fr) International Arachis Newsletter no.18. (Eds. Waliyar, F. and Umeh, V.C.).Supplement. 82pp. Andra Pradesh, India: ICRISAT. ISSN 1010-5824.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[FAOSTAT (2015). Statistical Database of the Food and Agriculture of the United Nations.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fernandez GCJ (1992). Effective selection criteria for assessing plant stress tolerance. In: Proceedings of the international symposium on adaptation of vegetable and other food crops in temperature and water stress. - Taiwan, pp. 257-270.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hossain AB, Sears AG, Cox TS, Paulsen GM (1990).Desiccation tolerance and its relationship to assimilate partitioning in winter wheat. Crop Science 30:622-627.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Jafari A, Paknejad F, AL-Ahmadi MJ (2009). Evaluation of selection indices for drought tolerance of corn (Zea mays L.) hybrids. International Journal of Plant Production 3(4):1735-8043.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Karimizadeh R, Mohammadi M, Ghaffaripour S, Karimpour F, Shefazadeh MK (2011). Evaluation of physiological screening techniques for drought-resistant breeding of durum wheat genotypes in Iran. African Journal of Biotechnology 10(56):12107-12117.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Nautiyal PC, NageswaraRao RC, Joshi YC (2002). Moisture-deficit-induced changes in leaf-water content, leaf carbon exchange rate and biomass production in groundnut cultivars differing in specific leaf area. Field Crops Research 74:67-79.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Porch TG (2006). Application of Stress Indices for Heat Tolerance Screening of Common Bean. Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science 192:390-394.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Raman A, Verulkar SB, Mandal NP, MukundVariar M, Shukla VD, Dwivedi JL, Singh BN, Singh O.N, Swain P, Mall A (2012). Drought yield index to select high yielding rice lines under different drought stress severities. Rice 5:31.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SAS Institute (2009). SAS Proprietary Software Release 9.3. SAS Institute, Inc., Cary, NC.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sio-Se MA, Ahmadi A, Poustini K, Mohammadi V (2006). Evaluation of drought resistance indices under various environmental conditions. Field Crop Research 98:222-229.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Talebi R, Fayaz F, Naji AM (2009). Effective selection criteria for assessing drought stress tolerance in durum wheat (Triticum durumDesf.). General and Applied Plant Physiology 35(1-2):64-74.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>