<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Public Health and Epidemiology</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-2316</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JPHE2019.1171</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Association of glycaemia control, age and duration of morbidity with the quality of life in patients of type 2 diabetes mellitus attending the tertiary care hospital in field practice area of Ottapalam Palakad]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Arjit</surname>
            <given-names>Kumar</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Singh</surname>
            <given-names>Amit Kumar</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">drarjitkumar@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>14</day>
			<month>08</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>15</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>12</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>136</fpage>
	  <lpage>141</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/5E47EF963848">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/5E47EF963848	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-full-text-pdf/5E47EF963848">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-full-text-pdf/5E47EF963848	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Diabetes is a chronic progressive endocrine disease characterized by elevation of blood glucose level. This disease is associated with decreased life expectancy; increased morbidity and diminished quality of life. The objective of the study is to assess the correlation of glycaemic control, age and duration of disease with quality of life in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus.  The present cross-sectional study was conducted in 200 patients (100 each from rural and urban centers), at field practice area of Department of Community Medicine, P.K.DAS, Pallakad. The study was conducted with the help of pretested, semi-structured questionnaire. Data were entered in Microsoft Excel and analysis was done with IBM SPSS (Statistical Package for Social Sciences) version 21. In the present study, 42% of the participants were in the age group of 61 to 70 years. Amongst them, 55.5% were males and about 24% of the participants have had the disease for the past 11 to 15 years. Males had higher quality of life (QOL) scores than females. QOL scores were also higher in participants of rural areas, without any complications/co-morbidities who were employed and with HbA1c level less than 7. Scores were minimum for the participants belonging to the age group of gt;70 years and of upper socio-economic class. Poor QOL was associated with increasing age, duration of disease and poor glycaemic control.

	Key words: Type 2 diabetes mellitus, quality of life, HbA1c.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Akinci F, Yildirim A, Gz H, Sargın H, Orbay E, Sargın M (2008). Assessment of health-related quality of life (HRQoL) of patients with type 2 diabetes in Turkey. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice 79(1):117-123.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Algaonker SS (1972). Diabetes mellitus as seen in Ancient Ayurvedic Medicine. In: Bajaj AS, editor. Insulin and Metabolism. Bombay (India): Indian Press, p. 1-19.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anumol M A, Anusree T, Aparna M A, Archana S, Athira M, Sachina B, Gireesh G (2014). Quality Of Life Among Type-Ii Diabetes Mellitus Patients In South India: A Descriptive Study. American International Journal of Research in Humanities, Arts and Social Sciences 2(7):197-200.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chawla A, Chawla R, Jaggi S (2016). Microvasular and macrovascular complications in diabetes mellitus: Distinct or continuum? Indian Journal of Endocrinology and Metabolism 20(4):546‐551.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Farquhar M (1995). Definitions of quality of life: taxonomy. The Journal of Advanced Nursing . Journal of Advanced Nursing22(3):502-5088
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kamarul Imran M, Ismail AA, Naing L, Wan Mohamad WB (2010). Type 2 diabetes mellitus patients with poor glycaemic control have lower quality of life scores as measured by the Short Form-36. Singapore Medical Journal 51(2):157-162.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumar A, Goel MK, Jain RB, Khanna P, Chaudhary V (2013). India towards diabetes control: Key issues. Australasian Medical Journal 6(10):524-531.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Laios K, Karamanou M, Saridaki Z, Androutsos G (2012). Aretaeus of Cappadocia and the first description of diabetes. Hormones 11(1):109-113.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[MacCracken J, Hoel D (1997). From ants to analogues: Puzzles and promises in diabetes management. Postgraduate Medical Journal 101:138-140. 143-145, 149-150.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[McGrew RE (1985). Encyclopedia of Medical history. 1st ed. London, (United Kingdom): McMillam Press, p. 74-297.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[NCD (1980). Risk Factor Collaboration (NCD-RisC). Worldwide trends in diabetes since 1980: a pooled analysis of 751 population-based studies with 4*4 million participants. Lancet 2016]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Papadopoulos A, Kontodimopoulos N, Frydas A, Ikonomakis E, Niakas D (2007). Predictors of health-related quality of life in type II diabetic patients in Greece. BMC Public Health 7(1).
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sen BC (1893). Diabetes mellitus. Paper presented at the Sixth Calcutta Medical Society meeting. The Indian Medical Gazette 28:240]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Seuring T, Archangelidi O, Suhrcke M (2015). The economic costs of type 2 diabeteseglobal systematic review. Pharmaco Economics 33(8): 811-831.8.36-Item Short Form Survey (SF-36) | RAND [Internet]. Rand.org. 2008 [cited 23 September 2016].
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Spasić A, Radovanović R, Đorđević A, Stefanović N, Cvetković T (2014). Quality of Life in Type 2 Diabetic Patients. Acta Facultatis Medicae Naissensis 31(3):193-200.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Thommasen HV, Zhang W (2006). Impact of chronic disease on quality of life in the Bella Coola Valley. Rural and Remote Health 6:528]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>