<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Soil Science and Environmental Management</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-2391</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JSSEM2019.0795</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Validation of blended NPSB fertilizer rates on yield, yield components of Teff [Eragrostis tef (Zuccagni) Trotter] at vertisols of Hatsebo, Central Tigray, Ethiopia]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Tewolde</surname>
            <given-names>Berhe</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Gebreyohannes</surname>
            <given-names>Girmay</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Abrha</surname>
            <given-names>Kidanemariam</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">tewolde2004@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>30</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>08</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>11</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>75</fpage>
	  <lpage>86</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/4F6A1D363827">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/4F6A1D363827	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-full-text-pdf/4F6A1D363827">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-full-text-pdf/4F6A1D363827	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Application of unbalanced nutrition was the main yield limiting factor in the study area. Hence, an experiment was conducted during the 2017 cropping season on farmersrsquo; fields to validate and determine optimum blended fertilizer rate for teff production. Eight levels of NPSB (0, 25, 50, 100, 150, 200, 250 and 300 kg ha-1) and recommended NP (100 kg ha-1 urea and 100 kg ha-1TSP) were used as treatments and set in randomized complete block design with three replications. All the fertilizers were applied at planting but nitrogen was top dressed in two time split. Surface soil samples was collected before teff sowing and after harvest; with total nitrogen, available phosphorus, extractable sulfur and boron found to be at low level. Application of different blended NPSB fertilizer rates significantly affected crop phonology, yield and yield components of teff. Highest mean teff grain yield (2803.09 kg ha-1) was obtained in response to 250 kg ha-1NPSB with 62.5 and 33.4% yield increment over the control and recommended NP. Similarly, the highest straw yield was also obtained from plot treated with that rate and it has 80 and 44.4% yield increment over the control and the recommended NP, respectively. The partial budget analysis also revealed that marginal rate of return was highest (1179.5%) at a rate of 250 kg ha-1NPSB+46 kg N ha-1 from which better biomass and economic advantage was attained. Hence it could be concluded that it is possible for optimum teff yield to be attained using 250 kg ha-1NPSB+46 kg N ha-1.

	Key words: Eragrostis tef, blended fertilizer, yield components, NP fertilizer, Laelay Maichew.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abdo W (2009). Effect of different rates of nitrogen fertilizer on yield, yield related traits and Quality of durum wheat (TriticumturgidumL.var durum). M.Sc. Thesis, Haramaya University, Haramaya, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Agricultural Transformation Agency, ATA (2014). Soil Fertility Status and Fertilizer Recommendation Atlas for Tigray Regional State; Ethiopia July 2014.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Amsal T, Tanner D (2001). Effect of fertilizer application on N and P uptake, recovery and use efficiency of bread wheat grown on two soil types in central Ethiopia. Ethiopian Journal of Natural Resources 3(2):219-244.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Assefa A, Tana T, Abdulahi J (2016). Effects of Compost and Inorganic NP Rates on Growth, Yield and Yield Components of Teff (Eragrotis teff (Zucc.) Trotter) in Girar Jarso District, Central Highland of Ethiopia. Journal of Fertilizer and Pesticides 7:174.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Berger KC, Truog E (1939). Boron determination in soils and plants. Industrial and Engineering Chemistry Analytical Edition 11(10):540-545
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Berhanu D (1985).The Vertisols of Ethiopia Their properties, classification and management. 5th Meeting of the Eastern African Soil Correlation and Land Evaluation Sub-Committee, 4-10 December 1983, Wad Medani Sudan. World Soil Resources Report 56.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Caldicott JJB, Nuttall AM (1979). A method for the assessment of lodging in crops. Netherland Journal of Agricultural Botany (15):88-91.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Central statistical agency (CSA) (2017). Agricultural sample survey for the 2016/2017 crop season. Volume I Report on Area and production of major Crops private peasant holdings, Statistical bulletin, FDRE/CSA, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[CIMMYT (1988). From Agronomic Data to Farmer Recommendations: An Economics Training Manual. Completely revised edition, Mexico. D.F conference held at International Livestock Centre for Africa (ILCA), 31 August - 4 September 1987.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[EMSA (Ethiopian metrological service agency) Tigray regional state branch (2017). Climatic data report of ten year for central zone of Tigray.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ethiopian Soil Information System (EthioSIS) (2015).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ethiopian Soil Information System (EthioSIS) (2014). Soil Analysis Report. Agricultural Transformation Agency (Unpublished).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fageria NK, Baligar VC, Jones CA (2011). Growth and Mineral Nutrition of Field Crops. 3rd Edn., Taylor Francis Group, New York, 530 p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fayera A, Adugna D, Muktar M (2014). Evaluation of Teff [Eragrostistef (Zuccagni) Trotter] Responses to Different Rates of NPK Along With Zn and B in Didessa District, Southwestern Ethiopia. World Applied Sciences Journal 32(11):2245-2249.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fenta A (2018). Effect of tef variety and rates of nitrogen fertilizer application on growth and yield components under Jimma condition. ARPN Journal of Agricultural and Biological science 13(3):34-42 ISSN 1990-6145.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) (2014). Guidelines for soil description. 5th edition. Rome.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) (2008). FAO fertilizer and plant nutrition bulletin: Guide to laboratory establishment for plant nutrient analysis, FAO, Rome, Italy. 203p.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Getahun D, Dereje A, Tigist AA Bekele A (2018). Response of Yield and Yield Components of Tef [Eragrostis Tef (Zucc.) Trotter] to Optimum Rates of Nitrogen and Phosphorus Fertilizer Rate Application in Assosa Zone, Benishangul Gumuz Region. Ethiopian Journal of Agricultural Sciences 28(1) 81-94]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gomez KA, Gomez AA (1984). Statistical analysis for agricultural research. John Willy and Sons Inc. pp. 120-155.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Haftamu G, Mitiku H, Charles FY (2009). Tillage Frequency, Soil Compaction and N-Fertilizer Rate Effects on Yield of Tef [Eragrostis Tef (Zucc) Trotter] in Central Zone of Tigray, Northern Ethiopia Thesis presented to Mekelle University Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Haftom G, Mitiku H, Yamoah CH (2009). Tillage frequency, soil compaction and N-fertilizer rate effects on yield of tef [Eragrostis tef (Zucc.) Trotter]. Ethiopia. Journal of Science 1(1):82-94.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hailu T, Seifu K (2001). Production and Importance of Teff in Ethiopian Agriculture. In: HailuTeffera, Getachew Belay and Mark Sorrells (eds).Narrowing the Rift: Teff Research and Development. Proceedings of the International Workshop on Teff Genetics and Improvement, 16-19 October 2000, DebreZeit, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hazelton P, Murphy B (2007). Interpreting soil test results: What do all the numbers mean? 2nd Edition.CSIRO Publishing 152p.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hirpa T, Gebrekidan H, Tesfaye K, Hailemariam A (2009). Biomass and. nutrient accumulation of green manuring legumes terminated at different growth stages. East African Journal of Sciences 3:18-28
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Holford ICR, Cullis BR (1985). . (1985a). Effects of phosphate buffer capacity on yield response curvature and fertilizer requirements of wheat in relation to soil phosphate tests. Australian Journal of Soil Research 23(3):417-427
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[IFPRI (2010). Fertilizers and soil fertility potential in Ethiopia: Constraint and opportunities for enhancing the system, working paper, Washington.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ketema S (1991). Germplasm evaluation and breeding work on tef (Eragrostis tef) in Ethiopia. In: Plant Genetic Resources of Ethiopia 323-328. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, New York Port Chester.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lal R (1979). Physical characteristics of soils of the tropics: determination and management. In: R. Lal and D.J. Greenland (eds.) Soil Physical Properties and Crop Production in tropics. John Wiley  Sons, New York, pp. 7-44.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Landon JR (1991). Booker Tropical Soil Manual: A hand book for soil survey and Agricultural Land Evaluation in the Tropics and Subtropics. Longman Scientific and Technical, Essex, New York.474p. OR John Wiley  Sons Inc., New York.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lawrence JR, Ketterings QM, Cherney JH (2008). Effect of nitrogen application on yield and quality of corn. Agronomy Journal 100 (1):73-79.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Legesse A (2004). Response of teff [Eragrostis tef (Zucc.) Trotter] to applied nitrogen and phosphorus in Sirinka, North Eastern Ethiopia. MSc Thesis, Alemaya University, Alemaya, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Lemlem H (2012). Evaluating the effect of low seeding rate, planting method and blended fertilizer application on Eragrostis tef(Kuncho variety) yield, yield component and nutrient uptake by grain grown on Regosols and Vertisols. MSc thesis, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Marx JH, Stevens RG (1999). Soil Test Interpretation Guide. Oregon State University Extension Service, EC 1478.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref34">
				<label>34</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Merga M (2018). Progress, achievements and challenges of tef breeding in Ethiopia. Journal of Agricultural Science and Food Research 9(1):1-8.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref35">
				<label>35</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mohanty M, Reddy SK, Probert ME, Dalal RC, Rao SA, Menzies NW (2011). Modelling nitrogen mineralization from green manure and farmyard manure from a laboratory incubation study. Ecological Modelling 222(3):719-726
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref36">
				<label>36</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[National Fertilizer Strategic Action Plan (NFSAP) (2007). National Strategy with Action Plan for Organic Agriculture of the Republic of reduced use of mineral fertilizers and plant protection agents. Minister for Agriculture, Forestry and water Economy ACO SPASENOSK.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref37">
				<label>37</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Okubay G, Heluf G, Tareke B (2014). Response of tef (Eragrostis tef) to different rates of slow release and conventional urea fertilizers in Vertisol of southern Tigray, Ethiopia. Advances in Plants and Agricultural Research 1(5):1-8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref38">
				<label>38</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Olsen R, Cole S, Watanabe F, Dean L (1954). Estimation of available phosphorusinsoils by extraction with sodium bicarbonate. United States Department of Agriculture Circ. 939.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref39">
				<label>39</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Reinke RF, Lewin LG, Williams RL (1994). Effect of sowing time and nitrogen on rice cultivars of differing growth duration in New South Wales. Yield and yield components; Australian Journal of Experimental Agriculture 34(7):933-938.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref40">
				<label>40</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[SAS (2009). SAS/STAT Users Guide, Version 9.1.3. SAS institute Inc., Cary, NC]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref41">
				<label>41</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Seyfu K (1993). Teff [Eragrostis tef(Zucc)Trotter]. Breeding, Genetics Resources, Agronomy, Utilization and Role in Ethiopian Agriculture.Ethiopian Institute of Geological Surveys, Ministry of Mines and Energy, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref42">
				<label>42</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Seyfu K (1997). Teff [Eragrostis tef(Zucc) Trotter].Promoting the conservation and use of underutilized and neglected crops. Institute of Plant Genetics and Crop Plant Research, Getersleben International Plant Genetic Resources, Rome, Italy]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref43">
				<label>43</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shaun C, Jim C, Stephen M (2012). Sulfur deficiency in Corn. Purdue university department of agronomy, soil fertility update.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref44">
				<label>44</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tekalign T (1991). Soil, plant, water, fertilizer, animal manure and compost analysis. Working Document. No. 13. International Livestock Research Center for Africa, Addis Ababa.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref45">
				<label>45</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Temesgen K (2001). Effect of sowing date and nitrogen fertilization on Yield and related traits of teff [Eragrostis tef (Zucc.) Trotter] on Vertisols of Kobo area, Northern Wollo. MSc Thesis, Alemaya University, Alemaya, Ethiopia.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref46">
				<label>46</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Tadele T, Wogi L, A Kidanemariam (2019). Supplementary nitrogen requirement of teff [Eragrostis teff (Zucc.) Trotter] under chickpea-teff rotation in northwestern Tigray, northern Ethiopia. International Journal of Agriculture and Biosciences 8(1):25-31. www.ijagbio.com.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref47">
				<label>47</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vavilov NI (1951). The origin, variation, immunity, and breeding of cultivated plants (translated from the Russian by K. Starr Chester). The Ronald Press Co., New York. pp. 37-38.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref48">
				<label>48</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wakene T, Walelign W, Wassie H (2014). Effects of nitrogen and phosphorus fertilizer levels on growth and development of barley (Hordeumvulgare L.) at Bore District, Southern Oromia, Ethiopia. American Journal of Life Sciences 2(5):260-266.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref49">
				<label>49</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Wassie H, Tekalign M (2013). The Effect of Potassium on the Yields of Potato and Wheat grown on the Acidic Soils of Chencha and HagereSelam in Southern Ethiopia. International potash institute, e-ifc No. 35.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>