<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Journal of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Health</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">2141-2529</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/JVMAH2019.0791</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Clinicians’ perception and assessment of risk factors for surgical site infections in small animal practice in South-West, Nigeria]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Eyarefe</surname>
            <given-names>O. D.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Adeyemi</surname>
            <given-names>I. M.</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">odeyarefe@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>19</day>
			<month>07</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>15</day>
			<month>01</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>12</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>66</fpage>
	  <lpage>77</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/4EC016063852">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/4EC016063852	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-full-text-pdf/4EC016063852">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-full-text-pdf/4EC016063852	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[This study evaluated the prevalence of Surgical Site Infections (SSIs), the enhancing risk factors in small animal hospitals and clinics, and cliniciansrsquo; perception of SSIs in South-west, Nigeria. Ten years (2007-2017) surgical patientsrsquo; case records from four government veterinary hospitals were initially studied. Fifty-seven copies of structured pre-tested questionnaires were further administered to practice representatives in government and private small animal facilities in 6 states of South-West, Nigeria. Data were analyzed with descriptive statistics and Pearson Chi-square at 95% confidence intervals. One hundred and twenty-six out of 584 small animal surgical patients satisfied the inclusion criteria. Eight (6.3%) cases from the case records had SSIs. Fifty out of 57 retrieved questionnaires satisfied the inclusion criteria for analysis. Sixty-four percent of respondents had the Doctor of Veterinary Medicine (DVM) degree while 36% had additional degrees. The majority (64%) of respondents had 1 to 3 years practice experience with the rest having above 3 years. Most of the respondents (96%) had good knowledge of SSI, 78.7% usually manage SSI cases and 18% had lost patients due to SSIs. Only 48% of the practices perform surgery in designated operating rooms. The environment (94%), hands of clinicians/caregiver (80%) and patientsrsquo; skin (62%) were the main sources of SSIs in respondentsrsquo; practice. Few respondents (19.1%) administer prophylactic antibiotics for all surgeries, 6.1% discontinue within 24 h post-surgery, while 75.5% continue antibiotic therapy for 3 to 7 days post-surgery. Lack of facilities (40%) and funds (54%) prevented some clinicians from keeping up with SSIs prevention measures. There was an association between the risk factors of post-operative wound dehiscence (P=0.006), classification of the surgical procedures (P=0.032) and SSI occurrence. Although many small animal practitioners are aware of SSIs risk factors, only few adhere to prevention protocols.

	Key words: Surgical site infection (SSI), risk factors, small animal clinicians, perception.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Adriaanse AH, Pel M, Bleker OP (2000). Semmelweis: the combat against puerperal fever. Europe Journal Obstetric Gynaecology Reproduction Biology 90:153-158.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ahern BJ, Richardson DW (2012). Surgical site infection and the use of antimicrobials. In: Equine Surgery, 4th edn. Eds: JA Auer JA Stick, Elsevier/Saunders, St Louis, Missouri. pp. 68-84.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Akinrinmade JF (2012). Evaluation of pattern of pet animal trauma at the veterinary Teaching hospitals, Ibadan, Nigeria. Nigeria Veterinary Journal 35(3):1007-1014.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Akinrinmade JF, Oke BO (2012). Antibiotic prophylaxis in Gastro-intestinal surgery: An evaluation of current Veterinary Practices in Southwest Nigeria. International Journal Administration Veterinary Advance 4(4):256-262.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Anderson ME, Foster BA, Weese JS (2013). Observational study of patient and surgeon preoperative preparation in ten companion animal clinics in Ontario Canada. BMC Veterinary Reserve 9:194.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Berros-Torres SI, Umscheid CA, Bratzler DW, Leas B, Stone EC, Kelz RR, Reinke CE, Morgan S, Slomkin JS, Mazuski JE, Dellinger EP (2017). Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Guideline for the Prevention of Surgical Site Infection, 2017. JAMA Surgery 152(8):784-791.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Birgand G, Azevedo C, Toupet G, Pissard-Gibollet R, Grandbastien B, Fleury E, Lucet JC (2014). Attitudes, risk of infection and behaviours in the operating room (the ARIBO Project): a prospective, cross sectional study. BMJ Open 4(1):e004274.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Clark FC (1907). A brief history of antiseptic surgery. Medical Library History Journal 5:145-172]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Culver DH, Horan TC, Gaynes RP, Martone WJ, Jarvis WR, Emori TG, Banerjee SN, Edwards JR, Tolson JS, Henderson TS, Hughes JM (1991). National Nosocomial Infections Surveillance System. Surgical wound infection rates by wound class, operative procedure, and patient risk index. American Journal of Medicine 91:152S-157S.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Eyarefe OD (2016). Risk factors, prevention and control strategies for surgical site infections in veterinary practice in Nigeria - A review. Journal of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Health 8(8):72-82.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Eyarefe OD, Adetunji AG (2018). Dog breeds acquisition and owners awareness of associated surgical conditions in Nigeria. Journal of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Health 10(7):173-179.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hemani ML, Lepor H (2009). Skin preparation for the prevention of surgical site infection: which agent is best? Reverse Urology 11(4):190-195.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Humes D, Lobo D (2005). Asepsis, antisepsis and skin preparation. Surgery (oxford). 23:297-298. 10.1383/surg.2005.23.8.297.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Imai E, Ueda M, Kanao K, Miyaki K, Kubota T, Kitajima M (2005). Surgical site infection surveillance after open gastrostomy and risk factors for surgical site infection. Journal Infect Chemotherapy 11:141-145.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kaye KS, Schmit K, Pieper C, Sloane R, Caughlan KF, Sexton DJ, Schmader KE (2005). The effect of increasing age on the risk of surgical site infection. Journal of Infect Disease 191:1056-1062.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Leaper DJ, Tanner J, Kiernan M (2014). Surgical site infection: poor compliance with guidelines and care bundles. International Wound Journal [Epub ahead of print].
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mangram AJ, Horan TC, Pearson ML, Silver LC, Jarvis WR, Hospital Infection Control Practices Advisory Committee (1999a). Guideline for prevention of surgical site infection, 1999. Infection Control and Hospital Epidemiology 20(4):247-280.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mangram AJ, Horan TC, Pearson ML (1999b). Guideline for Prevention of Surgical Site Infection, 1999. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Hospital Infection Control Practices Advisory Committee. American Journal Infect Control 27(2):97-132.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[McMillan S (2014). An evidence-based approach to infection control in the operating theatre. Veterinary Nurse 5(4):194-200.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[National Nosocomial Infections Surveillance (NNIS) (1999). System report, data summary from January 1990-May 1999, issued June 1999. American Journal Infectious Control 27(6):520:
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Owens WD, Felts JA, Spitznagel EL Jr (1978). ASA physical status classifications: a study of consistency of ratings. Anesthesiology 49:239-243.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Sabbatani S, Catena F, Neri F, Vallicelli C, Ansaloni L, Sartelli M, Coccolini F, Di Saverio S, Catena R, Lazzareschi D, Tarasconi A, Abongwa HK, De Simone B, Pinna A (2014). The Bolognese surgeon Guiseppe Ruggi: how and why septic surgery was introduced in Bologna in the middle half of the XIX century. Journal Surgical Resource 192:555-563
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Umit UM, Sina M, Ferhat Y (2014). Surgeon behavior and knowledge on hand scrub and skin antisepsis in the operating room. Journal Surgical Education 71(2):241-245.at
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Verwilghen D (2015). Surgical site infections: What do we know? Equine Veterinary Journal 47:753-755.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Verwilghen D, Singh A (2015). Fighting surgical site infections in small animals are we getting anywhere? Veterinary Clinical North American Small Animal Practice 45:243-276.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Verwilghen D, Findji S, Weese JS, Singh A, Dupre G, Catry B, Van Galen G (2013). Evidence based hand hygiene in veterinary surgery: what is holding us back? In: Annual Symposium of the American College of Veterinary Surgeons, ACVS, San Antonio, Texas.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Windahl U, Bengtsson B, Nyman AK, Holst BS (2015).The distribution of pathogens and their antimicrobial susceptibility patterns among canine surgical wound infections in Sweden in relation to different risk factors. Acta Veterinaria Scandinavica. 57:1.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>