<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Scientific Research and Essays</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1992-2248</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/SRE2020.6671</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Knowledge and understanding of energy efficiency in air-conditioning: Exploring perceptions from the manufacturing sector in Ghana]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Jones</surname>
            <given-names>Lewis Arthur</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Josephine</surname>
            <given-names>Fianu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">jonesarthur2002@yahoo.co.uk</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>20</day>
			<month>02</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>07</day>
			<month>05</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>15</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>33</fpage>
	  <lpage>40</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B98B52E63874">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B98B52E63874	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-full-text-pdf/B98B52E63874">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-full-text-pdf/B98B52E63874	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[The study investigated Energy Efficiency (EE) measures and practices from the perspectives of Ghana#39;s manufacturing sector. A mixed methods approach that applied both qualitative and quantitative methodologies guided the study. The quantitative approach was relevant to establish statistical inferences and the qualitative methods used to provide further in-depth understanding to statistic(s) provided by the quantitative analysis. A total of 774 respondents (636- food processing Industry, 138- Cement Industry) provided the population for the study. A sample size of 260 informed the study. Various sampling frames including purposive, cluster and simple random were adopted to select respondents. The study concluded that knowledge on EE awareness and practices occurring at the departmental levels was mixed but clear on servicing and cleaning of air-conditioning since the manufacturing industries placed premium on regularity of servicing ACs in their places of work. Also, the findings identified that failure to clean the heating, ventilating and air-conditioning systems, failure to close doors and windows while ACs were on and avoidance of the use of efficient refrigerants and new ACs as key factors that negatively impacted  EE for the manufacturing industries. The contribution of single speed ACs to energy efficiency was minimal compared to the other energy wasting activities associated with the use of air-conditioning.

	Key words: Air-conditioning, energy, management, efficiency, wastage]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ahmadi-Karvigh S, Ghahramani A, Becerik-Gerber B, Soibelman L (2018). Real-time activity recognition for energy efficiency in buildings. Applied Energy 211:146-160.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ahmad S (2015). Green human resource management: Policies and practices. Cogent Business and Management 2(1):1030817.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Allouhi A, El Fouih Y, Kousksou T, Jamil A, Zeraouli Y, Mourad Y (2015). Energy consumption and efficiency in buildings: current status and future trends. Journal of Cleaner Production 109:118-130.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Bertram D (2006) Likert Scales: CPSC 681-Topic Report. Poincare, 1-11.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Calvillo CF, Snchez-Miralles A, Villar J (2016). Energy management and planning in smart cities. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 55:273-287.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cao X, Dai X, Liu J (2016). Building energy-consumption status worldwide and the state-of-the-art technologies for zero-energy buildings during the past decade. Energy and Buildings 128:198-213.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Chel A, Kaushik G (2011). Renewable energy for sustainable agriculture. Agronomy for Sustainable Development 31(1):91-118.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Cole JC, McDonald JB, Wen X, Kramer RA (2018). Marketing energy efficiency: perceived benefits and barriers to home energy efficiency. Energy Efficiency 11(7):1811-1824.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Finnerty N, Sterling R, Contreras S, Coakley D, Keane MM (2018). Defining corporate energy policy and strategy to achieve carbon emissions reduction targets via energy management in non-energy intensive multi-site manufacturing organizations. Energy 151:913-929.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Fowlie M, Greenstone M, Wolfram C (2018). Do energy efficiency investments deliver? Evidence from the weatherization assistance program. The Quarterly Journal of Economics 133(3):1597-1644.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gellings CW (2009). The smart grid: enabling energy efficiency and demand response. The Fairmont Press, Inc.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Goetzler W, Guernsey M, Young J, Fuhrman J, Abdelaziz O (2016). The future of air conditioning for buildings. US Department of Energy, Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Building Technologies Office.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Gyamfi S, Modjinou M, Djordjevic S (2015). Improving electricity supply security in Ghana-The potential of renewable energy. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 43:1035-1045.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Hejase AJ, Hejase HJ (2013). Research Methods: A Practical Approach for Business Students (2nd edition). Philadelphia, PA, Masadir Inc.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[International Energy Agency (2013). Transition to Sustainable Buildings: Strategies and Opportunities to 2050. OECD/IEA.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[International Energy Agency (2017). Market Report Series: Energy Efficiency 2017. P 135.
				
					View]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Johansson MT, Thollander P (2018). A review of barriers to and driving forces for improved energy efficiency in Swedish industry-recommendations for successful in-house energy manage-ment. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 82:618-628.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Joshi A, Kale S, Chandel S, Pal DK. (2015). Likert scale: Explored and explained. British Journal of Applied Science and Technology 7(4):396.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kambule N (2014). A survey on the state of energy efficiency adoption and related challenges amongst selected manufacturing SMMEs in the Booysens area of Johannesburg (Doctoral dissertation, University of Johannesburg).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kemausuor F, Obeng GY, Brew-Hammond A, Duker A (2011). A review of trends, policies and plans for increasing energy access in Ghana. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 15(9):5143-5154.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Koizumi S (2007). Energy Efficiency of air conditioners in developing countries and the role of CDM. Paris: International Energy Agency.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Krejcie RV, Morgan DW (1970). Determining Sample Size for Research Activities. Educational and Psychological Measurement 30(3):607-610.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Kumi EN (2017). The Electricity Situation in Ghana: Challenges and Opportunities. Center for Global Development.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Laitner JAS (2015). The energy efficiency benefits and the economic imperative of ICT-enabled systems. In: ICT Innovations for Sustainability. Springer, Chem. pp. 37-48.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Loe DL. (2003). Quantifying lighting energy efficiency: a discussion document. Lighting Research and Technology 35(4):319-326.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Maclean R, Jagannathan S, Panth B (2018). Overview. In Education and Skills for Inclusive Growth, Green Jobs and the Greening of Economies in Asia . Springer, Singapore. pp. 1-18.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Oh SJ, Ng KC, Thu K, Chun W, and Chua K JE (2016). Forecasting long-term electricity demand for cooling of Singapores buildings incorporating an innovative air-conditioning technology. Energy and Buildings 127:183-193.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Owusu A (2010). Towards a reliable and sustainable source of electricity for micro and small scale light industries in the Kumasi Metropolis (Doctoral dissertation).]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref29">
				<label>29</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Raj KB. (2018). Smart Grid Technology for Smart Homes-Risks and Benefits. In: ICRTEMMS Conference Proceedings 634(640):634-640. Swarna Bharathilnstitute of Science and Technology.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref30">
				<label>30</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Şahin M, Oğuz Y, Byktmtrk F (2016). ANN-based estimation of time-dependent energy loss in lighting systems. Energy and Buildings 116:455-467.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref31">
				<label>31</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shanker R, Bhanugopan R, Van der Heijden BI, Farrell M (2017). Organizational climate for innovation and organizational performance: The mediating effect of innovative work behavior. Journal of Vocational Behavior 100:67-77.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref32">
				<label>32</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Worrell E, Kermeli K, Galitsky C (2013). Energy Efficiency Improvement and Cost Saving Opportunities for Cement Making an ENERGY STAR Guide for Energy and Plant Managers.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref33">
				<label>33</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Xu L, Pan Y, Yao Y, CAI D, Huang Z, Linder N (2017). Lighting energy efficiency in offices under different control strategies. Energy and Buildings 138:127-139.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>