<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.0 20040830//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/2.0/journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.0" xml:lang="EN">
  <front>    <journal-meta>
      <journal-title>Scientific Research and Essays</journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1992-2248</issn>      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>Academic Journals</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5897/SRE2019.6660</article-id>
      <title-group>
        <article-title><![CDATA[Impact of some heavy metals on bacterial utilization of kerosene in liquid medium]]></article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Okobo</surname>
            <given-names>Uchenna Jude</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Chibuzor</surname>
            <given-names>Nwadibe Eze</given-names>
	          </name>	
        		        	<name name-style="western">
	            <surname>Akpi</surname>
            <given-names>Uchenna Kalu</given-names>
	          </name>	
        	        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
		<corresp id="cor1">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">uchennaokobo@gmail.com</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
      	<day>30</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2020</year>
      </pub-date>
      <history>
      			<date date-type="received">
			<day>22</day>
			<month>11</month>
			<year>2019</year>
		</date>
						<date date-type="accepted">
			<day>12</day>
			<month>03</month>
			<year>2020</year>
		</date>
			  </history>
      <volume>15</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
	  	  <fpage>26</fpage>
	  <lpage>32</lpage>
      <permissions>
		<license xlink:type="simple">
			<license-p>
			This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.
			</license-p>
		</license>
	  </permissions>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/83857B563833">
		This article is available from https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/83857B563833	  </self-uri>
	  <self-uri xlink:href="https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-full-text-pdf/83857B563833">
		The full text article is available as a PDF file from https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-full-text-pdf/83857B563833	  </self-uri>
	  
      <abstract><![CDATA[Potential petroleum degrading bacteria, Pseudomonas aerogenosa and Micrococcus sp. was isolated from petroleum contaminated soil in petroleum microbiology laboratory, Department of Microbiology University of Nigeria, Nsukka. Hydrocarbon utilization in liquid media was assessed through time ndash; course optical density measurement. Concentrations of the heavy metals ranging from 50 to 200 mg/L were introduced into 100 ml of mineral salt medium containing 10 ml of kerosene inoculated with P. aeruginosa or  Micrococcus sp. and incubated at room temperature (25-30deg;C) for 384 h. Control samples contained kerosene but no heavy metals. At low concentrations the heavy metals significantly (p lt;0.05) improved the growth of the isolates as indicated by the highest OD600 obtained with 50 mg/L of the metals which was the lowest concentrations. This was confirmed by the bacterial cell number extrapolated from an OD standard curve. At higher concentrations of the heavy metals (150 to 200 mg/L) there was a decline in the growth rates of the isolates. The effects of the heavy metals on the hydrocarbonoclastic efficacy of the isolates were dose-dependent and their growth rates in the presence of the metals were in the following order: Lead gt; Cadmium gt; Mercury.

	Key words: Heavy metals, kerosene, bioremediation, bacteria.]]></abstract>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
      <body/>
    <back>
		<ref-list>
			<title>References</title>
						<ref id="ref1">
				<label>1</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Abioye OP, Aina, PF, Ijah UJJ, Aransiola SA (2019). Effects of Cadmium and Lead on Biodegradation of Diesel-Contamdeeinated Soil. Journal of Taibah University for Science 13:628-638.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref2">
				<label>2</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Aguilera F, Mendez J, Pasaro E, Laffon B (2010). Review on the effects of spilled oil to human health. Journal of Applied Toxicology 30(4):291-301.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref3">
				<label>3</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Atlas RM, Bartha R (1973). Degradation and Mineralization of petroleum in seawater Limitations by Nitrogen and phosphorus. Biotechnology and Bioengineering 14:309-317.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref4">
				<label>4</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Azubuike CC, Chikere BC, Okpokwasili GC (2017). Bioremediation Classification Based on Site of Application: Principles, Advantages, Limitations and Prospects. World Journal of Microbiology and Biotechnology 10:141-146.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref5">
				<label>5</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ekpenyong MG, Antai SP (2007). Cadmium toxicity on species of Bacillus and Pseudomonas during growth on crude oil. Trends in Applied Science Research 2:115-123.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref6">
				<label>6</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ekperusi OA, Aigbodion IF (2015). Bioremediation of heavy metals and petroleum hydrocarbons in diesel contaminated soil with the earthworm: Ethiopian Journal of Environmental Studies and Management 9(2):1036-1046.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref7">
				<label>7</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ellison RJ, Larnimaa K, Margary SA, Mata JM, Muller JM, Peterson DR, Dmytras B, Short D, Simpson BJ (1999). Exposure Profile: Kerosines/Jet Fuels Prepared for the CONCAWE Petroleum Products Management Group.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref8">
				<label>8</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Eze CN, Okobo UJ, Odo CK (2019). Effects of lead and mercury on crude oil utilization by Pseudomonas aerogenosa. Applied Research Journal of Biotechnology 2(1):1-9.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref9">
				<label>9</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Giwa EO, Ibitoye FO (2017). Bioremediation of Heavy Metals in Crude oil contaminated soil using isolated indigenousmicroorganism cultured with E.coli DE3 BL21. International Journal of Engineering and Applied Sciences 4(6):2394-3661.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref10">
				<label>10</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Greenwood NN, Earnshaw A (1997). Coherence of the even odd rule with an effective-valence isoelectronicity rule for chemical structural formulas: application to known and unknown single covalent bonded compounds. Chemistry of the Elements 2nd Edition.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref11">
				<label>11</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Irwin RJ, Movwerik V, Stephens L (1997). Kerosene Entry. National Park Service, Water Resources Division,Water operation branch ;Oak ridge Drive, Suite Fort Collins,Colorado 80525. Environmental Contaminants Encyclopedia. Distributed within the Fedral Government as an electronic document)(Google Scholar.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref12">
				<label>12</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Iyagba AG, Offor US (2014). Effect of crude oil and biostimulant (bioremediation) on growth extract of maize and cowpea. European Scientific Journal 10(6):55-124.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref13">
				<label>13</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Krishna KY, Gupta N, Kumar V, Singh JK (2017). Bioremediation of Heavy Metals from contaminated Sites using Potential Species; A Review. Indian Journal of Environmental Protection 37(1):65-84.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref14">
				<label>14</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Le TT, Son MH, Nam IH, Kang, YG, Chang YS (2017). Transformation of hexa bromocyclododecane in contaminated soil in association with microbial diversity. Journal of Harzardous Materials 325:82-89.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref15">
				<label>15</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Matveev SS, Chechet IV, Valeri YA, Sergey VL, Sergey GM (2017). Experimental Study of Combustion of kerosene and binary surrogate in the model combustion chamber. Journal of Combustion 2017: 6.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref16">
				<label>16</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Mona SZ, Nadia E, Hamman AM, Shalaby SI (2014). Aquatic bioremediation of metals. Life Science Journal 11(4):66-72.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref17">
				<label>17</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Okpokwasili AC, Okorie BB (1988). Biodegradation potentials of organisms isolated from car engine lubricating oil. Tribology International 21:215- 221.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref18">
				<label>18</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Okpokwasili GC, Odokuma LO (1990) Effect of salinity on biodegradation of Oil Spill dispersants. Waste Management 10(2):141-146.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref19">
				<label>19</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Owabor CN, Onwuemene OC, Enaburekhan I (2011). Bioremediation of polycyclice aromatic hydrocarbon contaminated aqueous-soil matrix: Effect of co-contamination. Journal of Applied Environmental Science 15(4):583-588.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref20">
				<label>20</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Panet SR, Marshal AC, Vendeuvre B, Monot F (2006). Characterisation of biodegradation capacities of environmental microflarae for diesel oil by comprehensive two dimensional gas chromatography. Biodegradation 17:577
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref21">
				<label>21</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Plohl K, Leskovsek H, Bricelj M (2002). Biological degradation of motor oil in water. Acta Chimica Slovenica 49(2):279-290.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref22">
				<label>22</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Poi G, Shasavari E, Aburto-Medina A, Mok, P, Ball AS (2018). Large Scale treatment of total petroleum hydrocarbon contaminated groundwater using bioaugmentation. Journal of Environmental Management 15(214):157-163.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref23">
				<label>23</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Raeds A-W, Shimaa RH (2014). Bacterial Biodegradation of crude oil using local isolates. International Journal of Bacteriology 2014:8.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref24">
				<label>24</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Ritchie DG, Still K, Rossi J, Rekkeda M (2003). Biological and Health Effects of Kerosene Based Fuel and Performance Additives. Journal of Toxicology and Environmental Health Part B.7:451.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref25">
				<label>25</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shabir G, Afzal FM, Anwar R, Tahseen ZK (2008). Biodegradation of kerosene in soil by a mixed bacterial culture under different nutrient conditions. International Journal of Biodeterioration Biodegradadation 61:161.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref26">
				<label>26</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Shamiyan R, Khan JI, Kumar NR, Jignasha GP (2015). Bioremediation of kerosene: Study of growth optimization and metabolic fate of P. Janthinellum SDX7. Braziliian Journal of Microbiology 46(2):397-406.
					]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref27">
				<label>27</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Siddique S, Rovina K, Azad SA (2015). Heavy metals contaminants removal from waste water using potential filamentous fungi biomass: A Review; Special Task Force on Petroleum Product Exposure Profiles (STF-14). Journal of Microbial and Biochemical Technology 7(6):384-393.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
						<ref id="ref28">
				<label>28</label>
				<mixed-citation publication-type="other" xlink:type="simple">
				<![CDATA[Vinothini C, Sudhakar S, Ravikumar R (2015). Biodegradation of petroleum and crude oil by Pseudomonas putida and Bacillus Cereus. International Journal of Current Microbiology and Applied Sciences 41:318-329.]]>
				</mixed-citation>
			</ref>
					</ref-list>
	</back>
    </article>