<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Academic Journals - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/articles</link><description>view the most recent articles from academic journals.</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Ultrasonic assisted extraction of bioactive compounds from different parts of Hancornia Speciosa Gomes</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/55E3DD363829</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/55E3DD363829</guid><description>
	The proper use of plants and their extracts, whether for medicine or as a food additive, requires the use of extraction and characterization methods that allow the identification and quantification of the active principles in each extract, associating them with the effect produced. With this objective, the present work was developed to study the ultrasonic extracts of mangabeira (Hancornia s...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of ethanol leaf extract of Gnetum africanum on testosterone and oestradiol induced benign prostatic hyperplasia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/3BA1CF663831</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/3BA1CF663831</guid><description>
	The effect of ethanol leaf extract of Gnetum africanum was studied in albino rats induced with benign prostatic hyperplasia. The animals (36) were randomly grouped into six with six rats in each group. Testosterone and oestradiol every other day for 28 days was used to induce hyperplasia. The test groups (2 - 4) were treated with 200, 400 and 800 mg/kg body weight of extract for another 28 d...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Separation and identification of phenolics and flavonoids from wild Pistacia palaestina extract and its antioxidant activity</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5C4B54E63866</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5C4B54E63866</guid><description>
	An in-vitro evaluation of the antioxidant activities of wild Palestinian Pistacia palaestina extracts was done. In parallel, the total phenolic content (TPC) and the total flavonoids content (TFC) were measured. The antioxidant activities were determined spectrophotometrically by DPPH, FRAP, CUPRAC and the ABTS methods. The phenolic and flavonoid contents were separated and identified using ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemical composition and antioxidant activity in the essential oil of Cinnamomum zeylanicum Nees with medicinal interest</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/693E48063868</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/693E48063868</guid><description>
	Cinnamon is an evergreen tree belonging to the genus Cinnamomun; it is commonly founded in various tropical countries, consisting of more than 250 species of trees and shrubs in the Lauraceae family. This plant has had great medicinal importance in traditional medicine since ancient times. In this research, the chemical composition of the essential oil of Cinnamomum zeylanicum Nees was evalu...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors associated with irregular consumption of fruits and vegetables among health professionals in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/419A12D62771</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/419A12D62771</guid><description>
	Fruits and vegetables (FVs) are an essential food group for humans and prevent non-communicable diseases (NCDs). The objective of this study is to know the level of consumption of FVs by health professionals in Ouagadougou and their determinants. This is a descriptive cross-sectional study conducted from May to August 2016 in the Central Region of Burkina Faso. It included 442 health workers...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysis of economic efficiency among smallholder sorghum producers in Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/6B83ABB63823</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/6B83ABB63823</guid><description>
	This study used Cobb-Douglas Stochastic Profit Frontier to analyze economic efficiency of sorghum farmers in Tharaka Nithi County, Kenya. Using a multi-stage stratified sample of 259 farmers, results depicted a wide range of profit efficiency between the best (0.96) and the worst (0.12) farmer with a mean of 0.17. The actual and potential profit was USD 164.88 ha-1 and USD 969.87 ha-1 respec...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Control of papaya fruits anthracnose by essential oils of medicinal plants associated to different coatings</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5BF161663528</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5BF161663528</guid><description>
	Chemical pesticides have been commonly used for the control of various plant diseases. Although pathogens can be controlled with the application of these products, there are hazardous impacts in human health and environment. In parallel, essential oils have been shown to be effective in plant diseases management and can be safely incorporated as suitable alternatives for synthetic fungicides...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The effects of aqueous extract of Bowdichia virgilioides Kunth in the immune functions of thymocytes and B-lymphocytes</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/086CB2463536</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/086CB2463536</guid><description>
	Bowdichia virgilioides Kunth (Fabaceae) is a tree species used in folk medicine against inflammatory disorders, and it is still unclear whether consumption of the B. virgilioides stem bark extract has any effect on immune cells. Thus, this study aimed to evaluate the effects of B. virgilioides stem bark extract (AEBv) on the functions of the thymus and B lymphocytes. The AEBv was obtained by...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Hydroethanolic stem bark extract of Vernonia amygdalina Del. (Asteraceae) suppresses yeast-induced pyrexia and Plasmodium berghei malaria in murine models</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/447934F63538</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/447934F63538</guid><description>
	Vernonia amygdalina has been widely utilized in Ghana and other West African states for numerous parasitic infections, diabetes and some inflammatory conditions. In this study we evaluated the antipyretic and antimalarial properties as well as in vitro antioxidant activities of an ethanolic stem bark extract of V. amygdalina (VAE). The antipyretic effect of VAE was assessed using Bakers yeas...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibacterial, cytotoxic, and schistosomicidal activities of the methanolic extract from Cassia grandis L.f. (Fabaceae) stem bark and its fractions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/74A5BA963542</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/74A5BA963542</guid><description>
	Cassia grandis L. (Fabaceae), a native tree from Amazon Forest, has been used in folk medicine against worms and intestinal parasites, and to treat stomach and respiratory problems, blood diseases, among others uses. This study aimed to evaluate the antioxidant, cytotoxic, antimicrobial, and schistosomicidal activities of the methanolic extract from C. grandis stem bark (CgME) and to elucida...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Biological properties and therapeutic applications of cannabidiol</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/1690A3D63559</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/1690A3D63559</guid><description>
	Cannabis sp. has important pharmacological activities, so it has been the focus of attention of the scientific community. Through the search for new drugs, it was found that cannabinoids present in the plant can modulate transient potential receptors (TPR). Cannabidiol (CBD), also known as medical marijuana, represents the second most abundant phytocannabinoid of the Cannabis plant and it is...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemical composition and biological potentials of Lebanese Cupressus sempervirens L. leaves&#x2019; extracts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/014F43E63709</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/014F43E63709</guid><description>
	The essential oils and defatted ethanolic extracts isolated from Cupressus sempervirens L. leaves collected from two geographically distinct regions in Lebanon; Beit El-Dein (mountain) and Jbeil (sea-side) were analysed for their chemical composition by GC/MS and qualitative phytochemical screening, respectively. These were then tested for their in-vitro antioxidant and antibacterial activit...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative effects of Moringa oleifera powder and soybean meal on the zootechnical parameters of the ISA Brown pullet</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BA4280F63802</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BA4280F63802</guid><description>
	Poultry farming is an important sector of the Beninese agriculture. But this sector is facing economic difficulties. The aim of this study is to evaluate the effects of Moringa oleifera powder and soybean meal on zootechnical parameters in the ISA Brown pullet. For this purpose, the experiment was carried out on a total of 250 day-old chicks with an initial average weight of 40  1 g. Among t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of nutritional flushing on reproductive and body weight performance of Abergelle goat does</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BB9723263804</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BB9723263804</guid><description>
	This study was aimed to evaluate the effect of flushing on the reproductive and body weight change on Abergelle breed does. The study indicated that a mix of 300 or 450 g wheat bran (WB) with 50 g noug seed cake (NSC) flushed per day improved the does conception rate (70 to 80%) and kidding rate (70%); while does flushed with low concentrate level (150 g WB plus 50 g NSC) or those not flushe...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The last of us? An online survey among German farm veterinarians about the future of veterinary training, livestock farming and the profession in general</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/448035D63806</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/448035D63806</guid><description>
	This online survey investigated how German farm veterinarians perceive the future of their profession. According to the participants, the following topics should play a greater role in veterinary training: Economics, herd health management, practical education, agricultural knowledge and animal welfare issues. The top answer indicates that knowledge about entrepreneurship is seen as a crucia...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Production of liquid fertilizer by fermented livestock liquid and application on crops</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/0D0B67463809</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/0D0B67463809</guid><description>
	The livestock liquid commonly contains humic acid, amino acids and minerals; hence, it can be used for the fertilization of crops. These studies were conducted to examine the use of livestock fermented liquid in producing liquid fertilizers and irrigation application on two kinds of crops (tomato and wax apple). The experiments were designed as common liquid fertilizer and diluted by groundw...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of combined salt and flooding stresses on the growth and physiological behavior of alfalfa (Medicago sativa L.)
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/2D9500063811</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/2D9500063811</guid><description>
	The present work focused on evaluation of the physiological and metabolic behavior of alfalfa (Medicago sativa L., var. Siriver), when faced with two important ecosystems constraints, namely salinity and flooding-associated hypoxia. After germination, seedlings in symbiosis with Sinorhizobium meliloti were grown on different salt concentrations (0, 20 and 50 mM NaCl). At four weeks post-germ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Promotion of rice growth and productivity as a result of seed inoculation with Azospirillum brasilense</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D0AFA7163813</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D0AFA7163813</guid><description>
	The present study refers to the results obtained in four experiments carried out in the 2015/2016 crop: Toledo/PR; Palotina/PR; Cascavel/PR; and So Miguel do Iguau/PR. The objective of the present study was to evaluate the agronomic efficiency of Azospirillum brasilense (pest strains Ab-V5 and Ab-V6) in four distinct rice culture regions (Oryza sativa L.). The tests were performed to meet th...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Severity and prevalence of the destructive fall armyworm on maize in Uganda: A case of 
Bulambuli District
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/E6D997463815</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/E6D997463815</guid><description>
	Maize kernel contains a large quantity of carbohydrates, proteins, vitamins, oils, fats and competes favorably with root and tuber crops as a rich energy source. In Uganda, the per capita consumption ranges from 28 to 125 kg per annum. However, the yields remain low, fluctuating around 1.5 tons per hectare. Although some losses to maize production occur through the post-harvest period, pre-h...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Potential of reduced agricultural lime application rates to increase yield and profitability of maize through microdosing in central Malawi - A short note</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/A317EA763817</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/A317EA763817</guid><description>
	Maize (Zea mays L.) is a staple food crop in Malawi, with average yields of 1.8 -2.2 t ha-1 compared to potential yields of 5 to 10 t ha-1. In some areas, soil acidity is a serious constraint in crop production. The current recommendation is to apply 2.0 t ha-1 of lime as pre-plant broadcast and incorporated into soils with pHW  5.5. A pilot study was conducted during 2015/2016 season at Bun...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Role of leaf rolling on agronomic performances of durum wheat subjected to water stress</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/7FFC4FE63819</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/7FFC4FE63819</guid><description>
	In arid and semi-arid climates characterized by low rainfall with a great annual and inter-annual irregularity, drought can occur at any time inducing large losses in crop yield. Leaf rolling is one of the adaptive morphological responses to the water deficit observed in a number of species including cereals. It reduces the leaf area exposed to sunlight and transpiration. The aim of the pres...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fertilizer-nitrogen use optimization for Tef in South Wollo Zone of Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/68FB5D363821</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/68FB5D363821</guid><description>
	Tef [Eragrotis tef] is a major staple cereal crop in Ethiopia but yields are low due to inadequate nutrient supply and other constraints. A field study was conducted in 2014 and 2015 in Jamma district of South Wollo Zone of Amhara Region to determine the economic optimum rate of fertilizer-N for tef. Fertilizer-N rates of 0, 23, 46, 69, 92, 115 and 138 kg ha-1 were evaluated. The randomized ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Selection of drought tolerant genotypes in groundnut (Arachis hypogaea L.) using indices</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/65D45BD63825</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/65D45BD63825</guid><description>
	A study was carried out to evaluate the effect of drought stress on pod yield and other traits of groundnut genotypes to select the ten best performing genotypes using indices. Ninety six genotypes including 90 F2:3 progenies, 4 parents and 2 checks were planted under well-watered (WW) and water-stressed (WS) conditions at the International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Validation of blended NPSB fertilizer rates on yield, yield components of Teff [Eragrostis tef (Zuccagni) Trotter] at vertisols of Hatsebo, Central Tigray, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/4F6A1D363827</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/4F6A1D363827</guid><description>
	Application of unbalanced nutrition was the main yield limiting factor in the study area. Hence, an experiment was conducted during the 2017 cropping season on farmers fields to validate and determine optimum blended fertilizer rate for teff production. Eight levels of NPSB (0, 25, 50, 100, 150, 200, 250 and 300 kg ha-1) and recommended NP (100 kg ha-1 urea and 100 kg ha-1TSP) were used as t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of some heavy metals on bacterial utilization of kerosene in liquid medium</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/83857B563833</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/83857B563833</guid><description>
	Potential petroleum degrading bacteria, Pseudomonas aerogenosa and Micrococcus sp. was isolated from petroleum contaminated soil in petroleum microbiology laboratory, Department of Microbiology University of Nigeria, Nsukka. Hydrocarbon utilization in liquid media was assessed through time  course optical density measurement. Concentrations of the heavy metals ranging from 50 to 200 mg/L wer...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The performance of artificial insemination delivery system in Amhara, Oromia, SNNP and Tigray Regions of Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/00B256663836</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/00B256663836</guid><description>
	The study was conducted in Amhara, Oromia, Southern Nations Nationalities and Peoples and Tigray regions of the country to provide information on the performance of Artificial Insemination (AI) service delivery system, its seasonality and effectiveness. Semi-structured questionnaire was prepared to interview AI technicians (on their performance and related issues) and farmers (about the outc...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>GC-MS analysis of bioactive compounds and evaluation of antimicrobial activity of the extracts of Daedalea elegans: A Nigerian mushroom</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/DBFDD5063838</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/DBFDD5063838</guid><description>
	Phytochemicals are naturally occurring compounds present in varying levels in plants and help significantly in protecting them against pathogens. The chemical composition of acetone and ethanolic extracts of Daedalea elegans were determined using Gas Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry. Twenty-eight and fourty-four compounds were identified in the acetone and ethanolic extracts respectively. On...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Risky sexual behaviors and substance use among youths in post-conflict Liberia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/E17DC3863839</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/E17DC3863839</guid><description>
	Sexually transmitted infections pose a public health crisis globally and in low and middle-income countries, and substance use has been linked to an increased risk of engaging in risky sexual behaviors among youths. This work aims to explore the relationship between substance use and risky sexual behaviors among school-based youths in Liberia. An 86-question survey was developed to collect i...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) associated with cotton (Gossypium hirsutum L.) growing in the Far-North region of Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/A270AA963842</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/A270AA963842</guid><description>
	The present study was carried out with the aim of highlighting the diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) associated with the rhizosphere of cotton grown in the Far-North region of Cameroon. To achieve this, composite soil and root samples were taken in six fields, chosen according to edapho-climatic conditions and types of cultural practices. After entrapping the glomales in the gr...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Knowledge and awareness of pregnant women on HIV and AIDS in Butwal, Nepal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/4A2BB6263843</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/4A2BB6263843</guid><description>
	This study examined knowledge and awareness regarding HIV and AIDS among pregnant women in Butwal, Nepal. Pregnant women were selected using a systematic random sampling method from the antenatal care registry at every 5th and 10th interval. Although 80% of women mentioned unprotected sexual contact as the major route of HIV transmission, only 36.7% women knew that HIV can be transmitted fro...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Association of glycaemia control, age and duration of morbidity with the quality of life in patients of type 2 diabetes mellitus attending the tertiary care hospital in field practice area of Ottapalam Palakad</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/5E47EF963848</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPHE/article-abstract/5E47EF963848</guid><description>
	Diabetes is a chronic progressive endocrine disease characterized by elevation of blood glucose level. This disease is associated with decreased life expectancy; increased morbidity and diminished quality of life. The objective of the study is to assess the correlation of glycaemic control, age and duration of disease with quality of life in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. The presen...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Efficacy of Newcastle disease vaccines and vaccination protocols commonly used in Mali, West Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/DDD000B63850</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/DDD000B63850</guid><description>
	Newcastle disease, caused by Avian paramyxovirus -1 (APMV-1), is a devastating disease of poultry that is endemic in many countries worldwide. Several commercial vaccines and protocols are available against the disease and in most cases, they provide good clinical protection. However, despite vaccination, cases of Newcastle disease are often seen in some countries, including Mali in West Afr...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Clinicians&#x2019; perception and assessment of risk factors for surgical site infections in small animal practice in South-West, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/4EC016063852</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/4EC016063852</guid><description>
	This study evaluated the prevalence of Surgical Site Infections (SSIs), the enhancing risk factors in small animal hospitals and clinics, and clinicians perception of SSIs in South-west, Nigeria. Ten years (2007-2017) surgical patients case records from four government veterinary hospitals were initially studied. Fifty-seven copies of structured pre-tested questionnaires were further adminis...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Perception and uptake of aquaculture technologies in Kogi state, central Nigeria: imperative for Improved Management practices for sustainable  aquaculture development</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/3FAFA8E63854</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/3FAFA8E63854</guid><description>
	The drivers of perception and adoption of aquaculture innovations were studied. Data obtained from 300 aquaculture operators, were analyzed using Heckman Probit sample selection model. Results revealed that perception and adoption of aquaculture innovations were high. Education (a=0.281), extension contact (a=0.149), experience (a=0.021), gender (a=0.440) and information source (a=0.145) inc...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of pre-rice cassava/legume intercrops and weed management practices on weed dynamics and yield of low land rice in Badeggi, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D3F328763856</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D3F328763856</guid><description>
	The effects of cassava/legume intercrop-rice relay and weed management practices on weed infestation, growth and yield of rice were investigated at Badeggi, Southern Guinea Savanna of Nigeria in 2011 to 2013 cropping seasons. The treatments consisted of factorial combination of cassava (IIT 427) intercrop with: Mucuna or Velvet bean [Mucuna pruriens (L.) DC.], Cowpea [Vigna unguiculata (L.) ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysing chicken meat production comparative advantage of South Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/5D6252463858</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/5D6252463858</guid><description>
	The study examined the relative efficiency of producing chicken meat in South Africa, in 2017, and its comparative advantage in chicken meat production in Southern African Development Community (SADC). The study used the Policy Analysis Matrix (PAM) to calculate the net financial and economic profitability, Nominal Protection Coefficient of output (NPCO), Nominal Protection Coefficient of in...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Responses of soybeans (Glycine max (L.) Merrill) associated with variable plant density stress applied at different phenological stages: Plasticity or elasticity?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/75769A563860</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/75769A563860</guid><description>
	The study evaluated developmental responses associated with plant population density stress applied at different phenological phases and effects on grain yield in determinate and indeterminate soybean (Glycine max L.). A split-split plot design with four replications, with variety (main plot), plant density (sub plot) and thinning time (sub-subplot) was adopted. Two determinate genotypes (Lu...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phenotypic detection of extended spectrum &#x3B2;-lactamase and Metallo &#x3B2;-lactamase production by Gram negative uropathogens after exposure to gamma radiation
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/5B812C163864</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/5B812C163864</guid><description>
	Eighty-five uropathogen isolates were collected and differentiated on the basis of their Gram stain reaction. Among the collected isolates, 25 (29.4%) were Gram positive cocci and 60 (70.6%) were Gram negative bacilli. Antibiotic susceptibility profile towards 15 different antibiotics concluded that impenime (IMP), amikacin (AK) and Pipperacillin/tazobactam (TZP) were the most effective agai...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phytochemical screening and toxicological effects of Amblygonocarpus andongensis aqueous stem bark extract in wistar albino rat

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/D6B976163870</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/D6B976163870</guid><description>
	Amblygonocarpus andongenesis is being used as antipsychotic. Hence, it may portend high risk of toxicosis. In view of this, phytochemical screening and toxicological effects of aqueous stem bark extract of the plant was studied in wistar albino rats. Qualitative screening of the stem bark extract revealed the presence of alkaloid, hydrolysable tannin, saponin, glycoside, cardiac glycoside, s...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determination and establishment of empirical relationship between magnetic susceptibility and mechanical properties of typical basement rocks in Southwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/28678DF63872</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/28678DF63872</guid><description>
	Magnetic susceptibility and mechanical properties of rocks in a typical basement complex Southwestern Nigeria were correlated with the aim of establishing empirical equations relating the two parameters and evaluate the parameters as related to its competency in hosting civil structures. A total of thirty rock samples were taken across the geology of the area and subjected to mechanical prop...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Knowledge and understanding of energy efficiency in air-conditioning: Exploring perceptions from the manufacturing sector in Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B98B52E63874</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B98B52E63874</guid><description>
	The study investigated Energy Efficiency (EE) measures and practices from the perspectives of Ghanas manufacturing sector. A mixed methods approach that applied both qualitative and quantitative methodologies guided the study. The quantitative approach was relevant to establish statistical inferences and the qualitative methods used to provide further in-depth understanding to statistic(s) p...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Nutritional characterization pulp of Chrysobalanus icaco L.</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/7A5591D63876</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/7A5591D63876</guid><description>
	After Southeast Asia, Brazil is the second largest producer of tropical fruits having more than 500 species, and many of these have high potential regarding nutritional content that can be marketed. Among them, Chrysobalanus icaco L., which can be found in abundance in several countries of South America stands out. Among its nutritional profile, it had low value of titratable acidity (0.41  ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Seasonal variation and modeling of leaf area growth in Jatropha curcas L. plants: Implication for understanding the species adaptation in the Sahel of Niger</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/70E419363878</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/70E419363878</guid><description>
	Jatropha curcas is a tree species introduced in Niger as a trial experiment to offset land degradation and for biofuel production. The objective of this study is to contribute to the understanding of this species potential for adaptation under the edaphic and climatic conditions of Niger through analysis and modeling of the leaf area dynamics. The nondestructive method is used to evaluate th...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Notice of Retraction: Analysis of the educational bulletin presented to the teachers of the basic stage in the Jordanian Ministry of Education and the future model extracted</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/204BCB463880</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/204BCB463880</guid><description>
	The editors ofthe Educational Research and Reviews(ERR) are retracting the article, Notice of Retraction: Analysis of the educational bulletin presented to the teachers of the basic stage in the Jordanian Ministry of Education and the future model extracted published in 2019 (Vol. 14(16), pp. 559-571, October, 2019).
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sub-acute and chronic toxicity of silver nanoparticles synthesized by Azadirachta indica extract</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/A0BFB2D63881</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/A0BFB2D63881</guid><description>
	In this study, biosynthesis of silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) and its toxicity were investigated. Different functional groups responsible for adsorption, morphology and absorption of the nanoparticle were characterized using UV-Vis, Fourier transmission infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), and scanning electron microscope (SEM) analyses, respectively. The toxicity of orally administered Azadirachta i...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Optimization of plant growth regulators for meristem initiation and subsequent multiplication of five virus tested elite sweet potato varieties from Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/C5E398963883</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/C5E398963883</guid><description>
	Vegetatively propagated crops are exposed to pests every growing season, providing them with the opportunity to feed on the plants and transmit diseases. Meristem culture is an important method to clean for viruses to restore high yields. Media optimizations with different concentrations and combinations of 6-benzylamino purine (BAP) and Naphthalene Acetic Acid (NAA) were tested for their ef...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Influence of wavelet phase rotation on post stack model based seismic inversion: A case study of X-field, 
Niger Delta, Nigeria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/8B16D9963885</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/8B16D9963885</guid><description>
	The effect of wavelet phase rotation on post inversion in X-field Niger Delta has been investigated. This paper demonstrates the influence of wavelet phase employed in model based seismic inversion. It presents the problem associated with variation in wavelet phases employed in post-stack model based seismic inversion which affect the discrimination of litho-fluid contrast from inverted seis...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Selection for and biochemical characterization of DDT resistance in laboratory strains of Anopheles arabiensis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/39DFE1463887</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJB/article-abstract/39DFE1463887</guid><description>
	Resistance to conventional insecticides still constitutes a major obstacle to control of malaria vectors. Xenobiotic pollutants encountered by aquatic stages of natural populations of malarial vector species in agricultural and domestic environment are often selected due to resistance to various insecticides. The Laboratory Matatuine (MAT) and Kayamba (KGB) strains of Anopheles arabiensis we...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of germination on structural and physicochemical properties of starch in glutinous brown rice</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/A25CDC863889</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/A25CDC863889</guid><description>
	This study compared the structural and rheological properties of native (GB0), 12 h (GB12), 24 h (GB24), 36 h (GB36), 48 h (GB48) and 72 h (GB72) germinated glutinous brown rice starch to improve the market value of glutinous rice through germination. The proportion of A chains (DP 6-12) increases and the proportion of B1 chains (DP 13-24) decreased with germination time. Interestingly, we o...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing landuse effect on soil properties in the Coastal plains sand, Imo State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/8C2A1A163891</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/8C2A1A163891</guid><description>
	Impacts of landuses [old home garden (HG), oilpalm plantation (OP), fallow arable field (FA), grass lawn (GL)] on physico-chemical properties of an ultisol on a flat in the Coastal plains sand of Imo State, Nigeria were evaluated. Landuse significantly (at 5%) influenced the properties sand, organic matter (OM) content, soil reaction (pH), exchangeable cations Ca, Mg, K, exchangeable acidity...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>