<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Annals of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Annals of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Possible impairment of surgical decision making and confounded outcome in Fontan surgery by Nakata Index</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/C6BA86162946</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/C6BA86162946</guid><description>
	Since cardiac structuring dimensions inform surgical decisions making, Z-score systematic error impairs surgical decision making and confounds outcome measurement, hence a similar error may affect the Nakata index. In this study, PubMed was searched using the terms: pulmonary, artery, size, Nakata, Fontan, and outcome. Studies that did not describe the outcome of the Fontan procedure and the...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Using technology and innovation to address the three delays in access to cardiac surgery.</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/036BDFF63312</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/036BDFF63312</guid><description>
	Cardiovascular diseases (CVD) make up the leading cause of mortality in the world with 17.65 million deaths every year, of which more than 80% occurs in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs). (1) With the ongoing shift of the global burden of CVD towards low-resource settings, a mortality rate of 25 million deaths is projected in these regions by 2030. (2) Nevertheless, it is estimated th...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The diagnosis and comprehensive management of congenital heart diseases in nations with severely restricted general and specialist healthcare services.</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/77EB43F63313</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/77EB43F63313</guid><description>
	Disease (CHD) in clinically sub-optimal settings. It is presented to provide simple diferences between certain conditions commonly seen in children with CHD for training doctors and nurses and other staff working within the speciality. In the majority of clinical presentations, a comprehensive, well structured training of a multidisciplinary team and carefully chosen hospital equipment and r...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prise en charge des varices des membres inferieurs au centre hospitalier universitaire de brazzaville</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/F990B0F63314</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/F990B0F63314</guid><description>
	Aim : To describe epidemiological, clinical, etiologic, and therapeutic aspects of lower limbs varicose veins.

	Patients-methods : It was a retrospective study, carried out from May 2016 to June 2018 at Brazzaville teaching hospital. All patients who has been operated and medical records had surgical approach data were included. Patients were classified according to modified Hawai 2004 cl...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chest surgical approaches in Africa: a constant challenge</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/B1BE19763331</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/B1BE19763331</guid><description>
	Objective:

	Thoracic surgical approach has taken a decisive turn since videoscopy utilization for cardiac and non-cardiac thoracic surgery. This study aims to present indications and results of chest surgical approaches performed in Cote dIvoire. Methods: Using the 1998 and 2014 nationwide inpatient database, we identified retrospectivly 814 patients including 475 men and 339 women who un...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Surgical aspects of rheumatic heart disease: Part 3</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/5D129A160755</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/5D129A160755</guid><description>
	Acute Rheumatic Fever (ARF) and Rheumatic Heart Disease (RHD) remain significant noncommunicable diseases in developing countries and emerging economies. Part one of this five part series discussed general aspects of ARF and RHD. Part two focused on medical and interventional approaches and treatment. The present part three will focus on surgical aspects of RHD. This will highlight the histo...</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges in open heart surgery (OHS) in Africa:
C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire experience
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/BF3BC2460757</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/BF3BC2460757</guid><description>
	I would like to thank the United States Chapter of the ISS (slide 3) for inviting me at the ACS clinical congress 2015(slide 4) and give me an opportunity to speak on Challenges in Open Heart Surgery in Africa: Cote dIvoire Experience(slide 5).
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>C&#xF4;te cervicale inductrice d&#x2019;un pseudo-an&#xE9;vrysme de l&#x2019;art&#xE8;re sousclavi&#xE8;re et d&#x2019;un syndrome de la travers&#xE9;e thoraco-brachiale : &#xC0; propos d&#x2019;un cas &#xE0; Yaound&#xE9; (Cameroun).</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/859219B60759</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/859219B60759</guid><description>
	La cote cervicale est une anomalie congnitale exceptionnelle, tout comme lanvrysme de lartre subclavire qui est une pathologie rare. Nous rapportons le cas dun homme, travailleur manuel prsentant des douleurs et gonflement cervical bas  droite dont le bilan scnographique a rvl une cte cervicale avec anvrysme de lartre subclavire

	Mots cls: cte cervicale, anvrysme
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Insurance type is a major predictor of lower extremity amputation following infra-popliteal arterial trauma</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/76924C060761</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/76924C060761</guid><description>
	Background: Following traumatic infrapopliteal arterial injury, salvageability of the leg is often attributed to injury-related variables. We investigated factors influencing amputation.Method: The United States National Trauma Data Bank was retrospectively examined identifying subjects aged  18 with tibial arterial injuries. Demographic, injury-related, co-morbid, and other variables were a...</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Open heart surgery in West Africa: history, surgical experience, and challenges</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/F15C4BF60845</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AATCVS/article-abstract/F15C4BF60845</guid><description/><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>