<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Agricultural Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Agricultural Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Production of liquid fertilizer by fermented livestock liquid and application on crops</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/0D0B67463809</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/0D0B67463809</guid><description>
	The livestock liquid commonly contains humic acid, amino acids and minerals; hence, it can be used for the fertilization of crops. These studies were conducted to examine the use of livestock fermented liquid in producing liquid fertilizers and irrigation application on two kinds of crops (tomato and wax apple). The experiments were designed as common liquid fertilizer and diluted by groundw...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of combined salt and flooding stresses on the growth and physiological behavior of alfalfa (Medicago sativa L.)
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/2D9500063811</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/2D9500063811</guid><description>
	The present work focused on evaluation of the physiological and metabolic behavior of alfalfa (Medicago sativa L., var. Siriver), when faced with two important ecosystems constraints, namely salinity and flooding-associated hypoxia. After germination, seedlings in symbiosis with Sinorhizobium meliloti were grown on different salt concentrations (0, 20 and 50 mM NaCl). At four weeks post-germ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Promotion of rice growth and productivity as a result of seed inoculation with Azospirillum brasilense</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D0AFA7163813</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D0AFA7163813</guid><description>
	The present study refers to the results obtained in four experiments carried out in the 2015/2016 crop: Toledo/PR; Palotina/PR; Cascavel/PR; and So Miguel do Iguau/PR. The objective of the present study was to evaluate the agronomic efficiency of Azospirillum brasilense (pest strains Ab-V5 and Ab-V6) in four distinct rice culture regions (Oryza sativa L.). The tests were performed to meet th...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Severity and prevalence of the destructive fall armyworm on maize in Uganda: A case of 
Bulambuli District
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/E6D997463815</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/E6D997463815</guid><description>
	Maize kernel contains a large quantity of carbohydrates, proteins, vitamins, oils, fats and competes favorably with root and tuber crops as a rich energy source. In Uganda, the per capita consumption ranges from 28 to 125 kg per annum. However, the yields remain low, fluctuating around 1.5 tons per hectare. Although some losses to maize production occur through the post-harvest period, pre-h...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Potential of reduced agricultural lime application rates to increase yield and profitability of maize through microdosing in central Malawi - A short note</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/A317EA763817</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/A317EA763817</guid><description>
	Maize (Zea mays L.) is a staple food crop in Malawi, with average yields of 1.8 -2.2 t ha-1 compared to potential yields of 5 to 10 t ha-1. In some areas, soil acidity is a serious constraint in crop production. The current recommendation is to apply 2.0 t ha-1 of lime as pre-plant broadcast and incorporated into soils with pHW  5.5. A pilot study was conducted during 2015/2016 season at Bun...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Role of leaf rolling on agronomic performances of durum wheat subjected to water stress</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/7FFC4FE63819</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/7FFC4FE63819</guid><description>
	In arid and semi-arid climates characterized by low rainfall with a great annual and inter-annual irregularity, drought can occur at any time inducing large losses in crop yield. Leaf rolling is one of the adaptive morphological responses to the water deficit observed in a number of species including cereals. It reduces the leaf area exposed to sunlight and transpiration. The aim of the pres...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fertilizer-nitrogen use optimization for Tef in South Wollo Zone of Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/68FB5D363821</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/68FB5D363821</guid><description>
	Tef [Eragrotis tef] is a major staple cereal crop in Ethiopia but yields are low due to inadequate nutrient supply and other constraints. A field study was conducted in 2014 and 2015 in Jamma district of South Wollo Zone of Amhara Region to determine the economic optimum rate of fertilizer-N for tef. Fertilizer-N rates of 0, 23, 46, 69, 92, 115 and 138 kg ha-1 were evaluated. The randomized ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Perception and uptake of aquaculture technologies in Kogi state, central Nigeria: imperative for Improved Management practices for sustainable  aquaculture development</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/3FAFA8E63854</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/3FAFA8E63854</guid><description>
	The drivers of perception and adoption of aquaculture innovations were studied. Data obtained from 300 aquaculture operators, were analyzed using Heckman Probit sample selection model. Results revealed that perception and adoption of aquaculture innovations were high. Education (a=0.281), extension contact (a=0.149), experience (a=0.021), gender (a=0.440) and information source (a=0.145) inc...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of pre-rice cassava/legume intercrops and weed management practices on weed dynamics and yield of low land rice in Badeggi, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D3F328763856</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/D3F328763856</guid><description>
	The effects of cassava/legume intercrop-rice relay and weed management practices on weed infestation, growth and yield of rice were investigated at Badeggi, Southern Guinea Savanna of Nigeria in 2011 to 2013 cropping seasons. The treatments consisted of factorial combination of cassava (IIT 427) intercrop with: Mucuna or Velvet bean [Mucuna pruriens (L.) DC.], Cowpea [Vigna unguiculata (L.) ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysing chicken meat production comparative advantage of South Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/5D6252463858</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJAR/article-abstract/5D6252463858</guid><description>
	The study examined the relative efficiency of producing chicken meat in South Africa, in 2017, and its comparative advantage in chicken meat production in Southern African Development Community (SADC). The study used the Policy Analysis Matrix (PAM) to calculate the net financial and economic profitability, Nominal Protection Coefficient of output (NPCO), Nominal Protection Coefficient of in...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>