<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Business Management - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Business Management</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>The effect of entrepreneurial orientation on firms&#x2019; performance of the telecommunication sector in Sudan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/30ABEA263800</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/30ABEA263800</guid><description>
	The purpose of this research is to investigate the effect of entrepreneurial orientation (EO) on firms performance in the telecommunication sector in Sudan. The EO is reflected in innovativeness, pro-activeness, risk-taking, competitive aggressiveness and autonomy which have been treated as a one-dimensional construct. Firms performance has been measured by financial and non-financial indica...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Doing well by doing well? Evidence from manufacturing sector of Pakistan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/87C200863451</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/87C200863451</guid><description>
	According to the value enhancement and agency cost theory, corporate voluntarily contribution has a positive or negative impact on the overall performance of a firm. In contrast to these theories sometimes corporate giving has no impact on the firms performance. This article will provide insight on the impact of corporate giving on Pakistans publically traded manufacturing companies. This ar...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The effect of workplace incivility on organizational outcome (mediating role of psychological capital)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/000637963499</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/000637963499</guid><description>
	The major purpose of this study was to assess the impact of workplace incivility on organizational outcomes as well as the mediating effect of psychological capital on this process particularly in academic organization in Fiji. To accomplish this purpose, personal distribution of 250 questionnaires was given to the teachers. The final response rate from employees was 90% (225/250). The resul...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Audit quality in non-listed Italian firms</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/D35890C63512</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/D35890C63512</guid><description>
	This study investigates the audit quality of Big-x auditing companies within the context of the Italian non-listed firms by examining (i) auditing ability to restrict accrual-based earnings management and (ii) the level of auditing independence. The Italian non-listed firms provide a unique set of auditing environment with multiple layers of audit quality compared to other European auditing ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The efficiency implications of corporate 
earnings retentions
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/083039063571</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/083039063571</guid><description>
	The study examines the efficiency of the investment of corporate income retention. If retained earnings are invested in positive net present value projects, they should enhance the shareholder value in the long run. It is believed that the stock market adds premium to a firms earnings when the firm signals more retention of earnings. However, the stock market is seen to reverse the disciplin...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors affecting women entrepreneurs in establishing their own business: The case of Afar Region, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/93441FF63278</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/93441FF63278</guid><description>
	Womens productive activities, particularly in industry, empower them economically and enable them to contribute more to overall development. Whether they are involved in small or medium-scale production activities, or the informal or formal sectors, womens entrepreneurial activities are not only a means for economic survival but also have positive social repercussions for the women themselve...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Technology and government regulation: A conceptual perspective of entrepreneurial orientation on creditworthiness of micro-enterprises</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/E2F71C063315</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/E2F71C063315</guid><description>
	Owing to globalization, enterprises continue to face increasing pressure from competition across the globe. When compounded with the changing needs of customers, complex business uncertainty and market instability, it becomes apparent that enterprises face increasing challenges in improving and maintaining business performance over time unless they actively manage these pressures. Entreprene...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How universities fill the talent gap: The data scientist in the Italian case</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/03FC69A62893</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/03FC69A62893</guid><description>
	This research paper explores Italian study programs in data science in order to verify if knowledge and skills developed during the universities path are fit with data scientist job demand. The issue is introduced considering the companies growing need to derive insights from data, and consequently, to search for a staff with analytical expertise, the so-called data scientists quite rare. Li...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Research on risk early-warning system of transitional operation of Africa-related enterprises</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/B83E78863206</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/B83E78863206</guid><description>
	The growing business prosperity in African countries has brought new opportunities for enterprises to carry out transnational operation in Africa; however, it may also be accompanied by some transnational operation risks. Enterprises incorrectly identify and analyze these risks, which brings enterprises great uncertainty and huge losses. So enterprises should establish a transnational operat...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How crowdfunding makes museum value relevant: An Italian university museum experience</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/87830E163223</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBM/article-abstract/87830E163223</guid><description>
	This study has attempted to enlarge the debate on museums relevant function, in connection to their mission to contribute to the development of the civic society. The research idea has stemmed from the issue of museum accessibility, through measured observation of a co-creation project carried out by a University Museum of Lombardy (Italy) through a crowdfunding campaign. The research has ai...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>