<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Biochemistry Research  - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Biochemistry Research </description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Vitellaria paradoxa fruit pulp bioethanol production potential: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/55DC41763563</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/55DC41763563</guid><description>
	In the last decade, bioethanol has become a powerful biofuel for the improvement of environmental pollution such as reduction in greenhouse gas levels. Yet, the source and type of substrate material plays a crucial role in the bioethanol production process due to the different compositional characteristics and availability of monomeric sugars. Different substrates of first, second and third ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluationof in vivo toxicity of rice husk used as fuel for cooking in households</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/D904F4C63565</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/D904F4C63565</guid><description>
	This study meant to assess the toxicological impact of nourishment cooked or water overflowed with a fan-helped top-lit-updraft rice husk fuelled gasifier stove named Paul Olivier 150 (PO150). Refined water was bubbled for 1 h utilizing this stove in an opened pot and shut room. This water was then cooled to room temperature before being managed to the rodents with body loads going from 70 t...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The effect of aqueous extract of zest of citrus sinensis (AEZCs) on cadmium chloride induced liver toxicity in wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/5C018F763079</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/5C018F763079</guid><description>
	The potency of the peels of Citrus sinensis against cadmium induced liver damage has not been explored in our environment. 48 wistar rats were used for this study. The animals were randomly divided into eight (8) groups of five (5) rats each. Group A was the positive control and received 5 mg/kg body weight (bw) of cadmium chloride (CdCl2) intraperitoneally as a single dose. Groups B and C r...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of dyslipidemia in a Burkinabe military population
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/CAC4DA362702</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/CAC4DA362702</guid><description>
	The objective of this study was to determine the prevalence of dyslipidemia in soldiers received at the laboratory of the Medical Center Camp General Aboubacar Sangoul Lamizana (CMCGASL) for a medical visit. This is a prospective study of 224 military personnel assigned to peacekeeping missions outside Burkina Faso. The study was conducted over the period of September 2017 to November 2017. ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lambda-Cyhalothrin induced hepato-nephro toxicity potentials and post treatment recovery in 
Clarias garipinus
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/B43B85763340</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/B43B85763340</guid><description>
	This evaluates the 28-day toxicity and 7-day post treatment effect of LCT on the behaviour, liver and kidney of Clarias gariepinus. Prior to the experiment, fishes were acclimatized for two weeks. 120 fishes of standard length (SL) / weight (W) 10-12 cm, 8 - 17 g were used for median lethal concentration (LC50) test and 120 fishes of SL / W 16 - 40 cm, 200 - 250 g were used for the behaviour...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Study of some biochemical parameters of the seeds of the fruit of the sweet Maniguette (Aframomum alboviolaceum (ridl.) k. Schum.)  harvested in the Republic of the Congo</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/0028E7263342</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/0028E7263342</guid><description>
	Aframomum alboviolaceum is a plant that belongs to the family of Zingiberaceae, genus Aframomum and species of A. alboviolaceum. It is wide spread across tropical Africa and represented about 50 species. Proximate analysis is usually done to determine the values of macronutrients present in plant or food sample; it gives the composition of the biomass in terms of gross components. Proximate ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Increased levels of mannose-6-phosphate/insulin-like growth factor 2 receptor (M6P/IGF2-R) found in serum of patients with breast cancer</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/050C7DA62653</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/050C7DA62653</guid><description>
	The multifunctional transmembrane mannose-6-phosphate/insulin-like growth factor-2 receptor (M6P/IGF2-R) has been proposed as a putative prognostic marker in breast cancer. Loss of heterozygosity (LOH) with mutations in the remaining allele have been described at the gene level. We previously reported significant decrease of M6P/IGF2-R at the protein level in cancer cells than normal peritum...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Proximate, mineral and phytochemical compositions of Vernonia amygdalina leaves grown under hot and humid tropical conditions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/578E3CA61631</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/578E3CA61631</guid><description>
	This study was conducted to determine the proximate and phytochemical compositions of Vernonia amygdalina leaves, to ascertain its nutritional potentials. V. amygdalina plants were cultivated, and the leaves were harvested at maturity, cleaned and apportioned into two; one portion was oven dried whilst the other was air-dried- all to a moisture content of about 15%. The dried samples were pu...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Statistical optimization of L&#x2013;glutaminase production by Trichoderma species under solid state fermentation using African locust beans as substrate</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/042FD6061305</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/042FD6061305</guid><description>
	Six strains of Trichoderma species isolated from soil and air samples were screened for extracellular L-glutaminase production. The highest enzyme producing isolate, Trichoderma longibrachiatum was subjected to screening and nutrients optimization experiments under solid state fermentation using a constant weight of African locust beans as substrate. A specific activity of 54.96 U/mg was ach...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The pro-oxidant effect of dextran sodium sulphate on oxidative stress biomarkers and antioxidant enzymes in Drososphila melanogaster</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/6EF3FF361311</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJBR/article-abstract/6EF3FF361311</guid><description>
	This study sought to evaluate the behavioural and biochemical effects of Dextran Sodium Sulphate (DSS) on the oxidative stress biomarkers and antioxidant enzymes. Drosophila melanogaster (both sexes) of 3 days old were exposed to various DSS incorporated diets at concentrations, 0.5 - 3.0% for a period of 14 days (Survival rate). The second phase comprised of 3 groups; Group I- Control (norm...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>