<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Cellular Pathology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Cellular Pathology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Effect of n-butanol extract of Cannabis sativa L. extract on the cerebral cortex of adult Wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/3D4607662980</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/3D4607662980</guid><description>
	The present study was aimed at investigating the effect of Cannabis sativa L. administration on neurobehavior and histology of the frontal cortex ofadult Wistar rats. Eighteen (18) adult Wistar rats (120 to 140 g) were divided into three (3) groups of six (6) animals per. Animals in group 1 (control) were given 1 ml/kg distilled water, while groups 2 and 3 were administered with 250 and 500 ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phytochemical and in vitro antioxidant studies on methanol extract of Vernonia calvoana leaf and its polar fractions: Preliminary study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/5C970A562632</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/5C970A562632</guid><description>
	This study aims to screen possible antioxidant potentials of methanol extract and polar fractions of Vernonia calvoana leaves and its phytochemical constituents since the leaves are used ethno medically in managing ailments like wounds, blood pressure, inflammation, arthritis, and bone diseases. Dried leaves (900 g) were ground and de-fatted with n-hexane. The dry marc was extracted using 80...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of the effect of post-natal lead exposure on the hippocampus of developing Wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/65BB6BA62423</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/65BB6BA62423</guid><description>
	This study examined the effect of post-natal lead exposure on the hippocampus of developing Wistar rats. Nine pregnant Wistar rats were randomly distributed into three groups of three rats each, consisting of a control Group 1 which received distilled water and experimental Groups 2 and 3 orally administered with 60 and 90 mg/kg bwt of lead acetate, respectively. The pups of the experimental...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A comparative study of cultural and molecular techniques for the identification of bacterial contaminants of cockroaches (Periplaneta americana)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/A1FC08D61715</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/A1FC08D61715</guid><description>
	The increasing trends of insect associated bacterial infection in humans are severely hampered by disparaging number of bacteria obtained with the culture-based technique. This study therefore determined how the analysis of the 16S rDNA sequences would compare in terms of precision and reliability to the most adoptable culture-based technique. Results obtained depict enhanced accuracy of mol...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Umbilical cord torsion leading to intrauterine fetal death</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/F0902D161224</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/F0902D161224</guid><description>
	The umbilical cord is the critical organ that links the placenta and fetus. The intrauterine conditions and fetal activity influences the umbilical cord length. The normal umbilical cord is spiraled. By ultrasound, the spiral nature of the umbilical cord can be demonstrated early in the &#xFB01;rst trimester. Most of the adverse pregnancy and perinatal outcomes are related to abnormal Umbilical Cor...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Temporal bone histopathology study on cochlear otosclerosis: A memoir for the cochlear 
implant surgeon
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/84DCA1261226</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/84DCA1261226</guid><description>
	The aim of this study was to describe the pathologic changes in temporal bones with cochlear otosclerosis that may have implications for cochlear implantation. Fifteen human temporal bones with otosclerosis were used for this study. In each temporal bone was studied: (1) medial wall of the middle ear and in particular the horizontal segment of the facial nerve canal; (2) the round window nic...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>CD34 positive stem cells recovered from cord blood remain viable after six months of cryoprotective storage process</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/7DFAAEF60946</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/7DFAAEF60946</guid><description>
	Cord blood can be used as an alternative source for bone marrow transplantation and its use is developing into a new field of treatment for patients presenting with haematological disorders, immunological defects and specific genetic diseases; including haemoglobinopathies. The aim was to assess the viability of frozen cord blood as a source of HSC which may be suitable for transplantation. ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of formalin fixation on DNA purity and quantity, nucleic acid, and amplicon size in cervical human papilloma virus detection</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/9AE449F58813</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/9AE449F58813</guid><description>
	Tissue fixation with 10% formalin and molten paraffin wax embedding (FFPE) is routinely used protocol for tissue preservation in histopathology laboratory. We therefore aimed at comparing the differences in DNA quantity, DNA purity, nucleic acid and its effect on primers (PCR) amplicon (bp) sizes between fresh cervical tissues and formalin fixed paraffin embedded (FFPE). The differences in D...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Some plasma biochemical changes in layers experimentally infected with Pasteurella multocida</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/689E09E58342</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/689E09E58342</guid><description>
	The present study was carried out to investigate some biochemical alterations in layers experimentally infected with Pasteurella multocida. A total of 20 eighteen-week old ISA Brown layers were used in the experiment. The birds were randomly assigned to two groups (infected and control) of 10 layers each. To establish infection, each bird in the infected group was challenged by intra nasal (...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of Theobroma cacao on renal function of wistar albino rats induced with anaemia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/91A36E458347</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJCPath/article-abstract/91A36E458347</guid><description>
	The study investigated the effect of Theobroma cacao on renal function of phenylhydrazine induced anaemic albino rats. Forty albino rats were divided into 8 groups of five rats each namely control (group A), Phenyl hydrazine (group B) while groups C, D and E were given phenylhydrazine and administered with 100,200 and 500 mg/kg of T. cacao respectively while groups F, G and H were given 200,...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>