<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Environmental Science and Technology  - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Environmental Science and Technology </description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Assessment of agricultural practices on water quality of the Tono Dam in the Upper East Region of Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/20E43FD63715</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/20E43FD63715</guid><description>
	Population growth has resulted in drastic increase in demand for agricultural products for consumption and also as raw materials for agro-based industries. Associated with this increased demand is the application of agrochemicals to increase yields. This study assessed the impact of agricultural practices employed by farmers in the Tono catchment in the Upper East Region of Ghana on water qu...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The mediating effect of effective decision making on the design of water resource management ICT model: The case of the management of Lake Victoria Basin</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/4A6A26263862</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/4A6A26263862</guid><description>
	Partial Least Square-Structural Equation Modelling (PLS- SEM) technique was employed to evaluate the mediating effects of effective decision making on water resource management policies and water resource management frameworks in the design of water resource management ICT model for an integrated water resource management of Lake Victoria Basin (LVB). Researchers took a quantitative approach...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The impact of sea water intrusion on the spatial variability of the physical and chemical properties of ground water in Limbe-Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/74E703563495</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/74E703563495</guid><description>
	A significant proportion of the population of Limbe, a coastal town in Cameroon, relies on ground water (gw) to satisfy their drinking water needs. The coastal aquifer is threatened by pollution from sea water intrusion and hence the aim of this study was to determine the suitability of the water. Physico-chemical analysis were carried out on samples collected from the study area and the Rev...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors affecting the development of effective water resource management policies: The case of the management of Lake Victoria Basin in Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/E131C1163635</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/E131C1163635</guid><description>
	Partial least square-structural equation modelling (PLS-SEM) was used to evaluate the factors affecting the development of effective water resource management policies. Researchers employed a purposive sampling method to come up with the most suitable respondents. The sample size of 152 respondents was computed from a population size of 245 water experts within Lake Victoria Basin (LVB) in U...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Land capability analysis and delineation of erosion prone areas in the case of Kulfo Watershed, Abaya Chamo Basin</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/E48A60963463</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/E48A60963463</guid><description>
	Land is a basic natural resource which is essential for the survival and development of human being, since it supports all kind of livelihood and infrastructure. But due to varying drivers it is under the threat of degradation. Thus, the aim of this research was to analyze the land capability and delineation of erosion prone areas for sustainable watershed management in the case of Kulfo wat...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impacts of climate change on sorghum production in North Eastern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/B7FDF7862990</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/B7FDF7862990</guid><description>
	Climate change/variability is a global concern that is seriously affecting developing and least developed countries which rain-fed based agriculture is predominantly the basis for their livelihood and socio-economic system. Adverse impacts of climate change and variability, in most developing and least developed countries like Ethiopia, is growing in time and exert pressure on agricultural s...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative study of physicochemical parameters of wastewater discharged at the beaches of the Dakar Coast</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/1D81C2B62994</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/1D81C2B62994</guid><description>
	The region of Dakar is characterized by a high population density often leading to a problem of development of the sewage network not equipped with a treatment station. The ejection of these raw untreated waters on the Dakar coast continually causes pollution of bays, seawater and threatens life in the aquatic environment and human health. The objective of this study is to assess the physico...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Application of a decision support tool for municipal solid waste open dumps remediation in Cape Verde</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/CFCA4AE62988</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/CFCA4AE62988</guid><description>
	Open dumps are places where solid waste is disposed directly on the ground, without any environmental assessment, resulting in environmental, societal and economic damages. In Cape Verde, most of the municipalities dispose their solid waste on open dumps. Cape Verdes new policies on solid waste management determined the closure and the remediation of all the dumps around the country. In this...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spatiotemporal variation of irrigation water quality at Bochessa Watershed in Central Rift Valley of Ethiopia </title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/E212F9D63172</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/E212F9D63172</guid><description>
	Water quality is a highly concerning issue as long as irrigation is planned to be used for crop production. Hence, groundwater at Bochessa catchment was assessed to determine the spatiotemporal variability of its quality and to evaluate its suitability for irrigation. For this study, 8 boreholes were selected and sampling was done during the dry and wet seasons between 2015 and 2017. Totally...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Agro-ecological assessment of physico-chemical properties of soils in Kulfo Watershed, South Western Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/F5CB67162520</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJEST/article-abstract/F5CB67162520</guid><description>
	Variation in physical landscape of the highlands gives rise to variations in agro-climatic and soil parent materials in Ethiopia. The aim of this research is to characterize the physio-chemical properties of soils in Kulfo watershed. For the study, primary data from transect walks, composite soil samples and GPS points and secondary data from satellite imaginaries, National Metrological Agen...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>