<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Food Science - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Food Science</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Microbial quality of artisanal yoghurt and D&#xE8;gu&#xE8; products collected in schools of Cotonou and Abomey-Calavi (Benin)
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/BD7EF2263914</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/BD7EF2263914</guid><description>
	The main aim of this study is to evaluate the microbiological quality of yoghurt and two types of dgu (couscous and millet) sold in Cotonou and Abomey-Calavi. Samples of dairy products were collected in 15 schools of Abomey-Calavi and Cotonou from vendors located inside the schools. In this study, 180 samples (60 yoghurt, 60-dgu millet and 60-dgu couscous) were analysed. The microbial qualit...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of Arabusta coffee hybrids [Coffea arabica L. X Tetraploid Robusta (Coffea canephora )] for  green bean physical properties and cup quality</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/DBE061163916</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/DBE061163916</guid><description>
	Robusta coffee is known to be high yielding than Arabica coffee, since it is more vigorous in growth. However, it is limited by the inferior cup quality. The aim of the study was to evaluate the performance of the Arabusta hybrids and its backcross derivatives for bean physical characteristics and organoleptic properties including their interrelationship. Nineteen coffee genotypes were evalu...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Influence of temperature and time on microbial, physicochemical and functional quality of goat milk</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/B43FB8363639</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/B43FB8363639</guid><description>
	Microbial load in fresh milk has a significant effect on its keeping quality and nutritional value. From Prehistoric time, human used heat process to reduce microbials load in raw milk to improve its sensory characteristics. This research is proposed to treat fresh goat milk with heating process to provide optimal pasteurization conditions that does not influence the goat milk chemical compo...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of processing methods on fatty acid profiles and biochemical compounds of Arabica coffee cultivars</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/05DA35E63735</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/05DA35E63735</guid><description>
	Coffee cherries were processed traditionally by the wet method that uses large quantities of water and eco-friendly methods that utilizes less water and operate mechanically to remove mucilage. The study is aimed at determining the effects of traditional and newly developed coffee processing methods on fatty acid profiles and biochemical components of two coffee cultivars. A complete randomi...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sensory evaluation of four pepper soup dishes prepared with four varieties of protein sources using Itsekiri pepper soup spices</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/C29669963737</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/C29669963737</guid><description>
	Four types of protein sources were used in the preparation of pepper soup dishes using Itsekiri pepper soup spices were evaluated. The protein sources used for the pepper soup dishes were: Cow-leg, goat meat, fresh fish and dry stock fish. Sensory evaluation of the four pepper soup dishes was done using 40 trained panelists based on a 5-point hedonic scale. Result on the acceptability of the...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of different processing conditions on the quality of canned sweet corn kernels produced and processed in Senegal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/AF8162D63784</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/AF8162D63784</guid><description>
	In Senegal, sweet corn is produced for export market while the canned ones are imported to supply national market. This work was carried out to investigate the effect of different processing conditions such as heating temperature and sterilization time on the microbial quality, color, ascorbic acid and shelf life of canned sweet corn produced in Senegal. The hygiene level of sweet corn sampl...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fruit juices in polysaccharides edible films</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/88A3F2F63420</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/88A3F2F63420</guid><description>
	In this study, jambolan and grape juices were used to produce polysaccharide-based edible films by the solvent-casting technique. The polysaccharides used were carboxymethyl cellulose, hydroxypropyl methyl cellulose, high-methoxyl pectin, low-methoxyl pectin, sodium alginate, and locust bean gum. The films exhibited good mechanical resistance and flexibility, with tensile strength (8 to 28 M...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Variability of nutrients in Parkia biglobosa kernels from three geographical regions in Burkina Faso</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/77721C163567</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/77721C163567</guid><description>
	This study aimed to determine the nutritional composition of the kernels of the African locust bean, Parkia biglobosa, collected in three populations (Louda, Nobr and Pni) representative of different environmental conditions, from more arid in the northern population (Louda) to wetter in the most southern population (Pni). Biochemical analyses were carried out using standard methods. Results...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of the incorporation of graded levels of turmeric (Curcuma longa) on different qualities of stirred yoghurt</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/E5F9C3C63637</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/E5F9C3C63637</guid><description>
	There is an increasing trend in yoghurt consumption due to the health benefits from the gut bacteria present in yoghurt. However, there is need to evaluate other inexpensive nutrient sources such as spices (turmeric) which contain a lot of phytochemicals to make yoghurt more nutritious. Fresh turmeric rhizome was sorted, washed, peeled and milled. Ethanol was added to obtain turmeric extract...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Isolation of Escherichia coli 0157:H7 from selected food samples sold in local markets in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/3782A9763156</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJFS/article-abstract/3782A9763156</guid><description>
	Food borne illnesses have major social and economic impacts. Escherichia coli O157:H7 is associated with food borne illness in human beings. It has been an important food borne pathogen that causes food borne diseases such as diarrhea, hemolytic uremic syndrome and hemorrhagic colitis. This study was conducted to detect the presence of E. coli O157: H7 in different food samples sold in Niger...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>