<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of History and Culture - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of History and Culture</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Critical analysis of archaeological research trends in Uganda: 1920-2018</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/8EF52CA63257</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/8EF52CA63257</guid><description>
	Much as the first collections of stone tools in East Africa were made by geologist J.W. Gregory, beginning in 1893, E.J. Waylands joined the government service in Uganda in 1919 to set East African Archaeology on the course that it was to follow for the next 40 years or more. However, over 90 years from its inception, a larger percentage of archaeological research in Uganda seems regionally ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Pawnship labour and mediation in colonial Osun division of southwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/B7C98F963125</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/B7C98F963125</guid><description>
	Pawnship was both a credit system and an important source of labour in Yoruba land. It was highly utilised in the first half of the twentieth century Osun Division, sequel to its easy adaptation to the colonial monetised economy. This study examined pawnship as a labour system that was deeply rooted in the Yoruba culture, and accounts for the reasons for its easy adaptability to the changes ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The shared pain of a culture&#x2019;s decline: A study of Femi Abodunrin&#x2019;s &#x2018;The Dancing Masquerade&#x2019;</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/3666B2062929</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/3666B2062929</guid><description>
	Although in recent years Africans have, through their very rich indigenous performing traditions, began once again to re-affirm the functionality of their arts, yet not many people today have tried to relate these to questions of mass mobilization and conscientization. It is believed that African art and particularly traditional African theatre, story-telling or art serve a social function w...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Increasing participatory space in Zimbabwean local governance democracy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/6A350F462540</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/6A350F462540</guid><description>
	The purpose of this paper is to unpack the extent to which citizen participation has been enhanced in local governance in Zimbabwe. The paper points out that citizen participation in local governance have proved to be of significance to all decision-making processes. Legislative provisions guiding citizen participation in local governance in Zimbabwe are prescribed in the Urban Councils Act ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Oyo-Ondo relations: A study in pristine inter-group relations in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/5384C7962232</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/5384C7962232</guid><description>
	The noticeable degree of Benin and Ife influence on Ondo has not obliterated the Oyo factor as a strong force in the history of Ondo, especially its traditions of origin. This paper focuses on Oyo-Ondo connections as a study in pristine inter-group relations. It argues that although Oyo is situated in the savanna region of Yorubaland, while Ondo is placed in the forest region, certain traits...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Democratization and nation-building in Nigeria, from 1914 to 2004: An appraisal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/FE8A15961573</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/FE8A15961573</guid><description>
	Nigeria came into being in 1914 following the British colonial authoritys amalgamation of the Northern and Southern protectorates during which various ethnicities were living independently of each other. However, the activities leading up to the 1914 amalgamation predates this date. It would therefore not be out of place to say that the most enduring legacy of British colonialism is the geo-...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Facing social-politcal challenges: A historical examination on the survival methods of the Nubi
 ethnic minority in Uganda
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/118886F60625</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/118886F60625</guid><description>
	Since the pacification of Uganda by the British Imperial Government in 1894, up to the time Nubians were recognized as an ethnic community in 1995, they continue to retain their indigenous ethnic identity, through professing Islam, speaking their traditional language (Ki-Nubi) and practicing their own traditional values, for example traditional dressings and foods. Nubians quest for survival...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Beneficiaries&#x2019; perceptions of the contributions of community development projects to peacebuilding process in South Sudan: A case of Terekeka State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/750108960692</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/750108960692</guid><description>
	Despite the fact that a lot of research has been done about community development in relations to peacebuilding, there are a few studies available on the contribution of community development projects to peacebuilding process. The intention of this article is to start to fill the gap by investigating beneficiaries perceptions of the contribution of the community development projects to peace...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>&#x2018;&#x2018;We Did Not Come as Mercenaries&#x2026;!&#x2019;: Linking the Origin, Ethnic Identity and Settlement of the Nubis in Uganda
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/3410C7860468</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/3410C7860468</guid><description>
	Focusing on the period 1894 to 1995 and drawing on both written and oral sources, this article explores the origin, ethnic identity and settlement of the Nubians since their advent in Uganda. Ugandan Nubians abandoned some aspects of their former African traditional customs and adopted new ones borrowed from the Arabic culture, constituting a unique and distinct ethnic group. Using a histori...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The predicaments of the&#x201C;Grand narrative&#x201D; of Ethiopian history:The challenges of post modernism</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/0A072A360291</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJHC/article-abstract/0A072A360291</guid><description>
	The shadow of skepticism that post modernist casted on the Meta narrative is so encompassing that it led to conspicuous cynicism on the objectivity of history as a scientific discipline. This article raises this issue by discussing and analyzing the arguments of Samir Yusuf; a post-modernist critique of Bahiru Zewdies A history of modern Ethiopia. The research, using such analytical tools as...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>