<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Mathematics and Computer Science Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Mathematics and Computer Science Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Funmatics: The future generation of African mathematical scientists - How their minds works</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/15853D263767</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/15853D263767</guid><description>
	Mathematics is the science that deals with the logic of shape, quantity and arrangement, and mathematical sciences have become important aspects of everyday life. It underpins many fields that provide benefits for humanities including but not limited to Internet search, medical imaging, computer animation, numerical weather predictions, and all types of digital communications (Hu, 2016)

	
</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Three-step optimized block backward differentiation formulae (TOBBDF) for solving stiff ordinary 
differential equations
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/ADC850063396</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/ADC850063396</guid><description>
	A three-step optimized block backward differentiation formulae for solving stiff ordinary differential equations of first-orderdifferential equations is presented. The method adopts polynomial of order 6 and three hybrid pointschosen appropriately to optimize the local truncation errors of the main formulas for the block. The method is zero-stable and consistent with sixth algebraic order. S...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An internal heat source in temperature rate dependent thermoelastic medium subjected to the effect of rotation and gravity field

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/6AF95AE62948</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/6AF95AE62948</guid><description>
	The present work is devoted to study the effect of rotation and gravity field in a homogeneous, isotropic elastic semi- infinite, which is at initial temperature, and subjected to heat source and load moving with finite velocity. In view of calculating general problems, a numerical solution technique is to be used. For this purpose, the normal mode analysis method is used. The results for th...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A mathematical model for solving integer linear programming problems</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/8AB802563098</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/8AB802563098</guid><description>
	A suggested algorithm to solve fully rough integer linear programming (FRILP) problems is introduced in this paper in order to find rough value optimal solutions and decision rough integer variables, where all parameters and decision variables in the constraints and the objective function are rough intervals (RIs). In real-life situations, the parameters of linear programming problem model m...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Volatility measure of Nigeria crude oil production as a tool to investigate production variability</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/493EA4662638</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/493EA4662638</guid><description>
	The interest to carry out volatility analysis of crude oil production in Nigeria in this paper is motivated by the shortfalls in quantities of crude oil produced in recent past, given the countrys high dependence on oil and its contribution to the nations economic development. In 2016 precisely, the country experienced drastic instability in prices of crude oil at international markets and d...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fixed lifetime inventory system with double order under useful lifetime based model</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/007D18E62718</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/007D18E62718</guid><description>
	The problem of outdating in the fixed lifetime inventory system has been the focus of researchers in the last decade. Results show that while outdating is being minimized, shortages have become a problem. To eliminate or reduce shortages in the fixed lifetime inventory system, we propose a model where, there are two orders, one period apart in arriving into the inventory system. The second o...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A short note on inequalities of interval-valued intuitionistic fuzzy matrices</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/376254962380</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/376254962380</guid><description>
	Inequality, also known as inequation, but unlike equation does not have rich history. After the introduction of equation, inequation captures its popularity in different fields namely algebra, geometry, trigonometry, probability, set theory, fuzzy set theory, logic, calculus etc. Whereas inequalities used in algebra are called algebraic inequalities, the ones used in geometry are called geom...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Total revenue function for non-regular fixed lifetime inventory system</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/2AB7A7662382</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/2AB7A7662382</guid><description>
	The fixed lifetime inventory system assumes that outdated items are discarded from inventory. Such inventory system is here referred to as regular inventory system. The non-regular fixed lifetime inventory system assumes that outdated items are not discarded from inventory. The features of both the regular and non-regular inventory systems are compared in this work and the total revenue func...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An air quality composite index based on pollutant concentration factor analysis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/85E774562138</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/85E774562138</guid><description>
	To overcome the problems of Air Quality Index in describing regional short-term air quality status and changing trend, based on the daily average concentrations of six air pollutants affecting regional air quality in Zhengzhou from 2015 to 2018, this paper analyzes their correlation characteristics and defines an air quality composite index instead of the original index by using factor analy...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative study of the direct and inverse finite element methods for pricing American options</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/704794060293</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMCSR/article-abstract/704794060293</guid><description>
	This paper investigates the computational performance of direct and inverse finite element methods for pricing American options. The underlying concept of the direct approach is similar to that of conventional finite element method. But the inverse approach is a relatively new development that involves trading the roles of financial variables. Based on the same constitutive model and linear ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>