<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Medical and Health Sciences - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Medical and Health Sciences</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Discontinuation of intrauterine device: Are the reasons changing?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/477179D63650</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/477179D63650</guid><description>
	Intrauterine devices (IUDs) are among the most widely used contraceptive methods and users discontinue use despite its effectiveness due to different reasons. This study is aimed at determining the reasons for IUD discontinuation. A retrospective survey was conducted at Family Planning Clinic of University College Hospital, Ibadan, Nigeria. Information on socio-demographic characteristics, I...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sero-prevalence of Hepatitis B and C infection among patients with end stage renal disease at 
haemodialysis initiation
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/3B57EF162830</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/3B57EF162830</guid><description>
	Hepatitis sero-positivity at initiation of haemodialysis may suggest a causal role or arise due to repeated blood transfusions and reduced immunity associated with advanced chronic kidney disease. This study was to determine the sero-prevalence of Hepatitis B and C infection at initiation of haemodialysis, and describe the clinical characteristics and outcome of patients. This is a cross-sec...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D status in non-elderly adults (18-64 years) working indoors at 40&#xB0; north latitude</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/9DFBD9862958</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/9DFBD9862958</guid><description>
	There are very few reports focusing on a role of vitamin D in falls and the related factors in the non-elderly (18-64 years). A cross-sectional survey was addressed to investigate associations between falls, the related factors, and 25[OH]D3 status in 256 non-elderly adults that regularly work indoors at latitude 40 north region. The mean value of the serum 25[OH]D3 was 15.6  7.0 ng/ml. We d...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Perineo-genital injury secondary to sexual assault in a 3-month old female</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/CD0ED7E62454</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/CD0ED7E62454</guid><description>
	Traumatic injuries to the perineum and external genitalia in children may be accidental, self-inflicted or the result of assault. Sexual assaults account for majority of the injuries in developed countries while accidental injuries occur more in underdeveloped and developing countries. The injuries may be isolated or associated with trauma to other areas of the body. Perineal injuries consti...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Quality of hospital admission documentation: A study in an emergency paediatric unit of a tertiary hospital in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/1F8363861326</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/1F8363861326</guid><description>
	Medical documentation, in addition to being a legal and research tool, is vital in providing quality patient care. In Nigeria, hand written documentation without proforma, is the norm. We assessed the quality of doctors documentation of children admitted into Emergency Paediatrics Unit (EPU), Usmanu Danfodiyo University Teaching Hospital (UDUTH). A 3-month cross-sectional study of admission ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An exploration on blood donation intention among population in Hawassa city, Southern Ethiopia; theory of planned behaviour approach: A qualitative study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/3354A8D61378</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/3354A8D61378</guid><description>
	Millions of lives are saved each year through blood transfusions. Blood donation is therefore considered as a humanitarian act and a positive behavioural phenomenon. To explore intention to donate blood among Hawassa city population, southern Ethiopia, 2017, a qualitative study using the theory of planned behaviour was employed. Data collection was done using a semi-structured interview guid...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Foeto-maternal outcome of abruptio placentae at a Nigerian tertiary hospital</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/AD1395961193</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/AD1395961193</guid><description>
	Abruptio placentae remain a major cause of maternal morbidity and mortality and a significant cause of perinatal loss especially in the resource poor countries like Nigeria. The objective of this study was to determine the risk factors, maternal and perinatal outcomes of patients managed for abruptio placentae at the University of Abuja Teaching Hospital, (UATH), during a five-year period. A...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Efficacy of intravenous tranexamic acid at reducing blood loss during elective caesarean section in Abakaliki: A double blind randomized placebo controlled trial</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/6ED18A060609</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/6ED18A060609</guid><description>
	Increasing caesarean section rate is a source of concern to obstetricians due to the attendant increased health risk, its commonest complication is bleeding, which occasionally may be life threatening. Tranexamic acid has recently been investigated as a potentially useful adjunct for the prevention of maternal morbidity. The research aim to evaluate the efficacy of tranexamic acid at reducin...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Utilization of Postnatal Care Services after home delivery in Ethiopia: A Multilevel Logistic 
Regression Analysis
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/28A656859983</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/28A656859983</guid><description>
	Despite postnatal care services significant role in improving maternal and new-born health, services are underutilized in most developing countries including Ethiopia. Utilization of postnatal care services in many countries is very low. This study aimed to determine the prevalence of postnatal care service utilization and also, identify determinant factors of utilization of postnatal care s...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence and Risk Factors for Helicobacter Pylori Infection in
Gastroduodenal Diseases in Kano, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/593312F57735</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMHS/article-abstract/593312F57735</guid><description>
	Background: Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) has been well noted as a causative agent of many diseases in the gastrointestinal (GI) tract notably, gastritis, peptic ulcer disease, and gastric adenocarcinoma. Determining the burden and the risk factors for acquiring this infection may be crucial to containing it and its sequelae in Kano, Nigeria.

	Methodology: The study was cross&#x2011;sectional ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>