<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Marketing Management - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Marketing Management</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Assessing the attitude towards mobile marketing among university students</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/3A6312463925</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/3A6312463925</guid><description>
	The study was initiated to assess the attitude towards mobile marketing among students of Bahir Dar University, Ethiopia. The objective of the study is to evaluate whether the university students have accepted Mobile/SMS advertising positively and to understand the issues students experienced and the thoughts they perceived from educational perspective considering different factors affecting...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors that influence participation in markets through collective action among smallholder maize farmers in Masindi district, Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/2F32B8F63208</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/2F32B8F63208</guid><description>
	In Uganda, smallholder maize farmers produce nearly 100% of the maize grain. However, these farmers sell their produce at low prices thus discouraging market participation. In addition, farmers are faced with several internal and external challenges like lack of market information and high observable and non-observable transaction costs. Several entities constructed a 3000 metric tons storag...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Satisfaction and retention strategies for Nigerian Generation Y customers</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/EF1779761798</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/EF1779761798</guid><description>
	Firms in the service industry have experienced a 15 to 30% drop in customer satisfaction ratings estimated at $10 billion annually due to the unpredictable tendencies of Generation Y customers, also known as Millennials. Researchers project that the population size, spending power and inconsistent behavioral pattern of this generational cohort might determine how customers will relate to ser...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Customers&#x2019; satisfaction and brand loyalty at McDonald&#x2019;s Maroc</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/8B2BB2161179</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/8B2BB2161179</guid><description>
	Customer satisfaction is paramount to businesses success. It has been researched in business and marketing since the 1970s. If customer satisfaction is achieved brand loyalty often results. Because of that, brand loyalty has also been heavily researched in the last few decades. The purpose of the current research was to determine the drivers of customer satisfaction and brand loyalty, as wel...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing food attributes and marketing services of private restaurants on the campus of University of Abomey-Calavi, Benin</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/D018A5C60470</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/D018A5C60470</guid><description>
	In Benin Republic (West Africa), the public student restaurant of the University of Abomey-Calavi is being criticized for its irregular and poor service. Therefore, private restaurants have settled on the campus streets to fill the gap. Which food attributes and marketing services do students value most? How do those restaurants compare with the Agro Maquis reference restaurant, which presum...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The determinants and key challenges of financial inclusion in Niger: the case of Orange Money</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/713B23F60146</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/713B23F60146</guid><description>
	This work focuses on the mobile payments used in Africa, a means to help solve the financial inclusion problem on the continent. It builds on the unified theory of acceptance and use of technology (UTAUT). The results of the investigations on a sample of 238 subscribers of Orange Niger show that the facilitating conditions are as decisive as the development of solar batteries and smartphone ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors influencing consumers&#x2019; choice of street-foods and fast-foods in China</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/F82FA1A59414</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/F82FA1A59414</guid><description>
	The overarching aim of this paper is to examine empirical findings on the arena of consumers behavior and attitude towards intake of street-foods (SFs) and fast foods (FFs) status as well as associated risks of consumption in China. Presently, consuming SFs and FFs have become a popular trend and is counted as the manifestation of modernity in most fast growing countries, for instance, China...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of brand elements on brand equity: An applied study on Jordanian Corporations</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/E46894E56804</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/E46894E56804</guid><description>
	This study investigated the impact of brand elements on creating brand equity of Jordanian corporations. Despite the significant development in branding globally and its role in increasing the equity of the companies, a quick preview of previous research indicates that there are still some gaps in research related to brand elements and its impact on creating brand equity and branding in gene...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Value congruence of manufacturer: Distributor guanxi orientation and manufacturer&#x2019;s relationship 
specific investments
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/4BA96A956145</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/4BA96A956145</guid><description>
	Values are very important for guiding firms attitude, minds and behaviors. From intra- to inter-firm management, value congruence between cooperative firms is the cornerstone for relationship building. This paper focused on guanxi orientation values, popular in Chinese business context, and found the positive effect of value congruence in guanxi orientation on manufacturers relationship spec...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The perceptions of people about family planning: The social marketing experience in Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/16E76F356024</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMM/article-abstract/16E76F356024</guid><description>
	The study aimed at analyzing the role and practice of social marketing as an approach to address issues related to attitudinal change about family planning. Based on the idea of social marketing and its application to positively influence the behavior through changing attitudes of individuals related to family planning and contraceptive use, the study was developed with the methodology appli...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>