<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Microbiology Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Microbiology Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>GC-MS analysis of bioactive compounds and evaluation of antimicrobial activity of the extracts of Daedalea elegans: A Nigerian mushroom</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/DBFDD5063838</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/DBFDD5063838</guid><description>
	Phytochemicals are naturally occurring compounds present in varying levels in plants and help significantly in protecting them against pathogens. The chemical composition of acetone and ethanolic extracts of Daedalea elegans were determined using Gas Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry. Twenty-eight and fourty-four compounds were identified in the acetone and ethanolic extracts respectively. On...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) associated with cotton (Gossypium hirsutum L.) growing in the Far-North region of Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/A270AA963842</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/A270AA963842</guid><description>
	The present study was carried out with the aim of highlighting the diversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) associated with the rhizosphere of cotton grown in the Far-North region of Cameroon. To achieve this, composite soil and root samples were taken in six fields, chosen according to edapho-climatic conditions and types of cultural practices. After entrapping the glomales in the gr...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phenotypic detection of extended spectrum &#x3B2;-lactamase and Metallo &#x3B2;-lactamase production by Gram negative uropathogens after exposure to gamma radiation
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/5B812C163864</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/5B812C163864</guid><description>
	Eighty-five uropathogen isolates were collected and differentiated on the basis of their Gram stain reaction. Among the collected isolates, 25 (29.4%) were Gram positive cocci and 60 (70.6%) were Gram negative bacilli. Antibiotic susceptibility profile towards 15 different antibiotics concluded that impenime (IMP), amikacin (AK) and Pipperacillin/tazobactam (TZP) were the most effective agai...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In vitro efficacy of Trichoderma asperellum and detached leaflet assay on late blight pathogen: Phytophthora infestans</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/E2EA6E663641</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/E2EA6E663641</guid><description>
	Late blight is highly variable adapting to new fungicides and overcoming host resistance. The objective of the study was to determine efficacy of Trichoderma asperellum against Phytophthora infestans and its compatibility with fungicides. T. asperellum at 33% (3  106), 66% (7  106) and 100% (1  107 CFU/mL; g/L), Ridomil (Metalaxyl 4% + Mancozeb 64%) and Mistress 72 (Cynamoxil 4% + Mancozeb 6...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing the polymorphism of DHFR gene from Plasmodium falciparum in the south of C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/475495B63643</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/475495B63643</guid><description>
	Since 2005, Cte dIvoire has adopted new strategies of malaria management including free provision of Artemisinin-based Combination Therapy (ACT) to children less than five years of age and sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine (SP) as Intermittent Preventive Treatment (IPT) for pregnant women. However, introduction of ATCs raises concerns about the extensive use of cheap SP which could increase Plasmodi...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Naftifine inhibits pigmentation through down-regulation on expression of phytoene desaturase gene CAR1 in Rhodotorula mucilaginosa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/9E1C79E63662</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/9E1C79E63662</guid><description>
	Naftifine, an antifungal drug, inhibits pigmentation in Rhodotorula mucilaginosa. However, the relative mechanism is minutely understood. In this study, regulation of gene expression by naftifine was investigated to elucidate mechanism of yeast de-pigmentation. RNA-sequencing (RNA-seq) was used to screen differentially expressed genes (DEGs), followed by quantitative PCR (qPCR). The qPCR res...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibacterial resistance patterns of bacteria isolated from clinical specimens at Uttara IbnSina Diagnostic Centre, Dhaka</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/1B504D263664</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/1B504D263664</guid><description>
	Nowadays, antibiotic resistance is a global public health threat. Bangladesh is accelerated to this owing to its sub-standards healthcare along with the self-medication and overuse of antibiotics. The study aimed to assess patterns of antibacterial resistance in the clinical samples. The study was carried out at Ibn Sina Diagnostic and Consultation Center Uttara, Dhaka, from January to Decem...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Occurrence of multidrug-resistant bacteria in aquaculture farms in C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire (West Africa)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/D4E869B63678</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/D4E869B63678</guid><description>
	Aquaculture provides a significant proportion of the fish consumed around the world. In West Africa, aquaculture is an important economic sector. However, several diseases with high fish mortality are caused by bacterial infections. Due to the lack of surveillance in aquaculture, this study investigated the presence of bacteria in fish farms. The purpose of the study was to isolate bacteria ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bacillus cereus, Lactobacillus acidophilus and Succinovibrio dextrinosolvens promoting the growth of maize and soybean plants</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/2F42C3E63751</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/2F42C3E63751</guid><description>
	Plant growth promoting bacteria can be an alternative to increase plant production, and reduce production costs and environmental impacts. Ruminal bacteria have several abilities and some of them are related to plant growth promotion. The aim of this study is to evaluate the increase in maize and soybean plants and in soils promoted by the inoculation of three ruminal bacteria: Bacillus cere...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Distribution of &#x3B2;-Lactam resistant Gram-negative bacteria isolated from clinical and environmental sources in two tertiary hospitals in Makurdi, 
Benue State, Nigeria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/EF6AFC063782</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJMR/article-abstract/EF6AFC063782</guid><description>
	For appropriate control of infections, it is necessary to possess updated awareness about occurrence of the causative agents. Gram-negative bacteria are considered important microorganisms that cause hospital infections. Clinical multidrug resistant Gram-negative bacteria were obtained from clinical samples including urine, high vaginal swab (HVS), wound swab (WS), stools, ear swab (ES), end...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>