<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Oral Health Sciences - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Oral Health Sciences</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Pregnancy epulis: Case series among pregnant women in Kaduna, Northern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/0FF1FE863555</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/0FF1FE863555</guid><description>
	The aim of this work is to report the clinical presentation and management of pregnancy epulis (PE) among pregnant women that attended ante-natal clinic in Barau Dikko Teaching Hospital, Kaduna, Northern, Nigeria. Three hundred and twenty self-administered, structured questionnaires were administered to pregnant women that attended ante-natal clinic in Barau Dikko Teaching Hospital, Kaduna. ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Computer-aided and 3d printing technologies; new frontiers in reconstructive surgery</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/FB5992F61388</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/FB5992F61388</guid><description>
	Computer-aided and 3D printing technologies have recently become accepted standard of care protocol for preoperative surgical planning and in the design pros-thesis.
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The potential of using 3d printed patient specific models in reconstructive surgery of the mandible &#x2013;review paper</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/5B2175761389</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/5B2175761389</guid><description>
	Additive manufacturing, also known as 3D printing is a manufacturing technique whose process involves laying down of material, one layer on top of the other such that a solid object is formed. Its capability to produce objects of complicated geometrical shapes (otherwise unachievable by traditional manufacturing techniques) within a relatively short time and without extra tooling has made it...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Root curvature in the maxillary first permanent molars in a 
Kenyan population
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/78DCD2561390</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/78DCD2561390</guid><description>
	Objective; To determine the root curvature in the maxillary first permanent molars. Methodology; A total of 187 maxillary molars were collected from male and female patients aged between10 and 40 years. The teeth were orientated in their anatomical positions on a calibrated graph paper and the root curvature determined with reference to the long axis of root from the bifurcation. Results; Ma...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Debilitating lymphangiomatous macroglossia-case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/72D7B2E61391</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJOHS/article-abstract/72D7B2E61391</guid><description>
	Objective; Lymphangiomatous macroglossia in children though uncommon may cause significant morbidity which maybe functional or developmental when untreated and also presents a significant surgical challenge when trying to balance complete surgical excision and maintenance of contour and function. Case report; We report a case of extensive tongue lymphangioma in which surgical excision was pe...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>