<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Pure and Applied Chemistry - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Pure and Applied Chemistry</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Evaluation of kinetics and equilibrium studies of biosorption potentials of bamboo stem biomass for removal of Lead (II) and Cadmium (II) ions from aqueous solution</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/B3A035A63561</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/B3A035A63561</guid><description>
	The discharged of lead and cadmium above maximum permissible limits into surface water and environment without any pre-treatment methods has caused severe heath challenges to humanity. In other to minimize the reoccurrence, this research aim to ascertain biosorption capacity of bamboo stem biomass to remove lead and cadmium from aqueous solution. Batch experiment and data evaluation under op...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phytochemical Profiling of the Hexane fraction of Crassocephalum crepidioides Benth S. Moore leaves 
by GC-MS
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/A242FE163233</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/A242FE163233</guid><description>
	Crassocephalum crepidioides is an edible plant which is also used in the ethnomedical treatment of stomach ulcer, indigestion, wounds, boils and burns in Africa and some other parts of the world. This study aims at identifying and characterizing the bioactive compounds present in C. crepidioides hexane fraction which may be responsible for the ethnomedicinal uses and reported activities of t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Synthesis and characterization of carboxymethyl cellulose from Musa paradisiaca and 
Tithonia diversifolia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/81D2AC963350</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/81D2AC963350</guid><description>
	Cellulose is the most abundant biomass in nature with properties that have enabled its application in different industrial processes. Its derivative, sodium carboxymethyl cellulose serves as an additive in food and non-food products such as desserts, detergents, paints etc. In this study, carboxymethyl cellulose (CMC) was synthesized from cellulose isolated from three ligno-cellulosic biomas...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determination of chlorogenic acid content in beans and leaves of coffea arabica using UV/Vis spectrometer</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/591169261700</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/591169261700</guid><description>
	Chlorogenic acid (CGA) is one of the compounds found in coffee beans and other parts of coffee plant. However, its relative content in different coffee plant parts is least researched. Therefore, this study was designed to determine the contents of CGA in coffee leaves and beans. Green coffee beans and leaves were collected from South part of Ethiopia to study the content of CGA using UV/Vis...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Adsorption of chromium by brewers spent grain -g- poly (acrylic acid-co-acryl amide) from 
electroplating effluent
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/56397C861703</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/56397C861703</guid><description>
	Toxic metal ions have lethal effects on all forms of life and these metal ions could enter the food chain when untreated waste effluents are discharged into the environment. In recent years, the use of low-cost adsorbent materials has been widely investigated in search of replacement for the costly methods that are currently used for removing these toxic metal ions from waste streams. In thi...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemical modification of cellulose from palm kernel de-oiled cake to microcrystalline cellulose and its evaluation as a pharmaceutical excipient</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/98455FA61491</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/98455FA61491</guid><description>
	Microcrystalline cellulose (MCC) is an important ingredient in pharmaceutical, food, cosmetic and other industries. In this research work, microcrystalline cellulose was synthesized from the alpha cellulose content of pretreated palm kernel de-oiled cake. The microcrystalline cellulose from palm kernel cake was obtained through acidified sodium chlorite, sodium hydroxide delignification foll...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Green sonochemical synthesis of silver nanoparticles using Bridelia micrantha extract and evaluation of their antibacterial activity</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/6A3208160355</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/6A3208160355</guid><description>
	The emergence of drug resistance and multiple drug resistance has necessitated the discovery of novel strategies for development of new generation of antimicrobial agents from natural substances for control of microbial infections. Metal nanoparticles have proven to have antimicrobial properties, but the chemical methods used in their production use hazardous chemicals and nanoparticles prod...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antioxidant activity, total phenolic and flavonoid content of selected Kenyan medicinal plants, sea algae and medicinal wild mushrooms</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/964192D60365</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/964192D60365</guid><description>
	Medicinal plants are good sources of bioactive compounds that guards the body against cancer and chronic ailments. A lot of studies have been done on medicinal values of higher plants but less on marine sources and wild non-edible mushrooms. The study aimed to assess the antioxidant activity, total flavonoid and total phenolic content from selected Kenyan medicinal plants, sea algae and mush...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Production and characterization of derived composite biosorbents from animal bone</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/AD20EC160230</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/AD20EC160230</guid><description>
	Composite biosorbents were produced from animal bone by carbonization, activation of animal bone char with phosphoric acid and zinc (II) chloride independently, and the obtained activated carbons were separately impregnated on chitosan. The chitosan was produced from chitin, which was extracted from shrimp shell through deminerization, deproteinization and deacetylation processes. Comprehens...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Toxicity studies of African Palmyrah palm (Borassus Aethiopum) shoots</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/7D262F060294</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPAC/article-abstract/7D262F060294</guid><description>
	The study examined the effect of feeding albino rats with 25, 50, and 75% Palmyrah Palm (Borassus aethiopum) shoots with respect to their body weight, liver and kidney function indices. Standard methods of biochemical analyses were employed using albino rats as the experimental animals. No mortality was observed in the LD50 test throughout the period of 48 h. Rats fed with 25 and 50% B. aeth...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>