<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmacology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Phytochemical screening and toxicological effects of Amblygonocarpus andongensis aqueous stem bark extract in wistar albino rat

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/D6B976163870</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/D6B976163870</guid><description>
	Amblygonocarpus andongenesis is being used as antipsychotic. Hence, it may portend high risk of toxicosis. In view of this, phytochemical screening and toxicological effects of aqueous stem bark extract of the plant was studied in wistar albino rats. Qualitative screening of the stem bark extract revealed the presence of alkaloid, hydrolysable tannin, saponin, glycoside, cardiac glycoside, s...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Nutritional characterization pulp of Chrysobalanus icaco L.</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/7A5591D63876</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/7A5591D63876</guid><description>
	After Southeast Asia, Brazil is the second largest producer of tropical fruits having more than 500 species, and many of these have high potential regarding nutritional content that can be marketed. Among them, Chrysobalanus icaco L., which can be found in abundance in several countries of South America stands out. Among its nutritional profile, it had low value of titratable acidity (0.41  ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Nutrients in Amazonian fruit pulps with functional and pharmacological interest</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/4461B8A63895</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/4461B8A63895</guid><description>
	In this research, nine fruits cultivated in Northern Amazon were studied: Abiu, acerola, ara, bacupari, birib, camu-camu, fruta-do-conde, graviola and tapereb, with the objective of carrying out a proximate and nutritional study of the pulps of the Northern Amazon fruits. They were graviola (76.83  0.02 Kcal 100 g-1), bacupari (53.15  0.02 Kcal 100 g-1) and fruta-do-conde (46.66  0.02 Kcal 1...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence and the level of evidences supporting off-label prescribing of antidepressant, antipsychotic and antiepileptic drugs in Makkah Almukarramah: A case sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/F0FC0BC63897</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/F0FC0BC63897</guid><description>
	Off-label prescribing is very common among physicians, particularly among psychiatrists and there is limited information regarding the extent of the unapproved drug use in Makkah city. The objective of this study was to assess the prevalence of off-label indications for antidepressant, antipsychotic and antiepileptic and the strength of evidence supporting use of the prescribed drug for the ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Haematology, serum biochemistry and histopathological findings associated with sub-chronic administration of methanol leaf extract of Pterocarpus santalinoides DC in albino rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0CB8EF163899</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0CB8EF163899</guid><description>
	The effects of sub-chronic administration of Pterocarpus santalinoides methanol leaf extract (PSME) on haematology, serum biochemistry and histology of albino rats were evaluated. Twenty female albino rats, randomly assigned into four groups (A-D) of five rats each, were used for the study. Groups A-C were treated orally with 500, 250 and 50 mg/kg PSME, respectively, while Group D was given ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemical characterization of seeds of Amazon fruits as nutritional contribution with functional medicinal potential</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/1C92CC363557</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/1C92CC363557</guid><description>
	The fruit seeds of the Northern Amazon Region were evaluated bromatologically and nutritionally in terms of the level of macro- and micro-elements and fatty acids present in them. Bromatologically, the seeds of camu-camu (369.08 kcal 100 g-1) and birib (364.78 kcal 100 g-1) have the highest energy value. In terms of the macroelements, the highest concentration was potassium (554.23 mg 100 g-...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative effect on liver fibrosis of bicyclol and silymarin</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0484AF763599</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0484AF763599</guid><description>
	Bicyclol and silymarin are widely used in the treatment of various liver diseases; however, there is no report on comparative effect of them on liver fibrosis. To compare their liver protective effect, liver fibrosis rats induced by bile duct ligation (BDL) were orally treated with 100 mg/kg bicyclol and 100 mg/kg silymarin respectively for 4 weeks. Liver index, liver function activities, in...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Designing polyethylene oxide and hydroxypropyl methylcellulose matrix tablets with comparable dissolution properties</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/C71101F63707</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/C71101F63707</guid><description>
	PolyoxTM coagulant (molecular weight 5  106 Da) and hydroxypropyl methylcellulose (HPMC) K4M (USP substitution type 2208) were used to identify the composition variables that ensure the production of polyethylene oxide (PEO) matrix tablets with the same dissolution characteristics as those containing HPMC. Based on the dissolution results obtained using Apparatus 3, a 53% concentration of PE...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The potential cardioprotective effects of Febuxostat versus Cilostazol on Isoproterenol induced cardiac dysfunction in rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/A241B0563765</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/A241B0563765</guid><description>
	Myocardial infarction causes an acute condition of necrosis of the myocardium resulting in increased production of free radicals and decreased levels of antioxidants. It was proposed that Febuxostat reduced myocardial oxidative stress and suppressed apoptosis. Cilostazol used to treat claudication has a growing evidence, suggesting that Cilostazol could be cardioprotective. This work aims to...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemical composition of essential oil of Melissa officinalis L. and antioxidant activity from Boa Vista-RR, Brazil</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0FD54B263389</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPP/article-abstract/0FD54B263389</guid><description>
	In this work, the chemical composition of the essential oil of lemon balm (Melissa officinalis L.) was determined by CG-FID.In the essential oil of M. officinalis,there area total of 22 chemical constituents, among them are geranial (34.6%), neral (26.0%), -caryophyllene (7.5%), caryophyllene oxide (5.3%), &#xF06D;-pinene (5.3%) and sabinene (3.6%); it also has antioxidant capacity and total phenol...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>