<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Plant Science - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Plant Science</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Seasonal variation and modeling of leaf area growth in Jatropha curcas L. plants: Implication for understanding the species adaptation in the Sahel of Niger</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/70E419363878</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/70E419363878</guid><description>
	Jatropha curcas is a tree species introduced in Niger as a trial experiment to offset land degradation and for biofuel production. The objective of this study is to contribute to the understanding of this species potential for adaptation under the edaphic and climatic conditions of Niger through analysis and modeling of the leaf area dynamics. The nondestructive method is used to evaluate th...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of woody species diversity, key drivers of deforestation and community perception; the case of Hotessa Forest, Bensa Woreda, Sidama Zone, Southern Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/750620963647</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/750620963647</guid><description>
	InEthiopia,deforestationisamajorchallengewhich leads toincreased human encroachment upon wild areas and threats to biodiversity. In line with this, the aim of the current study was to assess woody species diversity and threats in Hotessa forest. Systematic sampling method was used to collect vegetation data. Accordingly, 100 plots each with 400 m2 (20 m  20 m) for woody species was laid alon...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Grain yield and protein content of upland rice (Oryza sativa L.) varieties as influenced by combined application of primary secondary and micronutrients under Nitisols
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/DDABEE363739</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/DDABEE363739</guid><description>
	Field experiment was conducted on Nitisols to evaluate the effects of combined application of primary, secondary and micronutrients on grain yield and protein content of upland rice varieties compared to the national recommendation. Factorial combination of five nutrient combinations (control, NP, NPK, NPKSZn and NPKSCaZn) and three upland rice varieties (Nechu Eruze, Superica-1 and NERICA-4...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard heterosis and trait association of maize inbred lines using line x tester mating design 
in Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/4FA003C63780</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/4FA003C63780</guid><description>
	Maize is one of the high priority crops to feed the ever increasing population in Africa, however, its production limited by shortage of high yielding variety coupled with biotic and abiotic stresses. The study was initiated to evaluate the heterotic performances of the F1 hybrids over the standard checks (Kolba and Jibat). Fifty entries consists 48 F1 single crosses developed from 24 inbred...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Occurrence, distribution and severity of finger millet blast caused by Magnaporthe oryzae in Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/A1A655063422</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/A1A655063422</guid><description>
	
		Finger millet is a food crop that provides nutritional security and is climatically resilient for farming and agricultural diversification. However, its quality and yield remain low due to biotic and abiotic factors, the greatest of which is blast disease caused by Magnaporthe oryzae. We surveyed the occurrence, distribution and severity of finger millet blast in five counties, namely, B...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild blackberry (Rubus spp.) differ in duration to reproductive phase under conventional production in Kenya
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/22BB9F063429</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/22BB9F063429</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study was to determine the duration from planting to reproductive phase, of wild blackberry (Rubus spp.) collected from the wild.It was carried out at the Horticulture Research and Teaching Farm, Egerton University, Njoro, Kenya. The experimental layout wasa randomized complete block design (RCBD) replicated three times; treatment was four wild blackberry species and one ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of chemical fertilizer types and rates on tuber yield and quality of potato (Solanum tuberosum L.) at Assosa, Western Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/4EC0A6963603</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/4EC0A6963603</guid><description>
	Potato tuber yield and quality is constrained by a number of biotic and abiotic factors, among which low soil fertility is the prime one. Thus, the objective of the study was to evaluate the effects of chemical fertilizer types and rates on tuber yield and quality of potato at Assosa, Western Ethiopia. The treatments consisted of control, three rates of NP combinations (55 kg N and 45 kg P2O...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Genetic divergence analyses of lowland rice genotypes in North Western Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/C66B03F63645</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/C66B03F63645</guid><description>
	Information on the nature and magnitude of genetic variability is one of the prerequisites for a successful breeding program in selecting genotypes with desirable characters. To estimate the level of genetic divergence of lowland rice genotypes, a field experiment was conducted using thirty-six genotypes during 2017 main cropping season. The experiment was laid out 6x6 simple lattice design....</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sorption characteristics, growth and yield response of wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) to application of essential nutrients on nitisol and vertisol of Central Highland 
of Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/5A9985863189</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/5A9985863189</guid><description>
	Wheat growth and yield response were evaluated in a greenhouse experiment using two major soils, Nitosols and Vertisols. Sorption capacities of the soils and crop response were employed to determine the availability of nutrients in the two soils. Eight fertilizer treatments (Optimum (Opt.),Optimum-N, Optimum-P,Optimum-K,Optimum-S,Optimum-B,Optimum-Zn and control) in Nitosols and six fertiliz...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Heterosis and combining ability of highland adapted maize (Zea mays. L) DH lines for desirable 
agronomic traits
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/5E8173963191</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-abstract/5E8173963191</guid><description>
	Maize (Zea mays L.) is one of the cereals that provide calorie requirements in the majority of Ethiopians diet. The national average maize yield in Ethiopia is low and thus knowledge of combining ability and heterosis is a prerequisite to develop high yielding maize varieties. The objective of the present study is to estimate combining abilities of double haploid (DH) maize inbred lines for ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>