<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Political Science and International Relations - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Political Science and International Relations</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Is there borderline in Nigeria's northeast? Multi-national joint task force and counterinsurgency operation 
in perspective
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/3CA422D63652</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/3CA422D63652</guid><description>
	Borderline as a defence line is central in countering transnational insurgency. Yet, countries in African Sub-region are lackadaisical about redefining inherited colonial borders. Primarily, the study examined the origin of Multi-National Joint Task Force (MNJTF) counterinsurgency (COIN) operational mandate as well as the linkage between border, threat of insurgency and MNJTF COIN operation ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>State, vigilantism and youth violence in Nigeria: A study of &#x2018;Onyabo&#x2019; in Ikorodu Local Government Area of Lagos State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/0509D4863658</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/0509D4863658</guid><description>
	Studies and institutional reports have argued that youth violence is a precursor to national insecurity in Nigeria. Contrary to youth as an agent of transformation and national development, their recurrence in violent conflicts has continued to undermine the national security of the country. Such security backlash is further conflated by the protracted Boko Haram insurgency which has rupture...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The impact of China on the agency and negotiating power of African countries: Cases of Angola and Niger</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/BA09C7462676</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/BA09C7462676</guid><description>
	The recent surge in cooperation between China and African countries challenges the western aid model thus giving African countries a better leverage and negotiating power in their relation with the west. It is obvious that the Chinese presence in Africa is motivated by its economic and energy security agenda, which consist in securing natural resources to ensure security of supply and demand...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Nigerian morbid federalism and demand for political restructuring
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/2EC678363175</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/2EC678363175</guid><description>
	The foundation of Nigerias problems lies in its historical development. This is linked to the swift design by predatory colonial masters aimed at achieving their political economy in colonialization of Africa. Sequel to the amalgamation of the southern and northern protectorates in 1914, Nigerias minimal state has continued to witness serial and intractable agitations, political interplays a...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Potency of ECOWAS mission strategy in resolving electoral conflict in West Africa: A case of C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/6DACE2663178</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/6DACE2663178</guid><description>
	Conflict is inevitable in all human relations, but when managed properly, the cost in human lives and properties are minimized. This paper examined the extent of ECOWAS Peace Strategy in resolving the Post-Electoral crisis in Cte dIvoire and the efficiency of the ECOWAS Election Mission Strategy. In-depth interview research design was adopted, that is, both primary (structured interviews) an...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Uganda and the refugee problem: challenges and opportunities
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/7B0972E62482</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/7B0972E62482</guid><description>
	Uganda is one of the top refugee hosting countries in Africa and the world. It has been praised as a generous country with progressive refugee policies and laws that reflect the countrys national, regional and international obligations. However, a number of challenges ranging from increasing refugee numbers, protracted refugee situations, the burden of hosting of refugees, to limited resourc...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysis of political parties&#x2019; ideologies influencing public policy formulation in Uganda&#x2019;s Nascent Hydrocarbon Industry</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/CA0C21362637</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/CA0C21362637</guid><description>
	This study examined political parties ideologies influencing public policy formulation in Ugandas nascent hydrocarbon industry. The study followed the four research objectives, research questions and hypotheses. The researcher applied a descriptive cross-sectional survey research design to guide the study. The research adopted both quantitative and qualitative approaches and data was collect...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Conflicts and insurgency: Barriers to global quality health service for internally displaced persons in the North Eastern Part of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/EE137A460962</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/EE137A460962</guid><description>
	Conflicts and insurgencies constitute some of the greatest challenge to societal peace and development. While daily effort are made by government and humanitarian organisations to address the problem of conflicts and insurgency, the absence of quality health service for those affected by conflicts have further amplified the potential for conflicts and human insecurity. The paper examines con...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The way-forward to make inter-governmental authority on development (IGAD) successful in actualizing a viable economic integration</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/3B19B0261133</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/3B19B0261133</guid><description>
	Inter-governmental authority on development (IGAD) as a regional bloc is operating with a lot of impediments that delayed the organization from attaining greater economic integration. The objective of this study was to show the ways in which IGAD can actualize credible economic integration in the region, though the best is yet to come. Qualitative data collection approaches (interview and li...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Nigerian senate and the politics of the non-passage of the gender equality bill</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/DBDB4D260777</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPSIR/article-abstract/DBDB4D260777</guid><description>
	The gender equality discourse assumed a global dimension since the fourth World Conference on Women held in Beijing, China in 1995. The hallmark of the Conference was the Beijing Platform for Action which was agreed upon by all 189 countries in attendance. Furthermore, the Millennium Development Goals (MDGs) subscribed to by United Nations member states in the year 2000, ascribed a worthy pl...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>