<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Biotechnology and Molecular Biology Reviews - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Biotechnology and Molecular Biology Reviews</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Major mycotoxins occurrence, prevention and control approaches</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/BE5B18359773</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/BE5B18359773</guid><description>
	Mycotoxins are secondary metabolites secreted by many fungal species and found in many feeds and foodstuffs of especially in plants during their pre-and post-harvest, transportation, processing and storage and are detected in cereal crops. They are capable of causing disease and death in both humans and livestock and thereby induce great economic crisis. This review aims to examine the occur...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Basics of animal cell culture: Foundation for modern science
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/7A2154261212</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/7A2154261212</guid><description>
	The culture of animal cells is one of the major aspects of science which serves as a foundation for most of our recent discoveries. The major areas of application include cancer research, vaccine manufacturing, recombinant protein production, drug selection and improvement, gene therapy, stem cell biology, monoclonal antibody production, in vitro fertilization technology, cryopreservation an...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Resistance to Bt Crops; Influence, mechanisms and management strategies</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/156B3C458824</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/156B3C458824</guid><description>
	The genetically engineered insect-resistant crops, Bt crops, were first commercially grown in 1996 and adopted in different countries. The economic benefits of Bt crops are reducing the use of insecticides and more safe to environment, however, development of resistance by insects might reduce their efficacy. Unfortunately, the field population evolved resistance to different Bt toxins and t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The reoccurrence of H5N1 outbreaks necessitates the development of safe and effective influenza vaccine technologies for the prevention and control of avian influenza in Sub-Saharan Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/9AA790354184</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/9AA790354184</guid><description>
	Africa is experiencing reoccurrence of avian influenza outbreaks with huge negative impact on the economy of the continent as a result of high mortality rate and extreme contagiousness of the disease. The epidemiology of highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) in Africa during the 2006-2008 outbreaks was complex and linked to movements of poultry commodities and wild birds. The peculiar ris...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Correlating aluminium toxicity, heterosis and epigenetic mechanisms in maize yield improvement in acid soils</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/1FFA2C251178</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/1FFA2C251178</guid><description>
	Overuse of inorganic fertilizers have contributed to an increase in soil acidity in global arable land and consequently caused an increase in Aluminium ion (Al3+) toxicity and a reduction of crop yield of between 30-50% in developing countries. Studies show that Al3+ toxicity inhibits cell division in the root tip meristem in sensitive plants even at micromolar concentrations. Applications o...</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunomodulatory effects of carbohydrates and advanced glycation end products</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/ADB05CF49520</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/ADB05CF49520</guid><description>
	Carbohydrates which comprise of monosaccharides, disaccharides and polysaccharides are heterogeneous complex structure in living systems and are found to bind to other organic molecules such as proteins and lipids. Advanced glycation end products (AGEs) are also heterogeneous group of molecules that accumulate in plasma and other body fluids and in cell and tissues. This review focuses on th...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative analysis of different immunological techniques for diagnosing fasciolosis in sheep: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/584B70E45949</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/584B70E45949</guid><description>
	Fasciolosis is a worldwide zoonotic infection caused by liver flukes of the genus Fasciola, of which Fasciola hepatica and a larger species, Fasciola gigantica are the most common representatives. These two food-borne trematodes usually infect domestic ruminants and cause important economic losses to sheep, goats and cattle. In commercial herds, fasciolosis is of great economic significance ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Co-culture: A great promising method in single cell protein production</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/9281ED545168</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/9281ED545168</guid><description>
	The term single cell protein (SCP) refers to the dried microbial cells or total protein extracted from pure microbial culture (algae, bacteria, filamentous fungi and yeasts) which serves as food or/and feed supplements. Different substrate and fermentation optimizations are being carried out to maximize SCP production. However, little attention was given to coculturing. SCPs are produced bet...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>DNA microarrays and their applications in medical microbiology</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/0B1584444931</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/0B1584444931</guid><description>
	Rapid diagnosis and treatment of disease is often based on the identification and characterization of causative agents derived from phenotypic characteristics. This can be laborious and time consuming, often requiring many skilled personnel and a large amount of lab space. However, the introduction of nucleic acid amplification techniques into molecular biology has transformed the laboratory...</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The large-scale use of feruloyl esterases in industry</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/68CC9AE40231</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/BMBR/article-abstract/68CC9AE40231</guid><description>
	Presently industrial enzyme companies sell enzymes for a wide variety of applications. The estimated value of world enzyme market is presently about US $ 4.3 billion and it has been forecasted to grow to almost US $ 5.1 billion by 2009. Detergents (37%), textiles (12%), starch (11%), baking (8%) and animal feed (6%) are the main industries; totally these industries use about 74% of industria...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>