<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Clinical Reviews and Opinions - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO</link><description>view the most recent articles from Clinical Reviews and Opinions</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Multiple primary malignancies: Vigilance is paramount in identification</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/7FB549163609</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/7FB549163609</guid><description>
	Ever since it was first described by Billroth, there is an increasing incidence of multiple primary malignancies cases, due to increase in the survival rate of cancer patients and improvement of diagnostic tools. Incidence of second malignancies in cancer patients is 10 to 20%. A total of 10 patients who fulfilled the inclusion criteria were included. All the 10 patients case sheets were pur...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Platelet-mediated clumping adhesion phenotypes of P. falciparum-infected erythrocytes: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/75C3D2B65583</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/75C3D2B65583</guid><description>
	Malaria is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in the world. In general, malaria is easily treated but in a subset of cases it develops to severe disease. Severe malaria has a high rate of mortality even with the best available care. This creates the need for intensive research to fully characterise the pathogenesis of the disease in order to create future novel therapies. One of the ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Methods for monitoring artemisinin-based combination therapies efficacy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/A2B926F63389</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/A2B926F63389</guid><description>
	Plasmodium falciparum resistance to artemisinin and its derivatives is spreading in South-East Asia, and there is growing concern that this may reach other endemic countries. Methods used to assess P. falciparum resistance to artemisinin-based combination therapies (ACTs) are multiple and often divergent. This paper is a review of online accessible research publications from the past 20 year...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Breast cancer awareness, attitude and screening practices in Nigeria: A systematic review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/1D8006E59710</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/1D8006E59710</guid><description>
	Previous research on the breast cancer awareness, attitude and screening practices has produced divergent results. This systematic review aimed to summarise evidence and to compare all existing evidence on the awareness of breast cancer, attitude and screening practices among women in the six geopolitical zones of Nigeria. Overall, 40 articles were included in the &#xFB01;nal analysis. The search w...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of seasonal malaria chemoprevention of sulphadoxine&#x2013;pyrimethamine plus amodiaquine on molecular markers resistance of Plasmodium falciparum malaria: A review in West Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/388202456910</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/388202456910</guid><description>
	The study discuss the potential impact of seasonal malaria chemoprevention (SMC) on the cases of malaria, anaemia and molecular markers resistance Plasmodium falciparum malaria; and also review the mechanism of action and the effect on immunity of SMC. SMC using an efficacious drug is likely to substantially reduce cases of clinical malaria in high transmission settings. However, an increase...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factor VIII genetic mutations and protein alterations in hemophilia A: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/E48B7E944718</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/E48B7E944718</guid><description>
	Hemophilia A represents a severe most common inherited hemorrhagic disorder caused by heterogeneous mutations, which lead to dysfunctional factor VIII protein. Besides the inversion 22 and intron 1 inversion, the mutations may describe 627 missense and 142 nonsense unique mutations. Changes in the protein sequence induce structural or functional impairment. This study aimed to review mutatio...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An ancient mystery &#x2018;unearthed&#x2019;!</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/718AAC64686</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/718AAC64686</guid><description>
	A 29-year-old female had presented to surgical out patients department complaining of lump in the anterior abdominal wall. Ultrasound and magnetic resonance imaging revealed a solid degenerated tumor in the anterior abdominal wall. It was surgically excised and histopathology confirmed it to be ancient schwannoma. To our knowledge, this is the second reported case of an abdominal wall ancien...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Desmoid tumours: The aggressive fibromatosis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/87F02C14706</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/87F02C14706</guid><description>
	Desmoid tumours are benign tumours that have a tendency to be locally invasive. We present a desmoid tumour of the lower abdominal wall in a 30 year old female patient, discussed the treatment options and reviewed literature of this uncommon lesion.

	

	Key words:Desmoid, abdominal wall, benign tumour.
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Recent trends in the diagnosis of toxoplasmosis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/DD5C3364650</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/DD5C3364650</guid><description>
	Toxoplasma gondiiis one of the most widely prevalent cyst forming apicomplexan parasite present worldwide. Felines serve as definitive hosts, while all non-feline vertebrates including humans, act as intermediate hosts of the parasite. There are several serological tests available for the detection ofT. gondiiantibodies such as the dye test (DT), indirect haemagglutination test (IHA), comple...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Measles complications in a Nigerian hospital setting</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/0DD54874660</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/CRO/article-abstract/0DD54874660</guid><description>
	In spite of active measles vaccination efforts in 2005 in southern Nigeria, re-emergence continues to occur. This study was carried out to ascertain the incidence of measles, severity, mortality and its complications, in order to enhance treatment and reduce under-five child mortality. Secondary data from the records in the measles ward of Oni Memorial Childrens Hospital, Ibadan was used. Th...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>