<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Educational Research and Reviews - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Educational Research and Reviews</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Notice of Retraction: Analysis of the educational bulletin presented to the teachers of the basic stage in the Jordanian Ministry of Education and the future model extracted</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/204BCB463880</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/204BCB463880</guid><description>
	The editors ofthe Educational Research and Reviews(ERR) are retracting the article, Notice of Retraction: Analysis of the educational bulletin presented to the teachers of the basic stage in the Jordanian Ministry of Education and the future model extracted published in 2019 (Vol. 14(16), pp. 559-571, October, 2019).
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Context-specific inclusive education: A local perspective on the enterprise</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/397EAD763629</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/397EAD763629</guid><description>
	Inclusive education is moulded by local factors. A qualitative case study was used to explore professionals perceptions of inclusive education (IE) practice in local schools along with interventions for a support model in the schools. Observations, focus group interviews and individual interviews were used to collect data from teachers, school principals, curriculum advisors and psychologist...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-routine problem solving performances of mathematics teacher candidates</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/8996E3663631</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/8996E3663631</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to determine the non-routine problem solving performances of mathematics teacher candidates. A descriptive survey model was used for this work and it was conducted with 50 teacher candidates studying elementary mathematics teaching in a medium-sized university in Turkey. To determine the non-routine problem solving performance of the teacher candidates, open ended no...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Adaptation of quantitative measurement tools to quantitative measurement of possibility</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/A0883BA63633</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/A0883BA63633</guid><description>
	When correlation between variables is not explicit, data can be collected by adapting the quantitative measurement tools in use for quantitative measurement of possibility, a nonlinear measurement. This adaptation is possible because measurement data can be evaluated more qualitatively using parameters for possibility. These can be defined as regular-symmetric, irregular-symmetric, symmetric...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Examining internet addiction levels of high school last-grade students
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/AB468CB63743</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/AB468CB63743</guid><description>
	Technological developments in the 21th century have enabled the emergence of tools that enable mass communication. This communication environment has brought about a continuing passion for technology in individuals and, with this passion, a communication pollution and addiction have begun to emerge. In this study, Internet addiction of high school last-grade students studying in Ye&#x15F;ilyurt di...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Investigation of the imagery and creativity of the 7th grade students using guided discovery method</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/24143F663745</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/24143F663745</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to investigate the imagery and creativity of the 7th grade students using guided discovery method. The research group was made 77 (age=12.7922+0.52158) 7th grade students, 37 females and 40 males studying in Imam Hatip Secondary School, Konya province, Ere&#x11F;li county. To achieve the purpose of the research, adaptation-innovation inventory creativity scale and sport im...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The effect of differential learning method on the international tennis number level among young tennis player candidates</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/1B1BA5F63786</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/1B1BA5F63786</guid><description>
	The objective of the study is to assess the effects of Differential Learning (DL) approach on learning the tennis stroke techniques, retention of skills, and improving the mobility time of young tennis player candidates in comparison with the traditional teaching methods and, accordingly, to present the teaching methods that are suitable for a more effective development in tennis education. ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing indicators of creative and productive leadership for basic education school administrators</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/822095963788</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/822095963788</guid><description>
	This research was conducted to develop indicators and test the congruence of structural relationship model and the indicator concurrent validity of creative and productive leadership for basic education school administrators. The first phase was creation of framework and outlining factors as well as indicators by focus group discussion with 9 experts selected by purposive sampling. The secon...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cultural similarities in Lausanne emigrants: An evaluation in terms of the hospitality value</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/018BA9F63356</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/018BA9F63356</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study is to compare the cultural similarities of Lausanne Emigrants who were forced to compulsory migration in accordance with the Treaty of Lausanne from Develi region of Kayseri to Kozani and Ioannina regions of Greece in terms of the hospitality value. Conducted during the two separate trips to the region during 2017 and 2019, the study has the characteristics of a des...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Migrant workers&#x2019; cash transfer effect on children&#x2019;s education</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/120A5CB63357</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ERR/article-abstract/120A5CB63357</guid><description>
	The rationale of this study is to examine the impact of cash transfer on school attendance in Indonesia and whether the proportion of school children receiving cash transfer and those not receiving cash transfer is having the same effect. Using the data of Indonesias Family Life Survey-5 (IFLS-5) in 2014 covering 19 provinces with total observations of 16.024 household obtained from Rand Cor...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>