<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Biodiversity and Conservation - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Biodiversity and Conservation</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Floristic assessment of semi evergreen forests of a peripheral site in Hadagarh Sanctuary, Odisha, India</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/E265B1E63336</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/E265B1E63336</guid><description>
	Phytosociological study was carried out in the outer periphery region of Hadagarh Wildlife Sanctuary, Odisha, India. An attempt has been made to find out the characteristics of the vegetation community of the forests of the sanctuary. Analysis of the vegetation was done following the standard ecological methods widely adopted for such studies (quadrat method). A total of 68 plant species fro...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ingestion of plastic debris affects feeding intensity in the rocky shore crab Pachygrapsus transversus Gibbes 1850 (Brachyura: Grapsidae)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/CC627E463338</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/CC627E463338</guid><description>
	The aim of this study was to investigate the plastic consumption by the rocky shore crab Pachygrapsus transversus and its effects in the species feeding activity. Specimens were collected monthly from August 2019 to January 2020 in a coral reef located in the north-eastern Brazilian coast, taken to the research laboratory, where they had their stomach removed, degree of fullness determined f...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of impact of ecological elevation on grass species&#x2019; diversity in Yabello Rangeland, Southern Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/1976CF363569</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/1976CF363569</guid><description>
	Elevation has great impact on species diversity; it creates ecologically diverse vegetation. Studying species richness patterns at different scales is very important both for ecological explanations and effective conservation design. In this study, grass vegetation data were collected using systematic sampling methods. 18 transects and 54 quadrants were laid, with 6 transects and 18 quadrant...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Polymorphism of Cyclops abyssorum mauritaniae (Copepoda, Cyclopoidae) collected from Algeria water bodies</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/BE0EA5663921</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/BE0EA5663921</guid><description>
	Three morphotypes A, B and C were isolated after description of Cyclops abyssorum mauritaniae populations obtained from 46 Algerian water bodies. These are described based on their morphometric characters. Morphotype A found in six localities characterized the east of Algeria, morphotype B was collected in the west of Algeria, while morphotype C was collected in High Mountain in the North. A...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of avifaunal assemblage and their distribution pattern across different habitat types of Gibe Sheleko National Park, South-western Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/EC12A2763073</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/EC12A2763073</guid><description>
	This study was conducted in Gibe Sheleko National Park from March to August 2015 covering wet and dry seasons. Sampling sites were taken based on the habitat characteristics and a transect line of 1 or less km with a distance of 250 to 300 m in between the transect lines was taken in the woodland habitat and point count was used in the riverine forest habitat. A total of 116 bird species con...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Woody species diversity, structure and biomass carbon of parkland agroforestry practices  in Gindeberet District, West Shoa Zone, Oromia Regional State, Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/CB881FF62598</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/CB881FF62598</guid><description>
	Parkland agroforestry woody species are prominent features in many landscapes worldwide, and their ecological, social and economic importance is widely acknowledged. It is the traditional agroforestry systems from different countries and is almost a universal occurrence in Ethiopia. This study was conducted in Gindeberet District, West Shoa Zone, Oromia Regional State, Ethiopia to assess the...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Biological diversity of agroforestry species in the socioeconomic context of producers in the Barh-k&#xF4;h Department, Southern Chad: Case of Kissimi, Mayel&#xE9; and Badara villages</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/FC5592A62600</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/FC5592A62600</guid><description>
	This study aims to better understand the woody biodiversity and the relationship between the state of tree cover in the Agroforestry Park and the management units, and also to know the socio-economic role played by the trees of the parks. The study was conducted in 3 villages in Barh-kh Department, Chad, between May and November 2018. A plot of 2500 m2 has been materialized in each managemen...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Forest structure and carbon stocks of Osun-Osogbo Sacred Grove, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/DAEA51462602</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/DAEA51462602</guid><description>
	Forest trees and soil are considered for climate change mitigation. Forest structure of the grove is required to predict its capacity to mitigate climate change. Therefore, the objective of this study was to determine the forest structure and carbon stocks of Osun-Osogbo Sacred grove. Five (30  30 m2) plots were demarcated in Old-growth forest (OF) and Re-growth forest (RF). Trees with 10 cm...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild potatoes of series Circaeifolia (Solanun section Petota) in the Bolivian Andean region, a new evaluation of its distribution</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/C2E97BB62706</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/C2E97BB62706</guid><description>
	The Circaeifolia series species are only from Bolivia. They are species that have particular morphological characteristics different from any other within the Petota section. The taxa of the series Circaeifolia, Solanum circaeifolim, Solanum capsicibaccatum and Solanum soestii (recently grouped as Solanum stipuloideum Rusby) have been distinguished by morphological characteristics and molecu...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Woody fodder species in three agro-ecological Parklands of Arba Minch Zuria Woreda, Gamo Gofa Zone, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/D1D28A862708</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBC/article-abstract/D1D28A862708</guid><description>
	This study was conducted in Arba Minch Zuria Woreda of SNNPR, Ethiopia on Parkland
	agroforestry practices in three agro-ecological zones. The objective of the study was to investigate the fodder tree and shrub species composition, richness, diversity and structure. Key Informant Interviews and Focus Group Discussions were held. In total, ninety 50 m  20 m plots were laid and standard proce...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>