<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Biotechnology and Molecular Biology Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Biotechnology and Molecular Biology Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>First detection of the BES-type Extended-Spectrum &#x3B2;-Lactamase produced by Enterobacteria at Saint Camille Hospital of Ouagadougou (Burkina Faso)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/45E102061767</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/45E102061767</guid><description>
	Several studies have been reported on the blaTEM, blaCTX-M and blaSHV genes in Extended-spectrum -lactamase (ESBL) producing Enterobacteria, however very few studies reported in the literature are related to blaBES in ESBL producing Enterobacteria. This study concerns the molecular epidemiology of the blaBES gene in Enterobacteria identified from in-patients and out-patients at Saint Camille...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Isolation, production and characterization of amylase enzyme using the isolate Aspergillus niger FAB-211</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/9DE922D56542</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/9DE922D56542</guid><description>
	Amylase enzymes are industrially important enzymes used in food, sugar, textile, pharmaceutical, paper and detergent industries. The main objective of this study was to isolate, produce and optimize -amylase enzyme using a fungal strain isolated from fruit peel soil wastes. Media optimization was done by one-factor at a time method. Average values of duplicate experiments were taken. Microso...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Postharvest quality of tomato (Solanum lycopersicum) varieties grown under greenhouse and open field conditions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/4E81FEF55879</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/4E81FEF55879</guid><description>
	An experiment was carried out to evaluate performances of four tomato varieties (Bishola, Eshet, Marglobe and Moneymaker) harvested at ripe stage from greenhouse and open field condition at Jimma for post-harvest quality characters (total soluble solid, weight loss, titratable acidity, sugar-acid ratio, and pH). Bishola and Eshet had better chemical quality characteristics maintained through...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Selection and optimization of lignocellulosic substrate for laccase production from Pleurotus species</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/51E07B766771</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/51E07B766771</guid><description>
	The aim of the current study was to investigate the potential of Pleurotus species for laccase production on different lignocellulosic substrates and determine the optimal levels of physicochemical conditions required for the production. The study was conducted in National Agricultural Biotechnological Research Center, Holetta. The fruiting bodies of fungi were collected based on their morph...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Genotype by environment interactions and grain yield stability of released and advanced Desi type chickpea (Cicer arietinum L.) genotypes in western Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/181ADDF66508</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/181ADDF66508</guid><description>
	Genotype by environment interaction (GE) obstructs breeding by persuading variations in genotype performance in different environments and thereby complicating selection. The aim of the present study was to determine the stability and yield performance of desi type chickpea varieties and advanced lines at multiple growing environments of western Ethiopia, using genotype-by-environment intera...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of two Portuguese strains of Botryococcus braunii as biofuel feedstock</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/99E48FE66109</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/99E48FE66109</guid><description>
	ACOI 58 and ACOI 1257, two different Portuguese strains of colonial green microalga Botryococcus bruanii Kutz obtained from Coimbra Collection of Algae (ACOI), were evaluated on their potential for biofuel production, which was assessed from batch culture in photobioreactors under indoors and outdoors conditions using pretreated waste water and semisynthetic culture media. In the experiments...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Callus growth and ion composition in response to long-term NaCl-induced stress in two sugarcane (Saccharum sp.) cultivars</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/57B0B2264888</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/57B0B2264888</guid><description>
	In this work, the effect of different concentrations of NaCl on calli induced from two sugarcane cultivars NCo310 and CP59-73 was studied. Growth and ion concentrations (Na+, Cl-, K+ and Ca2+) of calli were determined after 1, 2 and 3 months of stress with the objective to understand the cellular mechanisms operating in salt stress tolerance and to determine the implication of inorganic frac...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Studies on various types of antigenic proteins of Fasciola spp. as a basis for the immunodiagnosis and vaccine development: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/926D78261087</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/926D78261087</guid><description>
	Fasciola spp. is responsible for huge economic losses and animal welfare issues within the agricultural sector worldwide. Protein profiling studies of the two economically important species of Fasciola, that is, Fasciola hepatica and Fasciola gigantica are important for identification of these species, their immunodiagnosis and also for vaccine designing. Protein profiling is expected to dis...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Efficient somatic embryogenesis of Jatropha curcas L. from petiole and leaf discs</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/FFCF7AA60770</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/FFCF7AA60770</guid><description>
	Jatropha curcas L. is peculiar treasured tree species for its uses and considerable economic potential as a biofuel plant. Propagation using seeds is limited by low viability and germination hence unable to provide high quality planting material for sustainable use. To achieve mass production of J. curcas, regeneration from leaf discs and petioles using different treatments of plant growth r...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Shoot nodal culture and virus indexing of selected local and improved genotypes of cassava (Manihot esculenta) from Sierra Leone</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/90909E059065</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJBMBR/article-abstract/90909E059065</guid><description>
	Cassava (Manihotes culenta Crantz) is among major food and income security crops in sub-Saharan Africa. However, high seed dormancy and delayed germination limit seed propagation. Using traditional stem cutting causes loss of superior genotypes and decreases productivity as a result of low multiplication ratio (1:10) and viral and bacterial diseases.Thus, the aim of this study was to optimiz...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>