<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Computer Engineering Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Computer Engineering Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Analysis and result of classification algorithm on email classification
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/C9AC37C61384</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/C9AC37C61384</guid><description>
	In this time, one of the most and fastest forms of communication is electronic mail or what we call e-mail. However, the increase of e-mail users has resulted in the dramatic increase of spam emails in the past few years. Spam is the use of electronic messaging systems to send bulk data. In this paper, e-mail data were classified as ham email and spam email using supervised learning algorith...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Framework for integrating fragmented information systems: Case of livestock information systems</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/688B63E65262</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/688B63E65262</guid><description>
	Information System (IS) is used for information communication. But the problem with the existing Agro-ISs is that they are not integrated. To integrate it, we need to have an integration framework. Generally, much has been done on the designing framework for IS integration. However, there are credible things which can be added to improve these frameworks. A framework can be designed in such ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In silico study in mitochondrial and chloroplast genomes of plants</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/0208F0359126</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/0208F0359126</guid><description>
	Simple sequence repeats (SSRs) or microsatellites constitute a countable portion of genomes. However, the significance of SSRs in organelle genomes has not been completely understood. The availability of organelle genome sequences allows us to understand the organization of SSRs in their genic and intergenic regions. In the current study, the mitochondrial and chloroplast genomes of differen...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Issues in a transactional database emanating from data warehouse project</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/43DC51758418</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/43DC51758418</guid><description>
	When a data warehouse (DW) is built, typical extraction, transformation, and loading operations are made, including cleaning tasks of the data, conflicts resolution, inconsistencies identification, and constrains checking, among others. In this work, two databases (DB) were combined to obtain indexes approved and failing course in basic sciences area (Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry) of the ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Real-time operating system (RTOS) with application to play models</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/195D6A948207</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/195D6A948207</guid><description>
	It is very important to improve the design of the real-time operating system (RTOS) especially if we want to use it in some special devices. Numerous researches have accepted conventional RTOS as being the customary approach for designing devices used by children. This is because these are able to facilitate the implementation different criteria such as clustering, stability and alternate pr...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The comparison of time division multiple access (TDMA) (global system for mobile communication, GSM) and wideband-code division multiple access (W-CDMA) (third generation, 3G) system based on their modulation techniques</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/55D552146260</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/55D552146260</guid><description>
	Mobile network communication system offers the users with seamless communication and this has caused wireless communication to increasingly become the preferred method of carrying multimedia traffic or messages such as voice, video, images, and data files. Time division multiple access (TDMA) is the multiple access scheme used in global system for mobile communication (GSM), while third gene...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An open source Geographic Information System (GIS) approach to water supply management, distribution and billing</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/39590068660</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/39590068660</guid><description>
	

	In this work a comprehensive solution for the Gatanga Water Trust (GWT) has been developed to assist it in managing its water supply and distribution. The solution comprises two subcomponents: a mapping component and a billing component which are tightly coupled together. The proposed system uses stable open source products for the mapping component and the database. At present the GWT ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Simulation analysis of proactive, reactive and hybrid routing protocols in mobile ad hoc network using Qualnet simulator 5.0.2</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/26610528663</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/26610528663</guid><description>
	

	Mobile ad hoc networks (MANETs) consist of a collection of wireless mobile nodes which dynamically exchange data among themselves without the reliance on a fixed base station or a wired backbone network. All nodes are mobile and can be connected dynamically in an arbitrary manner. There is no static infrastructure such as base station. All nodes of these networks behave as routers and t...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>New Holder-type inequalities for the Tracy-Singh and Khatri-Rao products of positive matrices</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/7C6247F8655</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/7C6247F8655</guid><description>
	

	Recently, authors established a number of inequalities involving Khatri-Rao product of two positive matrices. Here, in this paper, the results are established in three ways. First, we find new Holder-type inequalities for Tracy-Singh and Khatri-Rao products of positive semi-definite matrices. Secondly, the results are extended to provide estimates of sums of the Khatri-Rao and Tracy-Sin...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Design and simulation of an SMS driven microcontroller for home automation using proteus software
 </title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/936EEC08649</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJCER/article-abstract/936EEC08649</guid><description>
	

	Technology has moved from a level at which a user is always present in a place before he/she can control or do anything at the place. Imagine what television used to be before the inception of remote control. With the inception of remote control, the television can be controlled while lying on the bed or sitting down on the chair. You do not have to move towards it and press the button ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>