<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Educational Administration and Policy Studies - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Educational Administration and Policy Studies</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Teachers&#x2019; decisional participation and job satisfaction in secondary schools in Ekiti State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/7F6881563020</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/7F6881563020</guid><description>
	This study investigated the relationship between teachers decisional participation and job satisfaction in secondary schools in Ekiti State. The study also examined the level of teachers participation in decision making and level of job satisfaction. A descriptive research design of correlation type was adopted for the study while the population for the study comprised all the teachers teach...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How school climate predicts teachers&#x2019; organizational silence</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/5E2E5D663057</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/5E2E5D663057</guid><description>
	This study aims to explore the relationships between school climate constructs and teachers organizational silence (OS) and to analyze how school climate predicts teachers OS. The study population comprised all teachers (2,237) working in private primary schools in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. The sample consisted of 329 responses, which represented 14.7% of the original population. Structural equa...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Policy strategies for effective implementation of inclusive education in Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/7CA7AE963263</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/7CA7AE963263</guid><description>
	Educational frameworks mandate schools to adopt, design and implement strategies that support inclusive education. Despite the inclusive education policy, disability remains a major course of exclusion in learning institutions. The paper discusses the impact of school strategies in overcoming physical barriers that hinder the implementation of inclusive education. The actual sample constitut...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Balancing work, family and personal life: Perspectives of female staff at the College of Distance Education, University of Cape Coast, Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/0E5ADDC63317</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/0E5ADDC63317</guid><description>
	The study examined how female staff of the College of Distance Education (CoDE), University of Cape Coast (UCC) balance work, family and personal life roles, amidst their busy work schedules. A 21-item well-structured questionnaire was developed to collect primary data. Using the convenient sampling technique, 32 female staff was selected for the sample. Statistical tools such as percentages...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Participatory monitoring and evaluation for quality programs in higher education: What is the way for Uganda?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/B1A4F3B63573</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/B1A4F3B63573</guid><description>
	Participatory monitoring and evaluation (PME) is an approach that higher education institutions should use to ensure achievement of objectives especially quality academic programs, research, consultancies, outreach services and administrative functions. Indeed, over the past 10 years PME has gained increased prominence over more conventional approaches to monitoring and evaluation in public ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The teacher-parent nexus in the competency based curriculum success equation in Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/0B4906263660</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/0B4906263660</guid><description>
	Competency Based Curriculum (CBC) is based on learners demonstrating the ability to apply the knowledge, skills, attitudes and values they acquire as they progress through their education. Despite initial resistance, this curriculum is now under implementation in Kenya after a pilot study conducted across counties. Successful implementation of this curriculum requires the concerted efforts o...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing necessary leadership characteristics indicators of Secondary Basic School Administrators 
in Thailand
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/F0AA8C161234</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/F0AA8C161234</guid><description>
	This research aimed to develop the necessary leadership characteristics indicators of the secondary basic school administrators in Thailand. The samples were grouped into four including: (1) 10 specialists in the secondary educational administration, (2) 10 secondary school administrators of the educational quality assessment and its result with the best level, (3) 120 participants in the ex...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Strategic leadership factors of school administrators influencing the effectiveness of small- sized schools</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/F0BD4A260781</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/F0BD4A260781</guid><description>
	This research is aimed to study the direct, indirect and total influence of strategic leadership factors of school administrators influencing the effectiveness of small-sized schools. The samples were 1,396 administrators of small-sized schools under the primary educational service area office, the Basic Education Commission in the academic year 2017. The population was 15,999 small-sized sc...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The affective commitment of academics in a university in Botswana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/66631F160619</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/66631F160619</guid><description>
	Affective commitment remains an essential factor in key outcomes such as work performance and productivity, and has been shown to have the strongest positive relation with positive work behaviours when compared with normative commitment and continuance commitment. Using a sample of 164 academic employees at the University of Botswana, this study assessed the extent to which they had affectiv...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determining the effect of reducing procrastination tendency on the academic achievement in physics course
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/9542DFC59697</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEAPS/article-abstract/9542DFC59697</guid><description>
	In this research, the effect of reducing procrastination tendency on the academic achievement of pre-service science teachers in the physics course was investigated. In this, a quasi-experimental research design was used, which included the experimental and control groups. Each group consisted of 35 pre-service science teachers. Both groups were taught a physics course at the undergraduate l...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>