<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of English and Literature - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of English and Literature</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Hesitancy as an innate flaw in Hamlet's character: Reading through a psychoanalytic lens</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/C39C39A63540</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/C39C39A63540</guid><description>
	This paper concentrated on hesitancy as a characters flaw from the Freudian psychoanalysis focal point. Hamlets uncertainty is especially identified with his natural complex which frames his oblivious love for his mom and his lethal abhor for his dad. Freuds ideas of mans concealed want for annihilation and eradication may shape the reason for understanding Hamlets craving for death and suic...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The contribution of Freud&#x2019;s theories to the literary analysis of two Victorian novels: Wuthering Heights and Jane Eyre</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/472AEFC63846</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/472AEFC63846</guid><description>
	Sigmund Freuds psychoanalytical theories can be used with reference to the analysis of literary works. Reading novels, poems and other compositions through the lens of psychoanalysis gives the opportunity to analyse and evaluate the works of literature in their genesis and presentation. Freudian doctrine can be considered as a reading tool that allows the investigation of the enigmatic areas...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Semantic roles in Ruluuli-Runyala</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/AA109D663425</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/AA109D663425</guid><description>
	In this paper, we provide a detailed analysis of the semantic roles of applicative arguments in Ruluuli-Runyala. We present the semantic roles of applicative objects in view of the participant roles as semantically defined under sense relations: There is a general assumption that arguments of a verb could be allocated only one of these roles. The analysis follows the theoretical framework wh...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Deconstructing postcolonial scopic regimes: The subversion of power imaginaries in the novels of Ngugi wa Thiong&#x2019;o and Sony Labou Tansi</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/1BB7D7562704</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/1BB7D7562704</guid><description>
	This paper examines the relationship between visuality, knowledge and power in the postcolonial African novel. With examples from selected texts of Ngugi wa Thiongo and Sony Labou Tansi, it argues that visual culture, usually employed in the analysis of cultural images and material iconographies in media studies, can aptly be employed in textual analysis given that postcolonial novels are pr...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>&#x201C;What a Lark! What a Plunge!&#x201D; The influence of Sigmund Freud on Virginia Woolf</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/4E690D761291</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/4E690D761291</guid><description>
	To what extent did Sigmund Freud influence Virginia Woolf? Although they shared an advocacy for truth by means of stream of consciousness narration and free association, Woolf claimed to have had only superficial knowledge of Freud. Even if this was true, she could not help but be aware of his theories of psychoanalysis through the media of her day or by way of her publisher Hogarth Press, w...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ambivalent identity and self repatriation in the plot characterisation of selected black 
auto/biographical novels
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/4EDF9DE60507</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/4EDF9DE60507</guid><description>
	Literature of the Black Diaspora locates within its multi-layered gamut, a kaleidoscope of artistic productions; self-narratives careered by the quest for identity and self-expatriation from a ruthless atmosphere of slavery and racial subjugation. Studies have fixated on thematic preoccupation, language form in works of Afro-American and Caribbean traditions. Not so much has been explored es...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Are these students strategic enough? The study of college students&#x201D; application of self-regulation strategy into task oriented English learning</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/8B2E99B59939</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/8B2E99B59939</guid><description>
	Self-regulation is a popular theoretical application into discussing the second language (L2) learning efficacy. Students apply a variety of strategies to regulate their learning processes. In order to explore students self-regulatory learning strategies, this study assigned a 3-minute English introduction for the freshmen of the sport college students and observed their process of completin...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The Magnificence of Arabic: Orwa ibn Al-Ward an Epitome
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/9E9E8E759599</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/9E9E8E759599</guid><description>
	Orwa ibn Al-Ward is one of the greatest knights, heroes and poets who presented elegant pictures of Arabs before Islam by word and deed. In this literary article, the researcher attempts to probe the depth of the poetry of Orwa ibn Al-Ward as an instance of the greatness of Arabic poetic language as well as being a symbol of dignity, hospitality, generosity, manliness and sacrifice. Orwa ibn...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An analysis of bullying in schools as presented by two Ugandan novels</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/9C53D8259277</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/9C53D8259277</guid><description>
	This paper analyzes the depictions of bullying in schools in two selected Ugandan novels: Goretti Kyomuhendos The First Daughter (1996) and Mary Karooro Okuruts The invisible Weevil (1998). The study is about the vices that education transmits to the learners depending on the socio-cultural and political context. One of them that education transmits is the bullying of fellow students. Bullyi...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lyrical life: The prevailing mysticism of the evolution and inevitable putrefaction of the great human race</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/63A2A8159324</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJEL/article-abstract/63A2A8159324</guid><description>
	Souls come to light after a fierce fight / among lovely xx or xy pairs at day or night This hypothetical review is regarding the poem Lyrical Life which is a fourteen-line poem in a sonnet structure written by the author of this article. This article is intended to share the authors philosophy of life with that of other scholars and philosophers including pre-Socratic ones around the globe f...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>