<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Fisheries and Aquaculture - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Fisheries and Aquaculture</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Is aquaculture production by small-scale farmers profitable in Zambia?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/556442662883</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/556442662883</guid><description>
	The current and anticipated demographic changes worldwide are expected to increase fish and other animal protein consumption. Capture fisheries alone cannot meet these requirements. Aquaculture offers a way out if it can further be developed. However, in most developing countries, aquaculture is still in its infancy and the evidence on the industry is quite thin. We assess the profitability ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Active surveillance of infection caused by Aphanomyces invadans in Malawi</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/75DE2C962747</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/75DE2C962747</guid><description>
	In Malawi, fish is regarded as a cheapest source of animal proteins and other macronutrients. Recent epizootic ulcerative syndrome (EUS) outbreaks reported in countries sharing Chobe-Zambezi river system like Zambia, Democratic Republic of Congo, Botswana, Namibia, Zimbabwe and Republic of South Africa, have posed a major threat to fish production. Malawis biggest and important Shire River c...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Stress evaluation in dourado females (Salminus brasiliensis) submitted to two different methods of induced spawning</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/CA72B1261205</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/CA72B1261205</guid><description>
	The goals of this study were to evaluate dourado female egg viability submitted to stress condition caused by two different reproductive induction methods, extruded and semi-natural. Sixteen females randomly chosen were induced with pituitary extract and allocated in two groups; the first, in which oocytes were manually extruded and the second group, females were allowed to naturally spaw. B...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Microbiota of catfish (Clarias gariepinus) tissues harvested from vials polluted with soil from 
e-wastes dumpsite
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/22B925061207</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/22B925061207</guid><description>
	In this study the microbiota of Clarias gariepinus tissues harvested from e-waste-soil polluted vials were assessed. Soil samples contaminated with e-waste were analyzed using standard analytical protocol while the microbial study was obtained using standard conventional microbiological techniques. The results revealed that the soil was sandy-loamy and blackish in colour. High organic matter...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bioeconomic analysis of Engraulicypris sardella (USIPA) in South east arm of Lake Malawi

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/682E6CD61197</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/682E6CD61197</guid><description>
	Usipa Engraulicypris sardella is the most abundant small pelagic species in Lake Malawi. It plays an important part in the lake communities economy and food security. However, much remains unknown on their stock status and bioeconomic importance. This study is carried out to estimate the maximum economic yield and maximum sustainable yield for Usipa fishery in the South-east arm of Lake Mala...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Growth and feed utilization in Clarias gariepinus fingerlings fed on Acacia auriculiformis leaf supplemented diets</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/F055CB060343</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/F055CB060343</guid><description>
	Effect of Earleaf plant (Acacia auriculiformis) as feed additive was examined on Clarias gariepinus fingerlings (4.20.5 g) over a period 56 days against farm-made feed which served as the control. A. auriculiformis leaves were collected, air-dried (under shade), powdered and added at varying inclusion levels (0, 0.5, 1.0, 1.5 and 2.0%) to basal diets containing 40% crude protein. Fish were r...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Socio-economic characteristics of small-scale catfish farming enterprise in Obio/Akpor Local Government Area, Rivers State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/25E5EC360347</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/25E5EC360347</guid><description>
	The study of the socio-economic characteristics of any group is a requirement to a successful implementation of effective government assisted programme. The study examined the socio-economic characteristics, production processes and production constraints of small-scale catfish fishing enterprises in Obio/Akpor Local Government Area in Rivers State, Nigeria. Simple randomized sampling techni...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The spatio-temporal dynamics of the fish assemblage of the man-made Lake Buyo (Cote d'Ivoire, West Africa)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/335325260351</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/335325260351</guid><description>
	This study aims to characterize the spatio-temporal variation of the fish assemblages in relation to the environmental variables of Buyo Dam Lake. Sampling was performed from July 2017 to June 2018 using experimental fishing and commercial fishing. Spatio-temporal analysis indicated a significant variation (p 0.05) in pH, electrical conductivity, total dissolved solids, and water transparenc...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The abundance, distribution and diversity of benthic invertebrates of Lake Malombe</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/496F52459919</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/496F52459919</guid><description>
	The benthic zone of Lake Malombe was sampled for invertebrates, fungi and bacteria using an Ekman Grab measuring 15.2 cm by 15.2 cm. Thirty-six stations were surveyed for macro-invertebrates which were identified to the lowest taxa and enumerated to estimate abundance for the lake. Snails were the most dominant macro fauna, belonging to four genera Melanoides, Bellamya, Bulinus and Lanistes ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of feeding rates and feeding frequencies on growth performance, uniformity of the batch and survival rate of Amazon ornamental fish larvae</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/6812B4F59923</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJFA/article-abstract/6812B4F59923</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to evaluate the effect of different feeding rates and frequencies on angelfish (Pterophyllum scalare) and severum (Heros severus) larvae. For this purpose, two similar experiments were conducted in parallel. For each experiment, a total of 360 larvae were distributed in 36-1 L aquariums. The experiments were done using a factorial 3x3 completely randomized design, wi...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>