<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Genetics and Molecular Biology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Genetics and Molecular Biology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Morphological diversity patterns among selected elite Shea trees (Vitellaria paradoxa C.F. Gaertn.) from Tchologo and Bagou&#xE9; districts in Northern 
C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/ED4608762797</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/ED4608762797</guid><description>
	Agromorphological diversity structure of the elite shea trees identified in village lands and conserved in situ in the districts of Bagou and Tchologo by the shea breeding program of the University of Peleforo Gon Coulibaly (UPGC, Cte dIvoire), are not known. In the present study, we characterized the agromorphological parameters of 220 elite shea trees using a set of 12 quantitative traits....</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapping of fourteen high-risk human papillomavirus genotypes by molecular detection in sexually active women in the West African sub-region</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/5A6E55D62927</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/5A6E55D62927</guid><description>
	The aim of this study was to determine the distribution of high-risk human papillomavirus genotypes (HR-HPV) in women from the general population of five West African countries. This was a cross-sectional descriptive study, involving 2133 women from nine cities of five West African countries: Benin, Burkina Faso, Cte dIvoire, Niger and Togo. Women were screened for precancerous cervical lesi...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Distribution of groundnut rosette disease and sequence diversity of groundnut rosette virus associated satellite RNA (Sat-RNA) in Western Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/81BC2FC63204</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/81BC2FC63204</guid><description>
	Production of groundnuts (Arachis hypogaea L.) in Western Kenya is mainly constrained by groundnut rosette disease (GRD) which cause up to 100% yield loss. This disease expresses different symptoms as a result of variations in the groundnut rosette virus (GRV) associated satellite-ribonucleic acid (GRV Sat-RNA). Over the past 20 years, no work had been done to document the status of the dise...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>First detection of the hemizygote frameshift variant of the DMD gene in a 13-year-old patient affected by dystrophinopathy (Duchenne DMD and Becker BMD) at Saint Camille Hospital of Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso: Case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/A29689563411</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/A29689563411</guid><description>
	Genetic diseases are poorly reported in sub-Saharan Africa, especially in Burkina Faso. The reasons for this reality are multifactorial including, the difficulty of diagnostic confirmation, financial accessibility and even the difficulty with referral of cases by medical staff. Genetic diseases, although relatively rare, exist in families and deserve special attention in our paraclinical ass...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Verification of single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) markers associated with maize (Zea mays. L) streak virus resistance in early generation maize lines</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/F85DF6163923</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/F85DF6163923</guid><description>
	Maize streak virus (MSV) is a devastating viral disease of maize in sub-Saharan Africa. The disease may cause up to 100% yield loss in susceptible crops. The use of molecular markers can facilitate the development of varieties resistant to the virus. The objective of this study is to assess the usefulness of Single Nucleotide Polymorphism (SNP) markers linked to MSV resistance in selecting f...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Characterisation of three morphotypes of Solenostemon rotundifolius [(Poir.) J. K. Morton] cultivated in Burkina Faso using quantitative traits</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/126BFC061420</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/126BFC061420</guid><description>
	Evaluation of intra specific variability is a key step toward conservation and sustainable use of species. This study was carried out to describe the morphotypes of Solenostemon rotundifolius (Lamiaceae) based on quantitative traits. Three accessions (E02, E35 and E20), representing the morphotypes A, B and C were characterised in Randomised Complete Block Design with three replications. Twe...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary morphological characterization of West African dwarf (Djallonk&#xE9;) ewes from C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire based on qualitative and quantitative traits</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/963D6EB61515</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/963D6EB61515</guid><description>
	Phenotypic characterization is used to identify and document diversity within and between distinct breeds, based on their observable attributes. Study to assess the body characteristics and variability of 204 Djallonk (West African dwarf) ewes was conducted in three agro-ecological zones (central, western and northern) of Cte dIvoire, from November 2016 to April 2017. Animals were described ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of radio-sensitivity for three cowpea genotypes to gamma irradiation</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/BED9C9262401</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/BED9C9262401</guid><description>
	Cowpea (Vigna unguiculata [L.] Walp) is an important food legume. However, production is limited by various biotic and abiotic constraints in sub-Saharan Africa and reduced genetic variability hinders crop improvement efforts. Gamma ray irradiation has been used as a mutagen to create variability but optimal dose determination is a prerequisite to maximize the recovery of mutant plants. In t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Coexistence between (TOHO-type and BES-type) extended-spectrum &#x3B2;-lactamase genes of identified enterobacteria at Saint Camille Hospital, Ouagadougou, West Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/A31A5C562415</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/A31A5C562415</guid><description>
	Coexistence between the TOHO-type and Brazilian extended-spectrum (BES)-type of extended-spectrum -lactamase (ESBL)-produced by bacteria caused public health issue. Several studies have been reported on the coexistence between blaTEM, blaCTX-M and blaSHV genes in ESBL in broad spectrum enterobacteria. The present study involved the prevalence of coexistence of blaTOHO and blaBES genes in ent...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Inheritance of maize (Zea mays L.) leaf traits</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/0DA8B1362574</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJGMB/article-abstract/0DA8B1362574</guid><description>
	Maize leaf plays an important role in the synthesis of organic compounds. It hosts the interception of light energy and conversion to organic energy, and the capture and assimilation of carbon dioxide in order to produce food. In this study, we explore the heritability of the maize leaf length, leaf width, and the number of leaves of two maize genotypes, JNE and BLC. The estimates of heritab...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>