<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Library and Information Science - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Library and Information Science</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Analysis of responsibilities of electronic readiness and software for museums online in national commission for museums and monuments in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/11A07B161521</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/11A07B161521</guid><description>
	This study was carried to identify level of electronic readiness in museums by assessing the uses of electronic readiness provision in museum services, and also to determine the factors responsible for ineffective use of electronic readiness in museums. Descriptive survey research was used for this study. Total enumeration sampling technique was adopted for the sampling procedure. This was c...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Library value through user satisfaction: The case of academic libraries in Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/098C63F61639</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/098C63F61639</guid><description>
	The study is an investigative survey of library users satisfaction of library services, resources, staff conduct and impact of the library on the academic achievements of users. Qualitative data was collected from College students, faculty and library staff of two academic libraries in Ghana using questionnaires and interview instruments. The survey established that library services, informa...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of information literacy competency among students of College of Nursing and Midwifery, Kafanchan, Kaduna State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/5E058E662354</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/5E058E662354</guid><description>
	This study investigates the level of information literacy competency among students of College of Nursing and Midwifery School Kafanchan, Kaduna State, Nigeria. The study focuses on three basic skills namely: Identification, accession and evaluating skills. A survey research method was employed for this study. The study was based on the data collected through questionnaire tagged information...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>University Libraries as facilitators of academic development: A case study of Noakhali Science and Technology University Library, Bangladesh</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/41C023362526</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/41C023362526</guid><description>
	

	This study focused on the role of Noakhali Science and Technology University Library in the academic development of the university. A mixed method research design was used whereby copies of questionnaires and structured interview guide were utilized to collect data. The study was conducted among 100 library users (students, faculty and university staff), librarian and another member of ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring the postgraduate students&#x2019; perceptions, usefulness and effectiveness of information literacy skills at University of Malaya library</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/928CC9A61401</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/928CC9A61401</guid><description>
	The aim of this study was to find out the extent to which the postgraduate students who attended the information skills session at University of Malayas library perceived the session to be useful as well as effective in their attempts to locate, access and use the information needed so as to avail themselves of the library resources. In order to evaluate the perceived usefulness of informati...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Pre-implementation failure of information systems in public universities in Kenya: A case study of Moi University, Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/97FB99461139</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/97FB99461139</guid><description>
	Moi University was established in 1984 and its first decade of growth and expansion necessitated the adoption and utilisation of Information and Communication Technology (ICT) to manage information generated by its operations. Through Dutch Joint Financing Programme for Cooperation in Higher Education (MHO) and other donors assistance, it established an ICT centre charged with, among other f...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Use of electronic resources by postgraduate students in University of Cape Coast</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/3FE030A60216</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/3FE030A60216</guid><description>
	The study investigates the use of electronic resources by postgraduate students in University of Cape Coast (UCC). It specifically targets first year postgraduate students of UCC. Awareness, usage, training, and access were explored. A survey method was employed and a structured questionnaire was utilized to solicit data. The findings revealed that, though students are aware of electronic re...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Information acquisition mechanism of universities libraries: An empirical study of public university libraries in Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/CB8D11E59953</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/CB8D11E59953</guid><description>
	This paper takes a critical look at how academic libraries in Ghana acquire their information/materials. The investigation was mainly based on interviews. The interviews were conducted in four Ghanaian public university libraries from January 2014 to March 2015. In all, 38 senior members were interviewed. The findings indicated among other that the libraries under study purchase their librar...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Proliferation of library and information science schools in Nigeria: Issues at stake and quality control</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/48EAB5959467</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/48EAB5959467</guid><description>
	This paper highlighted the key issues at stake by the proliferation of Library and Information Science schools in Nigeria without due regard to the established standards. In terms of physical infrastructure, location, staffing issues, curriculum, laboratories and programme(s). The paper pointed out the use of other departmental facilities, building, over-relying on institutions library staff...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Provision of E-resources in Engineering College Libraries in India: A pilot study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/005FC9259353</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLIS/article-abstract/005FC9259353</guid><description>
	Libraries and information systems have been witnessing continuous transformation since the last two decades, particularly with regard to the collection of information resources and services. A spectrum of E-resources that have emerged during this time are chiefly responsible to this transformation and changed landscape of libraries in terms of collection development, storage and provisioning...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>