<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Livestock Production - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Livestock Production</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Comparative effects of Moringa oleifera powder and soybean meal on the zootechnical parameters of the ISA Brown pullet</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BA4280F63802</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BA4280F63802</guid><description>
	Poultry farming is an important sector of the Beninese agriculture. But this sector is facing economic difficulties. The aim of this study is to evaluate the effects of Moringa oleifera powder and soybean meal on zootechnical parameters in the ISA Brown pullet. For this purpose, the experiment was carried out on a total of 250 day-old chicks with an initial average weight of 40  1 g. Among t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of nutritional flushing on reproductive and body weight performance of Abergelle goat does</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BB9723263804</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/BB9723263804</guid><description>
	This study was aimed to evaluate the effect of flushing on the reproductive and body weight change on Abergelle breed does. The study indicated that a mix of 300 or 450 g wheat bran (WB) with 50 g noug seed cake (NSC) flushed per day improved the does conception rate (70 to 80%) and kidding rate (70%); while does flushed with low concentrate level (150 g WB plus 50 g NSC) or those not flushe...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The last of us? An online survey among German farm veterinarians about the future of veterinary training, livestock farming and the profession in general</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/448035D63806</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/448035D63806</guid><description>
	This online survey investigated how German farm veterinarians perceive the future of their profession. According to the participants, the following topics should play a greater role in veterinary training: Economics, herd health management, practical education, agricultural knowledge and animal welfare issues. The top answer indicates that knowledge about entrepreneurship is seen as a crucia...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The performance of artificial insemination delivery system in Amhara, Oromia, SNNP and Tigray Regions of Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/00B256663836</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/00B256663836</guid><description>
	The study was conducted in Amhara, Oromia, Southern Nations Nationalities and Peoples and Tigray regions of the country to provide information on the performance of Artificial Insemination (AI) service delivery system, its seasonality and effectiveness. Semi-structured questionnaire was prepared to interview AI technicians (on their performance and related issues) and farmers (about the outc...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative test of the two final commercial  dual-purpose breeds during early growth performance under on-farm management conditions in two districts of Jimma Zone, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/ECF35B363759</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/ECF35B363759</guid><description>
	This study was conducted to evaluate the production and reproduction performance of chicken breed under semi-scavenging system of Seka Chekorsa and Omo Nada districts of Jimma Zone. A total of 800 day old chicks were obtained from Debre Zeit Agricultural Research center. 50 day old chicks were distributed with hay box brooder, and the experiment was arranged in a nested design. The result of...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Indigenous browse species and goats&#x2019; preferences in selected districts of Gamo Gofa and Wolayta 
zones, Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/658515F63185</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/658515F63185</guid><description>
	Important browses in selected districts were identified using goats preference and farmers knowledge. A total of 296 plots (20  20 m area) were placed along 16 transect lines randomly laid in plane and sloppy communal grazing lands to assess frequency of occurrences and density of the browse species. A total of 48 browse species out of which 31 were recognized by farmers were observed being ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Estimation of major livestock feed resources and feed balance in Moyale district of Boran Zone, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/4DB93ED63187</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/4DB93ED63187</guid><description>
	The study was conducted to assess the major livestock feed resources and estimating annual feed production and feed balance in Moyale district of Boran Zone, Southern Ethiopia. A simple random sampling technique was employed to select the households (HHs) and 96 representative households were selected. Data were collected using group discussions, structured questionnaire, secondary data and ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Characterization of Begait cattle using morphometric and qualitative traits in Western Zone of Tigray, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/580CC8962879</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/580CC8962879</guid><description>
	The aim of the study is to characterize Begait cattle using morphometric and qualitative traits. The breed was kept under farm and ranch management systems in Western Tigray, Ethiopia. A total of 368 Begait cattle which included 24 male Begait cattle were selected using simple random sampling method and the data were analyzed using statistical packages for social sciences and statistical ana...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Immune response following Newcastle disease immunization and growth performance of kuroiler, broiler and local Tanzanian chickens</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/F4E0B3462613</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/F4E0B3462613</guid><description>
	Chicken is a major livestock species raised by smallholder households in rural areas in developing countries of Sub-Saharan Africa as a chief source of meat protein and income generation. However, Newcastle disease largely compromises the production of this precious bird under backyard production settings. The purpose of the study was to assess antibody responses and growth performance follo...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Characterization of scavenging and intensive chicken production system in Lume District, East Showa Zone, Oromia Regional State, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/9A64AA162789</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJLP/article-abstract/9A64AA162789</guid><description>
	This study is aimed at characterizing scavenging and intensive chicken production system in Lume district of East Shoa Zone, Oromia Region, Ethiopia. Random samplings were employed to select sample kebeles and purposively select respondents based on numbers of chicken population in scavenging and production system (intensive) to identify the specific challenges affecting chicken production. ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>