<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Medicine and Medical Sciences - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Medicine and Medical Sciences</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Information and communication technologies and patient empowerment: A complex skein</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/E0A943B63370</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/E0A943B63370</guid><description>
	This article aims to explore the relationship between patient empowerment and information and communication technologies (ICTs). Indeed, ICTs are considered important for increasing access to medical information and for patients other experiences, thereby nourishing the empowering rhetoric. The paper presents a research study conducted in Italy that focuses on the self-assessments made by on...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cause specific and trends of mortality in Nigeria: A six-year study of a tertiary hospital</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/6A4E3C162609</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/6A4E3C162609</guid><description>
	Mortality data necessary for proper healthcare planning, policy formulation, and implementation is hampered by a decline in hospital autopsy practice. Therefore, non-autopsy based death profile reviews provide a framework for the presentation and discussion of reliable mortality data. This study aims to present the general mortality profile of the University of Port Harcourt Teaching Hospita...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Arousal perception/misperception and total sleep time misperception in subjects with sleep disorders</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/11D9FD961013</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/11D9FD961013</guid><description>
	Limited studies have examined arousal perception in obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) or other sleep disorders. The aim of this study is to evaluate the factors that affect patients arousal and total sleep time perception. This is a retrospective study of 210 subjects divided into 5 groups: Primary insomnia; upper airway resistance syndrome (UARS)/primary snoring; mild, moderate and severe OSA. ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Common ultramarathon trail running injuries and illnesses: A review (2007-2016)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/D54816860527</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/D54816860527</guid><description>
	Regardless of the significant growth of ultra-marathon trail-running races over the last 40 years, epidemiological research is lacking. Presently, no review paper exists that integrates the empirical surveillances of ultra-marathon trail runners injuries and illnesses. The purpose of this work is to integrate the empirical findings of injuries and illness among trail runners during the perio...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Correlates and self-management strategies of premenstrual dysphoric disorder (PMDD) among nursing students in a Nigerian teaching hospital</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/466E22D60329</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/466E22D60329</guid><description>
	Premenstrual dysphoric disorder (PMDD) is a severe premenstrual disorder characterized by distressing symptoms and significant impairments in personal, social and professional functioning. The study aimed to determine the magnitude of Premenstrual syndrome (PMS) and PMDD among nursing students of Usmanu Danfodiyo University Teaching Hospital (UDUTH) Sokoto State, Nigeria. A cross-sectional s...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of the trend and risk factors of under-five diarrhea morbidity and mortality in two selected communities in the West-Mamprusi District</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/1FEBBC560413</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/1FEBBC560413</guid><description>
	Diarrhea episodes among children under five years with its devastating consequences have been a concern to stakeholders in child survival strategy programs. Mothers are key in the prevention of diarrhea among children since they are the care givers. The main aim of this paper is to assess the trend and risk factors of under-five diarrheal disease in the study areas. Descriptive research desi...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of preoperative hypertension and its intraoperative anesthetic management among patients undergoing elective surgery at Hawassa University Comprehensive Specialized Hospital, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/A4DB2A860228</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/A4DB2A860228</guid><description>
	Overall, twenty of the worlds adult populations live with hypertension. Blood pressure determination forms an integral part of anesthesiologists evaluation of the patient prior to and during surgery. 25% of surgical patients have hypertension preoperatively. There are several risks related to untreated preoperative hypertension in perioperative and postoperative phase. The objective of this ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence and risk factors of acute backache after spinal anesthesia in surgical procedures at Asella Teaching and Referal Hospital, Asella, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/59B731F59949</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/59B731F59949</guid><description>
	Spinal anesthesia is one of the routinely anesthetic procedures done in practice. Post spinal backache is one of the complications causing discomfort in patients, leading to rejection of its use for next operations. The aim of this work is to assess the prevalence and factors associated with backache after spinal anesthesia from October to January at Asella Teaching and Referral Hospital, As...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cystatin C protection of human umbilical vein endothelial cell against oxidative stress injury through activating autophagy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/8638FA459582</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/8638FA459582</guid><description>
	Cystatin C (CysC)-induced autophagy may play a beneficial role in preventing subarachnoid hemorrhage-induced cerebral vasospasm. The role of CysC in endothelial cells (ECs) autophagy is unknown. This study explores the role of CysC during the process of oxidative stress in human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs). Oxidized LDL (oxLDL) was used to stimulate HUVECs in vitro study. The l...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Updating traumatic optic neuropathy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/B9E5EF959265</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJMMS/article-abstract/B9E5EF959265</guid><description>
	Traumatic optic neuropathy (TON) is the affectation of the visual function, secondary to a damage caused by a direct or indirect traumatic mechanism over the optic nerve. It occurs in approximately 0.5 to 5% of closed head injuries, and in 2.5% of patients with maxillofacial trauma and mid-face fractures. The types of TON are direct, anterior indirect, posterior indirect, and chiasmal. This ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>