<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Nutrition and Metabolism - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Nutrition and Metabolism</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Vitamin D status of pregnant Moroccan women during the last gestational trimester</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/A09A2CB63306</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/A09A2CB63306</guid><description>
	This work is a prospective study that aims to evaluate the vitamin D status of Moroccan women during the last trimester of their pregnancy to establish the prevalence of hypovitaminosis D. We carried out, within the Mohammed V Military Teaching Hospital (HMIMV), a six-month prospective study on the vitamin status D of 152 Moroccan women during their last gestational trimester. Maternal blood...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The level of adherence to food by prescription (FBP) program among adults living with HIV/AIDS in Addis Ababa City, Ethiopia: A facility-based cross-sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/BB219DE63308</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/BB219DE63308</guid><description>
	Considering the importance of nutritional health for people living with HIV, programs delivering nutritional support have been scaled up globally. Among various programs, the Food by Prescription (FBP) program has been implemented in Ethiopia since 2010. This study was undertaken to assess the level of adherence to the FBP program and identify the associated factors among HIV infected adults...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of the nutritional status of adult subject with cancer at the Treichville University hospital center</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/342A49162260</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/342A49162260</guid><description>
	While multidisciplinary consultation meetings on therapeutic protocols, psychological management, treatment of pain for patients living with cancer are setting up, their nutritional status in Cte-dIvoire is almost absent in oncology units. This study aimed to assess the nutritional profile of adult patients with cancer, followed at the oncology service of the University Hospital of Treichvil...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Appropriate complementary feeding practice among mothers of 6-23 months old children in Kedida Gamela district, south Ethiopia: A community based cross-sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/E14DCBE61542</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/E14DCBE61542</guid><description>
	Introduction of complementary foods to infants is a common practice. However, according to recommended infant and young child feeding protocol the timing of introduction, frequency of feeding and the quality of diet are not appropriate. Thus, the aim of this study is to determine the magnitude and identify the predictors of appropriate complementary feeding practice among mothers of children...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Production and nutritional evaluation of cookies blended from sorghum, cowpea, plantain and sweet potato</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/71A56F061545</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/71A56F061545</guid><description>
	This study was carried out to produce and evaluate the nutritional quality of cookies formulated from sorghum and fortified with cowpea, plantain and sweet potato. The sorghum and cowpea were subjected to processing technique of sprouting while plantain and sweet potato was peeled oven dried at 45C. The sorghum variety used was Chakalari white, a low tannin variety, cowpea (Borno red), plant...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Protective effect of vitamin C against theobromine induced hepatorenal and cardio toxicity in male albino Wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/C07886260451</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/C07886260451</guid><description>
	The protective effect of vitamin C against theobromine induced toxicity in male albino Wistar rats was investigated. Twenty-five (25) male Wistar rats weighing between 140  160 g were divided into 5 groups with 5 rats in each group. Group 1 served as the control. Group 2 received 700 mg/kg body weight of theobromine daily for 4 days. Group 3 was administered 100 mg/kg body weight of Vitamin ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Acute glycemic level and its association with physical activity recommendation among type 2 diabetic patients in Illubabor zone oromiya, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/A3A0E3459889</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/A3A0E3459889</guid><description>
	Poor and inadequate glycemic control among patients with Type 2 diabetes constitutes a major public health problem and major risk factor for development of diabetes complications. In clinical practice, optimal glycemic control is difficult to obtain because the reasons for poor glycemic control in Type 2 diabetes are complex. This study aims to determine Acute glycemic level and its associat...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors associated with nutritional status among lactating mothers at Shashemene Woreda, West Arsi Zone, Oromia, Ethiopia: A comparative cross-sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/EABA99159391</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/EABA99159391</guid><description>
	Inadequate nutritional intake prior to pregnancy, during pregnancy and lactation process increases postnatal nutritional stresses and health risk of the mother resulting in a high maternal mortality. The aim of this study was to compare nutritional status and associated factors of urban and rural lactating women from Shashemene Woreda, West Arsi Zone of Oromia, Ethiopia. A community based co...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Wearable nutrition and dietetics technology on health nutrition paradigm shift in low and middle income countries</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/238827C57981</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/238827C57981</guid><description>
	Real-time, effective and affordable nutrition and dietetics wearable technology and sensors are emerging field with immense opportunities and benefits to the global nutrition challenge. As a powerful public health nutrition game changer, it requires more research and development support in tackling food security and nutrition safety challenges and evidence in local and global priorities need...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of a pasture-based pork production system on the expression of genes involved in lipid metabolism and meat quality characteristics</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/E59A68A57389</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNAM/article-abstract/E59A68A57389</guid><description>
	Studies have shown that pasture-raised pork is fresher and of higher nutritional value than its conventional counterpart. This study was to determine the effect of grazing systems on meat quality, carcass traits, and on lipid metabolism gene expressions. Control pigs were fed 100% commercial diet. Fifty/fifty (50/50) group was placed on 50% of the diet consumed by control group plus free acc...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>