<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Nursing and Midwifery - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Nursing and Midwifery</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Experiences and coping strategies of perinatally bereaved mothers with the loss</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/F86D55C63653</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/F86D55C63653</guid><description>
	This study explored the experiences, coping strategies, and support systems available for perinatally bereaved mothers. A descriptive phenomenological design was employed to explore lived experiences of perinatally bereaved mothers and saturation was reached with the 12th participant. Participants were recruited through purposive sampling and data was collected by in-depth, individual and fa...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Perceived determinants of home delivery following antenatal care in general hospital Ikara, Ikara Local Government Area, Kaduna State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/95EEA7263656</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/95EEA7263656</guid><description>
	The study aim to determine the factors that make women deliver at home after attending antenatal care, to determine the awareness of women on risks associated with home delivery, to determine the type of birth attendants available during home delivery, and to explore the opinions of women on various strategies to prevent home delivery. A non- experimental cross-sectional design was used, wit...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A case series of maternal-newborn delivery outcomes in rural Zambia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/121223A63393</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/121223A63393</guid><description>
	In rural Zambia, pregnant mothers are referred from rural primary health facilities designed to provide Basic Emergency Obstetric and Newborn Care (BEmONC) to district hospitals where Comprehensive Emergency Obstetric and Newborn Care (CEmONC) can be provided when needed. Maternity waiting homes (MWH) are residential dwellings where mothers can await delivery and may offer a possible early r...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evidence of perpetration of intimate partner violence among HIV positive couples: A systematic scoping review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/BADD5E563413</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/BADD5E563413</guid><description>
	Intimate partner violence (IPV) is a key public health and social concern among couples in countries globally. A systematic review was conducted to find out information concerning literature on the perpetration of IPV among couples infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). The main objective of this study was to search for evidence of IPV among couples infected with HIV. Specifically...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of tetanus toxoid immunization training program on knowledge and attitude on female nursing students in Government Universities in Khartoum State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/D97B84963483</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/D97B84963483</guid><description>
	Tetanus is an acute infectious disease, most cases occur due to lack of vaccination or incomplete immunization on exposure leading to increase morbidity and mortality. Studies reveal that adequate knowledge regarding tetanus is more important for the prevention of maternal and neonatal tetanus in the future. The study aims to study effect of tetanus toxoid immunization training program on kn...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Midwives perspectives on risk factors influencing maternal morbidity and mortality rates in Zambia: A case of Lusaka and Mumbwa Districts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/42394BD63485</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/42394BD63485</guid><description>
	Maternal and neonatal mortality has remained a public health challenge in developing countries, particularly in Zambia despite the efforts to improve access and use of maternal health care services universally. Majority of these maternal deaths could be prevented by ensuring access to good-quality maternal health services, such as antenatal and postnatal care, and skilled attendance during c...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurses&#x2019; perspectives about context specific job factors and coping strategies for back pain experiences among nurses in Lusaka, Zambia: A qualitative study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/66199A963321</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/66199A963321</guid><description>
	Nurses comprise the largest group of the health care workforce and play a central role in patient care activities. This study explored nurses perspectives about context specific job factors and coping strategies for back pain experiences among nurses in Lusaka, Zambia. An interpretive paradigm qualitative research design was used. Participants were selected using maximum variation including ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence and factors related to hot flashes and night sweats in postpartum women in Japan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/6831BBD62982</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/6831BBD62982</guid><description>
	Hot flashes and night sweats commonly occur during menopausal transition period due to estrogen deficiency, but these conditions can also occur during postpartum period in which there are marked hormonal fluctuations. This study determined the prevalence and examined factors related to hot flashes and night sweats among the Japanese women in the postpartum period. The design of this study wa...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Work engagement among midwives working at advanced perinatal care facilities in Japan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/61EBE9562635</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/61EBE9562635</guid><description>
	This study seeks to clarify the current situation and associated factors regarding Work Engagement (WE) among midwives working in advanced care facilities, which bear the brunt of care for high-risk pregnancies, as well as the contribution of WE to quality of care. A self-administered questionnaire survey was conducted in 2016 with the participation of 503 midwives working in 36 general peri...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Views of health care providers on factors hindering women with obstetric fistula in seeking fistula repair services in Zambia: The case of Muchinga, Luapula, Eastern and Southern provinces</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/71A71AF62753</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJNM/article-abstract/71A71AF62753</guid><description>
	Poor use of fistula repair services has contributed to the continued consequences of obstetric fistula that are physical, psychological, social, financial and economic among the afflicted women. The study was designed to assess views of health care providers on factors hindering women with obstetric fistula in seeking fistula repair services. A descriptive cross sectional design was used. Si...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>