<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Psychology and Counselling - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Psychology and Counselling</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Personality traits and emotional intelligence among health care professionals in a tertiary hospital</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/E92799B63376</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/E92799B63376</guid><description>
	Emotional Intelligence (EI) is considered fundamental to get along with others in the workplace. The dearth of literature on personality traits and EI among healthcare professionals calls for concerns. Therefore, this study examined personality traits and emotional intelligence among healthcare professionals in a tertiary hospital in Maiduguri. A cross-sectional survey design was adopted, an...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Social guidance and counselling support services on the study habits of distance learners: A case of learners in Bachelor of Education programmes by distance learning of University of Nairobi, Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/A98901862853</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/A98901862853</guid><description>
	Distance learners in some studies have reported feelings of isolation and lack of direction in developing effective study habits. The purpose of this study is to establish the extent to which social guidance and counselling influence study habits of learners in Bachelor of Educational programmes by distance learning of the University of Nairobi. Data were collected using structured questionn...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Making space for the adolescent unconscious: A case-based reflection on practice
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/128F78E63062</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/128F78E63062</guid><description>
	Community-based psychotherapists and school counsellors work to assist adolescents through sharing resources, building awareness of cognition and behavior, and skill development in communicative competence. However, adolescents, eager to delve deeper into the unknown territory of their being, also present us with speech and acts coming from the unconscious, in the form of metaphors, forgetti...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Influence of psychological training on personal and professional development and group cohesiveness among the staff of residential campus, BRAC University</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/B46EDC763158</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/B46EDC763158</guid><description>
	The present study aims to identify the impact of psychological training on the staff of BRAC University and how it has increased the group bonding of staff members. To see the impact, researchers conducted a series of training session with the participants over a span of one year. After the training, data were collected through interview method from the 18 participants. Besides, observation ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A historical perspective of the field of emotional and behavioral disorders: A review of literature</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/662F88D62183</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/662F88D62183</guid><description>
	The purpose of this paper is two-fold. First, to review relevant literature forming the foundation of the field of emotional and behavioral disorders. This historical methodology focuses on examining research from the 1700s to 2017, starting with the history of emotional disorders, the Freudian theory, the federal special education laws that emerged throughout history, and lastly tracing its...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Expanding the internalized homonegativity Scale by including the factor of fear of being identified as a non-heterosexual person</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/39A4CAC61759</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/39A4CAC61759</guid><description>
	The purpose of this instrumental research was to expand the Internalized Homonegativity Scale to assess a new factor, the fear of being identified as a non-heterosexual person, and to validate the new instrument. A questionnaire was applied to an incidental sample of 200 medical students from a private university in Monterrey, Mexico. This questionnaire was composed of four items about socio...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Differential item functioning of the career aspiration scale within Arab context</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/EE1264361423</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/EE1264361423</guid><description>
	The aim of the study was to examine the psychometric properties and the differential items functioning of short version of Career Aspiration Scale (CAS) in a sample of 2700 of Omani high school students. The results of the total score of CAS showed acceptable internal consistency (Cronbachs =0.67). An exploratory factor analysis yielded a support for nine items version identifying single con...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Understanding the psychology of youths: Generation gap</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/E100ED461403</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/E100ED461403</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to understand the mind set of youths in relation to gender, college, and achievement levels. It is of essence, that counsellors, educators, parents and policy makers are able to uncover the factors that increase the gap between generations, so that they are can help them adjust to educational institutions, family system, work environment, and life in general. A sampl...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The impact of bullying and victimization among deaf students in residential schools and distressful behaviors of deaf students</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/7A9036361079</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/7A9036361079</guid><description>
	Bullying and victimization remains a persistent phenomenon in schools within the United States of America. However, no studies have focused on bullying and victimization among deaf students. This cross-sectional study was conducted to determine the frequency of bullying and victimization among deaf children. Further, the study examined deaf children who could read and write at their respecti...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effectiveness of counselling services on retention rate of undergraduate students in selected universities 
in Kenya
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/2E29C4560734</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPC/article-abstract/2E29C4560734</guid><description>
	The purpose of the study is to assess the extent to which counselling services in universities in Kenya influences students retention rate. The study was carried out in 2018 where one hundred and one medical students in first year second semester from two public universities were studied to determine the effectiveness of counselling services on retention rate of undergraduate students. Quant...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>