<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Peace and Development Studies - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Peace and Development Studies</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Urban local authorities in Zimbabwe and the new constitution</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/50134E362923</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/50134E362923</guid><description>
	Urban areas have always attracted the attention of political parties due to their dense demographic compositions, hence their popularity as battle grounds among political parties. This has resulted in amendments and consolidation of local government legislation to ensure that urban local authorities enjoy only delegated powers and remain accountable to the central administration. Consequentl...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust relationship: The way of peace between India and Pakistan
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/698862A62682</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/698862A62682</guid><description>
	This article investigates the root cause of conflict between India and Pakistan and ways to mitigate it. Following Trust Relationship theory, both countries can send a number of their citizens to the neighbour country for some useful purposes. But as they come to the other country as a part of Trust Relationship pact, they need not to be harassed by long process of Passport and Visa processi...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Extremist violence, secular and religious: Is there a more basic counter path?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/810FBCA61362</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/810FBCA61362</guid><description>
	This paper argues that the present counter-measures to deal with the plague of extremist violence in the world are inadequate, in that they are largely reactive rather than addressing the root causes, which are prejudices of various kinds. It postulates the need for a united global approach in this matter based on spiritual principles.

	

	Key words: Extremism, extremist violence, terro...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Presenting natures, factors, and security implications of farmland related inter-household conflict in Northern Ethiopian Highlands of Wollo: Evidences from Jamma Woreda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/C9F9E6661348</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/C9F9E6661348</guid><description>
	The focus of this study is to investigate and analyze the different factors of inter-household conflicts over farmland. The study further sought to assess the human security implications on the community of the study area. It has been found that farmers in the study area are suffering from land-related conflicts and its associated impacts. Descriptive-case study was employed in the study. In...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Christian-Muslim dialogue with particular reference to Pentecostals and Muslims in Nairobi, Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/B9C98D159691</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/B9C98D159691</guid><description>
	Interfaith dialogue is becoming a household name in our global society within the context of religious pluralism. Christians and Muslims are widely spread across the globe commanding almost a half of global population. Some Christians, particularly among some Pentecostals view Muslims with distrust, apprehension and rivalry. In Nairobi, Kenya, features of mistrust, disharmony, and intoleranc...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Countering &#x201C;Islamic fundamentalism&#x201D; and out group hostility in North-East Ethiopia: Kemissie city administration Muslims</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/A5681A259693</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/A5681A259693</guid><description>
	Religious fundamentalism and inter/out group conflict have gained international concerns. Fundamentalism in relation to Islam is subject to debate and controversy, in particular because of the way in which Islam has been objectified as the fundamentalist by the West. Fundamentalism is understood as exclusive to religion. And the research intends to explore the responses, positions and views ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Rural development: Lessons never learnt</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/847A79F58734</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/847A79F58734</guid><description>
	Life is supposed to be a great teacher, but in the development field lessons have never been learnt because errors of decades ago continue being entrenched today, by more enlightened people. This paper deploys critical theories of rural development and community participation to explain why communities resist development projects. One such incident is community resistance to a donor-funded m...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Community participation in transformation of rural livelihoods and climate smart farming technologies in the semi-arid lands of Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/0F08B9258736</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/0F08B9258736</guid><description>
	Semi-arid areas in developing countries continue to depend on rain-fed agriculture which is exacerbated by climate change and poor governance. Despite efforts and investments by governmental and non-governmental organizations to address the issue of food insecurity in the semi-arid areas of Kenya, the problem still persists. The communities have designed themselves to be resource poor wherea...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Remedying the retreat in the protection of citizens&#x2019; international human rights</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/2571CC058011</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/2571CC058011</guid><description>
	The article argues that in the light of the many continuing gross abuses of international human rights perpetrated in many parts of the world and the growing disillusionment with the international human rights regime as a whole, the regime needs comprehensive reassessment. It is argued that the underlying cause of this situation is the disunity of the present global system and its competing ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Security, peace and development: Unpacking discursive constructions of wartime rape and sexual violence in Syria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/1772B2C57007</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPDS/article-abstract/1772B2C57007</guid><description>
	The rape-as-a-weapon of war narrative has been particularly influential in the securitization of sexual violence. Drawing upon ideas about the fetishization of Conflict-Related Sexual Violence (CRSV), this article unpacks the language used within this security paradigm. Using an original case study, discourse analysis is used to unpack how policymakers, activists and the news media construct...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>