<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Plant Physiology and Biochemistry - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Plant Physiology and Biochemistry</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Haulm application and dipping treatments of gibberellic acid on tuber dormancy breaking and sprout induction of potato (Solanum tuberosum L.) in Central Highlands of Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/7BABDD662996</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/7BABDD662996</guid><description>
	Potato, an important food and nutrition security can be produced two or more times in a year in Ethiopia. It plays an important role in human diet and a source of income for smallholder farmers. However, its productivity is low owing to limited availability of planting materials and poor tuber sprouting of improved varieties. Lack of quality seed is a major problem affecting expansion of pot...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative qualitative phytochemical analysis of oil, juice and dry forms of garlic (Allium sativum) and different varieties of onions (Allium cepa) consumed in Makurdi metropolis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/A0BE6C763447</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/A0BE6C763447</guid><description>
	The qualitative phytochemical analysis of oil, juice and dry forms of garlic and three species of onions (red, brown and white onions) was investigated. Samples of fresh and dried garlic, red, brown and white onions were prepared and analyzed. All the samples were analyzed for the presence of phytochemicals which include saponins, flavonoids, phenols, tannins, triterpenoids, cardiac glycosid...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phosphates solubilizing bacteria like promoter&#x2019;s agent of cocoa-tree growth and biocontrol of Phytophthora megakarya Brasier and M.J. Griffin, agent of black pod disease
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/D842F4F61543</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/D842F4F61543</guid><description>
	Black pod is an important fungal disease of Theobroma cacao L. which causes significant yield losses in the field and consequently, inhibits the growth and development of the plant. For this purpose, the objective of this work was to evaluate the impact of phosphates solubilizing bacteria on growth of cocoa-tree and the biocontrol of Phytophthora megakarya, which is the most aggressive agent...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of salt stress on flowering, fructification and fruit nutrients concentration in a local cultivar of chili pepper (Capsicum frutescens L.)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/5C7758E61485</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/5C7758E61485</guid><description>
	Salt stress is one of the major environmental constraints limiting agricultural productivity and influencing the concentration of bioactive compounds of vegetables. In this study, we assessed the effect of NaCl salt stress on flowering, fructification and fruit nutritional quality of a local cultivar of chili pepper. The experiment was carried out in a screen house as a completely randomized...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cytokinin levels and expression profiles of cytokinin metabolic genes in late stage maize kernels</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/AB11ABD59147</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/AB11ABD59147</guid><description>
	Cytokinins (CK) are key determinants of seed size and their level can impact crop yield. The biological activities and chemistry of cytokinins are well defined but less is known about their molecular mode of action during maize kernel development, especially in late stage kernels. To understand the regulation of cytokinin levels at late stage kernel development, we examined the levels of act...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of salinity stress on growth in relation to gas exchanges parameters and water status in amaranth (Amaranthus cruentus)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/F3A2AAD58459</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/F3A2AAD58459</guid><description>
	Salinity is a major detrimental abiotic factor for plant growth. The main purpose of this study was to analyze the effects of different NaCl concentrations on growth and some physiological parameters related to gas exchanges and water relations in amaranth (Amaranthus cruentus) plants. Three weeks old amaranth plants from the cultivar Locale were exposed in nutrient solution to 0, 30 or 90 m...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Estimation of auxins and cytokinins requirements in sugarcane soma clones for effective in vitro regeneration procedure</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/3D5364F56565</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/3D5364F56565</guid><description>
	Three sugarcane varieties were used in this experiment to optimize specific plant hormones. The present work was conducted in 2014 at Nuclear Institute of Agriculture (NIA), Tando jam. The experiment was designated with three sugarcane varieties (NIA-2012, NIA-105 and GULABI-95) obtained from Nuclear Institute of Agriculture (NIA) Tando jam. Regeneration of plantlets was compared under diffe...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Allelopathic effects of alkaloid fraction of Crotalaria retusa Linn on growth and some biochemical parameters of bean seedlings (Phaseolus vulgaris</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/B3D854156255</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/B3D854156255</guid><description>
	The study investigated the potentials of alkaloidal fraction of leaf and stem of Crotalaria retusa with a view to understanding its mechanism of allelopathy in bean (Phaseolus vulgaris) seedlings. The study involved collection of C. retusa (leaves and stems), identification, dried, pulverized and extracted with methanol to yield methanolic extract (MECR). Crude alkaloid fraction was prepared...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of jasmonic acid on some biochemical and physiological parameters in salt-stressed Brassica napus seedlings</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/D265EAB65969</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/D265EAB65969</guid><description>
	The present study demonstrated the effect of jasmonic acid (JA) on pigments and vitamins involved in photosynthesis or other metabolic activities during salt stress in Brassica napus L. Exposure to different concentrations of NaCl decreased pigments such as total chlorophyll, -carotene, and lycopene to significant low levels but interestingly salinity increased total protein of B. napus L. s...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Identification of Pisum sativum L. cytokinin and auxin metabolic and signaling genes, and an analysis of their role in symbiotic nodule development</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/EE2C33E64910</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPPB/article-abstract/EE2C33E64910</guid><description>
	The present work was designed to study the role of the phytohormones, cytokinin and auxin, in the symbiosis development between pea Pisum sativum L. and Rhizobium leguminosarum bv. viciae. To achieve this aim, the temporal expression patterns of the genes related to the cytokinin and auxin biosynthesis, perception, and response were studied. It was found that most of these genes showed speci...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>