<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Physical Sciences - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Physical Sciences</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Determination and establishment of empirical relationship between magnetic susceptibility and mechanical properties of typical basement rocks in Southwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/28678DF63872</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/28678DF63872</guid><description>
	Magnetic susceptibility and mechanical properties of rocks in a typical basement complex Southwestern Nigeria were correlated with the aim of establishing empirical equations relating the two parameters and evaluate the parameters as related to its competency in hosting civil structures. A total of thirty rock samples were taken across the geology of the area and subjected to mechanical prop...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Interpretation of aeromagnetic data over some parts of Sokoto Basin, Nigeria, using source parameter imaging and 3D Euler deconvolution methods</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/B00067F63907</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/B00067F63907</guid><description>
	This investigation is aimed at determining depth to the bottom of magnetic source and to reveal some certain geological features across Sokoto basin using source parameter imaging and 3D Euler deconvolution techniques. The investigation employed fifteen number aeromagnetic sheets covering longitude 430E - 600E and latitude 1100N - 1330N. The total magnetic intensity of the area was subjected...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Influence of natural additives and crushed bricks on the physical and mechanical properties of repair and restoration mortars</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/4991DF663770</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/4991DF663770</guid><description>
	This study aims to evaluate the influence of different additives, including natural additives such as olive oil and eggs, on repair and restoration mortars. This work enables us to verify the effects of these natural components and their impact on the physical and mechanical characteristics of various types of repair mortars. Four mortar formulations were developed and analysed: Two jointing...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Preparation of thermal neutron absorber based B4C/TiO2/polyaniline nanocomposite</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/F61EFBD63493</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/F61EFBD63493</guid><description>
	B4C nanoparticles (NPs) have been integrated at that point veiled by TiO2 NPs lastly composited by utilizing polyaniline (PANI), (B4C/TiO2/PANI). Shields of thermal neutrons by B4C/TiO2/PANI have been considered, B4C/TiO2/PANI nanocomposite was described by FTIR spectroscopy, and nanometer size, morphology, and structures of tests were estimated by SEM and XRD. The electric property was addi...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Solar events and seasonal variation of foF2 at Korhogo station from 1992 to 2002</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/4AE4EC963139</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/4AE4EC963139</guid><description>
	In this paper we report the effect of solar events (CMEs and solar winds) on foF2 diurnal profiles at Korhogo Station (Long 8.427 W; Lat: 9.336 N; dip: -1.88) from 1992 to 2002. We reviewed on seasons and all the four geomagnetic activity classes (Quiet activity, recurrent activity, Shock activity, and Fluctuating activity). The results show that (1) Coronal Mass Ejections (CMEs) and high-sp...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Performance assessment of cross polarization models at millimetre wavelengths along Earth&#x2013;Space path 
in Nigeria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/789BFBD63141</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/789BFBD63141</guid><description>
	Rain-induced depolarization impairments have been a constraint on the effective use of satellite communication systems at millimetre wave band especially in the tropical regions like Nigeria. This region often experiences high and varying degree of rainfall intensity accompanied with large raindrops due to distortion of raindrops when dual orthogonal polarization is employed to double the ch...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Estimation of swelling potential of Enugu Shale using cost effective methods</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/01F7D2C62950</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/01F7D2C62950</guid><description>
	The behavior of swelling soils is mainly governed by its mineralogical composition as well as its environmental factors and stress history. Enugu Shale is one of these shales that assessment of its soil swelling potential cannot only be based on its mineralogical composition alone. The identification of its clay mineral types is basic to understand the roles of other factors of swelling in t...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of groundwater quality condition at Tarauni dumpsite area, Kano Northwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/021BC6D62787</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/021BC6D62787</guid><description>
	2-D resistivity imaging and physicochemical analysis were used to investigate the intrusion of leachates on groundwater quality around a dumpsite in Tarauni Local Government Area of Kano State, Nigeria. Four (4) imaging traverse lines were established and Wenner configuration was adopted using an electrode spacing from 5.0, 10.0, 15.0 to 60.0 m. Data collected from the imaging were inverted ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>On the slow-time geomagnetic field modulation of cosmic rays</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/DA5722762348</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/DA5722762348</guid><description>
	In this work, monthly means of cosmic ray count rates from two mid latitude (Hermanus and Rome), and two higher latitude (Inuvik and Oulu) neutron monitors (NM) were employed and their variability was compared with geomagnetic stations that are in close proximity to the NMs. The data spans 1966 to 2008 and covers four solar cycles. The difference (CRdiff) between the mean count rate of all d...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of heavy metal pollution in marine sediments receiving produced water, Delta State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/3304B4962062</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJPS/article-abstract/3304B4962062</guid><description>
	Every aspect of oil and gas operations poses significant negative impacts on the environment in varying levels, these environmental impacts have economic and public health consequences on the indigenes of the operation locality. Produced water discharge is one of such aspects of the upstream oil and gas operation whose potential for environmental degradation has necessitated both local and i...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>