<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Sociology and Anthropology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Sociology and Anthropology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Moral panic and social order: Analysis of Akwa Ibom street children</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/F4FD98063378</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/F4FD98063378</guid><description>
	The incidence of street children around the world had raised concern about social order. Scholars have paid attention to socioeconomic and psychological implications ignoring the cultural dynamics that contribute to this development. This paper focuses on a category of street children in Akwa-Ibom state of Nigeria. They are the child-witches, thrown to the street due to witchcraft label mast...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Knowledge and perceptions of female genital mutilation among African immigrant women in Windsor, Canada</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/B83F93C63627</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/B83F93C63627</guid><description>
	The objective of this is to investigate African immigrant womens perceptions of female genital mutilation (FGM) within the Canadian Criminal Code. Ten African immigrant women resident in Windsor, Canada were selected using snowball sampling for interviews. These women were of four African nationalities, namely Nigeria, Ghana, Somalia and Sudan. Semi-structured interview protocol with open an...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Possible selves of a hashtag: Moving from the theory of speech acts to cultural objects to interpret hashtags</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/31E6E0B63132</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/31E6E0B63132</guid><description>
	In recent years hashtag studies have increased their numbers. The role of hashtags becomes increasingly predominant in social media studies. Many researchers wonder how to study them, ending up treating them in an aggregate way and turning to big data and static-mathematical modeling. This type of studies seem to consider hashtags as tools, favoring a single analysis perspective. In fact, Th...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Recognising religious and superstitious rituals within higher education contexts: A case study of Stellenbosch University, South Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/2D5A87763261</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/2D5A87763261</guid><description>
	In South Africa the task of decolonising the curriculum in higher education institutions falls upon researchers and lecturers. Within the case study of the Visual Communication Design curriculum at Stellenbosch University we noticed that students superstitious and religious beliefs and rituals surfaced in their responses to the coursework even though there was an attempt to steer away from t...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The psycho-social context of Lake Ziway/Dembel: Oromia Regional state, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/7FAE59463292</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/7FAE59463292</guid><description>
	The general purpose of this study was to organize psycho-social information pertaining to the some issues. These include: Local peoples awareness and perception of risk of ecological problems associated with Lake Ziway/Dembel; the issues of community participation and mobilization in resource conservation, preservation and sustainable use; psycho-social consequences of the adverse climatic h...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Home truths behind closed doors: Reciting the lived experiences of child domestic workers in selected towns of Gedeo Zone, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/C23EF1862536</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/C23EF1862536</guid><description>
	This qualitative study was aimed at looking into the lived experiences of child domestic workers in the selected towns of Gedeo Zone. A triangulation of key informant interviews, in-depth interviews, focus group discussions, informal conversations, non-participant observations, and life histories were employed to collect the required data from child domestic workers, brokers, urban residents...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A concentric approach to understanding herders-farmers clashes in Benue and Nasarawa States, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/E4FB68261456</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/E4FB68261456</guid><description>
	This paper provides a theoretical appraisal as regards the phenomenon of Herders and farmers clashes in north central of Nigeria, specifically Benue and Nassarawa States. By way of qualitative discourse, grounded on secondary sources, the paper gives insight and a deep understanding on the contending issues surrounding resource struggle by host farmers and migrating herders. The approach of ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Witchcraft stigmatization and abuse of children in Akwa-Ibom state, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/56468CE61458</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/56468CE61458</guid><description>
	In this age of intellectual progress and technological advancement, strange beliefs are still rife, and misfortunes are blamed on witches in many societies. In the past, the avowed witches were the aged. Lately, focus has shifted to vulnerable and defenseless children who have become victims of witchcraft stigmatization and abuse. In Akwa-Ibom State, Nigeria, hundreds of children have been l...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A comparative analysis on the perspectives of African Feminism Vs Western Feminism: philosophical debate with their criticism and its implication for women&#x2019;s rights in Ethiopia context</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/C2CE88061829</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/C2CE88061829</guid><description>
	Feminism internationally aims to realizing the liberation of women from all types of oppression and providing solidarity among women of all countries. However, the remarkable difference is growing gap between North and South. Women from the North are harvesting the fruits of capitalism and global economy, whereas women from the South are all too often confronted with poverty and terrible lab...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lived experiences of young Emirati women in the combined family: Extending and rethinking sociological concepts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/796D03D61297</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSA/article-abstract/796D03D61297</guid><description>
	Using evidence from 72 young Emirati women experiences who have participated in a series of eleven focus groups, this study rethinks and extends traditional sociological concepts and classifications. This research propose the concept of combined family to show a unique pattern of family relationships and economic participation that exists in some areas of UAE that combines the wealthiest and...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>