<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Science and Technology Education Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Science and Technology Education Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Seismic risk management education: Its place in life and earth science textbooks for secondary schools 
in Morocco
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/031A22E61655</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/031A22E61655</guid><description>
	This research is based on Life and Earth Sciences (LES) textbooks (El Moufid in LES and El Massar in LES) used in Morocco for second year of college. It is aimed at showing the place of seismic risks education in LES. The methodology used is based on the content analysis of seismic risk management education in these manuals. The results show that this approach is more or less neglected in th...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Classroom science with everyday life:  A means for improving performance in sciences and national development in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/80DBF3861877</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/80DBF3861877</guid><description>
	Science is a body of knowledge about the natural world (the environment) that is testable, verifiable or falsifiable by using organized scientific methods and skills. It has been generally asserted that the rate of development of any nation depends on the level of her citizens scientific literacy and competence in science process skills. The methods of teaching/learning science in Nigeria ha...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Utilization of the internet by undergraduate students of the University of Ibadan, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/FD94CA062066</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/FD94CA062066</guid><description>
	The internet technology over the past few decades has become an important tool in higher education for learning, teaching and research. The study investigated the internet activities engaged in, frequency of use of the internet and challenges limiting the use of the internet among the undergraduate students of the University of Ibadan, Nigeria. A survey research design was adopted. A close-e...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of social media on undergraduate students&#x2019; achievement and interest in chemistry in the North-central geo-political zone of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/9FB200060785</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/9FB200060785</guid><description>
	This paper gives a report of the effect of social media on undergraduate students achievement and interest in chemistry in the north-central geo-political zone of Nigeria. The research design adopted was a cross-sectional survey. The population of this study comprised all undergraduate chemistry students from the universities in the north-central geopolitical zone of Nigeria. 240 undergradua...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Distribution of ABO and Rh (D) blood groups among students attending secondary and preparatory schools in Bote town, Oromia national regional state, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/AFCB08B60439</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/AFCB08B60439</guid><description>
	Knowledge of distribution of ABO and Rh blood groups is helpful for effective management of blood banks and safe blood transfusion services. The prevalence of these blood groups varies worldwide and may not be found in equal numbers even among ethnic groups. The aim of this study was to find out the distribution of ABO and Rh (D) blood groups among students attending high schools in Bote tow...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring the Mathematics and Science subject matter content in the Primary School Level in Lesotho teachers
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/C1A461A59687</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/C1A461A59687</guid><description>
	Mathematics and Science education is very important for any nation to realise meaningful economic development. Most studies looking at this important aspect of education focus on post primary to tertiary education leaving the primary level which is a foundation for those levels making the story incomplete. This study explored the dynamics of primary school teaching of Mathematics and Science...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Predictive modelling and analysis of academic performance of secondary school students: Artificial Neural Network approach</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/070599057163</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/070599057163</guid><description>
	The need for educational managers and policy makers to design and implement pedagogical and instructional interventions necessitates the development and validation of a predictive model for analyzing the academic performance of students before gaining admission into university. This study adopts feed-forward neural network to establish and analyze the complex nonlinear relationship that exis...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Single basis function method for solving diffusion convection equations</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/372CB1966023</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/372CB1966023</guid><description>
	In this study, we developed a new numerical finite difference method for solving various diffusion convection equations. The method involves reduction of the diffusion convection equations to a system of algebraic equations. By solving the system of algebraic equations we obtain the problem approximate solutions. The study of the numerical accuracy of the method has shown that the method pro...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand&#x2019;s classroom learning practices in secondary level: Are we ready for learning in the 21st-Century?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/E561C4B63532</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/E561C4B63532</guid><description>
	Based on data from a survey of students and teachers in 933 Thailand secondary schools in the Northeastern area of the country, this study explores students and teachers perspectives of current-, issues and needs of the classroom practices towards 21st century learning. The majority of the reported current instructional circumstance is traditional. The results found unsteady and slow interne...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Internet Acceptance and Use Model in Ethiopian Agriculture Education and Research: the case of two Universities</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/49A712D60721</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJSTER/article-abstract/49A712D60721</guid><description>
	Many studies proposed models of ICT acceptance and use in order to better predict and explain users behavior to account for the changing technologies. Hence, a question is whether models of technology use and acceptance that have been developed and used in the developed world can be applied to explain Internet acceptance and use by Agriculture staff of two Universities in Ethiopia. To this e...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>