<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Vocational and Technical Education - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Vocational and Technical Education</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Psycho productive skills multiple choice test items for assessing students in mechanical engineering craft in technical colleges in Nasarawa State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/6078FF560789</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/6078FF560789</guid><description>
	This study focused on the development and validation of psycho productive skill multiple choice test (PSMCT) for assessment of technical college students achievement in mechanical engineering craft. The study adopted the instrumentation research design and was conducted in Nasarawa State, Nigeria. The population of the study was 248 National Technical Certificate (NTC) III students comprisin...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Implementation of competence-based curriculum in technical colleges: The case of Arusha City, Tanzania</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/95D5C4460089</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/95D5C4460089</guid><description>
	Competence-based education and training (CBET) is a functional approach to education as it emphasizes that learners need to gain necessary knowledge, skills, understanding and attitudes or values to work successful in their own profession or occupation. It is regarded as a holistic approach to education. This study aimed at finding out how technical college trainers implement CBET curriculum...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An evaluation of equipment for the teaching and learning of Business Studies in Public Junior Secondary Schools in Enugu State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/EFA41DD59211</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/EFA41DD59211</guid><description>
	This study seeks to evaluate the equipment for teaching of business studies in Public Junior Secondary Schools in Enugu North Local Government Area. It adopts the survey design. Two research questions and one hypothesis tested at 0.05 level of significance were used. Population and sample consisted of 82 business studies teachers and principals. A validated questionnaire with coefficients of...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluating the effectiveness of Students Industrial Work Experience Scheme (SIWES) programme to ensure quality of technical, vocational education and training in technical colleges in Lagos State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/1AC91D459213</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/1AC91D459213</guid><description>
	This study evaluated the effectiveness of SIWES Programme in Lagos State to ensure quality of technical, vocational education and training. Three research questions and two hypotheses guided the study in which survey research design was used. The entire population of 130, comprising 120 teachers of technical vocational education and training in Lagos State and also 10 industrial supervisors ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Knowledge of formally and informally trained dressmakers on the application of dart principles in garment designing</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/08A092958949</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/08A092958949</guid><description>
	This study assessed and compared formally and informally trained dressmakers with regard to their use of dart principles in pattern making and garment designing. The descriptive research design was used for the study with a sample size of 50 dressmakers selected from three districts in the central region of Ghana. The instruments used for data collection were a semi-structured interview guid...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Theoretical knowledge competencies required by trade artisans in domestic and industrial electrical installations in Enugu State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/3E3E9B858673</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/3E3E9B858673</guid><description>
	Technological development especially in the field of electrical/electronics posses a great challenge for electrical trade artisans with obsolete skills. The need to enhance the relevance of these artisans necessitated this study to determine theoretical knowledge competencies they require for domestic and industrial electrical installations in Enugu State. One research question guided the st...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Implementation of mechanical engineering curriculum in school and industry in the 3 and 4 years vocational high school programs (VHS) for the improvement of the quality of graduates to meet the requirement of ASEAN economic community</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/2ACE57657930</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/2ACE57657930</guid><description>
	In field application, there are various models of Vocational High School (VHS) education based on the period of study, education design in school or industry and competence design. There are 3 year VHS programme, 4 year VHS programme and community college. Vocational education in Indonesia challenges the Asean Economic Community. The appropriate vocational education curriculum either 3 year ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ghanaian university students&#x2019; perception of their readiness to teach cutting out of garments 
upon graduation
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/C804F6257485</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/C804F6257485</guid><description>
	The Universities of Cape Coast (UCC) and Education Winneba (UEW) are public universities in Ghana where students are trained to become teachers mainly at the secondary level. This paper was aimed at finding out the readiness of graduates from these two universities to teach cutting out of garments, through making pattern or cutting freehand, upon graduation. All final year students who had o...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Repositioning business education programme for post-oil boom economy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/0AF70FF56069</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/0AF70FF56069</guid><description>
	The main purpose of this research was to assess the current position of business education; the need to reposition business education for post oil-boom economy; and the possibilities of repositioning business education for post oil-boom economy. A total of 132 business educators from universities and colleges of education in Edo and Delta States participated in this study. Survey design was ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Teachers&#x2019; opinion on availability of e-learning opportunities for effective technical and vocational education and training (TVET) programme in tertiary institutions in South east Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/D79FEFB55715</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJVTE/article-abstract/D79FEFB55715</guid><description>
	Modernity and technological developments have necessitated the need to expose opportunities in e-learning for effective technical and vocational education and training (TVET) programme. The opinion of the teachers regarding availability of these e-learning opportunities raises concern in teaching circles. It could be that teachers appear not worried about the availability of these opportunit...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>