<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International Journal of Water Resources and Environmental Engineering - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE</link><description>view the most recent articles from International Journal of Water Resources and Environmental Engineering</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Watershed delineation and morphometric analysis using remote sensing and GIS mapping techniques in Qena-Safaga-Bir Queh, Central Eastern Desert</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/DD6AB9863619</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/DD6AB9863619</guid><description>
	The development of drainage basins to raise aquifer potentiality is considering the major target in Qena-Safaga-Bir Queh (central Eastern Desert). It is attributed to drought, scarce groundwater resource, expansion of agriculture, growth population, infrastructures, and civilization. Geological, hydrogeological, and morphometric information is used to prepare the drainage development plan an...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Probability functions of road failures in a typical basement complex region, South-western Nigeria: A case study of Akure - Oba Ile Airport Road</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/FB8654A63439</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/FB8654A63439</guid><description>
	In this study, effort has been made to achieve a comprehensive geophysical investigation on immediate and remote causes of structural/foundation failures, specifically highway(s) within the southwestern basement complex region of Nigeria. Geophysical survey involves the use of Very Low Frequency Electromagnetic method (VLF-EM) which was complemented with electrical resistivity method using t...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Post drilling investigation for prolific groundwater aquifer using geoelectric logging at Nigeria LNG base, Port Harcourt</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/B56A46963273</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/B56A46963273</guid><description>
	Post-drilling investigation for prolific groundwater aquifer was conducted in a well at the Nigeria LNG Base, Port Harcourt using geoelectric logging. Resistivity (Short Normal and Long Normal) and Self-Potential (SP) logs were employed. Two zones (A and B) were tested to determine the porosity (&#x278;), permeability (k) and the total dissolved solids (TDS) in the aquifer. Results show that the i...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spatial and temporal fluctuation of groundwater depth in Amibara, middle Awash, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/8AF4A2262230</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/8AF4A2262230</guid><description>
	Soil salinity is a threat for agriculture under irrigation as it affects the growth and development of plants and the problem is widespread in middle Awash where Amibara irrigated farms are present. Therefore, Measurements of groundwater depth were taken from thirty piezometers in the months of August, September, October, November and December to investigate spatial variability and temporal ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Estimate of bed load transport and scour depth in Kwadna watershed in Minna, Niger State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/43C721362331</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/43C721362331</guid><description>
	Knowledge of sediment transport has been used to determine whether erosion or deposition will occur beneath the hydraulic structures, especially the magnitude of this erosion or deposition, and the time and distance over which it will occur. This paper, utilizes the stream gauging by wading method in estimating the bed load transport and scour depth in Kwadna Basin. The estimate of bed load ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Geographic Information System (GIS) based soil loss estimation using Universal Soil Loss Equation Model (USLE) for soil conservation planning in Karesa Watershed, Dawuro Zone, South West Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/584CEAF62204</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/584CEAF62204</guid><description>
	Soil erosion is the most challenging and continuous environmental problems resulting in both on-site and off-site effects in the world particularly in Ethiopia. Karesa watershed is one of the most erosion-prone watersheds which received little soil conservation attention. This study was conducted to estimate average annual soil loss rate using Geographic Information System and Universal Soil...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Enhancing the adsorption of Pb(II) and Fe(II) in the reactor by the thermally treated alluvial clay from Far North Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/628E5C461761</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/628E5C461761</guid><description>
	The objective of this work was to investigate the influence of the thermal treatment of alluvial clay on the ad-sorption capacity of Pb(II) and Fe(II) to reduce clogging during adsorption phenomenon. The chemical, X- ray diffraction (XRD), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), scanning electron microscope (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) analysis of the alluvial cla...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Finite difference method to design sustainable infiltration based stormwater management system</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/F57025B61364</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/F57025B61364</guid><description>
	Infiltration based stormwater best management practices bring considerable economic, social and ecological benefits. Controlling stormwater quantity and quality are primarily important to prevent urban flooding and minimizing loads of pollutants to the receiving waters. However, there have been growing concerns about how the traditional design approach contributes to the failure of infiltrat...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of the current water quality of Lake Hawassa, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/C99932861552</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/C99932861552</guid><description>
	The research aimed to evaluate the current wter quality of Lake Hawassa in order to identify potential pollution sources and suggest appropriate measures. Physico-chemical water quality parameters have been determined by taking duplicate samples from seven sampling sites and the results were compared with WHO and FAO standards. The findings of the study revealed that the concentration of met...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of sand-dam water quality and its suitability for domestic use in arid and semi-arid environments: A case study of Kitui-West Sub-County, Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/03934C661299</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/IJWREE/article-abstract/03934C661299</guid><description>
	Sand dams are one of the most successful rainwater harvesting methods, adopted in most of arid and semi-arid lands (ASALs) of Kenya to secure domestic water supply and micro-irrigation. Their ability to maintain acceptable water quality, under extreme climatic conditions of recurrent drought and floods, is therefore of paramount public health concern as various pollutants find easily their w...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>