<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>International NGO Journal - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ</link><description>view the most recent articles from International NGO Journal</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Rural transformation in Liberia: Strategies for civil society participation</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/DFA0D3763211</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/DFA0D3763211</guid><description>
	Rural transformation involves a dynamic structural, cultural and economic transition of rural areas to a more economically viable society. This encourages the reduction of inequality, eradication of poverty and enhancement of the living conditions of rural dwellers. Rural areas from the agricultural perspective sustain the urban demand for food and despite this role, lacks basic infrastructu...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mainstreaming psychological first aid response during disaster events in Nepal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/4FEBA2662490</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/4FEBA2662490</guid><description>
	Mental health and psychosocial intervention to disaster events is comparatively new and growing concept in Nepal, which often gets neglected during the emergencies. Though the government has acknowledged the importance of mental health components, psychosocial intervention still deserves the long journey to be mainstreamed in disaster response. In this context, Japan International Support Pr...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Contrasting the impact of the Movimento dos Sem Terra &#x2013; MST and the International Land Coalition - ILC on empowerment of local communities</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/B82476961627</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/B82476961627</guid><description>
	The influence of international donors of non-governmental organizations (NGOs) acting in developing countries has been the subject of a significant amount of academic literature. This article adds to such body of study by examining specifically the effect of international donors in the fight for land. Through contrasting how the International Land Coalition - ILC and the Movimento dos Sem Te...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The participatory structures of poverty in Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/CB559FD61679</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/CB559FD61679</guid><description>
	Participatory structures of poverty in Africa are founded in ideology, foreign aid, guilt from colonialism, paternalism, democracy, and capitalism. The latter two are becoming more well known to the general public, forcing the subject matter to be acknowledged in diplomacy circles. Actively participating in a structure that maintains poverty, works against humanity. Dr. Martin Luther King Jr...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The optimal structure for managing NGOs` projects in Lebanon
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/12803A261800</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/12803A261800</guid><description>
	In response to the structural problems faced by some of the non- governmental organizations (NGOs) in Lebanon, evaluating the different structures` performance is particularly important especially in developing countries that require NGOs to provide speedy, timely and effective response to beneficiary needs. The aim of this paper is to identify the optimal structure for managing NGOs` projec...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Understanding the importance of malaria control tools by pregnant and nursing mothers is key to ending malaria burden in Nigeria: A case study of eight communities in South-South Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/448E5E962308</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/448E5E962308</guid><description>
	The current National Malaria Strategy Plan (NMSP) 2014 to 2020, aims to transit Nigeria from malaria control to malaria elimination status by 2020. However, the most recent WHO Malaria Report 2018 revealed that Nigeria accounted for 25% of 219 million of the global malaria cases and 19% of 435,000 malaria deaths in 2017. The strategies of NMSP among others are: To significantly scale up Indo...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Trans-border good deeds: Overseas NGOs in Yanbian Korean autonomous prefecture of China</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/2F0CDA761286</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/2F0CDA761286</guid><description>
	Yanbian Korean Autonomous Prefecture (YKAP) is one of the main settlements of Chinese-Korean in China. It is also the border Fortress adjacent to Korea and Russia. Its sensitive geographical location, special ethnic composition, rich cultural and economic characteristics have attracted wide attention of international Non-governmental organizations (NGOs). Considering religious tenets, humani...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The distribution of Micro Project Programme (MPP) and relative poverty incidence across Nigeria south-south vegetation belts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/05FE73261289</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/05FE73261289</guid><description>
	The European Union in collaboration with some non-governmental organisation initiated the European Micro Projects Programme (MPP) in south-south States of Nigeria. Basically, the aim of the progamme was to help improve the poor living condition of communities situated in these areas, by the provision of basic infrastructures. One of the key derivatives from the ecological zones/vegetation be...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Food insecurity conundrum: A case study of Amathole district in the Eastern Cape province of South Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/16AC3C660906</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/16AC3C660906</guid><description>
	Over half of the population in the Amathole district in South Africa experiences food insecurity, despite on-going government initiatives to combat the problem. The study reported here investigated factors that inhibit the achievement of food security by households in the district and government responses, to better understand the factors that might account for the persistence of this challe...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Parents&#x2019; and children&#x2019;s perception of the challenges of acquiring primary and post-primary education in rural communities of Rivers State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/D8E39A560393</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/INGOJ/article-abstract/D8E39A560393</guid><description>
	This study investigated parents and childrens perception of the challenges of acquiring primary and post-primary education in Tai and Etche communities of Rivers State. Qualitative data were obtained via individual interviews and Focus Group Discussions (FGD). Parents within the age range of 16 to 45 years and children in the secondary school within the ages of 14 to 18 years participated in...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>