<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ISABB Journal of Food and Agricultural Sciences - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS</link><description>view the most recent articles from ISABB Journal of Food and Agricultural Sciences</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Analysis of fish market chain for Lake Zeway, Central Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/26F258C62889</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/26F258C62889</guid><description>
	Although fish is economically and socially important, its marketing chain and their characteristics have not yet been studied and analyzed for Lake Zeway, Central Ethiopia, where great potential of fish production exists. The study was initiated to investigate the fish marketing chain in this area. This was done by identifying the marketing channels of fish and the major factors influencing ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Value chain analysis of potato: The Case of South Achefer and Jabi Tehinan districts of West Gojam 
Zone, Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/7CA133259681</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/7CA133259681</guid><description>
	The study was conducted in South Achefer and Jabi Tehinan districts for mapping, identifying actors and analyzing constraints and opportunities of potato value chain. Simple random sampling technique was used to select producers (100), traders (70), and end consumers (40). Quantitative and qualitative data were collected from primary and secondary sources. Hence, qualitative and quantitative...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Influence of seed size on the germination of four cowpea (Vigna unguiculata (L) Walp) varieties</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/599BB4357574</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/599BB4357574</guid><description>
	A study was conducted to investigate how seed size affects germination and vigor of cowpea seeds. Four cowpea varieties, (Asontem, Nhyira, Soronko and Tona), were obtained from Crops Research Institute of the Centre for Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR-CRI). The seeds were grouped in two sizes (large and small), by manually sorting by length, width and thousand seeds weight. Laborato...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fungi associated with black rot disease of pineapple (Ananas comosus L.) fruits and the effects of the disease on nutritional value of the fruits</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/2071C0856382</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/2071C0856382</guid><description>
	Pineapple (Ananas comosus L.) is one of the most important crops grown in Africa. The fruit is consumed fresh by many people and hence, source of essential mineral elements, nutrients and vitamins. This study was conducted to investigate the fungi associated with black rot disease of pineapple fruits and the effect of the disease on nutritional value of the fruits. The fungi isolated from bl...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of red beetroot (Beta vulgaris L.) intake on the level of some hematological tests in a group of female volunteers</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/DC9907956091</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/DC9907956091</guid><description>
	The plant kingdom constitutes a source of new chemical compounds which may be important owing to their potential use in medicine and other applications. This study discussed the effect of taking 8 g of beetroot (Beta vulgaris L.) for 20 days on the blood samples of female volunteers where the hemoglobin levels before and after the study was recorded. The results showed mild increase in hemog...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Striga infestation and its interaction to density of sorghum, basic chemical and physical properties of the soil across Tigray Region, Northern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/4FBCB8755799</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/4FBCB8755799</guid><description>
	In Ethiopia, sorghum is the major crop next to teff grown all over the country. Though the productivity of sorghum has increased in the last few years, the overall national productivity of sorghum is low (2.106 t/ha) compared to the average production of 2.3 t/ha of developed countries. The low productivity of sorghum is attributed mainly to infestation by Striga. The annual yield loss and g...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of solar dryers on drying and sensory properties of salted Tilapia filets, Tigray, Northern Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/570706366959</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/570706366959</guid><description>
	Solar dryers are used to preserve very perishable foods like fish for long period of time by lowering the moisture content in high temperature areas and contribute to fish postharvest loss reduction. Therefore this study was conducted to evaluate dryers on moisture loss, moisture contents, drying and sensory properties of salted tilapia fillets. The experiment consisted of a factorial design...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Influence of harvesting and postharvest processing methods on the quality of Arabica coffee (Coffea arabica L.) in Eastern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/B53DFEF62906</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/B53DFEF62906</guid><description>
	Eastern Ethiopia is among the regions naturally known for producing the best quality Hararghe specialty coffee. However, due to poor pre-and post-harvest handling practices, the quality of its coffee is below level of its inherent quality characteristics. Therefore, this study was conducted to evaluate different harvesting and postharvest handling methods on the inherent quality of Hararghe ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of boiling, pressure cooking and germination on the nutritional and antinutrients content of cowpea (Vigna unguiculata)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/5DDCEC161368</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/5DDCEC161368</guid><description>
	The study was conducted to investigate the effect of boiling, pressure cooking and germination on the proximate, nutrients, amino acids and anti-nutrients content of cowpea (Vigna unguiculata). The results showed that the germinated cowpeas (GMC) had the highest value of crude protein (22.89%), crude fat (3.81%) and crude fibre (2.10%) followed by raw cowpeas (RWC) and pressure cooked cowpea...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of the performance of laying hens placed on drinking water fortified with waterleaf (Talinum triangulare (Jacq.) Willd) aqueous extract</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/FB7861454047</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JFAS/article-abstract/FB7861454047</guid><description>
	This study was carried out to evaluate the effect of waterleaf (Talinum triangulare (Jacq.) Willd) aqueous extract on the performance of laying hens. This study was arranged in a completely randomized design with five treatments (T1, T2, T3, T4 and T5) with 0, 50, 100, 150 and 200 ml of waterleaf aqueous extract (WAE), respectively in their drinking water. Forty (40) Nera black hens at 24 we...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>