<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ISABB Journal of Biotechnology and Bioinformatics - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB</link><description>view the most recent articles from ISABB Journal of Biotechnology and Bioinformatics</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>In silico detection and correlative analysis of antibiotic resistance plasmid-incompatibility (Inc/ rep) groups from different environments</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/9A9E86662195</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/9A9E86662195</guid><description>
	Plasmids are extra-chromosomal mobile DNA elements found mostly in bacteria, and often serve as vectors for accumulation and transfer of antibiotic resistance genes (ARGs) within bacterial populations in different environments. Plasmid mediated transfer of ARGs has accounted for the spread of antibiotic resistance within clinically relevant pathogenic bacteria; this has escalated into a glob...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Relationship and prediction of body weight from morphometric traits of indigenous highland sheep In Tigray, Northern Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/6BC6A3E63461</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/6BC6A3E63461</guid><description>
	The study was conducted in Atsbiwonberta district to determine the relationship between live weight and linear measurements and predict live weight from morphometric traits. Three potential peasant associations namely, Habes, GolgolNeale and Gebrekidan were selected. Randomly selected 257 sheep (121 males and 136 females) were grouped into four age groups (0 PPI, 1 PPI, 2 PPI, and 3 PPI). Li...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of ascorbic acid on blackening and sprouting of Musa spp shoot tips</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/9FB714744866</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/9FB714744866</guid><description>
	

	  The effect of ascorbic acid (0, 5, 10, 20, 30, 40 and 150 mgl-1) on blackening and sprouting of Musa  spp genotypes was investigated using shoot tip culture. Ascorbic acid did not minimize blackening, but rather markedly reduced the sprouting of cultured shoot tip explants. Ascorbic acid, genotype and genotype x ascorbic acid interactions were significant for shoot tip blackening and ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Studies on the optimization of bioelectricity production from industrial and domestic waste using immobilization of microbial cells</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/6CEFB4544867</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/6CEFB4544867</guid><description>
	

	A unique type of fuel cell with a potential in long-term is the bio fuel. The data obtained from the studies undertaken reflect glucose yielding the peak voltage. However, sucrose is cheap, similar to glucose in the electricity production pattern. Using glucose in anaerobic culture conditions, the microbial fuel cell produced a peak voltage of 1.35 by organisms Saccharomyces cerevisiae ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Computational studies on Ribavirin binding to RNA-dependent RNA polymerase, inducing Crimean-Congo hemorrhagic fever</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/FC337E944861</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/FC337E944861</guid><description>
	

	The Crimean-Congo hemorrhagic fever is aviral disease, widespreadamongst domesticas well as wild animals, and probably may affects humans too. This virus belonging to Bunyaviridae family contains viral RNA-dependent RNA polymerase catalyzing the biosynthesis of the RNA strands. As a consequence of inhibition of a target enzyme protein, namely, RNA-dependent RNA polymerase there is a pro...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Identification of Zinnia leaf curl virus infecting Zinnia elegans in India</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/5114C1D44863</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/5114C1D44863</guid><description>
	

	In a survey during 2007 to 2009 at Gorakhpur and nearby locations of North Eastern Uttar Pradesh, India leaf curling, foliar deformation and distortion symptoms were observed on Zinnia elegans plants. The associated White fly population indicated the possible presence of begomovirus in the field. Therefore, Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) was performed with the begomovirus specific prim...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Investigation of the role of calcium in prolonging the shelf life of fluted pumpkin (Telefairia occidentalis Hook F.)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/FCA19DE44854</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/FCA19DE44854</guid><description>
	

	  A 16-week study using 2 certified land races of Telfairia occidentalis Hook F plants, to ascertain the effectiveness of calcium in prolonging the shelf life of the leaves and identify the pathogens that cause leaf rot of the plant was carried out. The two varieties were subjected to 5 levels of calcium carbonate treatments (0.25, 0.50, 0.75, and 1 g and control (0 g) in 20 kg polythen...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Protein engineering of yellow fluorescent protein insertion in outer membrane protein OmpF from Salmonella typhi</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/48C091E44858</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JBB/article-abstract/48C091E44858</guid><description>
	

	  Each monomer of the trimeric outer membrane porin OmpF of  Salmonella typhi folds as a 16-stranded -barrel with eight short turns at the periplasmic side and eight loops on the cell surface side. Yellow fluorescent protein (YFP) has been engineered into Loop 7 of OmpF. HindIII and  EcoRV restriction sites were introduced in the region corresponding to Loop 7 of ompF gene. Flanking the...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>