<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ISABB Journal of Health and Environmental Sciences - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE</link><description>view the most recent articles from ISABB Journal of Health and Environmental Sciences</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Factors associated with irregular consumption of fruits and vegetables among health professionals in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/419A12D62771</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/419A12D62771</guid><description>
	Fruits and vegetables (FVs) are an essential food group for humans and prevent non-communicable diseases (NCDs). The objective of this study is to know the level of consumption of FVs by health professionals in Ouagadougou and their determinants. This is a descriptive cross-sectional study conducted from May to August 2016 in the Central Region of Burkina Faso. It included 442 health workers...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Modeling schistosomiasis infection using Kriging interpolation method in Osun State, South west, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/D024FFE60353</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/D024FFE60353</guid><description>
	Schistosomiasis, an environmentally-mediated disease, contracted by swimming or wading in freshwater bodies harbouring the snail intermediate hosts of the genus Schistosoma consisting of five human species: S. haematobium S. mansoni, S. japonicum, S. intercalatum and S. mekongi. Transmission is on the increase with consequent adverse effects on childrens health and school attendance. There i...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Latrine utilization and associated factors among Kebeles declared open defecation free in Wondo Genet district, South Ethiopia, 2015</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/9585CBF59530</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/9585CBF59530</guid><description>
	The government of Ethiopia has been working in creating and increasing the number of open defecation free kebeles as a strategy of improving sanitation coverage in the country. However, apart from increasing sanitation coverage, data on utilization of the constructed latrines was not well investigated. Therefore, the study objective was to assess the latrine utilization coverage of the kebel...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An analysis of wastewater irrigation practices and its impacts on the livelihood generation and food chain contamination in Faisalabad District, Pakistan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/D51D0B458968</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/D51D0B458968</guid><description>
	In the irrigated agricultural areas of Pakistan, the major sources of irrigation are canal water and groundwater. Due to the scarcity of canal water the dependency on groundwater is rapidly increasing in many areas of Pakistan. The groundwater is not only expensive, inadequate, and non-affordable for the small farmers but also of inferior quality. Much of the wastewater which is produced in ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Internalization of enteropathogenic human bacteria in lettuce and coriander plant tissue</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/1248CB557437</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/1248CB557437</guid><description>
	The ability of plant rhizosphere and to some extent phyllosphere to support metabolism of some human enteric bacteria has been widely demonstrated. The nutrients provided by seedlings during germination support bacterial survival in tissue of growing plants. Plant rhizosphere has been described as being high in nutrients, and rhizosphere microbiomes are well adapted to this environment, ente...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lightning generation correlation with widespread irrigation and means of protection</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/A53C8F556111</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/A53C8F556111</guid><description>
	Indias lightning fatalities correlate with her spatial extent of water bodies. Evaporation from reservoirs and irrigated lands provides moisture for cloud formation. Hot and humid air flowing overland can rise over mountains where it expands under reduced pressure, cools down to promote condensation in contact with sea salt, dust particles, soot from forest fires, bacteria, etc. Agitation wi...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Women&#x2019;s empowerment on contraceptive use among married women in Amhara Region, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/DFE2E0155828</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/DFE2E0155828</guid><description>
	Ethiopia is among the African countries with high maternal and child mortality rates, with a fast-growing population. To prevent the fast growing population; availability, the stability of contraceptive method and identifying factors that affects the practice of modern contraceptives should be given a priority. Thus, this study aims to identify the practice of contraceptives focusing on wome...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapping epilepsy risks through porcine farming in North West Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/FE2088365608</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/FE2088365608</guid><description>
	This study posits that socioeconomic factors determine the patterns of epilepsy. The transmission of cysticerci between pig and man is facilitated by traditional pig rearing, slaughtering, and the poor detection of Taenia solium in slaughter pigs. Neurocysticercosis, resulting from T. solium is often associated with focal epilepsy. To ascertain this relationship, a co-relational design was a...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The problem of solid waste management and people awareness on appropriate solid waste disposal in Bahir Dar City: Amhara region, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/5F8EE9559300</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/5F8EE9559300</guid><description>
	The problem of solid waste management (SWM) and its implications to health and environmental problems has become increasing. The issue of SWM in Bahir Dar city appeared to be one of the problems that need a great improvement. The principal results show that institutional, economic and social factors hinder SWM service in Ethiopia with particular focus on Bahir Dar city. Also, the results of ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Environmental and health hazards associated with exploration of barite from Bukkuyum (Zamfara State), Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/939930C53702</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/ISABB-JHE/article-abstract/939930C53702</guid><description>
	Barite is barium sulfate with the chemical formula of BaSO4. Unlike barite witherite (BaCO3) it is not chemically inert, it can dissolve in water and, when dissolved, can cause an environmental hazard. Barite forms in many geologic environments with both metallic and nonmetallic minerals. Minerals associated with the ore are a main concern when mining and processing barite. In many barite de...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>