<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Agricultural Biotechnology and Sustainable Development - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Agricultural Biotechnology and Sustainable Development</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Laboratory evaluation of some botanicals and fermented cow urine against Chilo partellus (Swinhoe) (Lepidoptera: Crambidae)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/52ADD9563199</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/52ADD9563199</guid><description>
	Chilo partellus (Swinhoe) is the most important destructive pest of sorghum in Africa which results in complete crop loss. Currently the management strategies rely heavily on chemical insecticides, which do not provide effective control. The uses of bio-pesticides are encouraging over chemical pesticides. The study was carried out to identify effective plant and animal products and optimum c...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing the impacts of climate change and variability on maize post-harvest system at Kongwa and Kondoa District in Tanzania</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/B80A0C563237</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/B80A0C563237</guid><description>
	This study attempted to investigate the pattern and trend of climate change, its influence and interaction with maize post-harvest system and established the current status of maize post-harvest losses at Kongwa and Kondoa district in Tanzania. Participatory rural appraisal technique and household survey methods were used to collect primary data. Secondary data for the study area including r...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of N fortified rice mill waste on soil chemical properties and yield of maize in Nigeria rainforest</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/850ECF662564</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/850ECF662564</guid><description>
	Organo-mineral nutrient sources are promising soil amendments for sustainable crop production in Nigeria. A field experiment was conducted at the Teaching and Research Farm of the Cross River University of Technology Obubra during the 2016 cropping season. The objective of the study was to evaluate the effects of nitrogen (N) and amended rice mill waste (RMW) on some soil chemical properties...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation in Gampela (Burkina Faso) of agronomic performances of peanut genotypes (Arachis hypogaea L.) selected in Texas</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/4DEDB7162370</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/4DEDB7162370</guid><description>
	Peanut is of paramount importance in human and animal nutrition, as well as in improving producers income. However, its production is faced with abiotic and biotic constraints. Among the biotic constraints, Cercosporiosis diseases are a major handicap in Burkina Faso. In order to minimize the impact of these diseases on peanut yield, important work has been carried out and is still ongoing t...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phylogenetic assessment of selected Ghanaian groundnuts, in reference to U.S. mini-core based on Kompetitive allele-specific PCR (KASP) and axiom single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) array protocols</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/7A0211362123</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/7A0211362123</guid><description>
	Groundnut farming has always been an essentially major agricultural venture, both commercially and in subsistence, to the inhabitants of the Northern Regions of Ghana. The current study sought to assess the relationship and genetic diversity, through a phylogenetic analysis, among twenty-five (25) Ghanaian groundnut genotypes, in reference to US groundnut mini-core collection, based on the K...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The influence of solvent&#x2019;s polarity on physicochemical properties and oil yield extracted from pumpkin (Cucurbita maxima) seed</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/ECC279862125</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/ECC279862125</guid><description>
	The effect of solvent polarity, polar and non-polar solvents, on pumpkin (Cucurbita maxima) seed oil yield and quality based on selected physicochemical properties was investigated. Five different solvents, like petroleum ether, hexane, cyclohexane, acetone and ethanol were used on a laboratory scale in this study. Results showed that both physicochemical properties and oil yield extracted f...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Integrated weed management systems in sorghum based cropping system in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/00F8C3B61440</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/00F8C3B61440</guid><description>
	Sorghum (Sorghum bicolor (L) Moench) is the fifth most important staple food crop after wheat, rice, maize and barley. Sorghum is consumed by more than 70% of the population. Striga hermonthica is a serious biotic constraint to cereal production in the dry savannas of sub-Saharan Africa. Striga infestation in sorghum is reported to be higher in Nigeria than in other West African countries wi...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Morpho-qualitative characterization of ten local cassava accessions (Manihot esculenta crantz) in 
Njomb&#xE9;, Cameroon
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/5CF782E60693</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/5CF782E60693</guid><description>
	The need of characterization of local ecotypes has emerged because of abandonment of traditional varieties and a loss of genetic resources, associated with increasing demography and environmental. Thus, a study was conducted at the Institute of Agricultural Research for Development (IRAD) of Njomb multipurpose station with the objective of characterizing ten local accessions of cassava both ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of seed coating substance (Genius Coat Disco Cereal AG L-439) on seed yield and yield component of chickpea (Cicer arietinum L.) in central highlands of Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/9E57C5360240</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/9E57C5360240</guid><description>
	Among the challenges of achieving increased chickpea production in Ethiopia is absence of seed quality enhancement technologies. The Genius Coat Disco Cereal AG L-439 is among the seed coating products produced by INCOTEC Company and introduced in our country. The current study was conducted to examine the efficacy of Genius Coat on seed yield and to determine its effective dosage for chickp...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmers&#x2019; knowledge and perceptions of leaf spot disease of groundnut and its management in Northern Region of Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/C9F40EC58567</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JABSD/article-abstract/C9F40EC58567</guid><description>
	Groundnut (Arachis hypogea L.) is an important food source as well as cash crop for the people of Northern Ghana. The crop yield is low partly due to biological constraints which include diseases like leaf spot. A survey was conducted among 200 farmers in four districts of the Northern Region of Ghana, from June to August, 2014 using a structured questionnaire. The objectives of this study w...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>