<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Agricultural Extension and Rural Development - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Agricultural Extension and Rural Development</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Fertilizer subsidy policy and smallholder farmers&#x2019; crop productivity: The case of maize production in 
North-Eastern Ghana
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/D7F160B63670</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/D7F160B63670</guid><description>
	Crop yield enhancing technologies such as inorganic fertilizers present opportunities for improving smallholder farmers crop yields, food security and incomes. This study examines maize productivity response to Ghanas fertilizer subsidy policy focusing on yield differences between participants and non-participants in the Tempane District in Ghana among smallholder farmers. An Endogenous Swit...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysis of the profitability and marketing distribution channels of sweet potato business in Sierra Leone</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/FD7588163725</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/FD7588163725</guid><description>
	The objective of this study is to examine the profitability and channels of distribution of sweet potato in Sierra Leone. Multistage sampling was used to select 150 sweet potato marketers from five major districts. Data was collected on socio-economics characteristics, distribution channels, market margins and net income, drivers and barriers of sweet potato marketers with aid of android dev...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Relationship between women demographic characteristics, household structure and socio-economic status in Morogoro District, Tanzania
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/F7E6F3963229</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/F7E6F3963229</guid><description>
	Factors responsible for poor household socio-economic status (hSES) vary in different social groups. Little information exists to explain how demographic and household characteristics are related to hSES in rural societies of Tanzania. This cross-sectional study assessed associations between selected women demographic characteristics, household structure and hSES in a rural area in Morogoro ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparison between public and private extension services for sugarcane production in Muzaffargarh District, Punjab, Pakistan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/D7255F362849</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/D7255F362849</guid><description>
	Sugarcane industry is at second position after textile industry in Pakistan. By the export of refined sugar, it plays a significant role in the economy of the country. Public and private sectors extension field staff work with sugarcane growers to improve their per acre yield. The research was conducted to compare and identify the services provided by those two sectors. A total of 150 respon...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic valuation of Nile Tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus) in Lake Hawassa, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/479A87A62362</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/479A87A62362</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study is to investigate the economic value of fish (Nile Tilapia) in Lake Hawassa and determine the factors affecting the households willingness to pay for a quality improved fish product. The survey was conducted through face-to-face interview of 467 households consuming fish caught from the lake. The respondents were aware on the poor quality of the fish due to domestic...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors determining crop farmers&#x2019; willingness to pay for agricultural extension services in Tanzania: A case of Mpwapwa and Mvomero Districts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/93DEF0462364</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/93DEF0462364</guid><description>
	This study assessed crop farmers willingness to pay for AESs and identified factors influencing their willingness to pay for AESs. Data were collected from 292 randomly selected crop farmers households between December 2017 and February 2018 using a questionnaire through face-to-face interviews. Data were analyzed using frequency counts, percentages and Tobit regression model. The study foun...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment on rural poultry production and marketing system of Horro chicken ecotypes in Western Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/D80B25762430</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/D80B25762430</guid><description>
	A cross-sectional study was conducted to assess production and marketing system of Horro chicken ecotypes, and to determine poultry health and marketing constraints across different agro-ecologies of western Ethiopia. A total of 360 householders were interviewed for the survey in Horro area (western Ethiopia) where the Horro chicken ecotypes are mainly found; the sample size was determined u...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Turning challenges into opportunity: Potential for adoption of e-extension in Lesotho</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/EA797A962148</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/EA797A962148</guid><description>
	Farmers in Lesotho mostly depend on rain-fed agriculture and are in need of access to agricultural information and knowledge in a timely, complete and quality manner. The traditional practice for delivering agricultural information has mainly relied on agricultural extension staff visiting farmers in order to provide advisory services. Due to the limited number of extension staff and other c...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determinants of adoption of improved sorghum package in agro-pastoral households of Somali Region of Ethiopia: A gender perspective</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/EEA486862150</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/EEA486862150</guid><description>
	The study analysed determinants of adoption of improved sorghum package between male-headed and female-headed households. The specific objectives were to analyse adoption differentials of improved sorghum package, and to identify factors that affect adoption decision of improved sorghum package by male and female-headed households. Purposeful sampling method was employed to select Woreda of ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors influencing the adoption of improved cowpea varieties in the Sudan Savannas of Northern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/7DEE51362301</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAERD/article-abstract/7DEE51362301</guid><description>
	The study was undertaken to determine the level and factors influencing adoption of improved cowpea varieties introduced by the Sudan Savanna Taskforce project in Musawa Local Government Area of Katsina State. Data were collected from a random sample of 300 households from ten communities in the study area. The analytical tools used for data analysis include descriptive statistics to examine...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>