<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of AIDS and HIV Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of AIDS and HIV Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Immunological and clinical response to antiretroviral therapy according to baseline CD4+ T-cell count in Karamara General Hospital, Jigjiga, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/1CCA6BB63927</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/1CCA6BB63927</guid><description>
	In resource limited countries, there is scarcity of information regarding the degree of immunological and clinical recovery in remote communities with ART service. This study retrospectively assessed the degree of immune recovery by CD4 count after initiation of ART. A retrospective cohort study was conducted on adult HIV patients who have been on ART for more than one year at Karamara Hospi...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges of the care of HIV positive adolescents in Jos, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/06AEF3B62255</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/06AEF3B62255</guid><description>
	The introduction of highly active anti-retroviral therapy (HAART) to children with perinatally acquired HIV has prolonged their lifespan to adolescence and beyond. These HIV positive adolescents on care face challenges as they undertake their treatment which this study aimed to determine. The study was a cross-sectional descriptive study of challenges faced by adolescents between the ages 10...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Unprotected sexual practice and associated factors among people on anti-retro-viral therapy at public health facilities of Arba Minch town:  Cross-sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/6A24C0862227</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/6A24C0862227</guid><description>
	Unprotected sexual practice with multiple partners is identified as the greatest risk factor for transmission of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) in Sub Saharan Africa and it is a public health concern among people infected with HIV. However, due to the focus of HIV prevention efforts was largely on people uninfected with HIV, people on anti-retroviral therapy (ART) were not addressed by p...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mode of transmission of HIV infection among orphans and vulnerable children in some selected States 
in Nigeria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/0FB044261824</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/0FB044261824</guid><description>
	Nigeria has high rate of pediatric HIV but there is a dearth of empirical data on the mode of HIV transmission. Association for Reproductive and Family Health (ARFH), with the support of USAID, is implementing a project to mitigate the impact of HIV on Orphans and Vulnerable Children (OVC) affected/infected with HIV/AIDS in Akwa-Ibom, Lagos, and Rivers states, Nigeria. The mode of HIV transm...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Treatment outcomes among adolescents on antiretroviral therapy in Machakos, Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/C1EE01461737</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/C1EE01461737</guid><description>
	It is estimated that in 2017 there were about 1.5 million people living with Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) in Kenya, of which 105,000 (7%) were adolescents. Adolescents have poorer antiretroviral therapy (ART) outcomes compared to adults. This study aimed to determine the treatment outcomes of adolescents on ART in Machakos County, Kenya. Adolescents on ART for at least two years from n...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Medication belief, locus of control, and adherence among patients on highly active anti retro viral therapy in Lagos, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/BD7B5E761611</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/BD7B5E761611</guid><description>
	Anti-retro viral therapy (ART) is a lifelong treatment and its effectiveness depends critically both on the efficacy of the antiretroviral drugs against the virus and achieving a very high level of adherence ( 95%) to the medications. This study evaluated the relationship between medication beliefs, locus of control and adherence to ART among people living with HIV/AIDS (PLWHA) in Lagos. A c...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Demographic characteristics of clients up taking free counseling and testing services in Ibadan, Oyo 
State, Nigeria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/B70EB8561214</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/B70EB8561214</guid><description>
	Nigeria has high burden of HIV/AIDS; antiretroviral therapy (ART) availability, a blessing to HIV patients. Unfortunately, most people do not know their HIV status. Association for Reproductive and Family Health (ARFH), Nigeria introduced mobile free HIV Counseling and Testing (HCT) services to complement its clinic services for HCT uptake. The characteristics of clients patronizing ARFHs HC...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors associated with non-adherence of HIV/AIDS patients to HAART regimen in a healthcare facility in Ikot Ekpene, Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/C8B7AF760486</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/C8B7AF760486</guid><description>
	Adherence to highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART) regimen, of at least 95%, is necessary for effective therapeutic response among people living with human immunodeficiency virus (PLWHIV). This study determined the factors associated with non-adherence of PLWHIV to HAART regimen among patients attending a healthcare facility in Akwa Ibom State, Nigeria. Two hundred and fifty one patie...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of wasting and its predictors among adults receiving highly active antiretroviral therapy in ART clinics of Hosanna town, Hadiya Zone, Southern Ethiopia &#x2013; A cross-sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/841F6F860271</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/841F6F860271</guid><description>
	In patients with HIV infection, wasting has been associated with increased mortality. Even in the era of Highly Active Antiretroviral Therapy (HAART), accelerated disease progression, loss of muscle protein mass, and impairment of strength and functional status are common. However, data on the magnitude of wasting and its risk factors among individuals receiving HAART are scarce in Ethiopia....</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence and associated factors of Helicobacter pylori Infection among HIV positive adults on Anti-retroviral Therapy </title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/9814CAA59887</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAHR/article-abstract/9814CAA59887</guid><description>
	Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori) infections are worldwide healthcare burdens. This study aimed to assess the prevalence and associated factors of H. pylori infection among HIV patients at Southern-Ethiopia. A Hospital based cross-sectional study was conducted at Hawassa University comprehensive specialized hospital on 390 HIV infected adults on antiretro...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>