<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of African Studies and Development - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of African Studies and Development</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>The politics of actor involvement in local economic development in Ghana: Empirical evidence from the Accra Metropolitan, Keta Municipal and Shai-Osudoku District Assemblies</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/065A9E663721</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/065A9E663721</guid><description>
	The main objective of the article was to examine the forces that shape the behaviour of the actors in the local economic development implementation process in Accra Metropolitan, Keta Municipal and Shai-Osudoku District assemblies. Using qualitative data from multiple sources combined with multiple case studies, the study found that the three Metropolitan, Municipal and District assemblies i...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Using the sustainable livelihood approach to explore determinants of off-farm diversification by land reform beneficiaries in Sanyati District-Mashonaland West Province-Zimbabwe</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/A52EFBB63741</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/A52EFBB63741</guid><description>
	The study explored the socio-economic determinants of off-farm diversification by land reform beneficiaries in Sanyati District, Mashonaland West Province, Zimbabwe. The major aim of the study was to establish the reasons for off-farm diversification by resettled farmers. It established sustainability of resettled farmers livelihoods and investigated farmers perceptions of agriculture and la...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Gendered patterns of labour-force participation and productivity in tourism and hotel sectors in Arusha and Moshi urban areas, Tanzania</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/D902F9F63352</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/D902F9F63352</guid><description>
	This study examines the position of gendered labour participation in influencing gendered productivity within the hotel and tourism sectors of the Tanzanian economy. The study aims to identify and analyse the extent to which gendered labour participation influences productivity of some selected firms in Tanzania. Drawing on a survey of hotels and tour operators in Arusha and Moshi, this stud...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Towards a theoretical model linking university education to climate change interventions in the African context</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/C5B8DC163354</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/C5B8DC163354</guid><description>
	Climate change education continues to gain popularity among educationalists especially at university level. The Paris Agreement on climate change 2015 advocated for support towards this approach especially for universities in the developing nations. This paper aims to present a model linking university education to climate change interventions in the African context. This model has been deve...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Performance management and health service delivery in the local governments of Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/23523FF62026</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/23523FF62026</guid><description>
	Today, many African countries are faced with enormous challenges of health service delivery; one of the arguments advanced for the persistent health service delivery malaise is the inadequate management of the health sector human resource. It should therefore be noted that performance management in the health sector has been paid lukewarm attention by both health resource managers. Performan...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The rationale behind the Penan Kubaan Ethnic Group&#x2019;s refusal to seek wage employment in the mainstream economy of Malaysia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/7FAD6F362064</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/7FAD6F362064</guid><description>
	Penan ethnic group in Sarawak, Malaysia are assumed to be lagging in development flows since Brooks administration. The Kubaan Penan ethnic group resides in the remote area of the forest and their daily activities are planting vegetable and hunting for food. Many of them refuse to go out to improve their quality of life financially. It is in contradiction to the Malaysian nature which works ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>State regulation of religion in Uganda: Fears and dilemmas of born-again churches</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/222D4B962201</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/222D4B962201</guid><description>
	Since 2016 when the government of Uganda announced its intention to enact a policy about regulating religions and faith-based organizations, there have been contrasting responses from those this policy intends to regulate. The mainstream religious groups especially; the Moslem community, Anglican Church of Uganda, the Seventh-Day Adventist Church, Roman Catholic Church, Greek Orthodox church...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Foster care ontologies: A qualitative study in Zimbabwe
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/029816762237</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/029816762237</guid><description>
	Both the African Charter on the Rights and Welfare and the United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child place premium on having children grow up in families. Foster care is one of the opportunities that can be used to ensure that children grow up in families on the African continent and Zimbabwe in particular. There are however some minefields which have to be explored carefully. The...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges of educational digital infrastructure in Africa: A tale of hope and disillusionment</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/38A96FF61548</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/38A96FF61548</guid><description>
	Technology-based distance learning is becoming popular throughout the world. In Sub-Saharan Africa, advancements in communication technology more than two decades ago raised much hope since technology-based distance education was seen as a promising cost effective and cost-efficient answer to expansion of access to education. These high hopes in technology-based distance education have, howe...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Security implications of oil exploration on social activities in South Lokichar Basin, Turkana County, Kenya
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/73A9F7A61578</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JASD/article-abstract/73A9F7A61578</guid><description>
	This study explored the security implications of oil exploration on the social activities in South Lokichar Basin, Turkana County, Kenya. It was motivated by the disagreements between the county government and national government on the exploration, extraction, production and sharing of oil benefits. Oil discovery and revenues fuel ethnic and political tension in any country, result in war a...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>