<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Accounting and Taxation - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Accounting and Taxation</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>The impact of value-added tax (VAT) implementation on Saudi banks</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/FAF16BC62857</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/FAF16BC62857</guid><description>
	The study aims to identify the impact of value-added tax (VAT) on Saudi banks, through measuring the impact of changes in the banks before and after the implementation of Value Added Tax (VAT), in all of total assets, total liabilities, customer deposits, retained earnings, total operating income, total operating expenses and net operating income. The study targeted the fourth quarter of 201...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxation efficiency and accounting assisted transparency, insight into a European framework</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/31C9E7463065</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/31C9E7463065</guid><description>
	This paper highlights the relationship between taxation, accounting and transparency for achieving disclosure and efficiency. Research takes into consideration taxation costs and legislation in order to discern an optimized business level of transparency. The data collected from questionnaires were analyzed by descriptive statistical analysis, followed by factor analysis and reliability test...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of executive compensation and share ownership on financial performance of listed deposit money banks in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/6BCBC0E62698</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/6BCBC0E62698</guid><description>
	It has remained a paradox whether people will be motivated if they believe that strong effort will lead to good performance and good performance will lead to desired rewards. Studies in this area have reported conflicting findings. To this end, the study examines the effect of executive compensation and share ownership on financial performance of listed Deposit Money Banks in Nigeria. Execut...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Creative accounting and investment decision in listed manufacturing firms in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/0857E5B63181</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/0857E5B63181</guid><description>
	Creative accounting involves the manipulation of companys records toward a predetermined target. Financial information manipulation is usually aimed at misleading the users of financial reporting through the provision of information that affects their decision making. This study evaluated the effects of creative accounting on investment decision in selected listed manufacturing firms in Nige...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Information technology and the accountant today: What has really changed?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/0F5E6B663319</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/0F5E6B663319</guid><description>
	One of the major advancements in information technology (IT) is the use of IT tools to perform accounting functions and processes. In this paper, we provide discussions on how IT has affected the accountancy profession. We argued that the traditional duty of accountants is the preparation of financial statements, and consequently, several tasks are carried out throughout that function. In th...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Investors&#x2019; perception and profitability of listed companies: Evidence from Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/BC5859462054</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/BC5859462054</guid><description>
	The stock market has continually been a source of economic development in most developing countries. This study examined the relationship between investors perception and profitability of quoted companies in Nigeria using secondary data obtained from the annual reports of forty (40) companies. The study employed the multiple regression techniques to analyze the relationship between investors...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The role of board characteristics on the relationship between International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) adoption and earnings management: Evidence from China</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/2A7249162056</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/2A7249162056</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) adopting on earning management by considering the role of board size and board independence. Univariate tests and multivariate regression analysis were employed to test whether the level of earnings management is significantly lower after the adoption of IFRS and whether the role of b...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Do economic variables still influence tax compliance intentions of self-employed persons in developing economies? Evidence from Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/F88B7C962314</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/F88B7C962314</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study was to establish whether tax compliance intentions of tax-registered self-employed persons are still influenced by economic variables instead of non-economic variables which are now at the centre stage in tax compliance research. A quantitative research design based on a survey of 453 self-employed persons randomly selected from 15 Small Taxpayers Offices across the...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of tax identification number on revenue generation in Southwest Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/87EC4C462393</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/87EC4C462393</guid><description>
	This paper examined the effect of tax identification number on revenue generation in south-west, Nigeria. The ex-post facto research design was adopted and the population covered all the states in the Southwest geopolitical zone of Nigeria, out of which three states namely Ekiti, Osun and Ondo States were selected as the study elements using simple random sampling technique. Quantitative sec...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Factor analysis on IFRS Adoption: A survey study on lenders, users and audit firms&#x2019; perspective in West Hararghe Zone, Oromia Regional State, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/C88F10F62619</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JAT/article-abstract/C88F10F62619</guid><description>
	The adoption of International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) around the world is occurring rapidly to bring about accounting quality improvement through a uniform set of standards for financial reporting standards and harmonization of reporting procedures. For the same purpose, Ethiopia begins the IFRS adoption process since the year 2014. For this study, 200 questionnaires were distri...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>