<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Brewing and Distilling - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Brewing and Distilling</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Evaluation of maturation congeners in beer aged with Brazilian woods</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/F00868C62891</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/F00868C62891</guid><description>
	Beer is the most consumed alcoholic beverage in Brazil. In this paper, wood aged beer was made with some Brazilian wood species, that is, chestnut, Cariniana sp., balsam, oak, and amburana. This maturation process can be done with wooden cubes, chips or in barrels. The main differences between the processes are related to the surface area of wood in contact with the beer as well as where it ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparison of unaged and barrel aged whiskies from the same Mash Bill using gas chromatography/mass spectrometry
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/7081B3F61216</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/7081B3F61216</guid><description>
	This study provides qualitative data on sensory compounds present in barrel aged U.S. corn-based whiskies (primarily bourbon) and their unaged counterparts. Whisky samples of commercial brands by Heaven Hill, Buffalo Trace, Makers Mark, and Nelsons Greenbrier Distillery were tested by direct injection gas chromatography/mass spectrometry. Chromatograms of samples were analyzed against NIST m...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of copper content in beers obtained from retail in Sweden</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/F6C0BF963648</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/F6C0BF963648</guid><description>
	A quantitative study of copper (Cu) content in 19 different beer brands produced in mainly European countries and consumed in Sweden were measured using atomic absorption spectrophotometer without sample digestion. Results showed that the Cu content in beers is below the permissible levels concentrations for potable drinking water recommended by World Health Organization. In addition, the st...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Application of high gravity fermentation worts to the brewing of industrial opaque beer</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/473938652215</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/473938652215</guid><description>
	Fermentation of worts with high concentrations of fermentable sugars has become common practice in large clear beer breweries that use high gravity worts containing 16-18% (w/v) dissolved solids to obtain high alcohol contents. Normal and high gravity worts, ranging from 12 to 20% (w/v) initial dissolved solid contents were used in industrial opaque beer brewing and the biochemical character...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Nitrogen compounds in brewing wort and beer: 
A review
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/0A7CB9248727</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/0A7CB9248727</guid><description>
	Traditionally, beer is obtained from the treatment and processing of three raw materials (barley malt, hops and water). From it, brewing wort fermented by the action of yeasts is obtained. Wort composition depends on the quality and type of raw materials used, as well as the control of the various processing steps. Wort composition also depends on the concentration and profile of nitrogen co...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Solid wastes in brewing process: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/0E6313746212</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/0E6313746212</guid><description>
	A large amount of agro-industrial waste is produced annually around the world from the beneficiated agricultural products or in food industrialization. The disposal of these residues in the environment results in a lot of inconvenience to the ecosystem, due to its significant nutritional value and high concentration of organic compounds that confers a high biochemical oxygen demand to the wa...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Role of magnesium ions on yeast performance during very high gravity fermentation</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/3015B4A282</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/3015B4A282</guid><description>
	

	The advent of highly efficient, environmentally friendly and cost effective fermentation technology has given impetus to research in the field of optimizing nutritional parameters for optimum yeast fermentative performance. Very high gravity fermentation is a novel fermentation technology that provides an increased production capacity from same size fermentation facilities, with outstan...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparison of the mashing and brewing potentials of crude extracts of Abrus precatorius, Burnatia enneandra and Cadaba farinosa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/E23DA03287</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/E23DA03287</guid><description>
	

	The mashing and brewing potentials of crude extracts of three plants commonly used in Northern Cameroon to make starch gruels sweet were assessed using sorghum cultivarSafrarias an adjunct. Alpha-amylase activities of the extracts fluctuated between 18 and 122 U/g, while the diastatic power and the -carboxypeptidase activities ranged between 83 and 123 WK, and 16 and 63 mg FAN/min/L, re...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of pasteurization and season on milk composition and ripening of Ras cheese</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/FA69293272</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/FA69293272</guid><description>
	

	The objective of this study was to compare between the raw and pasteurized Ras cheese from cows milk through the season. The chemical composition of cheese was also demonstrated as the ripening period progressed. High solids in winter milk and low solids in summer milk were observed and were attributed to the hot weather and the poorer quality pastures. Casein as a percentage of true pr...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Consumer preferences and market potential for sorghum based clear beer in Tanzania</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/AD5438E258</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBD/article-abstract/AD5438E258</guid><description>
	

	This paper assessed the influence of consumers on sorghum based clear beer (Eagle) value chain in Tanzania. The specific objectives were to assess consumers preferences and market potential of Eagle beer in Tanzania. The study areas were Moshi Rural and Karatu Districts in Kilimanjaro and Arusha regions respectively in Northern Tanzania. In these regions, the Eagle beer was launched for...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>