<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>African Journal of Bacteriology Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR</link><description>view the most recent articles from African Journal of Bacteriology Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Genetic diversity and resistance profile of mycobacterial strains isolated in Senegal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/C2B880B62434</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/C2B880B62434</guid><description>
	Tuberculosis remains a major public health problem in Senegal. The aim of this study was to determine the resistance and molecular profiles of mycobacterial strains isolated over a four-year period in Senegal. Mycobacterial isolates worked on were obtained at the National Reference Laboratory of the National Antituberculosis Program (NAP) in Senegal. These strains were cultured on Lowenstein...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Occurrence of biofilm producing bacteria in packaged water sold in Lagos, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/5E6B0E860726</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/5E6B0E860726</guid><description>
	Bacterial biofilms have been linked with protracted and recurring human infections, and considering that biofilms shed microorganisms into their environment it becomes pertinent to examine their role in waterborne diseases through consumption of treated packaged water. To evaluate the consortia of bacteria in packaged water for the ability to form biofilms. Using membrane filtration techniqu...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Detection of Mycobacterium bovis in whey, by multiplex polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and 
bacteriological culture
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/2258D7C59035</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/2258D7C59035</guid><description>
	The objective of this study was to detect the presence of Mycobacterium bovis (M. bovis) in whey. A total of 233 cow milk samples were analyzed together with 26 tank milk samples that came from dairy herds of several states of the Mexican Republic (Quertaro, San Luis Potos, Guanajuato, Hidalgo, Coahuila). DNA was obtained from whey and used for polymerase chain reaction-multiplex (PCR-M). Tu...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Multidrug resistant Escherichia coli isolated from asymptomatic school going children in 
Kibera slum, Kenya
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B1E2C3059037</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B1E2C3059037</guid><description>
	Pathogenic Escherichia coli are of different types, currently grouped into six groups depending on the virulence gene(s) they possess. This study isolated pathogenic E. coli from 580 stool samples obtained in the month of August, 2016. The samples were obtained from asymptomatic school going children in one of the biggest urban slums in Kenya. Ten primary schools were randomly sampled and 40...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In vitro assessment of Leuconostoc mesenteroides zinc nanoparticles against Salmonella serovars recovered from broilers chickens</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B187ABB58437</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B187ABB58437</guid><description>
	Salmonella serovars are responsible for a variety of acute and chronic diseases in poultry. Leuconostoc mesenteroides probiotic can exert antimicrobial activity by producing diverse fermentative metabolites with bactericidal or bacteriostatic activities such as lactic and acetic acids, fatty acids, hydrogen peroxide or diacetyl and antimicrobial proteins such as bacteriocins and peptidoglyca...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibacterial and antioxidant activities of crude aerial part extracts of Satureja Punctata (Benth) Briq</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B96350058435</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B96350058435</guid><description>
	This study evaluates the antimicrobial and antioxidant activities of the crude extract of an aerial part of Satureja punctata (Benth.) Briq. The dried aerial part of S. punctata (Benth.) Briq was extracted separately using aqueous, ethanol and n-hexane. The antibacterial activity against Staphylococcus aureus, Escherichia coli and Pseudomonas aeruginosa was assessed using disc diffusion meth...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibiotic resistance genes in diarrheagenic Escherichia coli (DEC) isolated from livestock organic wastes in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/99730D658439</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/99730D658439</guid><description>
	Diarrheagenic Escherichia coli (DEC) are often disseminated through the fecal matter of livestock and waste products including slurry and manure. The study aimed to characterize archived DEC recovered from cattle fecal matter, manure and slurry for quinolone resistance and extended spectrum beta-lactamases (ESBLs) with focus on trends in antimicrobial susceptibility patterns. The susceptibil...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Enteric bacterial communities associated with the Omubhira Stream in Kakamega County, Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B16387457880</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/B16387457880</guid><description>
	The present study was undertaken to establish the distribution and diversity of enteric bacterial communities along the Omubhira stream and also determine if physico-chemical parameters influence their distribution in water in terms of total coliforms (TC) and Escherichia coli. Stratified random sampling was used and four strata with 15 selected sampling sites identified along the stream. Se...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Physicochemical analysis and microbial quality of cow butter obtained from Menz district of Amhara region, Ethiopia
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/7CB80FA57882</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/7CB80FA57882</guid><description>
	Menz has long been known for its quality butter production but traditional milk products are generally reported to be of substandard quality. Therefore, this investigation was conducted to access physiochemical and microbial quality of butter from Menz district along the market value chain. The study was conducted by using laboratory analysis of physiochemical and microbial quality. The micr...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An overview of epidemiology and etiology of bacteria associated with diabetic injuries and their dominant infection at Central Region, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/1D5DBDB57644</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBR/article-abstract/1D5DBDB57644</guid><description>
	Diabetes mellitus (DM) is one of the most chronic and dangerous diseases worldwide and in the Saudi society in particular. Swabs (168) from DM injuries were collected from inpatient and outpatient departments. Analysis of variance revealed the high incidence of diabetic foot infections compared to other injuries by an average of 51 and 33, respectively. Adults category was significantly the ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>