<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Bioinformatics and Sequence Analysis - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Bioinformatics and Sequence Analysis</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Computational characterization of providence virus non-structural proteins: Evolutionary and functional implications</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/06DF3CF60644</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/06DF3CF60644</guid><description>
	Providence virus is the only member of the family Carmotetraviridae and carries a positive single stranded RNA genome that encodes three open reading frames. The smallest open reading frame encodes the structural proteins. The largest open reading frame encodes a large putative protein, p130. The second overlapping open reading frame encodes two non-structural proteins; p40, a proposed acces...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Vitis vinifera gene expression differential analysis assessing microarrays data pre-processing dynamism by RNA-Seq approach</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/2FCA55B60202</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/2FCA55B60202</guid><description>
	Oligonucleotide microarrays data pre-processing procedures impacting gene expression differential survey performances were fully evoked. RNA-Seq tool exhibited high performances (sensitivity) as opposed to microarrays in transcriptomic as well as genomic studies. The aim of this study is to evaluate microarrays data pre-processing dynamism on gene expression differential analysis outcomes, a...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluating the computing efficiencies (specificity and sensitivity) of graphics processing unit (GPU)-accelerated DNA sequence alignment tools against central processing unit (CPU) alignment tool</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/B39CEF858061</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/B39CEF858061</guid><description>
	Bioinformatics is an emerging field, where information technology usage can significantly accelerate life science research. It is a relatively new field and the scope of exploring new tools and techniques seems immense. One major field where bioinformatics plays important role is next generation sequence analysis (NGS), in which an unknown genome is shuttered into pieces and tried to align i...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysis of factors affecting codon usage bias in human papillomavirus</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/849296A55758</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/849296A55758</guid><description>
	Indices of codon usage pattern of human papillomavirus (HPV) were analyzed to understand the key determinants of synonymous codon usage in the HPV genome. The complete sequences of 39 HPV genomes were downloaded from the website of the National Center for Biotechnology Information. The relative synonymous codon usage values, effective number of codons, GC content, percentage of GCs at the th...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In silico characterization of beta-galactosidase using computational tools</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/FECF9C959898</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/FECF9C959898</guid><description>
	-galactosidase (EC.3.2.1.23) is an important enzyme, mainly used in the preparation of lactose hydrolyzed milk suitable for people with lactose intolerance. It is essential to understand the structural and functional aspects of various -galactosidase produced from different sources. The present work deals with the use of bioinformatics to describe the physiochemical, functional and structura...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Primer designing for PreS region of hepatitis B virus from the most conserved patches of hepatitis B virus genome
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/398802849921</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/398802849921</guid><description>
	The most conserved regions for 15 hepatitis B virus complete genome of different subtypes were aligned using PCGENE software CLUSTAL to design a new pair of primer that can bind to each subtype of hepatitis B virus (HBV), to amplify PreS region of HBV genome. A pair of primer from these conserved patches was selected using software PRIMER and named as Nhepf1 and Nhepr1. Nhepf1, forward prime...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bioinformatics with basic local alignment search tool (BLAST) and fast alignment (FASTA)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/093849744377</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/093849744377</guid><description>
	Following advances in DNA and protein sequencing, the application of computational approaches in analysing biological data has become a very important aspect of biology. Evaluating similarities between biological sequences is crucial to our understanding of evolutionary biology, and this can be achieved by basic local alignment search tool (BLAST) and fast alignment (FASTA). BLAST and FASTA ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Competitiveness of Ljubljana city</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/8D78AD72406</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/8D78AD72406</guid><description>
	Ljubljana can be observed through different perspectives. Urban development is often written on the basis of economic level, social development, benchmarking results with similar economies, on the basis of past experiences. By urbanistic way of life we cover the main Slovenian areas in polycentric net, that is well organised in EU space. City is forced to lead a vital, beautiful and clean en...</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prediction of MHC Class II binders/non-binders using negative selection algorithm in vaccine designing</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/FE6EE595768</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/FE6EE595768</guid><description>
	

	The identification of major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class-II restricted peptides is an important goal in human immunological research leading to peptide based vaccine designing. These MHC class II peptides are predominantly recognized by CD4+ T-helper cells, which when turned on, have profound immune regulatory effects. Thus, prediction of such MHC class-II binding peptide is v...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In silico identification of miRNAs and their target prediction from Japanese encephalitis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/0943E915791</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSA/article-abstract/0943E915791</guid><description>
	

	MicroRNA is a family of small non-coding RNAs that regulate gene expression in a sequence-specific manner. miRNAs are a class of post-transcriptional regulators. miRNAs are a family of 19 to 25 small nucleotide RNAs. Since miRNAs have been discovered and their role in gene regulation established, it has been theorized that viruses could generate miRNAs as well and that these viral encod...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>