<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Biophysics and Structural Biology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Biophysics and Structural Biology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Physical basis of the DNA double helix</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/AEA730862925</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/AEA730862925</guid><description>
	Despite the widely spread acceptance that the enthalpy of DNA duplex unfolding does not depend on temperature and is greater for the CG base pair held by three hydrogen bonds than for the AT base pair held by only two hydrogen bonds, direct calorimetric measurement has shown that the enthalpic and entropic contributions of both base pairs are temperature dependent and at all temperatures the...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Extrapolating human toxicity data with target organ dose (TOD-Wb) model: A meso-scale allometric analytical approach</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/48F63E566015</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/48F63E566015</guid><description>
	An allometric target organ dose model (TOD-Wb) with variable scaling exponent, b = br + bo(bm) - bi, is proposed for the extrapolation of animal toxicity to human. The exponent b comprises four constituent parameters representing the intake mode to entry organ (bi), route of transportation to target organ (br), mass of target organ (bo), and rate of metabolism at target organ (bm). This expr...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spectroscopic approach of the interaction study of ceftriaxone and human serum albumin</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/337345B44936</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/337345B44936</guid><description>
	Under physiological conditions, interaction between ceftriaxone and human serum albumin was investigated by using fluorescence spectroscopy and ultra violet (UV) absorption spectrum. From spectral analysis, ceftriaxone showed a strong ability to quench the intrinsic fluorescence of human serum albumin (HSA) through a static quenching procedure. The binding constant (k) is estimated as K=1.02...</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Epigenetic regulation of PGC1 &#x3B1; in human type 2 diabetes</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/5E917DE10946</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/5E917DE10946</guid><description>
	Type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) is the most common metabolic disease in theworld, reaching epidemic proportions. PPARGC1A mRNA expression is reduced in islets from patients with diabetes 2 and it is influenced by both genetic and epigenetic factor. The epigenetic modification, results as a two fold increase in DNA methylation of the PGC1A promoter of diabetes. This two fold increase in DNA m...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Changes in airway resistance with cumulative numbers of cigarettes smoked</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/0E5387640425</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/0E5387640425</guid><description>
	This work was performed with smokers of Virginia tobacco cigarettes without taking into consideration brand or type of cigarettes. An experimental study was conducted for the variation of cigarettes number and the increments in airway resistance for both normal and respiratory disordered subjects using body plethysmograph for testing individuals. Seventeen (17) nonsmokers and ten smokers wer...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The use of a continuity equation of fluid mechanics to reduce the abnormality of the cardiovascular system: A control mechanics of the human heart</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/869F30E10933</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/869F30E10933</guid><description>
	The paper is aimed at presenting the differential equations for the cardiovascular system with the help of continuity equation of fluid mechanics to reduce the abnormality of the rate of blood flow and variation of blood volume in different parts of the system. The equations are used to explain the Frank-Starling mechanism, which plays an important role in the maintenance of the stability of...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Using electrical impedance tomography in following up skin conductivity change for different sonophoresis conditions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/473AD5E10939</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/473AD5E10939</guid><description>
	Sonophoresis is the using of ultrasound waves to increase the entrancement of genes and drugs surpassing the skin barrier. Many mechanisms have been described to illustrate the sonophoresis mode of action; some describe changes in skin resistance during sonophoresis. Electrical impedance tomography (EIT) technique uses voltage measurement through a group of electrodes and reconstructs the da...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>pH uniquely modulates protein arginine methylation</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/9C9A69A10916</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/9C9A69A10916</guid><description>
	Protein arginine methyltransferases (PRMTs) function in the alkaline milieu of the nucleus and at neutral pH of the cytosol. Accordingly, several PRMTs are broadly active over a range of pHs. We investigated the effect altering pH had on protein arginine methylation using a variety of defined substrates, recombinant PRMTs and cell extracts.We demonstrate that pH-induced alterations in the ex...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Crystal structure of the allosteric-defective chaperonin GroELE434K mutant</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/6A0374B10924</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/6A0374B10924</guid><description>
	The chaperonin GroEL adopts a double-ring structure with various modes of allosteric communication. The simultaneous positive intra-ring and negative inter-ring cooperativities allow alternating functionality of the folding cavities in both protein rings. Mutation of glutamic acid 434 (located at the ring interface), to lysine alters the negative inter-ring cooperativity. The crystal structu...</description><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of the tannoid enriched fraction of Emblica officinalis on &#x3B1;-crystallin chaperone activity under hyperglycemic conditions in lens organ culture</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/85D4DDB10897</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JBSB/article-abstract/85D4DDB10897</guid><description>
	Chaperone-like activity (CLA) of-crystallin is known to be compromised in diabetic conditions and associated with cataract formation. Protecting-crystallin CLA may help in delaying and/or preventing cataracts. In this study, we employed a lens organ culture model to study the effect of hyperglycemia on the CLA of-crystallin and investigated the protective effect the tannoids ofEmblica offici...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>