<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Cell and Animal Biology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Cell and Animal Biology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>GFSKLYFamide-like neuropeptide is expressed in the female gonad of the sea cucumber, Holothuria scabra</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/CFBFDED62964</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/CFBFDED62964</guid><description>
	Neuropeptides are mediators of neuronal signalling, controlling a wide range of physiological processes that cut across many organisms. GFSKLYFamide is a neuropeptide that belongs to the Echinoderm SALMFamide group of peptides. This study was aimed at determining the expression of GFSKLYFamide-like neuropeptide in the female gonad of the sea cucumber Holothuria scabra. Ten female H. scabra w...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phenotypic variations of indigenous sheep breed ecotypes of Ethiopia: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/0B1A03862966</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/0B1A03862966</guid><description>
	Updated result of the phenotypic characterization and description of the indigenous sheep population was reviewed. The reviewed paper used reporting and tabulating published descriptive phenotypic information on Ethiopian breeds with the aim of dissemination of relevant information for the beneficiaries. The original sheep breed types in Ethiopia that migrated from South West Asia to Africa ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Review on breeding objectives and practices of dairy cattle production in Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/3FE155660011</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/3FE155660011</guid><description>
	The review aims to examine dairy cattle production system together with pastoral and agro- pastoral, small holder, peri urban and urban intensive dairy cattle production system, breeding practice including mating system (natural mating and Artificial Insemination), breeding objectives, reproductive and productive traits of dairy cattle in Ethiopia. In Ethiopia most farmers use natural, unpla...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of Kelulut honey from Trigona sp. on zebrafish (Danio rerio) embryo that mimics human embryonic development</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/878BC4E58225</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/878BC4E58225</guid><description>
	Kelulut honey (KH) is a type of honey with various pharmacological properties that can be found in Malaysia. Nevertheless, the safety aspects of this honey have not been adequately addressed. This study evaluated the developmental toxicity of KH from Trigona sp on zebrafish (Danio rerio) embryos. Viable zebrafish embryos at 3 hours post fertilization (hpf) (early stage) and 24 hpf (organ dev...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Camel milk improvement of antioxidant and lipid profile in hypercholesterolemic rabbits</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/E662C6056782</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/E662C6056782</guid><description>
	Dietary intervention can improve lipid profile and therefore impede the progress of atherosclerosis. The primary aim of this study is to assess the possible role of camel milk in enhancing the antioxidant capacity in rats fed a high fat diet. Thirty rabbits were individually divided into three groups, the control, HFD and HFD with camel milk. The control group fed on 100 g/day of NOR diet ra...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Specific sperm abnormalities observed in rams (Ovis aries) following cypermethrin treatment</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/2522AF364133</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/2522AF364133</guid><description>
	This work was designed to make further observations on the specific types of sperm abnormalities present in Cypermethrin treated rams and contribute information towards understanding how Cypermethrin affects males reproduction. Sixteen sexually-mature, healthy Yankasa rams aged 18 to 30 months and weighing between 21.5 to 46.5 kg were used. The 16 rams were divided equally into two groups (A...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sheep and goats pasteurellosis: Isolation, identification, biochemical characterization and prevalence determination in Fogera Woreda, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/29701AF62093</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/29701AF62093</guid><description>
	A cross sectional study was carried out on pasteurellosis of small ruminants in Fogera Woreda, Ethiopia. The objectives of this research were isolation and characterization of the bacterial species by culture and biochemical testes, and determining the prevalence in apparently pneumonic small ruminants. Out of the total 988 samples examined, 322 were detected positive for pasteurella with an...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The occurrence of Cysticercus bovis at Gondar ELFORA Abattoir, Northwest of Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/B83163760568</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/B83163760568</guid><description>
	A cross-sectional survey was undertaken in the abattoir to study the prevalence of Cysticercus bovis in cattle originated from different localities and to determine the cyst prevalence as well as distribution in different organs within infected animals in Gondar ELFORA abattoir. Out of the total 450 cattle slaughtered and examined at Gondar ELFORA abattoir, 9 animals (2.0%) were identified p...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Characterization and anti-tumor effect of shark liver extraction</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/0A7D89058852</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/0A7D89058852</guid><description>
	Shark liver oil (SLO) has been widely used as a food supplement to boost human immunity. The extraction method of shark liver oil is immature. In this study, four different extraction methods of shark liver oil were tried, the effect of the solid-liquid ratio, quality of the enzyme, reaction pH and temperature on SLO extraction rate have been discussed. Infrared spectroscopy, gas chromatogra...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of different levels of Satureja hortensis essential oil on performance, carcass characteristics, acidity and intestinal microflora population in broilers</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/EDEF4E556950</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCAB/article-abstract/EDEF4E556950</guid><description>
	This experiment was carried out to study the effects of dietary supplementation of Satureja hortensis essential oil on growth, carcass parts, pH and luminal microbe in broiler chicken. A total of 400 one week old ROS 308 male chicks were used in a completely randomize design model with 5 treatments and 4 replicates, each composing of 20 chicks. Duration of experiment was 35 days until the ag...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>