<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Computational Biology and Bioinformatics Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Computational Biology and Bioinformatics Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Multivariate analysis of groundnut (Arachis  hypogaea  L.) cultivars based on oil traits</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/E13343562972</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/E13343562972</guid><description>
	The existence of genetic variation is essential in plant breeding for increasing yield, wider adaptation, selection of parents for hybridization, desirable quality, and pest or disease resistance. This study was planned to investigate genetic variability based on cluster analysis of groundnut cultivars based on morpho-agronomic traits. The crop was sown in randomized complete block design (R...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The perils of artificial intelligence in healthcare: Disease diagnosis and treatment</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/709CF4D60751</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/709CF4D60751</guid><description>
	For the past decade, artificial intelligence (AI) and its related technologies have made remarkable advances in marketing and business solutions based on AI-driven big data analysis of customer queries, and it, when coupled with bioinformatics, seemingly holds out great promise for use in healthcare. In reality, however, AI is still largely a buzzword when it comes to disease diagnosis and t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Theoretical and conceptual derivation of threshold phenomena and metabolic switching models in a chemostat system</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/5EC422C58976</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/5EC422C58976</guid><description>
	A chemostat cell culture is a polyphasic dispersed system. Three models using net transport and metabolization (T/M) kinetics of hyperbolic form have been described. The first uses only one metabolic pathway and has been studied under various conditions. The second uses two metabolic pathways, with either high or low affinity for the substrate. The third adds excretion of fermentative produc...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Selection of T cell epitopes from S. mansoni Sm23 protein as a vaccine construct, using Immunoinformatics approach</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/C9C1DC757412</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/C9C1DC757412</guid><description>
	Schistosomiasis, a neglected and most prevalenttropical diseases after malaria, have been a threat to people living in endemic areas. With regards to possible resistance to the popular drug (praziquantel) use for treatment of schistosomiasis, the need for a permanent vaccinating approach has been justified. This study uses an in silico approach to identify potential target vaccine candidate ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Computational sequence analysis and in silico modeling of a stripe rust resistance protein encoded by wheat TaHSC70 gene</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/573BB7D52788</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/573BB7D52788</guid><description>
	TaHSC70 gene of Triticum sp. is an associate of the heat shock protein family and plays a significant role in stress-related and defense responses educed by contagion with stripe rust fungus through a Jasmonic acid dependent signal transduction pathway. Hence, understanding molecular structure and function of the protein coded by this gene is of paramount importance for plant biologists work...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Development of genodynamic metrics for exploring the biophysics of DNA polymorphisms</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/60FC53E48559</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/60FC53E48559</guid><description>
	Single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) represent an important type of dynamic sites within the human genome. These common variants often locally correlate within more complex multi-SNP haploblocks that are maintained throughout generations in a stable population. Information encoded in the structure of SNPs and SNP haploblock variation can be characterized through a normalized information co...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Does a protein coevolve with its multiple interacting partners? A case study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/FF035ED9875</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/FF035ED9875</guid><description>
	Protein-protein interactions are playing a fundamental role in different cellular activities. Although the coevolution of interacting protein pairs has been established by several groups, whether a protein having multiple interacting partners coevolves with all of its interacting partners or not have not been studied, so far. Here, the coevolution of proliferating cell nuclear antigen (PCNA)...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>MLH1 gene: An in silico analysis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/381F7A49804</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/381F7A49804</guid><description>
	The MLH1 gene responsible for colon cancer has been examined to identify functional consequences of single-nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). 16 SNPs have been identified in the MLH1 gene in which all are found to be nonsynonymous. Non synymous SNPs are relevant in many of the human inherited diseases since they change the aminoacid sequence of the protein. 56% of the identified nsSNPs have be...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Annotation of virulence factors in schistosomes for the development of a SchistoVir database</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/19EC4499816</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/19EC4499816</guid><description>
	Scientific efforts in the eradication of neglected tropical diseases, such as those caused by the parasitic helminthes, can be improved if a database of key virulence factors directly implicated in pathogenesis is available. As a first step towards creating SchistoVir, a database of virulence protein factors in schistosomes, in this study, we curated, annotated and aligned sequences of twent...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Establishment of rice yield prediction model
using canopy reflectance</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/79C67CA9725</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBBR/article-abstract/79C67CA9725</guid><description>
	The major objectives of this study were to identify spectral characteristics associated with rice yield and to establish their quantitative relationships. Field experiments were conducted at Shi-Ko experimental farm of TARIs Chiayi Station, during 2001 to 2005. Rice cultivar Tainung 67 (Oryza sativaL.), the major cultivar grown in Taiwan, was used in the study. Various levels of rice yield w...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>