<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Cell Biology and Genetics - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Cell Biology and Genetics</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Pancreatic response after treatment with 1,5-Bis(3,5- dimethylpyrazol-1-yl)-3-oxapentane diacetatocopper in rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/5BD7ADB53698</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/5BD7ADB53698</guid><description>
	3,5-Dimethylpyrazole (U-6245) is a hypoglycemic and antilipolytic agent used in the treatment of diabetes mellitus. Complex 1,5-Bis(3,5-dimethylpyrazol-1-yl)-3-oxapentane diacetatocopper was prepared in 2009. This study indicated that 1,5-Bis(3,5-dimethylpyrazol-1-yl)-3- oxapentane-diacetatocopper has hypoglycemic properties by decreasing glucose level in blood but caused histopathological c...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Basic biology and therapeutic application of stem cells in various human and animal diseases
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/6BA497E49112</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/6BA497E49112</guid><description>
	Stem cells are a population of precursor cells that are capable of developing into many different cell types in the body. They are unspecialized cells that can give rise to specialized cells and capable of dividing and renewing themselves for long periods. Based on the potency, stem cells can be totipotent, pluripotent, multipotent, oligopotent, unipotent and based on source it can be divide...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Role of ginger extract and N-acetylcysteine in acute renal tubular necrosis: Histological, immunohistochemical and gene expression study in rats
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/616B24948488</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/616B24948488</guid><description>
	Acute renal failure (ARF) is a syndrome associated with high mortality rate in humans. ARF now known as acute kidney injury (AKI) represents a significant and devastating problem in clinical medicine. This work was performed on adult male albino rats to study the possible protective effects of ginger which is considered as one of the promising medicinal plants and N-acetylcystiene on acute t...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Constitutive activation of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) propel mitochondrial biogenesis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/5C3A3F748035</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/5C3A3F748035</guid><description>
	Mitochondrial biogenesis is primarily a critical adaptation aimed to balance an increased workload in an attempt to maintain appropriate body perfusion. Until recently, the signaling mechanisms responsible for this response are poorly understood. To examine the role of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK), an evolutionarily conserved fuel sensor, in mitochondrial biogenesis, we used constitut...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fine structure of adrenal gland of Indian wild caught female bat Taphozous kachhensis (Dobson)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/99C795145196</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/99C795145196</guid><description>
	The Indian wild caught bat, Taphozous kachhensis at Ambai Nimbai (Maharashtra) shows continuous asynchronous breeding, exhibiting a seasonal polyoestry. The adrenal gland of T. kachhensis is made up of adrenocortical and chromaffin tissues. The adrenocortical tissue is comprised of two main types of cells, the steroid cells with abundance of lipid inclusions and eosinophilic cells with eosin...</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Blockade of Akt/mTOR pathway and enhancement of histone acetylation by PHI to induce cells apoptosis in prostate cancer PC3 cells</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/E0DD1B81158</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/E0DD1B81158</guid><description>
	Mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) has merged an important therapeutic target for cancers. Our object is to demonstrate that phenyhexyle isothiocyanate (PHI), a synthetic isothiocyanate, blocked Akt/mTOR signaling in prostate cancer PC3 cell line, in addition to inhibited histone deacetylase to induce cell apoptosis. Apoptotic cells were measured by TUNEL assay. Histone acetylated H3, H4 a...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Genetic diversity evaluation of Paraschistura bampurensis (Nikolskii, 1900) in Shapour and Berim Rivers (Iran) using microsatellite markers</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/3CFAD7C1169</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/3CFAD7C1169</guid><description>
	Paraschistura bampurensisis one of the species of genus Paraschistura.It is distributed in Iran and Pakistan freshwater. This paper reports a study carried out on genetic diversity and population structure ofP. bampurensisin Shapour and Berim river basins, Iran. 100 samples of 50 fish each were collected from each river and were used. Microsatellite markers have been increasingly used in pop...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of genetic diversity in Berberis lycium Royle complex using RAPD markers</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/27E52341003</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/27E52341003</guid><description>
	Genomic diversity among fifty accessions ofBerberis lyciumRoyle complex was studied, using random amplified polymorphic DNA (RAPD) markers. Out of 80 RAPD primers, 28 were polymorphic and showed reproducible results. Total of 11,683 amplicon generated 50 accessions ofB. lyciumcomplex with 28 primers. 332 amplification products scored, 284 (85%) were polymorphic and 48 monomorphic. Maximum nu...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bone morphogenetic proteins (BMP) 2, 4, 6 and 7 affect ovarian follicular development through regulation of follicle-stimulating hormone receptor (FSHR) and luteinizing hormone receptor (LHR) expression in goat granulosa cells</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/27899C51043</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/27899C51043</guid><description>
	Bone morphogenetic proteins (BMPs), belonging to the transforming growth factor-beta family, are crucial factors in follicular growth and development in the mammalian ovary. In this study, we examined the effects of BMP2, 4, 6 and 7 on goat granulosa cells byin vitroculture. The results showed that BMP2, 4 and 7 increased follicle-stimulating hormone receptor (FSHR) level in goat granulosa c...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Molecular characterization of fusion transcripts in prostate cancer patients: A tool having diagnostic implications in Pakistan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/654591F939</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCBG/article-abstract/654591F939</guid><description>
	Substantial fraction of information has been added with reference to fusion transcripts in hematological malignancies. However these fusion transcripts have been characterized in epithelial cells of prostate and are documented to gear up the process of neoplasia. TMPRSS2-ERG and related transcripts are key offenders in the subversion of core biological systems driving oncogenic transformatio...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>