<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Civil Engineering and Construction Technology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Civil Engineering and Construction Technology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Study of physico-mechanical properties of concretes based on palm kernel shells originating from the locality of Haut Nkam in Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/7E3662763729</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/7E3662763729</guid><description>
	This study is based on the use of palm kernel shells as aggregate in the manufacture of concrete. Several (0, 25, 50, 75 and 100%) substitutions were used in the volume fraction of the aggregates. In order to evaluate the effect of this substitution, the mechanical properties at 7 and 28 days for compression was determine, 28 days for bending and then the physical properties of fresh and har...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluating mixed reality technology for architectural design and construction layout</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/9809BDF63510</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/9809BDF63510</guid><description>
	Mixed reality (MR) technology has attracted increasing interest in the architecture and construction industry since the commercial availability of head-mounted MR devices in 2016. With its ability of overlaying digital building models in real construction sites, building owners, architects, engineers, and contractors have quickly recognized the value of MR technology in on-site architectural...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Reliability assessment of progressive failure of a low rise framed building on weak 
soil-foundation interaction
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/8BF6B9962468</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/8BF6B9962468</guid><description>
	A 4-storey reinforced concrete framed buildings was modelled in 3-dimensional analysis with the same sections and loadings for both rigid and weak foundations respectively using ETABS and FORM5 Softwares in accordance with Euro code provisions. The weak foundation was initially analysed and designed as a fixed column-foundation joint and later re-analysed and redesigned as a hinged column-fo...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Variability of visible and near-infrared (vis-NIR) diffuse spectral reflectance of cement-based solidified/ stabilized pre-treated oil-based drill cuttings</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/611C48662510</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/611C48662510</guid><description>
	This study investigated the effects of solidification/stabilization (S/S) variables on visible and near-infrared (vis-NIR) spectral reflectance of solidified/stabilized low-temperature thermally desorbed (pre-treated) oil-based drill cuttings. Partial least squares (PLS) regression models were also developed to rapidly estimate the levels of total petroleum hydrocarbon (TPH), Cu, and Ba pres...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Enhancing the strength of sandcrete blocks using coarse aggregates</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/F2FA46462140</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/F2FA46462140</guid><description>
	This current article explores the possibility of adding aggregate (10 mm size) to sandcrete mixes in order to enhance the strength of the sandcrete blocks. Four different kinds of mixes were made; the first one was used as a reference without the addition of course aggregate, and in the remaining three, course aggregates were added in percentages of 5, 10 and 15% by volume of the reference m...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Recent advances in non- destructive testing of concretes and structures: An outlook</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/EFBFF5B61741</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/EFBFF5B61741</guid><description>
	Non Destructive Testing (NDT) of materials and structures is one of the most common forms of quality control. The Nigerian infrastructure systems continue to deteriorate due to lack of integrity checks on some identified projects in both public and private sector. Analysis of various sectors in Nigeria revealed that there are abandon projects in building and constructions industry while majo...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Modeling of compressive strength of concrete using pulse velocity values from a non-destructive testing of concrete</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/DB911AE61211</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/DB911AE61211</guid><description>
	In this research, ultrasonic pulse velocity (UPV) and crushing strength tests were carried out. Major factors which affect the strength of concrete such as concrete mix, aggregate size, and water-cement ratio were considered such that the model obtained could be used for the determination of strength of concrete elements made under different conditions. Three proposed models were calibrated ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of building construction defect causes in North Shoa zone, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/CDC776361017</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/CDC776361017</guid><description>
	Ethiopia is one of the developing countries; and many projects are being carried out with some of the firms acting unprofessionally, leading to lots of defects in buildings. This study was focused on identifying the types of defects and assessing the causes of defects occurring in residential and office buildings located in North Shoa zone, Ethiopia. To identify the types and causes of defec...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A comparative study of sustainable end-of-life management in automobile and construction industry: A case of Kano City, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/8C8CC1157893</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/8C8CC1157893</guid><description>
	It was argued that either the construction industry to continue to be conservative and inefficient on the premise that it was distinctive or it should have opened-up to learn lessons from the best practices models in other sectors like manufacturing. This paper is a comparative study of the sustainable end-of-life management practices in the automobile and the Nigerian building sector with t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Towards enhancing sustainable reuse of pre-treated drill cuttings for construction purposes by near-infrared analysis: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/0AE5A8A57340</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCECT/article-abstract/0AE5A8A57340</guid><description>
	Sustainable reuse of pre-treated drill cuttings (a hazardous waste) as part substitute for fine aggregate in concrete for construction purposes is becoming increasingly attractive; however, issues remain. With recent studies focusing on the use of near-infrared spectroscopic technique for non-invasive determination of chloride concentration in concrete structures, this review examines the ap...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>