<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Akbari-Ganji&#x2019;s method &#x201C;AGM&#x201D; to chemical reactor design for non-isothermal and non-adiabatic of mixed flow reactors</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/959C7AC63731</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/959C7AC63731</guid><description>
	In this paper, the chemical reactor with the energy changing (non-isotherm) and non-monotonic reactions in a mixed flow is investigated and also the sets of complex nonlinear differential equations obtained from the reaction behavior in these systems are solved by a new method. The set of differential equations are consisted of the mass equilibrium and energy (temperature) changing at concen...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of plasma magnet power supplies operating temperatures on the thermal life of space-vehicles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/BE6364F61050</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/BE6364F61050</guid><description>
	The galactic and solar radiation effect on astronauts in space during manned-space missions is one of the issues that scientists are dealing with to overcome this disaster. Furthermore, in space missions to Mars, Titan, and beyond, a powerful propulsion system is required. Recently, with the enhancement of technology in plasma generation, scientists tried to design and build a plasma radiati...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding the safest planet for carbon structures in terms of thermal life</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/41D852D60634</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/41D852D60634</guid><description>
	With achieving higher technologies, and as the population of our planet grows and sources of Earth consume every day, scientists are trying to find an alternative planet to build a second home for mankind. During the last decades, Mars seemed to be the first planet as a candidate for second home of human. Nevertheless, a few years ago a new planet has been discovered to be suitable for human...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Objects impact effect on thermal fatigue life of unidirectional T700 Carbon Fiber/Epoxy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/478E64460234</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/478E64460234</guid><description>
	The main objective of this study is to investigate the effect of meteorites and debris impact on thermal fatigue life of unidirectional T700 carbon fiber/epoxy composite material. This composite material may be applied in space structures for space missions. These structures are exposed to thermal cycles as they go in and out of the planets shadow. If in this environmental condition, meteori...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Thermal life of space Elevators</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/FD1AD1F59522</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/FD1AD1F59522</guid><description>
	Since the introduction of space elevators by Tsiolkovsky in 1895, many researchers, engineers, and designers stepped forward to suggest theories for the construction of space elevators. Based on the investigations made by many authors for building space elevators, Earth-to-space, Lunar space, and Mars-to-space elevators can contribute for future space exploration and colonization. In the pre...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Super reinforcement of MWCNT/Epoxy by considering thermal fatigue resistance management technology</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/4AC923859293</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/4AC923859293</guid><description>
	Strengthening fibers and layers in nanocomposites can make these materials suitable for many applications such as automobile, sport goods, aerospace, etc. Currently, scientists are still looking for materials with higher strength, but still lightweight because of consuming less fuel and energy in industries such as automobile and aerospace. In this research, by considering thermal fatigue re...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Critical temperature estimation method for triple-walled carbon nanotubes (CNTs)/epoxy resin 
composite material
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/FACBC5E58929</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/FACBC5E58929</guid><description>
	The main objective of this research is to estimate the critical temperature for triple-walled carbon nanotubes (CNTs)/epoxy resin. Critical temperature in this study is the temperature that inter-laminar shear stress in interfaces of triple-walled CNTs and epoxy resin is the maximum value. At maximum inter-laminar shear stress, the stress concentration between triple-walled CNTs and epoxy re...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Production of bioethanol from stems of Sorghum saccharatum monitoring kinetic parameters 
of fermentation
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/792A6E958597</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/792A6E958597</guid><description>
	The objective of this study was to evaluate the performance of three stumps of Saccharomyces cerevisiae in the ethanol bioconversion of the diluted stems of sweet sorghum (Sorghum saccharatum L.) and to monitor the kinetic parameters of fermentation. Therefore, different initial concentrations of three stems from S. cerevisiae are used to ferment the juice. The juice obtained was formulated ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of artificial aging heat treatment on mechanical properties and corrosion behaviour of AA6XXX aluminium alloys</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/9DBE83558785</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/9DBE83558785</guid><description>
	In this study, the effects of artificial aging heat treatment on mechanical properties and corrosion behaviour of AA6XXX alloy were investigated. The effects of artificial aging time on microstructure and mechanical properties of alloy were analysed and at the same time corrosion behaviour was determined by corrosion tests. For experimental investigations, the alloy samples prepared in appro...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cycle numbers to failure for magnesium and its alloys in human body fluid</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/51E0E8456598</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCEMS/article-abstract/51E0E8456598</guid><description>
	The fundamental goal of this research is to provide a method to predict the fatigue life of Magnesium and its alloys in human body fluid environment. Estimation of fatigue life of Magnesium and its alloys in human body fluid environment can help doctors and patients to choose the best biomaterial for implantation surgery. This fact is true due to the reason that based on the fatigue life of ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>