<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Clinical Immunology and Immunopathology Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Clinical Immunology and Immunopathology Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Effect of haemolysis, icterus and lipemia on prothrombin time (PT), activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) and fibrinogen measured using Sysmex CA50 Hemostasis Analyzer</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/D3D7A9062956</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/D3D7A9062956</guid><description>
	Plasma prothrombin time (PPT) and activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) are coagulation tests routinely performed in laboratories to evaluate the function of the coagulation system. Generally, samples with haemolysis, icterus and lipaemia are rejected in different laboratories which delays medical care and cause discomfort to patients. This was a cross sectional study conducted to det...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunopathological effects of some Biomphalaria pfeifferi proteins against Schistosoma mansoni infection in BALB/c mice</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/2373B9360607</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/2373B9360607</guid><description>
	Intestinal schistosomiasis remains a major cause of morbidity and mortality in most parts of the world, despite decades of widespread chemotherapy use. The present study determined the intermediate host proteins expressing the immunogenic properties against the parasite by determining the efficacy. Digestive gland and foot parts were isolated by dissection from the Biomphalaria pfeifferi, pr...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The heterogeneity and distribution patterns of ABO and RH D phenotypes in the voluntary blood donors of Kenya
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/E54233A66538</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/E54233A66538</guid><description>
	Blood groups (antigens) are proteins, glycoproteins or glycolipids inherited surface markers on the red blood cell membranes, which determine the blood phenotypes of human beings. There are 36 blood group systems with over 300 antigens. Among them, ABO and Rh are of clinical significance. For a safe transfusion, a blood donor and recipient should be ABO and Rh D compatible. The heterogeneity...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Interferon-gamma (IFN-&#x3B3;) and Interleukin-2 (IL2) as immunological markers in pulmonary tuberculosis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/297111760090</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/297111760090</guid><description>
	Early diagnosis and treatment are important in prevention of tuberculosis (TB) infection. World commonly diagnose pulmonary TB using ZN stain, culture and TST. These tests are either low sensitive or required a long time. Recently intracellular interferon gamma flow cytometry assay has been available for diagnosis of pulmonary TB. We assess this diagnostic method in the diagnosis of pulmonar...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Blood tissue cytological status of prognosis and predictive markers in the natural history of solid cancer development</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/590B1FF53470</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/590B1FF53470</guid><description>
	Cancer is the major burden of disease worldwide. Each year, tens of millions of people are diagnosed with cancer around the world, and more than half of the patients eventually die from it. In many countries, cancer ranks the second most common cause of death following cardiovascular diseases. With significant improvement in treatment and prevention of cardiovascular diseases, cancer has or ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cytokine levels associated with experimental malaria pathology during Plasmodium berghei ANKA infection in a mouse model</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/573DB3D5877</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/573DB3D5877</guid><description>
	Successful recovery from malaria involves striking a balance between counteracting cytokines. The cytokine imbalance contributes to pathological features, but their exact levels have not been elucidated. This study aimed at investigating the role played by circulating cytokines in pathophysiology of cerebral malaria using experimental cerebral malaria (ECM) model by profiling four serum cyto...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sharing information and internet resources of immunological interest</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/8E2F7A95893</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/8E2F7A95893</guid><description>
	Human genome project produce vast quantities of data with new sequences being added to Deoxy ribonucleic acid (DNA) databases on an average of once a minute. It is expected that over 1,000 genome will be sequenced within the next 5 to 10 years. Internet access has turned into an important part of any biological study. The extensive range of information available on the internet can save indi...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Allergen-specific immunoglobulin E (IgE) antibodies and skin test reactivity in patients with asthma in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/5B9AF2E5806</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/5B9AF2E5806</guid><description>
	Studies have shown that allergens are important sensitizing agents in asthma, but the study on prevalence of allergy markers in Nigerian asthmatic patients is scarce. Also, no study on serum concentration of allergen specific immunoglobulin E (IgE) in Nigerian was encountered. This study was therefore designed to investigate this dearth of knowledge. Serum samples of eighty adult asthmatic p...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The antibiogram and role of antibody in prophylaxis of albino rats against diarrhoea caused by Escherichia coli O157:H7</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/F85AF275834</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/F85AF275834</guid><description>
	The antibiogram and role of antibody in prophylaxis toEscherichia coliO157:H7 infection in albino rats was investigated in this study. 500 stool samples were collected from apparently healthy individuals, out of which 80 were positive for the organism. The sensitivity patterns of the isolate to conventional antibiotics were investigated. Moreover, the role of antibodies to actively or passiv...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determination of effective praziquantel dose in different mouse strains: BALB/c and Swiss mice in treatment of Schistosoma mansoni</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/F630DB55748</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCIIR/article-abstract/F630DB55748</guid><description>
	Schistosomiasis is a parasitic disease, second to malaria, affecting humans tropics and sub-tropics. The disease condition varies in severity depending on parasite species and strain, organ system infected, geographical region, genetic constitution of the individual and nutritional status. The drug praziquantel has been the choice of drug for the treatment of schistosomisias; however, the ef...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>