<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Clinical Medicine and Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Clinical Medicine and Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Choice of contraceptives and determinants influencing utilization among women: The case of Muk-Lami town, western Wollega zone of Oromia Regional State, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/A1ED5CC61669</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/A1ED5CC61669</guid><description>
	This study was conducted in Muk-Lami town located at 498 km from Addis Ababa and 54 km far from the Western Wollega zonal city, Ghimbi. The study was concerned with reproductive health and contraception where females in the study area have less exposure to contraceptives, choice and proper utilization of methods. This study attempted to investigate major determinants of contraceptive choice,...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Knowledge, attitudes and perceived barriers to post-operative pain management: Institution based cross sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/8B8F4C665945</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/8B8F4C665945</guid><description>
	Post-operative pain is a common problem after surgical procedure. Undertreated and uncontrolled post-operative pain reduce physical and social performance, impaired quality of life and patient dissatisfaction, delayed discharge, increased use of health care resources and high cost on their hospital stay. Even if the problem is vast, researches on the area lack adequate data. This study aimed...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Predictors of postoperative sore throat among surgical patients at Ethiopian teaching hospitals</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/43EF71461830</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/43EF71461830</guid><description>
	Post-operative sore throat significantly impact patients satisfaction during post-operative period. Many factors can contribute to postoperative sore throat and the incidence varies with the method of airway management. To determine the predictors and incidence of postoperative sore throat. In this facility based cross sectional study, 245 elective gynecologic and general surgical patients w...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Decrease in expression of some proteins among breast cancer patients in Sudan comparison to healthy tissues
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/6F28C2D54712</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/6F28C2D54712</guid><description>
	Breast cancer is one of the most common cancers in women, and rated the second most common cancer and a significant cause of death in females in the Sudan. This study aims to identify tumor protein that elicits humoral immune responses in breast cancer patient in comparison to tissues from healthy individuals as well as from normal tissues of the cancer patient. Serum samples and breast canc...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Treatment of recurrent refractory mantle cell lymphoma by thalidomide in combination with interferon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/AA29A7453113</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/AA29A7453113</guid><description>
	Mantle cell lymphoma (MCL) is a highly aggressive non-Hodgkins lymphoma with poor prognosis. This study aims to explore a new, safe approach for patients with recurrent refractory MCL. A total of six patients with recurrent refractory MCL were recruited. They all accepted thalidomide tablets (100 mg/day) orally every night, accompanied with interferon -2b (3 million units, injected subcutane...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mental health problems of street children in residential care in Zambia: Special focus on prediction of psychiatric conditions in street children</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/A2834DE51456</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/A2834DE51456</guid><description>
	This study aims to find out mental health problems and examine their role in prediction of psychiatric conditions in street children in residential care. Five (5) street children residential centres in Lusaka District, as well as a cross-section of street children (74) in residential care aged between 7 and 17 years were used for this study. Overall, 74 (68 males and 6 females) children in r...</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Vaginal colonization and resistance profile of group B Streptococcus among pregnant women in Yaound&#xE9; Gynecology, Obstetric and Pediatric Hospital in Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/8DE509248691</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/8DE509248691</guid><description>
	In order to obtain reliable data on vaginal carriage of Streptococcus agalactiae in pregnant women and to formulate a prevention program of neonatal Group B Streptococcus (GBS) disease, we carried out a prospective cross sectional study for 6 months. The general objective of the study was to evaluate the prevalence of vaginal carriage and the resistance profile of GBS. The study involved 142...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Using of hemofiltercytological blood test to monitor the quality of patients radically operated on for colorectal cancer adjuvant chemotherapy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/1E95FC745450</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/1E95FC745450</guid><description>
	Application of hemofiltercytological analysis shows its ample opportunities in assessment of polychemotherapy completeness and quality through the study of drug pathomorphosis. The objective of the study was development and studying of the clinical relevance of hemofiltercytological venous blood test as completeness and quality control of patients with colorectal cancer adjuvant chemotherapy...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Epistaxis in Kaduna, Nigeria: A review of 101 cases in a resource constrained setting</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/FEA93A342475</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/FEA93A342475</guid><description>
	Epistaxis is defined as hemorrhage from the nostril, nasal cavity, or nasopharynx. Sufferers and clinicians may develop significant anxiety despite the fact that majority of patients may be treated successfully by the first attending physician. The objective of this study was to review the incidence, common etiological factors and management modalities of epistaxis in a resource constrained ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative in vitro potency of four fluoroquinolones on clinical isolates over a year period</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/B20022042476</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCMR/article-abstract/B20022042476</guid><description>
	This study aimed at evaluating the efficacy of four common fluoroquinolone drugs over a year period on some clinical isolates. It also aimed at comparing statistically the average effects of each drug on the isolates. Five different clinical samples (urine, sputum, wound, blood and high vaginal swab [HVS]) from patients attending a university medical centre (between June 2011 and May 2012) w...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>