<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Cereals and Oilseeds - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Cereals and Oilseeds</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Effect of germination on structural and physicochemical properties of starch in glutinous brown rice</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/A25CDC863889</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/A25CDC863889</guid><description>
	This study compared the structural and rheological properties of native (GB0), 12 h (GB12), 24 h (GB24), 36 h (GB36), 48 h (GB48) and 72 h (GB72) germinated glutinous brown rice starch to improve the market value of glutinous rice through germination. The proportion of A chains (DP 6-12) increases and the proportion of B1 chains (DP 13-24) decreased with germination time. Interestingly, we o...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Growth and yield response of two groundnut cultivars to row pattern in the forest-Savannah Transition Zone of Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/D6ECFE063231</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/D6ECFE063231</guid><description>
	Two field trials (2017 and 2018) were conducted at the research field of the University of Education, Winneba, Mampong Campus from May to August to determine the growth and yield response of groundnut to row pattern. The experimental design was a 2 x 4 factorial arranged in a randomized complete block design (RCBD) with three replications. The factors studied included: (A) Cultivar [(i) Yeny...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Yield evaluation and character association of linseed (Linum usitatissimum L.) genotypes in moisture stress areas of South Tigray, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/5469C9363302</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/5469C9363302</guid><description>
	Linseed (Linum usitatissimum L.) is one of the most important highland oil crops of southern Tigray, Ethiopia and it is considered as the least expensive source for oil related home consumptions. The 12 genotypes of linseed including two standard checks were evaluated in the highland and moisture stress area of Southern Tigray under rain fed condition with the objective of evaluating yield a...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of Alternaria sp on seed germination in rapeseed, and its control with seed treatment

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/583020C62978</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/583020C62978</guid><description>
	The role of Alternaria sp on seed vigor of rapeseed, Brassica napus, was investigated. Seed samples were collected from rapeseed growing regions of Sindh province. The samples were processed for fungal recovery using blotter paper and agar plate methods. Both methods produced a number of parasitic and saprophytic fungi. Among the recovered fungi, Alternaria sp was predominant with 16% averag...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of NPSZnB fertilizer levels on yield and yield component of maize (Zea mays L.) at Laelay Adiyabo and Medebay Zana districts, Western Tigray, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/120132A62366</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/120132A62366</guid><description>
	The use of right amount of fertilizer based on crop requirement has a significant importance for sustainable crop production. Study was undertaken to investigate the effects of NPSZnB blended fertilizer for maize yield production at Laelay Adiyabo and Medebay Zana districts. Seven treatments were used for the field experiment. Treatments were without fertilizer, blanket recommended NP (64 kg...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Technological application of the butter of Pentadesma butyracea: A comparative evaluation of its cosmetic behaviour with Vitellaria paradoxa butter</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/68B066262142</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/68B066262142</guid><description>
	Pentadesma butyracea butter is a vegetable fat obtained from the kernels of the P. butyracea tree. It is a potential source of fat for the food and cosmetics sectors. This study evaluated the quality characteristics of the cream and soap processed from the butter of P. butyracea in comparison to similar product from the Vitellaria paradoxa butter. The same cosmetic products were produced wit...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of seed oil yield and characteristics of ten castor plant (Ricinus communis L.) Accessions in Ogbomoso, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/6E98F0F61867</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/6E98F0F61867</guid><description>
	Experiment was conducted to assess the seed oil yield and physical and chemical characteristics of ten castor plant accessions. The experiment was laid out in a Randomized Complete Block Design replicated three times. At maturity, the racemes were harvested and seeds were extracted. One hundred gram of seed was taken from each accession for oil extraction. The extracted oils were analysed fo...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of diallel crosses of maize at multilocation (Zea mays L.) for saline tolerance</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/F71C47261942</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/F71C47261942</guid><description>
	A diallel cross was produced using diverse maize (Zea mays L.) germplasm of saline tolerant and saline susceptible maize lines as parents. Agronomic performance of the offspring of the diallel cross was examined. Eight germplasm lines bearing diversified agronomic traits of five known tolerant and susceptible lines were involved as parents of the diallel cross that was evaluated at three dif...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Biomass accumulation and yield expression among winged bean (Psophocarpus tetragonolobus L. DC) accessions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/2E2A81461625</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/2E2A81461625</guid><description>
	Winged bean accessions were screened to evaluate biomass yield potential. The experiments, carried out during 2015 and 2016 to test nineteen accessions were laid out in Randomized Complete Block Design and replicated three times. Data collected on number of days to 50% flowering (DTF), number of days to 50% pod (DTP), total number of pods (TNP) per plant fresh (FSW) and dry shoot weight (DSW...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Moisture requirement and water productivity of selected rainfed rice varieties grown under controlled water environment in Ifakara, Tanzania</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/D1B8A9F61191</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCO/article-abstract/D1B8A9F61191</guid><description>
	Moisture availability is a fundamental challenge to rice productivity in the rainfed environment. Most of the rice varieties released for cultivation under rainfed ecosystem in Tanzania are missing out on information about their moisture requirement under different soil moisture regimes. A pot experiment was conducted at Ifakara in a split-plot design. The main plots was assigned to water re...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>