<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Clinical Pathology and Forensic Medicine - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Clinical Pathology and Forensic Medicine</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Isolated posterior inferior cerebellar artery stroke secondary to near-hanging: A case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/ECE884B65369</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/ECE884B65369</guid><description>
	Suicide is the eighth leading cause of death in males, while strangulation injuries account for approximately 2.5% of all traumatic deaths worldwide. Hanging or self-suspension is a form of ligature strangulation where the pressure is produced by the weight of the body itself. It is easily accessible, comparatively painless, almost always suicidal and cheap method of committing suicide. Thes...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Role of mean platelet volume in individuals with type II diabetes mellitus</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/75CF87257512</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/75CF87257512</guid><description>
	Diabetes mellitus (DM) is a global pandemic. Large platelets are highly thrombotic and thus put the patient at a higher risk. Mean platelet volume (MPV) is a determinant of platelet functionality and increased MPV are associated with increased risk for hyperglycemic complications. We aimed to investigate the association of MPV, a marker for platelet size and activity with fasting blood gluco...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalent latent adenocarcinoma of the prostate in forensic autopsies
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/9A315AF53933</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/9A315AF53933</guid><description>
	In the aging society, elder people commonly suffer cancer, which is associated with increased rates of fractures due to osteoporosis from cancer. In the present study, the prevalence of prostatic cancer, so-called latent adenocarcinoma, is investigated among forensic autopsy cases. Retrospective histo-pathology was performed on 114 subjects (61.8  13.3 years old). Forth-four specimens (38.6%...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An autopsy case of Group A Streptococcus meningoencephalitis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/A45D7EB53475</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/A45D7EB53475</guid><description>
	Group A Streptococcus (GAS), which frequently colonizes the oropharynx, causes significant morbidity worldwide due to invasive infections such as pneumonia, necrotizing fasciitis, bacteremia and streptococcal toxic shock syndrome. However, this organism does not usually invade the central nervous system. Here, we report the autopsy of an adult Japanese patient who died from a fulminant infec...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Sudden death due to intracranial colloid cyst: About three cases</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/94B5C0652673</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/94B5C0652673</guid><description>
	The colloid cyst is a rare and benign congenital intracranial tumor, commonly located in the anterior part of the third ventricle. It is a rare cause of sudden death whose mechanisms of occurrence are still been discussed. We report three cases of sudden death due to colloid cyst(s) discovered at autopsy. Death occurred in a man and two women, aged 45, 43 and 33 years, respectively. Pre-mort...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Histological characterization of wound healing of flank verses midline ovariohysterectomy in 
different age groups of cats
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/74FADC043961</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/74FADC043961</guid><description>
	The study was carried out to determine the histological characterizations of wound healing in cats. For the purpose, 24 feral/stray with mean age of 7 to 33 months and body weight between 1.72 to 4.02 kg cats were selected and divided in 4 subgroups. Ovariohysterectomy was performed in all the cats. The cats operated through flank approach healed earlier and histological characterization sho...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Left ventricular non-compaction of myocardium 
in forensic autopsy
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/4A0D90043964</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/4A0D90043964</guid><description>
	Left ventricular non-compaction of the myocardium is a rare cardiac disorder characterized by prominent meshwork formation and deep intertrabecular recesses of the left ventricle. Echocardiography provides clinical diagnosis of the non-compaction region, but it is sometimes difficult to distinguish this disorder from cardiomyopathies of other types. This report describes two autopsy cases of...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Accidental hanging: A report of four cases and review of the literature</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/32A2E7A45342</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/32A2E7A45342</guid><description>
	Accidental hangings have far common characteristics that cause death in unsuspecting victims. It is a rare medico-legal aspect of death, raising difficulties of differential diagnosis with the suicide hanging and even with other causes of death. This study presents four observations of accidental hanging which occurred to three children and an adult, in strange circumstances sometimes. The m...</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Delivery and death on railway track: A case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/6E7EEAF3034</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/6E7EEAF3034</guid><description>
	Injuries and deaths due to accidents are inescapable in the modern way of living. The accidental deaths are mostly due to the road traffic, but the deaths due to railway fatalities are also not negligible, especially in the areas where railway traffic is high. Southern railways are major mode of transportation of the passengers and goods; consequently, the incidences of railway fatalities an...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuronal alterations in the prefrontal cortex of rats with carbon tetrachloride (CCl4) induced hepatic damage</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/486DE1C3075</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCPFM/article-abstract/486DE1C3075</guid><description>
	In cirrhosis, some toxic substances accumulate in the brain and modify its functional integrity. In this study, we investigate the impacts of liver damage on the neuronal profile of the prefrontal cortex (PFC) in a rat model of hepatic damage induced with carbon tetrachloride (CCl4). This study also evaluated the possible role of liver dysfunction in the etiology of neurodegenerative charact...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>