<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Cancer Research and Experimental Oncology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Cancer Research and Experimental Oncology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Prevalence of cervical intraepithelial neoplasia and its associated factors among women attending healthcare services in Eastern Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/4F13EA163589</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/4F13EA163589</guid><description>
	Cervical malignancy is still the leading cause of death for middle-aged women in the developing world. In Uganda, literature has shown that, cervical cancer incidence and death rates was 45.6 and 25 per 100,000 women respectively. However, the actual magnitude of cervical malignancy in Uganda might be higher since most of the cases are never reported. This study assessed the prevalence of ce...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Head and neck lipomas: A clinicopathologic analysis of 36 cases</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/419434062262</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/419434062262</guid><description>
	Lipomas are common benign soft tissue tumors, with 15 to 20% of the cases affecting the head and neck region and 1 to 4% involving the oral cavity. The literature has many reported cases of head and neck lipoma but few comprehensive studies hence, the aim of this study was to review and analyze the clinical and histopathologic features of head and neck lipomas in Nigerians. A fifteen-year re...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Human natural killer (NK) cell activation by luteolin from Brucea javanica leaves</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/B3D352E59611</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/B3D352E59611</guid><description>
	There is growing interest in using natural substances from plants to potentially enhance anticancer activity. A key target in this respect is natural killer (NK) cells in order to generate an anticancer-immune response. Luteolin used in this study was derived from a local plant Brucea javanica leaves extract; through a bioassay-guided fractionation. The expression of interleukin-2 (IL-2) and...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The influence of life behaviour, diet, physical activities on the incidence of breast cancer among women attending Obafemi Awolowo University Teaching Hospital Complex, Ile-Ife</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/691CDAE55691</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/691CDAE55691</guid><description>
	The aetiopathogenesis of cancer has been linked to life behaviour in a significant percentage of cases. Overweight, sedentary lifestyle, smoking and the excessive use of alcohol have been shown to play important roles. This study is aimed at determining the effect of life behavioural patterns and diets in the incidence of breast cancer in Nigerians population. A prospective case-controlled s...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Detection of cervical human papillomavirus in women attending for cervical cancer screening by visual inspection in C&#xF4;te d' Ivoire</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/B88EAB266595</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/B88EAB266595</guid><description>
	Human papillomaviruses (HPV) cause precancerous lesions and cancers of the cervix. In Cte dIvoire, cervical cancer screening program based on visual inspection is the gold standard. This study aimed to detect high risk (HR) HPV DNA on women attending cervical cancer screening program based on visual inspection after application of acid acetic and Lugol. From March to December 2015, cervical ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Retrospective study on gastrointestinal tract tumors in humans in Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/AB0BAA364455</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/AB0BAA364455</guid><description>
	A retrospective study of gastrointestinal tract (GIT) tumors of humans in Zaria was carried out to determine the prevalence rates. Of the 124 human cases recorded in Ahmadu Bello University Teaching Hospital (ABUTH) Zaria, 39 (31.45%) had upper GIT tumors while 42 (33.87%) had tumors located in the lower GIT. All age groups were affected. The risk for developing tumors increased with age in ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mean platelet volume and mean platelet volume/platelet count ratio as markers for hepatocellular carcinoma in patients with chronic hepatitis C virus related cirrhosis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/45A6D2360297</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/45A6D2360297</guid><description>
	Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) is the most common primary malignant tumor of the liver. The lack of efficient and precise HCC biomarkers prevents early detection resulting in a poor prognosis. Recently, mean platelet volume (MPV) and MPV/platelet count (PC) ratio have been proposed as potential markers of HCC. This study was carried out to verify MPV and MPV/PC ratio in diagnosis of HCC in E...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of unilateral arm lymphedema among breast cancer patients one year after completing treatment at Cancer Diseases Hospital in Lusaka</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/AD8630160299</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/AD8630160299</guid><description>
	Lymphedema of the arm and/or hand is a long-term complication of breast cancer treatment. Accurate estimates of the incidence and prevalence of lymphedema are lacking, as are the effects of this condition on overall quality of life. The objective of this study was to determine the prevalence of unilateral arm lymphedema among breast cancer patients one year after completion of treatment at C...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Health related quality of life among breast cancer patients with unilateral arm lymphedema at cancer diseases hospital in Lusaka, Zambia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/7F63AAF59773</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/7F63AAF59773</guid><description>
	This study aims to determine health-related quality of life (HRQOL) of breast cancer patients with unilateral arm lymphedema one year after completion of treatment at Cancer Diseases Hospital. The study design comprises of a cross sectional study, where we assessed the HRQoL controlling for patient demographics, cancer stages and treatment types. Short form of 36 interview schedule was used ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunotherapy against cancer: A comprehensive review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/9EECDCA59698</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JCREO/article-abstract/9EECDCA59698</guid><description>
	The endeavor of this paper was to review cancer immunotherapy which means the modulating and using of the patients own immune system to target the cancer cells rather than using an extrinsic means of therapy. The best way to prevent and remove infections is through the natural sterilising action of the immune response that combines elements of both innate and adaptive immunity to ward off fo...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>