<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Development and Agricultural Economics - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Development and Agricultural Economics</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Analysis of economic efficiency among smallholder sorghum producers in Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/6B83ABB63823</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/6B83ABB63823</guid><description>
	This study used Cobb-Douglas Stochastic Profit Frontier to analyze economic efficiency of sorghum farmers in Tharaka Nithi County, Kenya. Using a multi-stage stratified sample of 259 farmers, results depicted a wide range of profit efficiency between the best (0.96) and the worst (0.12) farmer with a mean of 0.17. The actual and potential profit was USD 164.88 ha-1 and USD 969.87 ha-1 respec...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Technical efficiency of rice farmers in Anambra State value chain development programme</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/2A28CFF63551</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/2A28CFF63551</guid><description>
	The study is aimed at determining the technical efficiency of rice farmers in Anambra State value chain development programme. A well-structured questionnaire was administered to elicit information from 372 rice farmers from the five participating Local Government Areas (Ayamelum, Awka North, Anambra West, Anambra East, and Orumba North) after which only 337 respondents were fit for the stud...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Performance analysis of Nigerian agricultural credit guarantee scheme: Bounds test approach to cointegration</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/C03BCBB63605</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/C03BCBB63605</guid><description>
	This study examined the performance of the Agricultural Credit Guarantee Scheme (ACGS) which is the major credit policy of the Federal Government of Nigeria. It was established in 1977 but started operation in 1978. Time series data from 1978-2014, extracted from the 2014 bulletin of the National Bureau Statistics were used for the study. Total volume and number of loans given were used to p...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Integration of post-harvest management in agricultural policy and strategies to minimise post harvest losses  in Lesotho</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/26F482663727</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/26F482663727</guid><description>
	Despite global efforts to increase food availability and curb high incidence of malnutrition in Africa, there are concerns with regard to high post-harvest losses in Africa. Lesotho like most countries in sub-Saharan Africa faces documented challenges with food insecurity and nutrition. Food availability could be increased by reduction of post-harvest losses without further exploitation of r...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Slash-and-burn agriculture, the major cropping system in the region of Faradje in Democratic Republic of Congo: Ecological and socio-economic consequences</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/60E4B5663298</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/60E4B5663298</guid><description>
	The present study aims to explore smallholders household living standard relevant to slash-and-burn agriculture, and determine trend of key crops grown with respect to their production and related generated average gross income in the region of Faradje, in the far northeastern region of the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC). Surveys were conducted on agronomic and social economic characteri...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spatial price transmission between white maize grain markets in Mozambique and Malawi</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/BCA4AE463300</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/BCA4AE463300</guid><description>
	The objective of this study was to measure white maize grain price transmission among markets in Mozambique and Malawi. Our analysis included two major deficit markets (Maputo in Southern Mozambique and Blantyre in Southern Malawi) and two major surplus markets (Chimoio in Central Mozambique and Nampula in Northern Mozambique). We used monthly wholesale white maize grain prices covering the ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing the likelihood of adoption of orange-flesh sweet potato genotypes in Sierra Leone</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/585585763325</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/585585763325</guid><description>
	The adoption of research outputs to bring the desired impacts is a major factor of any research work. Based on this premise, adoption likelihood analysis was used to determine the maximum likelihood of adoption of orange flesh sweet potato (OFSP) in Sierra Leone. The study was conducted in Western Area, Moyamba, Bo, Kenema and Bombali districts. A multi-stage sampling procedure was employed ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of technical efficiency of edible oil production: The case of canola production in 
Kieni West Constituency, Kenya
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/279CD7F63327</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/279CD7F63327</guid><description>
	Globally, the vegetable oil demand is growing due to rising food consumption in emerging countries such as China and due to the high demand for biofuels. The current world vegetable production estimates stand at 187 million tons for the year 2016/2017. Of the estimated vegetable oil production, 70.3 million tons (37.6%) comes from palm and palm kernel, 55 million tons (30%) arise from soybea...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determinants of recommended agronomic practices adoption among wheat producing smallholder farmers in Sekela District of West Gojjam Zone, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/E1916A663096</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/E1916A663096</guid><description>
	Development of the Ethiopian economy is directly related to the transformation of the agricultural sector which is manifested with low utilization of recommended agronomic practices, improved farm inputs, and dependency on traditional farming and rainfall. As a result, low production and productivity of agriculture were prevalent over the last years. This study aims to identify the factors i...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Measuring rural poverty among rural households in Gedeo Zone, SNNP Region, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/B01D84862873</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDAE/article-abstract/B01D84862873</guid><description>
	Poverty is a phenomenon that is complex and has multidimensional features. It involves people experiencing various degrees of material deprivation; the concept is used to cover a wide ranging set of interrelated life chances. The purpose of this study was to measure poverty in rural Gedeo zone, southern Ethiopia with specific objectives of measuring poverty among the rural households. The re...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>