<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Developmental Biology and Tissue Engineering - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Developmental Biology and Tissue Engineering</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Micropropagation of wild fennel (Foeniculum vulgare var. vulgare) via organogenesis and somatic embryogenesis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/06126C552166</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/06126C552166</guid><description>
	Wild fennel (Foeniculum vulgare var. Vulgare) is a perennial aromatic herb. It is native to the Mediterranean region and currently it iscultivated as an annual or perennial herb worldwide. Dried ripe fruits are commonly used plants part for obtaining essential oil. Fruits oil of wild fennel contains many volatile oils, such as -pinene, phellandrene, p-cymene, fenchone, estragole, anethole an...</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A study on the formation and development of Panax bipinnatifidus Seem. adventitious root</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/4F434B746465</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/4F434B746465</guid><description>
	This study aimed to generate adventitious roots from root and stem-derived callus of Panax bipinnatifidus Seem. Callus formation was observed best (83.3%) in MS media supplemented with 3.0 mg/L 2,4-dichlorophenoxyacetic acid (2,4-D) and 0.1 mg/L indolebutyric acid (IBA). Callus generated adventitious roots in MS media supplemented with 2.0 mg/L IBA at high frequency (66.7%). The optimal cult...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Morphology and histology of the alimentary tract of adult palm weevil, Rhynchophorus phoenicis Fabricius (Coleoptera: Curculionidae)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/FB18E4B10608</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/FB18E4B10608</guid><description>
	Palm weevil (Rhynchophorus phoenicis)is a notorious pest of oil palm trees, worldwide. Investigations were conducted on the alimentary tract of the adult insect. Results of the morphology and histology of the alimentary tract revealed that the alimentary tract consisted of a foregut, which was made up of a buccal cavity, oesophagus, crop and proventriculus. The crop big or small and the prov...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Markers are shared between adipogenic and osteogenic differentiated mesenchymal stem cells</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/B8A57C010632</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/B8A57C010632</guid><description>
	The stem cell differentiation paradigm is based on the progression of cells through generations of daughter cells that eventually become restricted and committed to one lineage resulting in fully differentiated cells. Herein, we report on the differentiation of adult human mesenchymal stem cells (hMSCs) towards adipogenic and osteogenic lineages using established protocols. Lineage specific ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Future of dentistry, nanodentistry, ozone therapy and tissue engineering</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/955BFF140376</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/955BFF140376</guid><description>
	Future of dentistry has become one of the most unique resources and providers of this oral systemic approach. In determining the patients unique needs, it is becoming increasingly important for the dentist to work with other cutting-edge, integrative practitioners to fully assess the individual requirements of the patient before, during, and after dental care. Witnessing the beginning of tru...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>3-D osteoblast culture for biomaterials testing</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/B82C1FA40378</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/B82C1FA40378</guid><description>
	Micromass cell cultures, osteomicrospheres, were formed by aggregation of primary osteoblasts. Cell differentiation during sphere formation and the integrity of the osteomicrospheres was evaluated by analyzing the immunohistochemical expression of osteonectin, osteocalcin, and collagen type I. Transmission electron microscopy facilitated the proof of the tissue-like microstructure inside the...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Round-bottomed Honeycomb Microwells: Embryoid body shape correlates with stem cell fate</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/B40B1AE40395</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/B40B1AE40395</guid><description>
	The differentiation of embryonic stem cells (ESC) into tissue-specific cells utilizes either monolayer cultures or three-dimensional cell aggregates called embryoid bodies (EB). However, the generation of a large number of EB of controlled sizes can be challenging and labor intensive. Our laboratories have developed a simple, robust, ultra-rapid, and inexpensive design of Honeycomb Microwell...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Study of cephalometric parameters among 4 to 11 years old Persian girls resident in Iran</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/4043DBB40397</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/4043DBB40397</guid><description>
	Anthropometry is applied in medical profession such as maxillofacial surgery, growth and development studies, plastic surgery, bioengineering and non-medical branches such as like shoe-making and eye-glasses industries. The aim of the present study was to determine facial and cranial parameters among 4 to 11 years old Mashhadian young girls in order to assess growth pattern in this age range...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mimicry of a natural, living intra-epidermal micro pattern used in guided tissue regeneration of the human epidermis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/F39AA3310572</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/F39AA3310572</guid><description>
	The methodology for the isolation of the living, intra-epidermal micro pattern using a tissue culture method is described. The disassembly of the stripped off epidermis (after Dispase digestion at 37C) into epidermal brown rosettes (their morphology under a phase contrast microscope) constitute intra-epidermal micro patterns. The stepwise reasoning in the recognition of epidermal basal layer...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An investigation on cephalometric parameters in Iranian population</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/105696910578</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDBTE/article-abstract/105696910578</guid><description>
	Anthropometry is the biological science of human body measurement. Anthropometry is applied in medical profession such as maxillofacial surgery, growth and development studies, plastic surgery, bioengineering and non-medical branches such as like shoe-making and eye-glasses industries. The aim of this study was to determine Iranian cephalometric parameters and cranial and facial anthropometr...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>