<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Diabetes and Endocrinology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Diabetes and Endocrinology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Usefulness of urinary fibronectin and laminin as biomarkers of glomerular injury in diabetics in Port Harcourt, Nigeria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/D28DEAE63546</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/D28DEAE63546</guid><description>
	About one-third of diabetes mellitus (DM) patients are complicated by diabetic nephropathy. It is even more challenging in type 2 DM in which this complication may occur before presentation. Microalbuminuria which is the traditional marker of early diabetic nephropathy is limited in its usefulness because it is detected when significant renal damage has already occurred. The aim of this stud...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antidiabetic properties of Moringa oleifera: A review of the literature</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/FF8279F63501</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/FF8279F63501</guid><description>
	The incidence of diabetes has been growing over the years with serious and costly consequences, both in terms of human and economic capital, particularly in low- and middle-income countries. Medicinal plants could be usefully included in the treatment of diabetes in an optimized strategy for better cost-effectiveness, given the high cost of pharmaceuticals and their side effects on patients....</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-adherence to selected self-care actions and its determinants among adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus in a tertiary hospital in Enugu State Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/3F6116662867</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/3F6116662867</guid><description>
	The study determined the prevalence of non-adherence to medication, self monitoring of blood glucose (SMBG), clinic visits and the associated factors among out-patient type 2 adult diabetics at a tertiary hospital in Enugu State Nigeria. Using a descriptive cross-sectional design, 200 patients was purposively selected. Researcher-developed questionnaire was tool for data collection. Analysis...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of dyslipidemia and its correlation with anthropometric and blood pressure variables among type-2 diabetic patients</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/5667F5462984</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/5667F5462984</guid><description>
	Co-morbidity of hypertension and dyslipidemia are found to be high in type-2 diabetes mellitus (DM) patients particularly with poor glycemic control. This study was aimed to assess the prevalence of dyslipidemia and its correlations with anthropometric and blood pressure variables among type-2 DM patients. The study was conducted on 314 type-2 DM patients at Hawassa University Comprehensive ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of the combination of Cnidoscolus aconitifolius and Metformin on the glycemia in streptozotocin-induced diabetes rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/C74734D62403</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/C74734D62403</guid><description>
	Currently, diabetes mellitus type two is a public health challenge worldwide. Even though there are many oral hypoglycemic agents, a large part of the population continues to use herbal remedies with proven benefits. However, there are few works aimed at evaluating combinations of drugs and herbal remedies. These combinations of drugs and herbal substances can lead to a decrease in the thera...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The effect of aqueous leaf extract of Adansonia digitata (baobab) on diabetes mellitus and the anterior pituitary of adult male wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/A593E2261386</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/A593E2261386</guid><description>
	This study was carried out to evaluate the anti-diabetic properties of aqueous leaf extract of Adansonia digitata leaf (ALEAD) on blood glucose level. 36 of the rats were randomly distributed into 9. Group one served as the normal control and Group 2 rats were administered with alloxan (150 mg/kg) intraperitoneally. Groups 3, 4, and 5 were orally administered with alloxan (150 mg/kg) intrape...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antidiabetic effect of aqueous extract of ripe Carica  papaya Linnaeus seed  in alloxan-induced diabetic albino rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/FAC3E8360154</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/FAC3E8360154</guid><description>
	This research was carried out to evaluate the antidiabetic effect of aqueous extract of ripe Carica papaya L. seed in alloxan-induced diabetic albino rats. Diabetes is a metabolic disease associated with sustained hyperglycaemia. Diabetes has become a global threat because its incidence is increasing on daily basis. Pathogenesis of diabetes mellitus and the possibility of its management by t...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Knowledge regarding diabetic complications among diabetic clients attending outpatient department in a tertiary hospital, Kathmandu</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/952038759933</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/952038759933</guid><description>
	Diabetes, a known medical problem for more than two millennia, provokes complication in many parts of body and increase risk of premature death. Prevalence of diabetes is steadily increasing everywhere, most markedly in the worlds low and middle- income countries. Diabetes Mellitus (DM) is a devastating disease but complications of Diabetes Mellitus can be prevented or delayed through proper...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antihyperglycaemic effect of aqueous extract of Moringa oleifera leaf on alloxan-induced diabetic male Wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/9A391EA59944</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/9A391EA59944</guid><description>
	This research was designed to investigate antihyperglycaemic impact of aqueous extract of Moringa oleifera leaf on alloxan-induced diabetic male wistar rats. Diabetes is a metabolic disease linked to weakened sugar metabolism. Managing diabetes devoid of any adverse effect remains an issue to health system. Therefore, there is an increase in the search for better anti-diabetic medicine. M. o...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antidiabetic and anti- hyperlipidemic effects of ethanolic extract of Dryopteris dilatata leaves</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/8A95D2458649</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDE/article-abstract/8A95D2458649</guid><description>
	The incidence of diabetes mellitus (DM) is increasing globally and it is a major source of concern. This study was undertaken to assess the antidiabetic effect of the ethanolic leaf extract of Dryopteris dilatata (ELEDD).Thirty adult Wistar rats with body weight (BW) of 120-150 g were randomly assigned to groups of five rats each (n=5). Groups 1 served as normal control; Groups 2-6 were diab...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>