<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Dentistry and Oral Hygiene  - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Dentistry and Oral Hygiene </description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Traumatic dental injuries among a selected population of adolescents in Southern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/DA9279563415</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/DA9279563415</guid><description>
	This work aims to determine the causes, scene and types of traumatic dental injuries (TDIs) among adolescents, and to compare the findings in males with those in females. Information was elicited from a selected population of junior secondary school students by means of a close-ended, structured, self-administered questionnaire. Information elicited included age, gender, previous experience ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A retrospective analysis of a large case series investigating a novel non-incisional periodontal therapy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/A5425CE62749</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/A5425CE62749</guid><description>
	Chronic periodontitis is a prevalent condition, affecting nearly half of the adult US population aged 30 years or older. When left untreated, the condition can lead to debilitating tooth loss. While there are well established therapies for all degrees of disease, many are expensive and out of reach to those who lack access to care for medical, socio-economic, or geographic reasons. Scaling a...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Miswak: The underutilized device and future challenges</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/A12105162146</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/A12105162146</guid><description>
	There have been many studies on the practice of maintaining dental health. Although most people currently use a toothbrush to maintain the cleanliness of mouth, specific populations still used miswak as an alternative tool for oral health care. This study was designed to answer the future challenges of use of miswak as a tool to maintain oral health according to modern sciences. The history,...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Interdisciplinary treatment approaches for cleft lip and palate patients to obtain esthetic and functional results</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/9451D2360763</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/9451D2360763</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to present the importance of interdisciplinary treatment approaches for the patients with clefts. In this study, the treatment of four patients with cleft lip and palate were presented. After the completion of fixed orthodontic treatment, proper overjet and overbite relationships were achieved and to obtain the esthetic and functional results, two of the patients had...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The importance of pH, salivary flow and different dental caries risk factors in pregnant women</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/59291A859663</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/59291A859663</guid><description>
	During pregnancy, there are certain changes in a womans body that can affect or alter oral health. Likewise, in this period some changes in factors such as pH and salivary flow can contribute to an increased risk of caries in pregnant women; therefore, this research was conducted on 85 women from the city of Montemorelos who attended Montemorelos General Hospital, of whom 53 were pregnant an...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative evaluation of short and long term in vitro antibacterial activity of white and gray mineral trioxide aggregate and calcium enriched mixture cement"</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/DD62C4558081</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/DD62C4558081</guid><description>
	The aim of this study was to investigate and compare the short and long term antibacterial effects of white and gray mineral trioxide aggregate (MTA) and calcium enriched mixture (CEM) on Streptococcus Sanguinis and Enterococcus faecalis which are commonly associated with endodontic infections. The test materials, including white MTA (WMTA), gray (GMTA), and CEM were manipulated strictly in ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>In vitro antimicrobial activity of CatDex against Porphyromonas endodontalis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/E5636B058290</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/E5636B058290</guid><description>
	An achievable goal in root canal therapy is to reduce the bacterial population to the lowest level. Irrigation and instrumentation play an important role in achieving this objective. Sodium hypochlorite (NaClO) is the most frequently used irrigation solution; however, its main disadvantage that it is cytoxic to soft tissues following inadvertent extrusion. CatDex is a substance that promises...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of the soft tissue chins thickness with different skeletal vertical patterns in Pakistani adults</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/B27E63057628</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/B27E63057628</guid><description>
	The aim of the study is to evaluate and compare the soft tissue chin thickness values among adult patients with different vertical growth patterns. A sample size of 180 adults patients (32 males and 148 females), with an average age of 21.42 years (range 17- 32 years), was selected. The sample was divided into three groups according to the vertical growth pattern using SNMP angle (hypodiverg...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Oral hygiene practice of adult diabetic patients and their awareness about oral health problems related to diabetes</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/690084763721</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/690084763721</guid><description>
	Diabetes mellitus is a major public health problem in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. Several studies have shown that diabetic patients are at a greater risk of developing oral health problems than non-diabetics. This study aims to evaluate the oral hygiene practices of adult diabetic patients and their awareness of oral health problems related to the disease. In this cross-sectional, Internet-...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of obesity among preschool children and its relation with dental caries</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/D8CF00F62733</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JDOH/article-abstract/D8CF00F62733</guid><description>
	There is increasing interest in investigating the association between dental caries and childhood obesity, particularly among preschoolers where the evidence is limited. We aimed to measure the prevalence of obesity/overweight among preschool children aged 3 to 6 years, and to determine the relationship between obesity and dental caries in the primary dentition. A cross-sectional study was c...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>