<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Evolutionary Biology Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Evolutionary Biology Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>The genome of a landlocked Atlantic salmon Salmo salar characterized through high-throughput sequencing</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/241F47261238</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/241F47261238</guid><description>
	A wide range of life-history tactics can be found within salmonid fish. The genetic basis for these adaptations remains largely unknown, but we have sought to investigate any large scale genetic changes associated with a non-anadromous life cycle. After the most recent ice age (approximately 9,500 years ago), some populations of Atlantic salmon Salmo salar L., were trapped in fresh water and...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Improvement in cocoon yield induced by phytojuvenoid on the multivoltine mulberry silkworm (Bombyx mori Linn.)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/C33127849694</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/C33127849694</guid><description>
	Impact of phytojuvenoid on commercial parameters in Bombyx mori, a monophagous insect, was studied. The variation in the phytojuvenoid concentration significantly influenced the length of cocoon and the number of larval treatment did not cause significant influence on the length of cocoon of B. mori. The length of cocoon increased from 2.88 cm (control) to the maximum level of 3.65 cm in 30%...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Somatic embryogenesis in two Nigerian cassava cultivars (Sandpaper and TMS 60444)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/93CA06048098</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/93CA06048098</guid><description>
	The embryogenic ability of two cassava cultivars (Sandpaper and TMS 60444) was investigated by culturing their young leaf lobes on an induction medium (DKW2 50P). The explants formed organized embryogenic structures regardless of the concentration of picloram in the medium. Organized embryogenic structures induction was enhanced by increasing the concentration of picloram in the induction me...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Insect visitation of peduncular and petiolar extrafloral nectar glands on castor bean (Ricinus communis L.) plants in Southern California</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/4658D2D45680</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/4658D2D45680</guid><description>
	Castor bean (Ricinus communis L.) is a myrmecophytic plant species with specialized extrafloral nectar (EFN) glands that serve to attract predatory insects, which in return defend plant-tissues against herbivores. The EFN glands on castor bean plants are located along the leaf petioles as well as on the peduncles of its imperfect (unisexual) flowers. This field-project evaluates the richness...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxonomic survey of crustacean zooplankton in Wular Lake of Kashmir Himalaya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/9E451C944944</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/9E451C944944</guid><description>
	Taxonomic survey of the crustacean community was conducted at five study sites in Wular Lake. Plankton samples were collected on monthly basis from September 2010 to August 2011 and identified in the laboratory under different magnifications using the Olympus microscope. Of the 42 taxa identified, 23 were Cladocera, 16 were Copepoda and only three were Ostracoda. Among the Copepoda, one taxa...</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Protective effects of vitamin C against biochemical toxicity induced by malathion pesticides in male albino rat</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/D5D0F6A4559</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/D5D0F6A4559</guid><description>
	Malathion is a chemical pesticide, commonly used by Egyptian farmers; however, its contamination of water sources has become an important issue. It is suggested that the role of vitamin C in alteration of enzymes responsible for energy metabolism was induced by administration of Malathion. The effect of malathion and malathion with vitamin C on some enzymes in the rat were recorded in the pr...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Biosystematic relationships of three sect plants in Elymus (Poaceae) based on the anatomical characteristics of leaf blades</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/8F88C244573</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/8F88C244573</guid><description>
	The anatomical characteristics of leaf blades of the major species of sect. Elymus, sect.Turczaninoviaand sect.MacrolepisinElymuswere examined. The results showed that: (1) The leaf epidermis usually consists of long and short cells, stomatal apparatus and prickle -hairs. It belongs to the typical festucoid type. Its long-cells are usually rectangle and its cell-walls are thin and straight o...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The allele frequencies of growth hormone gene on the parental and progeny of Ongole-crossbreed cattle population in the North Sulawesi of Indonesia using PCR-RFLP</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/7D95D4E4502</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/7D95D4E4502</guid><description>
	The objectives of this research were to identify the allelic frequency of growth hormoneMspIenzyme-restriction, to define the genetic inequilibrium in selected superior and inferior body weight groups of the cows (G0) and to upgrade genetically the genetic equilibrium of their Ongole-crossbred progenies (G1) population. A total of 74 blood samples were collected from G0 and G1 at the artific...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Gene expression and phenotypic characterization of flooding tolerance in tomato</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/7E658F94521</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/7E658F94521</guid><description>
	The effect of flooding on gene expression of four tomato genotypes was studied under a controlled environment. Four different flooding treatments (0, 2, 4, and 8 days) were used for flooding tolerance in four tomato genotypes. The experiment was laid out in a randomized split plot design with flooding treatment as main plot and the genotypes subplot. Treatments were replicated five times. Th...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Biological and biochemical responses of infected Biomphalaria alexandrina snails with Schistosoma mansoni post exposure to the pesticides Basudin and Selecron and the phytoalkaloid Colchicine</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/5D161134419</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEBR/article-abstract/5D161134419</guid><description>
	This study aims to detect the molluscicidal properties of the pesticides Basudin and Selecron and the phytoalkaloid Colchicine againstBiomphalariaalexandrinasnails including their infection withSchistosoma mansoni,production of cercariae, the levels of total protein, globulin and albumin and the activities of alanine and aspartate transaminases (AlT and AsT) and acid and alkaline phosphatase...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>