<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Environmental Chemistry and Ecotoxicology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Environmental Chemistry and Ecotoxicology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Level and ecological risk assessment of heavy metals in old landfill in Bayelsa state, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/27A314A63690</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/27A314A63690</guid><description>
	This study assessed the ecological fate of heavy metals within the vicinity of an area formally used as dump site in Igbogene, Bayelsa state. Soil auger was used to collect samples at 0 - 20 cm depth at 50, 100 and 150 m distances from the four cardinal points viz: North east and west and south east and west. The soil samples were sieved, ashed, digested and analyzed using atomic adsorption ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bioaccumulation of heavy metals in mangoes (Mangifera indica L.) found in the vicinity of gold mining sites of Zamfara State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/764729263705</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/764729263705</guid><description>
	The impact of gold mining on mango (Mangifera indica L.) grown in the vicinity of gold mining sites in Zamfara State, Nigeria have been assessed over the dry and wet seasons. Samples of mango plant parts were collected from 3 impacted sites and a control site monthly between March and August 2014, and analysed for selected heavy metals using Atomic Absorption Spectrophotometer. The results o...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Seasonal assessment of the physico-chemical properties of surface water and sediments in the vicinity of a scrap metal recycling industry in Southwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/84A837763271</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/84A837763271</guid><description>
	The study assessed the seasonal variations in the physico-chemical properties of surface water and sediments in some villages located around a scrap metal recycling industry in Ile-Ife. This is with a view to monitor the impact of the industry on the quality of surrounding water. The three water bodies (one river, one stream and one pond) identified in the area were sampled every other month...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of industrial effluents, domestic wastewater and natural dams on heavy metals concentrations in vegetables cultivated in Northern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/3C07CF663043</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/3C07CF663043</guid><description>
	Vegetable cultivation is increasing because of its health benefit. However, in areas with limited fresh water, irrigation is from industrial and domestic wastewaters. Consumption of crops with high heavy metal content poses concern to health. A comparative analysis was conducted using AAS (Atomic Absorption Spectrophotometer) to determine the concentration of heavy metals in some vegetables ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Induction of vitellogenin in cultured fish: Vitellogenin gene expression response of blue fin and yellow fin breams to injected 17 &#x3B2;-estradiol</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/046F27663045</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/046F27663045</guid><description>
	Aquatic organisms in the coastal regions are often exposed to many anthropogenic effluents. Kuwait Bay receives considerable quantities of sewage and industrial effluents, and thus, naturally, many endocrine disrupting chemicals (EDCs) find their way into the coastal waters. These EDCs could influence the physiology of the aquatic organisms inhabiting the coastal region. Response of two impo...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ingestion of lead-contaminated vegetables could affect the intelligent quotient of school children</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/C34107163047</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/C34107163047</guid><description>
	Lead (Pb) is a potential environmental contaminant that has the capability of causing some human health problems, especially when it accumulates in food crops. This study aimed to evaluate the risk of ingesting Pb-contaminated vegetables on the intelligent quotient (IQ) of school children, using target risk quotient methodology. From the responses to the questionnaires administered to the sc...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The impact of household and similar solid wastes on Kara River quality due to their potential to release nitrogen</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/790758562440</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/790758562440</guid><description>
	This study purpose to assess the real share of nitrogen the household and similar solid wastes can release in direct contact with water. The maximum amount of nitrogen could release was determined by a leaching test. The concentrations of total and organic nitrogen, ammonium and nitrates ions and the pH values were measured in the initial and incubated juices. The leaching test showed that t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy dispersive X-Ray fluorescence determination of minor and major elements in soils of Mambilla Plateau Northeastern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/E555F4160279</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/E555F4160279</guid><description>
	This study focuses on energy dispersive X-ray fluorescence determination of minor and major elements in selected soils of Mambilla Plateau. The 12 sampled soil composites analysed were done by energy dispersive X-ray fluorescence technique for minor and major elements. The elemental oxides determined were Al2O3, CaO, K2O, TiO2, SiO2, BaO, Fe2O3, and MnO. The result obtained in the study show...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Groundwater quality distribution by geostatistical investigation (GIS), Nile Delta, Northern Egypt</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/794CB0560021</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/794CB0560021</guid><description>
	The Nile Delta represents two-thirds of agricultural output with low precipitation and population growth that depletes the groundwater. The Quaternary aquifer is consisted of Holocene (aquitard) underlain by Pleistocene (aquifer), and groundwater flows from south to north, northwest, and northeast directions. The total dissolved solids (TDS) concentration increases toward the western and nor...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Heavy metal remediation from municipal waste water using arrowroots (Amaranta arundinacea)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/38DA9C258235</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JECE/article-abstract/38DA9C258235</guid><description>
	Municipal wastewater contains high levels of pollutants since it is a collection of wastes from various sources of human activities. Municipal treatment of such wastewater is usually aimed at lowering the levels of pollutants to permissible amounts before discharge into recipient environment. Several conventional methods are available for treatment of wastewater. However, most of them are co...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>