<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Impact of electromagnetic interface of soft magnetic sensor on IoTs current detector: Design 
and development
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/5517C8560648</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/5517C8560648</guid><description>
	This paper presents the electromagnetic interface (EMI) impact on the current transformer with amorphous HB1-M core, printed circuit board (PCB) power transformer and the filter of inductor for Internet of Things (IoTs) device. According to the antenna principle, the radiation emission power responses of PCB transformer and current transformer are estimated and found to be negligible due to ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-way comparison between stitched transmission lines with copper wires and conductive threads, and with conductive threads only</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/D0B6BB066100</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/D0B6BB066100</guid><description>
	This paper presents a two-way comparison between a stitched transmission line constructed with a copper wire and conductive thread, and a stitched transmission line constructed with conductive threads only from Light Stitches. The stitched transmission lines which are both 150 mm long consist of a copper inner conductor surrounded by a tubular insulating layer made up of polyethylene. For sh...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Using COMSOL to model high frequency surface acoustic wave (SAW) device</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/B89A6B359713</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/B89A6B359713</guid><description>
	Finite element method (FEM) analysis of SAW devices is recently popular to be achieved using the basic information of stress and strain equations for linear elastic piezoelectric materials. A delay line is modeled using Gallium arsenide piezoelectric substrate and is modeled and simulated with center frequency of 1.5 GHz to be used in many electronic devices like oscillators at ultrahigh fre...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Optimization of diode cell arrangement in solar cell array</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/F0DEEC354767</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/F0DEEC354767</guid><description>
	The arrangement of diodes in a solar cell array affects the Maximum Power Point (MPP) of the solar cell system. Thus, a pre-wiring method for determining the optimal arrangement of the diodes, which results in the highest MPP, is desirable. This paper proposes a numerical algorithm that predicts the optimal diodes arrangement. A computer program, written in Spice, measures the MPP of many di...</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Application of new modeling and control for grid connected photovoltaic systems based on artificial intelligence</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/4C4351850117</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/4C4351850117</guid><description>
	This review-paper focuses on the development the intelligent technology for modelling (Multi-Model Approach (MMA)) and control (Artificial Neural Networks Controller) of grid connected photovoltaic energy conversion system. This approach (MMA) is based on a black box modeling. A database consists of input variables (sunshine, temperature and voltage at the terminals of photovoltaic generator...</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Runge kutta to precise the detection of lesion for magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) image</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/4C349F048633</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/4C349F048633</guid><description>
	In this paper, we translate non linear model to linear one and used numerical analysis: Runge kutta4 (RK4) is mathematical solutions to study the approximations solutions of ordinary differential equations, then pass to the statistical study for multiple regression to applied anova technique and with it, we extract the place of the lesion on medical image MRI by two ways: Distribution of gau...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Reduction of side lobe level in non-uniform circular antenna arrays using the simulated annealing algorithm</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/EAB4EFC46665</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/EAB4EFC46665</guid><description>
	This paper investigates the reduction of side lobe level in antenna arrays. Reduction of side lobe level in antenna arrays has some limitations including fixed width of the beam. We have modeled the side lobe level reduction as an optimization problem using simulated annealing technique for side lobe level reduction of a specific beam width. The advantage of this method compared with other m...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Transformerless impedance matching networks for automotive power line communication</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/BE18BD146667</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/BE18BD146667</guid><description>
	The automotive industry is constantly looking for ways of improving vehicles fuel economy, reliability, and reducing cost of manufacturing and maintenance. As a result, vehicle manufacturers have looked into power line communication (PLC) technology as a possible solution. However the nature of a vehicles power lines such as extremely low impedances, time varying channel characteristics, and...</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Estimating global solar radiation on horizontal surface from sunshine hours over Port Harcourt, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/5221D4045188</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/5221D4045188</guid><description>
	A model for estimating sunshine hours from some meteorological parameters was developed. An eleven year (1997 to 2007) period of relative humidity, maximum and minimum temperatures, rainfall and wind speed measured at Port Harcourt, Nigeria (Latitude 45626.2N) was analyzed. The results of the correlations show that the four variable correlations with the highest value of R gives the best res...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Design of a double clad optical fiber with particular consideration of leakage losses</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/C7CB23330071</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEEER/article-abstract/C7CB23330071</guid><description>
	In this paper we present a double clad optical fiber that consists of core, inner cladding and outer cladding. The refractive index of the core and the outer cladding are the same and the value of refractive index of the core is greater than the refractive index of inner cladding. The cutoff number Vcis calculated and plotted with respect to the ratio of the radius of inner cladding and the ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>