<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Economics and International Finance - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Economics and International Finance</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Impact of foreign direct investment and inflation on economic growth of five randomly selected Countries in Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/F975B8B63469</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/F975B8B63469</guid><description>
	Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) has been viewed as a major source of finance for developing countries and it has gained significant momentum since the sweep of globalization in the early 1990. This is because most of the developing countries see FDI as important in their strategy for growth. In this study, the impact of FDI and inflation on economic growth was examined. Five countries in Afr...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Estimating the Marshall-Lerner condition of China</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/0202CBD63360</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/0202CBD63360</guid><description>
	The US labeled China a Currency Manipulator in August 2019 because of the massive trade balance surplus of China. The correlation between RMBs exchange rate and Chinas trade balance has been discussed worldwide. The Traditional Marshal-Lerner Condition states if the sum of the absolute value of export and import price elasticity of demand is more than 1, the trade balance will be adjusted th...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Unconditional convergence of Chinese provinces (1952-2017): Some statistical analysis results</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/703812363445</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/703812363445</guid><description>
	This research tests the economic convergence hypothesis of 31 inland Chinese provinces over the period from 1952 to 2017. Regression and descriptive analysis methods are adopted to study the economic convergence among these Chinese provinces in terms of GDP growth and per-capita GDP growth. The research results show that GDP growth does not exhibit a tendency of convergence, rejecting the ab...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The determinants of credit demand among farmers in Hurungwe District of Mashonal and West Province in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/893307663577</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/893307663577</guid><description>
	Bank credit availability in the agricultural sector empowers farmers to adopt modern technologies and inputs that are vital for breaking poverty in developing economies like Zimbabwe. This study sought to establish the determinants of credit demand among farmers in Hurungwe District of Mashonaland West Province in Zimbabwe. A questionnaire survey was conducted on a sample of 354 farmers sele...</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Causal links between foreign direct investment and import demand in ECOWAS Countries: A view through meta-analysis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/3B0F9E662855</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/3B0F9E662855</guid><description>
	This study examines the relationship between Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) and import demand for 11 member countries of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) during the period 1970-2017. We employ a causality test based on Meta-analysis which considers the issues of cross-sectional dependency and slope heterogeneity among countries. The empirical findings indicate that the...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Market opening and economic growth in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/08FA83763011</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/08FA83763011</guid><description>
	Market opening positively impacts economic growth due to reduction in the cost of capital and international risk diversification, amongst others in Nigeria. Using a robust set of econometric approach involving unit root test, co-integration, vector error correction model and granger causality, there is evidence that current value of economic growth responds to disequilibrium from past values...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The role of internal auditors to implement IFRS9: Case of Lebanese banks</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/B866C1162897</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/B866C1162897</guid><description>
	The implementation of IFRS9 as with any structural change to accounting policies requires a strategic development and implementation, and a concerted effort from many departments. This paper investigated the role of internal auditors at Lebanese banks in the implementation of accounting standards. The local banking system is surveyed in a targeted manner to test for significant shortcomings ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Temperature-based options for Vietnam: An option pricing and policy insight</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/A88A3D963160</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/A88A3D963160</guid><description>
	The purpose of this paper is to test a temperature-based pricing model of Alaton (2002) in main rice-growing cities of Vietnam. The results of the test are then used for loss hedging analysis and policy implications for Vietnamese farmers, investors and related parties. Data are collected from General Statistics Office (GSO) of Vietnam, 2017 and Vietnam Meteorological and Hydrological Admini...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The impact of money laundering in beautiful places: The case of Trinidad and Tobago</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/368FCCC63276</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/368FCCC63276</guid><description>
	This paper investigates the relationship between money laundering and economic growth in Trinidad and Tobago. It utilizes annual secondary time series data for the period 1990 to 2017. The proxy of fraud offences and narcotics is used to estimate the volume of money laundering. Cointegration analysis and Error Correction Modelling is employed to test the long-run and short-run relationship b...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative migration studies of Burmese, Cambodian and Laotian migrants in Thailand: Multivariate approach</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/729744C62484</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEIF/article-abstract/729744C62484</guid><description>
	The paper outlines main economics factors determining migrant workers to Thailand, and the comparative studies between migrants, that are Myanmar, Cambodia and Laos. This research is quantitative in nature using logistic regression analysis. The results indicate demand on migration of Burmese migrants relevance to four factors, two related to personal factors (employment and past income) and...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>