<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Entomology and Nematology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Entomology and Nematology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Control potential of some indigenous biochars against meloidogyne incognita [(Kofoid and White) Chitwood] in tomato (Solanum lycopersicum L.)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/84B702763717</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/84B702763717</guid><description>
	The use of biochar has been shown to suppress populations of soil-borne pathogens. Hence it has been promoted as one of the eco-friendly alternatives to synthetic pesticides. In the current study, the effects of different sources of indigenous biochar on Meloidogyne incognita and overall growth and yield of tomato were evaluated under screenhouse condition in 2016 and 2017. A total of 10 tre...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Management of Plodia interpunctella (h&#xFC;bner) [Lepidoptera: pyralidae] using ethanolic oil extract of Plumbago zeylanica (LINN.)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/B05FB8D63115</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/B05FB8D63115</guid><description>
	This study investigated the insecticidal effects of ethanolic oil extract of Plumbago zeylanica against Plodia interpunctella infestation in stored maize grains. Oils from the plant were administered at 5, 10, 15, 20 and 25% concentrations to maize grains inside plastic containers. The treated samples were air-dried for 3 h. The three developmental stages of the moth (egg, larval and adult) ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Persistent of low-level diapause and generation effect in Microplitis rufiventris wasps under mass rearing conditions
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/001EB3B62584</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/001EB3B62584</guid><description>
	The solitary endoparasitoid, Microplitis ru&#xFB01;ventris is considered one of the principal wasps on the cotton leaf moth, Spodoptera littoralis larvae. It has a strange sort of obligate diapause. The data present an evidence of persistent low-level diapause throughout the year and every year that observed under mass rearing conditions. When continuous rearing was done throughout the year at 25C ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Infestation rate of Mangifera indica fruit fly in Sudanese zone of Mali</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/459A4C762586</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/459A4C762586</guid><description>
	Mali has a potential for mango production across the country. However, this plant is facing phytosanitary problems mainly related to fruit flies. The study was conducted to evaluate the infestation rate of fruit flies on mango varieties in Sudanese zone of Mali (Kati). Stung mangoes were weekly collected from three sites. Fruits were weighted and placed inside plastic bags containing sand to...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of integrating entomopathogenic fungi and botanical extracts against Russian wheat aphid, Diuraphis noxia Mordvilko (Hemiptera: Aphididae) in West Showa, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/0BF0F7762690</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/0BF0F7762690</guid><description>
	Ethiopia is the only country in Sub-Saharan Africa where smallholder wheat production meets more than 70% of the national consumption demand. Russian wheat aphid (RWA; Diuraphis noxia (Mordvilko) (Hemiptera: Aphididae) is one of the major insect pests of wheat throughout the world including in Ethiopia. Wheat yield loss due to RWA damage in Ethiopia was estimated to be 70%. Therefore, the pr...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Preliminary evaluation of the effect of three rates of ground leaves and fruits powders of Myristica fragrans on Meloidogyne incognita infecting sunflower in vivo</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/6E4C86C62050</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/6E4C86C62050</guid><description>
	Three rates of ground leaves and fruits powders of Myristica fragrans(5, 10 and 20 g/pot) were evaluated for their nematicidal effect against M. incognita infecting sunflower plants under greenhouse conditions. Results indicated that all tested applications significantly enhanced sunflower plant growth characters. Moreover, all tested treatments significantly gave better results with a signi...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Characterization of the Soil Nematode Fauna of Makerere Hill, Kampala, Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/F82FA2462098</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/F82FA2462098</guid><description>
	Soil nematode faunal analysis is necessary to ascertain the health status of the soil ecosystem. Composite soil samples were taken at designated sites; A, B, C and D from the Makerere Hill area, Kampala and analyzed to characterize the nematode fauna status. Soil samples were collected vertically at 0-5 cm, 5-10 cm and 10-15 cm core depths with a 5 cm wide soil auger. A total of 7,900 nemato...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Notice of Retraction: Electromagnetic radiation (EMR) clashes with honeybees</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/0830A9061484</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/0830A9061484</guid><description>
	The editors ofthe Journal of Entomology and Nematology (JEN) are retracting the article, Electromagnetic radiation (EMR) clashes with honeybees published in 2012 (Vol. 4(1), pp. 1-3, January 2012). This is informed by the multiple publication of the article under different titles in other journals (http://ipublishing.co.in/jesvol1no12010/EIJES2044.pdf; https://academicjournals.org/journal/JH...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A survey of geographical distribution and host range of white mango scale, Aulacaspis tubercularis Newstead (Hemiptera: Diaspididae) in Western Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/F2C90DE61653</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/F2C90DE61653</guid><description>
	White mango scale (WMS) is a sucking insect which poses severe threat to mango plantation. A survey of the distribution and host range of WMS, Aulacaspis tubercularis was conducted in western Ethiopia from May 10, 2016 to July 15, 2016. The surveys were started from Loko village, the focus of its first record, and extended over series of mango farms in the four cardinal directions. This stud...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Seasonal pattern of Bancroftian Filariasis transmission in Ebonyi State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/192E10661125</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JEN/article-abstract/192E10661125</guid><description>
	Bancroftian filariasis in Nigeria is endemic with 22.1% of the population thought to be infected. The main mosquito genera implicated with Wuchereria bancrofti transmission are Anopheles and Culex. The study was carried out to compare the infectivity rates of the vectors between the high transmission (rainy) and the low transmission (dry) seasons. Mosquitoes were sampled from houses and comp...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>