<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Ecology and The Natural Environment - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Ecology and The Natural Environment</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Customs and traditional management practices of coastal marine natural resources in Lower Casamance: Perspectives of valorisation of endogenous knowledge</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/FB932D163590</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/FB932D163590</guid><description>
	In southern Senegal, specifically in Lower Casamance, many marine and coastal resources are of significant sociological importance for Jola populations. They are essential both for worship and for sustenance. Thus, through different customs and practices, the Jola helps to preserve their natural environment, even if their primary motivations were hardly conservation. Perceptions, beliefs, an...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Tree&#x2019;s spatial pattern, diversity and distribution in sub humid mountains ecosystems in south-west Togo</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/1DDF2FA63593</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/1DDF2FA63593</guid><description>
	West African Guinean forests are among the most diverse and threatened ecosystems in the world. The study aims to provide new insights about tree species patterns, abundance, and diversity for better management in Togo. Species diversity and density of trees were assessed in 170 plots randomly selected in the study area. Each tree with DBH 10 cm was identified and measured. Stem density, bas...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Diurnal activity pattern and social behavior of Swayne&#x2019;s Hartebeest in Maze National Park, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/8140CEA63719</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/8140CEA63719</guid><description>
	Swaynes Hartebeest (SHB) is an endangered endemic animal to Ethiopia. However, its activity pattern and social behavior are not well documented. Hence, we investigated the diurnal activity pattern and social behavior of SHB in the Maze National Park. Data were collected by direct observation of focal-animal from October 2018 to April 2019 and analyzed using descriptive statistics and X2-test...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Contribution of spring and summer hydrodynamic conditions in the eutrophication process at Lake 
Taihu, China
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/513CF0663792</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/513CF0663792</guid><description>
	Contribution of different hydrodynamic conditions caused nutrients released and algal blooms growth and deteriorates water quality. Important factors related to climate variation, such as water temperature, precipitation, wind, solar radiation, and human activities can influence trophic conditions in the water column. A field survey was conducted at Meiliang Bay during spring and summer seas...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Minerology, geochemical composition and geotechnical properties of termite mound soil</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/48B748362645</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/48B748362645</guid><description>
	Termitarian, the epigeal biogenic structure constructed by termites are widespread in the forest and derived savannah regions of Nigeria. Soil modification, with particular focus on the mineralogy, variation in geochemical composition and geotechnical properties of termite mound soil samples collected from nine location in the Ika area, Delta State of Nigeria are the objectives of this repor...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The role of logged timber stump sprouting in natural forest regeneration in the Akak forest area of Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/C59CD6163152</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/C59CD6163152</guid><description>
	Natural forest regeneration is the renewal of a forest crop by self-sown seed or by sprouting of stumps. However, there have been few studies on sprouting in the Cameroon tropical rainforest. The main objectives of this study were to examine the influence of stump sprouting of timber species in natural forest regeneration in the Akak forest area in Cameroon.In this study, stumps were located...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An assessment and local perception of sand deposits induced desertification in Sokoto State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/B5647BD63286</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/B5647BD63286</guid><description>
	Sokoto State is one of the states in Nigeria that are prone to desertification. This study attempts to identify and delimit areas affected by desertification in the three northernmost Local Government Areas of Sokoto State, namely: Illela, Gada and Tangaza. Field study was carried out to verify the incident and occurrence of desertification and the menace of sand deposition. A simple random ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Structure of Acacia senegal (L.) wild settlements in southwest Niger: Case of the gum tree site in the rural district of Gu&#xE9;ch&#xE9;m&#xE9;</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/CAC476463344</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/CAC476463344</guid><description>
	This study conducted in the rural district of Guchm (Tibiri county, Dosso region, Niger) aims at characterizing Acacia senegal settlements of the village of Lido. The methodology consisted in floristic sampling of 1000 m2 plots, measuring diameters 20 cm off the ground for shrubs and 1.30 m for trees. The results made it possible to determine the structure of A. senegal, representing signifi...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Applying an indirect method for estimating and modelling the aboveground biomass and carbon for wood energy in the arid ecosystems of A&#x3CA;r Ten&#xE9;r&#xE9; of Niger
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/E872CED62132</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/E872CED62132</guid><description>
	Maintaining the economic, ecological and social services provided by the oases and the valley ecosystems of A&#x3CA;r, in the northern part of Niger, is important for local communities. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the supply and regulation services provided by these ecosystems through wood energy and carbon sequestration. Semi-structured surveys and dendrometric parameter measurements...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Forest land use and native trees diversity conservation in Togolese mega hotspot, Upper Guinean, West Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/A3C45E862300</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JENE/article-abstract/A3C45E862300</guid><description>
	In tropics, species diversity in agricultural systems is often assessed without distinction between native and exotic species. However, the conservation value of an ecosystem depends on its richness in native species. This study was conducted to determine the conservation value of agricultural systems in Togo megahotspot, one of the species-rich sites in Upper Guinean. Specifically, the stud...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>