<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Engineering and Technology Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Engineering and Technology Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Agricultural tractor and machinery performance and serviceability in Delta State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/0C7DAA262209</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/0C7DAA262209</guid><description>
	A sufficient tractor and implements utilizations in agricultural activities and their proper serviceability optimize agricultural productivities in farm operations. A study was conducted in Delta State, Nigeria assessing level of machinery utilization in farm operations and serviceable conditions. Eight (8) government owned tractors locations with 60 tractors and eight private owned farms wi...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Modeling of the adsorption isotherm of Pleurotus ostreatus using Guggenheim-Anderson-de Boer (GAB) equation</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/2FB56C361247</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/2FB56C361247</guid><description>
	Moisture sorption isotherms of Pleurotus ostreatus were determined at three different temperatures (10, 30 and 40) and relative humidity (6 to 88%), using standard static gravimetric method. The samples were used to determine the equilibrium moisture content and the data fitted to the Guggenheim-Anderson-de Boer (GAB) equation to describe the moisture adsorption characteristics within the wa...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Predicting tractor fuel consumption during ridging on a sandy loam soil in a humid tropical climate</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/BB413B161109</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/BB413B161109</guid><description>
	A predictive model for the determination of optimum fuel consumption of a tractor during ridging operation has been developed. The model development involved field experimentations to determine the various parameters affecting tractor fuel consumption, like draught, speed, depth of cut, soil moisture content, cone index and width of cut. The field investigations were carried out at the farm ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Application of plasma technology in aerospace vehicles: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/73D919660773</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/73D919660773</guid><description>
	The galactic and solar radiation effects on astronauts in space during manned-space missions is one of the issues that scientists are dealing with to come up with a reasonable solution to overcome this disaster. Furthermore, in space missions to Mars, Titan, and beyond them, a powerful propulsion system is required. Recently, with the enhancement of technology in plasma generation, scientist...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fast transmission of image, reduction of energy consumption and lifetime extension in wireless cameras networks</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/0336C9A60770</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/0336C9A60770</guid><description>
	In this paper, a fast image processing was proposed. It ensures energy efficiency and the extension of both the lifetime and the proper functioning of the network. It is a filtered zonal discrete cosine transform that allows and optimizes an effective adjustment of the trade-off between power consumption and image distortion. This is a remarkable energy saving method, in this kind of network...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparison of bioremediation capabilities of poultry droppings and avocado pear seed cake in petroleum polluted soil</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/6E2B9A159606</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/6E2B9A159606</guid><description>
	A crude oil polluted soil remediation was investigated using a mixture of avocado pear seed cake and poultry droppings. The seed cake was obtained through the Soxhlet method by extracting the oil from the pear seed. The experiment was carried out within a span of two months. Contamination was done by applying crude oil on 10 experimental reactors containing agricultural soil. The therapeutic...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Analytic network process in petroleum hydrocarbon decontamination management in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/5BA6B7E58433</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/5BA6B7E58433</guid><description>
	This study examined the application of the Analytic Network Process (ANP), a multi-criteria decision analysis tool, in the selection of the best bioremediation technique for the remediation of a hydrocarbon-polluted site at Kwawa (43629.26N, 72855.70E) in Ogoniland, Niger Delta province, Nigeria. The decision-making problem involved four bioremediation techniques (that is, landfarming, field...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Development of hot spring fed incubator for duck eggs</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/9EB02DB57656</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/9EB02DB57656</guid><description>
	The development of hot spring heat source incubator for duck eggs was deemed necessary to design the utilization of hot spring as heat source for incubating duck eggs, to reduce the use of electricity. This study addressed issues such as replacing conventional source of energy with geothermal energy in Los Ba&#x148;os, Laguna, Philippines for incubation of eggs (ducklings, ballot and penoy). The e...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of pre-treatment by torrefaction and carbonization on temperature field, energy efficiency and tar content during the gasification of cotton stalks</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/DD350C257265</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/DD350C257265</guid><description>
	The present study focused on the gasification of raw and pre-treated cotton stalks (CS) by torrefaction and carbonization. Temperature fields, mass balance, energy balance, energy efficiency and tar content of the gas were investigated for the gasification of different types of biomass materials (raw, torrefied and carbonized CS). High temperature and thick reduction zone were obtained durin...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Online electronic laboratory notebook: A secured cloud storage system scripted in Hypertext Pre-processor (PHP) programming language</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/3E747E956778</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JETR/article-abstract/3E747E956778</guid><description>
	Notebooks in research are an important part in tracking information of both wet and dry analytical data. Paper books or excel sheets remain the most popular and conventional ways of record keeping. To meet these demands, an open source electronic laboratory notebook is developed that can track users research need. Based on the user specifications, this suite is written in Hypertext Pre-proce...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>