<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Fine and Studio Art - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Fine and Studio Art</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Emotion and colour perception: A psychoanalytical theory of graphic design in consumer of goods</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/6860CC256463</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/6860CC256463</guid><description>
	The study focuses on the psychological theory of colour in graphic design on the advertisement of consumer goods. The specific objectives identify the impact of colour perception and emotion as it psychologically affects and influences the behaviour of consumers in purchasing the products advertised. Descriptive research study, that is, employing qualitative methodology was used to address t...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Space as a unique context for sculpture theory and praxis in Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/E3B35AB61013</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/E3B35AB61013</guid><description>
	This paper explores autonomous space as subject and object in studio sculpture experimental studies with the backdrop of spatial subjectivities inherent culturally in Ghana. The study looks at contemporary Ghanaian art presentation of space as integral in sculptural compositions contextually, with interests shuffling between inner and outer space, as corresponding to spatial conception in co...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Carlos S&#xE1;nchez: In search of beauty</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/9BF149957968</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/9BF149957968</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study is to review the life and works of Carlos Snchez, a Guatemalan born prolific painter and architect, whose masterpieces were exhibited at Dartmouth Colleges Hood Museum of Art in Hanover, New Hampshire. His paintings have left an immeasurable legacy to the world of art. Born in Guatemala in 1898, he graduated from Dartmouth College in 1923, and then finished the Yale...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Bharatanatyam and Mathematics: Teaching Geometry Through Dance</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/502FA2F55648</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/502FA2F55648</guid><description>
	Bharatanatyam is a highly codified and schematized Asian Indian style of classical dance that accommodates the different kinds of learners. This dance is culturally relevant to Asian Indian American students, but the findings are applicable to students from other demographics that are interested in learning math through dance. Many Asian Indian students learn Bharatanatyam for cultural maint...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Graphical territory, series and memory</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/66CC37555498</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/66CC37555498</guid><description>
	Our world is multiple. It is a hyper-industrialized world, which can indiscriminately copy and reproduce any object, text or image. A situation that in the artistic circuit promotes certain duplicity: we can observe how to differentiate both the unique and singular to the multiple, the original name of your copy. For years we have differentiated the singular from the multiple, holding the wa...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital painting evolution: A multimedia technological platform for expressivity in fine art painting</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/3000A4E49299</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/3000A4E49299</guid><description>
	As an emerging art form of the twenty first century, digital painting has gained acceptance as a two-dimensional art form, paralleling major traditional forms of painting in the art world. However, this aspect of the visual arts, rather underexplored, has not received the same degree of global acceptance and recognition accorded to well known fine art forms such as sculpture, painting and dr...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Technologies in the art classroom: Using technologies in art classrooms to overcome cultural limitations to support teaching and learning</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/5ED27916059</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/5ED27916059</guid><description>
	

	The purpose of this paper is to review the benefits of using technology and the Internet in the educational sector. I will discuss how we can apply the findings to the specific environment of the art classroom and a specific culture: Saudi Arabia, to enrich the experience of learning and teaching in art education. The paper draws and reflects upon my thirteen years experience of teachin...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Visual illustration using printmaking as a medium: A case study of coronation ceremonies of kings among the Yoruba of South West Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/4A51CBB6081</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/4A51CBB6081</guid><description>
	Coronation ceremonies are traditional rites to formally install kings to the throne of their forefathers as community leaders who are symbol of authority between their people and the outside world. The funfairs that accompany these ceremonies are worth documenting using printmaking as a vehicle of visual and historical expression. The prints represented in this paper are expression of myths ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Minimalism in Art and Design: Concept, influences, implications and perspectives</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/3A668BC6040</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/3A668BC6040</guid><description>
	The term Minimalist is often applied colloquially to designate or suggest anything which is spare or stripped to its absolute essentials. It has its origins with an art critic seeking to describe what he saw, but has also been used to describe such diverse genres as plays by authors such as Samuel Beckett, films by director Robert Bresson (the narratives of Raymond Carver), the simple musica...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Auctioning: A new way of placing good old-fashioned art</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/77291B26006</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JFSA/article-abstract/77291B26006</guid><description>
	

	This article reflects on a new phenomenon in auctioning art by placing it in the perspective of the historical tradition of generating an artworks aura through the aid of special places. Historically, special places such as churches and galleries have tended to maximize an artworks experiential value in particular. Today, however, the intention of certain new special places such as auct...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>