<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Geology and Mining Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Geology and Mining Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Sequence stratigraphic study of &#x2018;X&#x2019; field in eastern offshore of Niger Delta, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/8A836E963905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/8A836E963905</guid><description>
	An integrated approach to Seismic interpretation that combines techniques of sequence stratigraphic analysis, seismic facies analysis and attribute analysis is one of the most effective approaches for hydrocarbon exploration in growth-faulted deltaic strata of offshore eastern Niger Delta. These strata are generally thick paralic/marine units deposited along an unstable progradational contin...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Migmatization process and the nature of transition from amphibolite to granulite facies metamorphism in Ikare area south western Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/D33DD8D63695</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/D33DD8D63695</guid><description>
	The Ikare area is underlain by rocks of the migmatite-gneiss-quartzite complex and older granite lithologic groups and charnockites. Categorization of these rocks in the literature and published map is generalized and the rocks are undifferentiated. Though reported in few literature as an area with rocks composed of granulite facie grade, the nature of transition is not well documented. Fiel...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrological characteristics of some cretaceous igneous rocks, in Southwest of Gboko, Southern Benue Trough, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/E5D239163514</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/E5D239163514</guid><description>
	Detailed field geological mapping, outcrop petrography and thin-section microscopy are employed to delineate and describe igneous rocks, and to infer the tectono-magmatic and geochemical constraints affecting their emplacement in the Tse-Agberagba area, Southwest of Gboko, Southern Benue Trough. Magmatic activity, coupled with folding and deformation were the effects of the Santonian tectoni...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The geotechnical properties of the oolitic ironstone formation, Wadi Halfa, North Sudan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/C244E6262828</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/C244E6262828</guid><description>
	Wadi Halfa Oolitic Ironstone Formation (WHOIF) covers large areas around Wadi Halfa border town in Northern Sudan. The detrital framework grains of sandstone of WHOIF are composed of sub-angular to sub-rounded quartz grains followed by feldspars, lithic fragments, micas and heavy minerals. The dominant cementing materials are iron oxides, carbonate cement, and some clay minerals. Twelve bloc...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Anisotropic properties of the near-surface in South-Western Niger Delta: Implications on 
geotechnical constructions
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/4BBEA9B62641</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/4BBEA9B62641</guid><description>
	The near-surface anisotropic properties within the South-Western Niger Delta were investigated to determine their impacts on geotechnical constructions. Uphole data analyses reveal a weathered layer that is thickest in the NW, E and SE with an average of 4.2 m and thinnest in the North-Central with a value of 3.8 m; a sub-weathered layer that is thickest in the NW and SW with an average of 3...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Applications of remote sensing and geographic information system (GIS) in regional lineament mapping and structural analysis in Ikare Area,  Southwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/4A5E12C62658</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/4A5E12C62658</guid><description>
	An attempt was made to use remote sensing technique to analyze some structural components of the metamorphic basement complex of the Ikare area in the SW Nigeria. Multiple data sets coupled with application of directional filtering techniques were used to extract linear features from Landsat ETM+ image with a view to improving on already produced regional structural map of the area and also ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Structure and tectonics of Hong Hills in Hawal Precambrian Basement Complex, North East Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/823C4AB62442</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/823C4AB62442</guid><description>
	The tectonics and impact of the Pan-African orogeny on the Hong Hills area of North Eastern Nigeria has been unraveled. This work basically used structural identification and tectonic inference to decipher the deformation episodes in this region. The results show that this area was subjected to multiple episodes of deformation and there were evidence of reworking of older structures by young...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Geology and petrography of Sabon Garin Kara and environs part of Malumfashi sheet 79 NE Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/3C7BF0862210</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/3C7BF0862210</guid><description>
	The study area is about 40 km2 that is (8 km  5 km) which is located in Gwarzo Local Government area of Kano State part of Malumfashi sheet 79NE which lies within Longitude E075719.5 and E080000 and Latitude N11 5130andN114700. Major rock types identified include medium grained biotite-muscovite granite, coarse grained muscovite-biotite granites, quartz-syenite, and quartz-monzonites. Most o...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Crustal structure of southern Benue Trough, Nigeria from 3D inversion of gravity data</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/87F9BB262212</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/87F9BB262212</guid><description>
	3D Moho interface has been computed from the airborne Bouguer anomaly beneath the southern part of the Benue Trough (BT), using the MATLAB program 3DINVER.M. From the study, the maximum Moho depth of 27.5 km and the minimum Moho depth of 18.1 km were computed. Interpretation of the gravity data of the southern part of the BT suggests that igneous input contributed greatly to the understandin...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Geological analysis of ground radiometric survey data of Hong hills, Hawal basement complex, N. E. Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/E86F8E860650</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMR/article-abstract/E86F8E860650</guid><description>
	A ground radioactivity survey report and it geological analyses are presented in this work. The survey was aimed at delineating possible zones of concentration of pegmatite intrusions, a rock whose components are useful in the in the electrical and ceramic industries among others. The survey covers longitude 1254-1300E and latitude 107-1015N, with a total surface area of 155.52 km2. Dominant...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>