<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of General and Molecular Virology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of General and Molecular Virology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Maize lethal necrosis and the molecular basis of variability in concentrations of the causal viruses in co-infected maize plant
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/BC07C4461466</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/BC07C4461466</guid><description>
	Maize lethal necrosis (MLN) disease is new to Africa. First report was in Kenya in 2012, since then the disease has rapidly spread to most parts of eastern and central Africa region including Tanzania, Burundi, DRC Congo, Rwanda, Uganda, Ethiopia and similar symptoms were observed in South Sudan. Elsewhere, the disease was caused by infection of Maize Chlorotic Mottle Virus (MCMV) in combina...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Genetic diversity of rice yellow mottle virus from Niger Office and Selingue Development Rural Office in Mali</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/503733A59743</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/503733A59743</guid><description>
	Virus is the most constraint of rice production in West Africa. Genetic diversity of rice yellow mottle virus (RYMV) was assessed in two rice growing areas of Mali. Forty-three (43) infected rice leaf samples were collected from five locations within the Niger Office and Selingue Development Rural Office rices growing areas. The infected samples were confirmed by Reverse Transcriptase Polyme...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Molecular characterization of genetic diversity of tomato (Solanum lycopersicum L.) begomovirus in Togo</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/95A7CA467106</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/95A7CA467106</guid><description>
	Geminiviruses, in particular the members of the genus begomovirus, are considered to be a major phytosanitary problem for tomato crops production in the world. They are responsible for yield losses of up to 20 to 100% and Togo is not spared from this situation. The present study aimed to investigate the genetic diversity of the begomoviruses affecting tomato crops production in Togo and thei...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparison of immunoperoxidase monolayer assay, polymerase chain reaction and haemadsorption tests in the detection of African swine fever virus in cell cultures using Ugandan isolates</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/50671A948774</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/50671A948774</guid><description>
	African swine fever (ASF) is a devastating viral disease of pigs and is among the major hindrances to pig industry in sub-Saharan Africa including Uganda. The aim of this study was to compare immunoperoxidase monolayer assay (IPMA) to PCR in detection of ASF virus in infected macrophage cultures and to categorize ASF viral isolates in Uganda by haemadsorption assay. Field strains of ASF viru...</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of the current status of HIV virus and predisposing factors among students at Dilla University and Dilla Referral Hospital, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/CD64F5F47278</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/CD64F5F47278</guid><description>
	Acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) cannot be transmitted by causal contact, air, food and water. People with acquired immunodeficiency syndrome have human immunodeficiency virus in their blood and body fluids that can enter the blood stream of an uninfected person upon contact with infected body fluids or sexual contact with an infected person. Primary data was collected by using stru...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phenotypic and molecular screening of cassava (Manihot esculentum Crantz) genotypes for resistance to cassava mosaic disease</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/92A90B945293</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/92A90B945293</guid><description>
	Cassava mosaic disease (CMD), caused by cassava mosaic geminivirus (CMG) is the most-important disease threatening production of cassava (Manihot esculenta) in Ghana. The disease is best managed through host-plant resistance. The study was conducted to assess resistance of 38 cassava genotypes to CMD, determine the associated resistance gene, and to identify the strains of CMG infecting cass...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Molecular characterization of influenza A (H7N9) virus from the first imported H7N9 infection case in Malaysia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/1D5662345295</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/1D5662345295</guid><description>
	H7N9 is an avian strain of the species Influenza virus that circulates among avian populations. Occasionally, some variants of this strain were known to infect humans. On March 30, 2013, a novel avian influenza A H7N9 virus that infects human beings was identified in China. In February 2014, the first case of H7N9 infection outside China was reported in Malaysia involving a Chinese tourist. ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Subgenogroup B5 maintains its supremacy over other human Enterovirus71 strains that circulated in Malaysia from 2010 to 2012</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/0CC94B144464</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/0CC94B144464</guid><description>
	Human enterovirus71 (HEV71) is responsible for hand, foot and mouth diseases (HFMD). Several outbreaks of HFMD were associated with severe neurological disease and deaths. In Malaysia, outbreaks normally occur periodically every two to three years but HEV71 were isolated throughout the year from HFMD cases. From 2010 to 2012, HEV71 strains were isolated from 37 children presented with typica...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Molecular characterization of adenovirus causing acute respiratory disease in Malaysia from 2003 to 2011</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/F7271F711071</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/F7271F711071</guid><description>
	

	Human Adenoviruses (HAdVs) are human pathogens that normally are associated with acute respiratory disease (ARD). Here, in this study, we characterized human adenovirus isolated from respiratory specimens collected from 2003 to 2011. Positive adenovirus were confirmed by cell culture and indirect immunoflourescence (IF) techniques. The isolates and positive clinical samples were subject...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The potential of house fly, Musca domestica (L.) in the mechanical transmission of influenza A subtype H1N1 virus under laboratory conditions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/8C61C9511084</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGMV/article-abstract/8C61C9511084</guid><description>
	

	A study on house flies was carried out to establish whether house flies can transmit the H1N1 virus mechanically due to their abundance, ability to transport pathogens and their behavioral traits of regurgitation and defecation. The objectives of this study were to examine the efficiency of house fly legs in picking up the influenza H1N1 virus particles, persistency of the virus particl...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>