<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Geography and Regional Planning - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Geography and Regional Planning</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Rural-urban migration and household livelihood in the Agona West Municipality, Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/36C7AE163427</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/36C7AE163427</guid><description>
	Rural-urban migration, a multidimensional phenomenon, is becoming part of the daily reality in Ghana and many other developing countries. For instance, the impact of migration on households whose member(s) migrated is relatively not very clear. A study was therefore undertaken to examine and explain the impact of rural-urban migration on rural migrants households livelihood in three communit...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate change and smart city development: The challenge of non- implementation of Abuja-Nigeria light rail project</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/52D489163597</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/52D489163597</guid><description>
	In the present century, there has been increasing global pressure on governments to implement policies to incentivize reductions in CO2 emissions based on the devastating effects of global climate change. Researchers generally have established the fact that the automobile sector generates more than 50% of the atmospheric carbon concentration. It has also become obvious that FCC-Abuja Nigeria...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Public-Private Partnership (PPP) in residential solid waste management in Ibadan: Challenges and opportunities</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/A44CE2E63794</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/A44CE2E63794</guid><description>
	Waste management authorities have adopted different strategies at different times in managing waste in Nigeria. In spite of the various efforts put in place, municipal solid waste remains one of the most conspicuous and repugnant environmental problems that threaten the Nigerian city. This paper examines the challenges and opportunities of Public-Private Partnerships (PPP) in residential sol...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Planning: The town planners&#x2019; perspective</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/05A321462000</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/05A321462000</guid><description>
	The concept of planning has been a subject of territorial debates amidst various disciplines and at all conclusions; everyone is a planner in his/her own right. It is against this background of oversimplification that this study attempts to explore the various meaning and scope of planning both from the general percept and town planners viewpoint. It relates the discus to Nigeria environment...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Urban land use planning and its effects on the provision of public sanitation facilities in the Wa Municipality, Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/C420EE362070</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/C420EE362070</guid><description>
	This study has investigated the implications of land use planning on the provision and management of public sanitation facilities in the Wa Municipality, using three zones (Zone 1-Jangbeyiri and Suriyiri; Zone 2-Kpaguri; Zone 3-Mangu) of different land use and socioeconomic characteristics. A mixed method approach was utilized. Field surveys including 374 respondents, key informant interview...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Trends in land use/land cover changes in the Densu River basin and its impact on the Weija reservoirs and the Densu Delta (Sakumo I lagoon) in Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/B5114C062649</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/B5114C062649</guid><description>
	The Densu River basin is one of the most import water resources in Ghana. It is a source of drinking water to more than half of the five (5) million populations of Accra and seven other communities within the basin. Rapid population growth and increasing development pressure within the basin is changing the basin land cover into settlement. This study examined the trend in land use and land ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Drivers to energy efficiency development in lighting and air-conditioning systems in manufacturing industries in Ghana for 2018</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/77106B961433</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/77106B961433</guid><description>
	The increase in electricity demand, coupled with drastic deficit in energy generation and depleting conventional energy resources continues to create complex challenges for the energy market in Ghana. But Energy Efficiency (EE) in lighting and air-conditioning has been considered as a green area for reducing energy consumption. The manufacturing sector has been considered as a key area for t...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Population move on Rajasthan: Regional analysis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/D818ECF61913</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/D818ECF61913</guid><description>
	The physiography of Rajasthan is not suitable for agricultural activity. Most parts of Rajasthan are sandy regions and Aravalli Mountain, which is a barrier for agriculture. Eastern part of Rajasthan is covered with plain soil but this region is also not suitable for agriculture. This is the reason why Rajasthan experienced a large proportion of out-migration from its different physiographic...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Provision of down market urban housing in Kenya through strategic application of public 
private partnerships
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/A0E7AB561254</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/A0E7AB561254</guid><description>
	Article 43 1 (b) of the constitution of Kenya (2010), alongside other international treaties which the country is party to, obligates the state to provide housing for all Kenyans. These instruments place a greater emphasis on the slums and informal settlements upgrading and development, key among which is down market urban housing. Down market urban housing is principally housing for the low...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The paradox of post-colonial urban growth in the city of Zaria, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/C75B2E159905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JGRP/article-abstract/C75B2E159905</guid><description>
	Post-colonial urban growth and expansion is spiralling in Nigerian cities, marked by a curious lack of planning in the newly developed areas despite an initial impetus during the colonial administration for some measure of formal regulation. This paper attempts to examine the character of the phenomenon and its contrasts with the foundation laid for modern formal town planning during the col...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>