<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Horticulture and Forestry - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Horticulture and Forestry</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Evaluation of forest litter mineralization capacity on the growth of Irvingia gabonensis in Ogwashi-Uku Forest Reserve, Delta State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/26D4BA063553</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/26D4BA063553</guid><description>
	The study evaluated litter production capacity of three forest plantation foliage litters as potential mineralization sources for the growth of Irvingiaga bonensis. Litter production capacity of Bamboo, Teak and Gmelina forest plantations was monitored for 70 days before Irvingia seeds were sown in open germination beds containing litters soil samples for vegetative development assessment. D...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Studies of the wood of some Nigerian alkaloid-rich Strychnos species</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/41C06EE63703</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/41C06EE63703</guid><description>
	The wood of three Nigerian species of Strychnos Linn. growing in different ecological zones was studied. The transverse, transverse longitudinal and radial longitudinal sections of the wood were made with sliding sledge microtome. The wood was macerated to measure its fiber and vessel dimensions. The wood was diffusing porous and intraxylary phloem occurred in the three species. Interxylary ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Woody species diversity conservation and carbon sequestration potential of coffee agroforestry systems in the Western Region of Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/366FE7363443</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/366FE7363443</guid><description>
	This study sought to assess the contribution of coffee agroforestry systems (CAFS) in conserving tree diversity and carbon stocks in the western region of Cameroon. Inventory was carried out in 52 plots laid out in CAFS and in adjacent secondary forest. Above-ground biomass was estimated using allometric method. A total of 30 species belonging to 19 families were identified in CAFS and 30 sp...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Screening of tree seedling survival rate under field condition in Tanqua Abergelle and Weri-Leke Wereda&#x2019;s, Tigray, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/CC1D3EF63253</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/CC1D3EF63253</guid><description>
	Rehabilitation of degraded lands through plantations is at the frontline of natural resource management in Ethiopia. However, plantations have been faced with various challenges mainly attributed to poor survival rate of tree seedlings. Hence, this research was conducted in Tanqua Abergelle and Weri Leke Weredas with the objective of screening tree seedlings for their survival rates under fi...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of multi-functional fodder tree and shrub species in mid-altitudes of South Omo Zone, 
Southern Ethiopia

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/3971E0F63329</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/3971E0F63329</guid><description>
	A study was conducted to evaluate the early growth performance and nutrient composition of some selected tree/shrub species in the fodder bank agroforestry system. Moringa stenopetala, Terminalia brownii, Morus alba, Melia azedarach, and Sesbania sesban were used for this study. Square quadrants of 16 m2 plot sizes were established with the RCBD of three replications. Seedlings were planted ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetable soybean, edamame: Research, production, utilization and analysis of its adoption in 
Sub-Saharan Africa

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/5CE1F8062588</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/5CE1F8062588</guid><description>
	Food and nutritional insecurity constitute a main challenge in most Sub-Sahara African countries. Efforts to provide diets with sufficient nutrients such as proteins, carbohydrates, vitamins and essential minerals should include the introduction of new vegetable and legume crops. Vegetable soybean edamame, is a nutritious vegetable legume well known and consumed in Asia and America, but unde...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Management and the influence of socioeconomic factors on tree species diversity in traditional agroforestry practices in Demba Goffa District,  South Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/253440562591</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/253440562591</guid><description>
	The study was designed to provide a baseline data on status of woody species diversity, local knowledge in use and the influence of socioeconomic factors. Interview and discussion with key informants and formal survey with structured questionnaires were employed to collect primary data. The assessment of tree species richness was done by inventorying trees at the sampled plots of the differe...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Morphological characterization and Simple Sequence Repeats (SSRs) based DNA fingerprinting of selected mango (Mangifera indica L.) genotypes in Bangladesh</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/5B1E80B62162</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/5B1E80B62162</guid><description>
	Nineteen genotypes of mango including nine released varieties viz. BARI Aam-1, BARI Aam-2 (Laxmanbhog), BARI Aam-3, BARI Aam- 4 (Hybrid), BARI Aam-5, BARI Aam-6, BARI Aam-7, BARI Aam-8, BARI Aam-9; one parental line viz. M- 3896 and nine Geographical Indication Crops (GIs) viz. Haribhanga, Surjapuri, Fazli, Gourmoti, Ashwina, Khirsapat, Gopalbhog, Langra and Ranipasand were characterized wit...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Integrated effect of nitrogen and vermicompost levels on yield and yield components of carrot (Daucus carota L.) at Woreta, Northwestern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/1123B4961617</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/1123B4961617</guid><description>
	The N fertilizer or organic resources alone may not provide sufficient amounts or may be unsuitable for improving specific constraints to crop production. In view of this, a field trial was conducted at Woreta ATVET College horticultural farm, Ethiopia to determine integrated effect of nitrogen and vermicompost levels on yield and yield components of carrot, nantes type, during 2017 main rai...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of tea processing methods on biochemical composition and sensory quality of black tea (Camellia sinensis (L.) O. Kuntze): A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/A3D83B461381</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHF/article-abstract/A3D83B461381</guid><description>
	Final quality of black tea depends mainly on the chemical composition of the raw tea leaves. Various plucking methods have direct effect both on yield and quality in different cultivated variety and environments. Different literature reports indicated that polyphenols, caffeine, essential oils and amino acids are responsible for aroma and flavor of black tea. The oxidation process begins at ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>