<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Hospitality Management and Tourism - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Hospitality Management and Tourism</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Assessing the impact of ecotourism on livelihood of the local population living around the Campo Ma&#x2019;an National Park, South Region of Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/AE3374863581</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/AE3374863581</guid><description>
	Ecotourism has been reported as a sustainable measure of bridging conservation goals and livelihood sustenance around protected areas, with very little information on the Campo Maan National Park (CMNP). This study was initiated to assess the impact of ecotourism activities on the livelihood of the local population living around the CMNP. Data were collected with questionnaires through house...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Research on a projected brand and perceived personality differentiation of tourist destination: A case study of Shandong, China</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/44ABE7B61081</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/44ABE7B61081</guid><description>
	Due to the accelerated pace of modern life, consumers reduce time of purchase decisions and tend to choose services that match their own personality. The development of the brand of tourist destination needs to introduce new, appropriate extension to meet the needs of tourists in order to maintain exuberant vitality. So, what the perception of the brand personality of tourist destination is ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>How to provide an optimal environment for tourists to manage their sleep? The roles of sleep amenities, sleep environment cleanliness, and sleep atmosphere</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/985D95860441</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/985D95860441</guid><description>
	For many tourists, a good night sleep is essential for business, creativity, travel and/or enjoyment of a holiday. To have better understanding on an optimal environment for the tourists to manage their sleep, this study aims to examine how the comfortability of sleep amenities and sleep environment cleanliness and sleep atmosphere influences tourists sleep quality by adopting the Pittsburgh...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing working-environment of employees in the hospitality industry: The case of hotels in Dessie and Kobolecha towns</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/C952A4F60002</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/C952A4F60002</guid><description>
	The study assesses the working environment of employees in the hospitality industry in the case of the hotel sector in Dessie and Kobolecha towns. Descriptive type of research was applied with a survey design. A close ended questionnaire method was used. The reliability measure of the questionnaire items is 0.86 based on Cronbachs Alpha. Samples of 78 employees were selected based on simple ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Potential and challenges of rock art for sustainable tourism development: The case of Harar - Dire Dawa region, South Eastern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/AC1985658267</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/AC1985658267</guid><description>
	Prehistoric rock art is one of the earliest form of human communication system. It has an aesthetic, spiritual, socio  cultural and artistic values. This study has attempted to address the role of rock art tourism for sustainable socio-economic development with the objective of describing the potential of rock art sites for tourism in Harar  Dire Dawa and in its environs. It also tried to id...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Enhancing employee performance using selected leadership styles of middle-line managers in the hospitality industry in Mid-Western Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/E88DAD657884</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/E88DAD657884</guid><description>
	This study explains the success of employee performance using selected leadership styles of middle-line Hotel managers in Mid-western Uganda. The simple random sample included 196 employees from ten Hotels. The respondents completed the measures of styles of leadership (democratic, autocratic and laissez faire) and employee performance. Bivarriate correlations and regression matrices were us...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Wunania Kosoye natural attraction, Ethiopia: Conservation values and their relevance to community-based ecotourism</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/D0623F457542</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/D0623F457542</guid><description>
	Community based ecotourism is one of the most rapidly growing industries in the world, and also an economic activity that can encourage local people in developing countries to protect and preserve natural resources. This study aimed to evaluate the potential of Wunania Konoye for conservation and community-based ecotourism development. Cross sectional study design with both quantitative and ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Utilisation of information and communication technologies in hotel operations in the central region of Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/0F7F63855772</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/0F7F63855772</guid><description>
	This research was conducted in the central region of Ghana to investigate the utilisation of ICT in hotels business operation. Primary data collections employed in the study were obtained from 200 respondents using well-structured questionnaires. Findings of the research study revealed that telephones, computers, internet, printers and fax machines were ICT applications in hotels business op...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of tourists&#x2019; patronage of Obudu Mountain Resort, Cross River State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/9553D6D65907</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/9553D6D65907</guid><description>
	Tourism in recent times has been expressed as a leisure and event-based activity. This study was carried out to examine tourists arrivals and patronage of the Obudu Mountain Resort in Cross River State, Nigeria. The data for the study were collected through questionnaire survey, interviews, field inventory and participatory rural appraisal methods. The data generated were analysed using desc...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing protected areas for ecotourism development: The case of Maze National Park, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/88319EC63381</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JHMT/article-abstract/88319EC63381</guid><description>
	Ecotourism is growing niche market with the potential of being sustainable development tool in protected areas. Ecotourism development needs preliminary assessment of the destination resources. This study was done with the objective of assessing ecotourism potential of Maze National Park for ecotourism development. The study used survey research design. Structured questionnaires and structur...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>