<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Infectious Diseases and Immunity - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Infectious Diseases and Immunity</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Ebola and its yet unproven therapeutic regimens</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/2C2A9D963607</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/2C2A9D963607</guid><description>
	Ebola is a viral disease transmitted by bats and a species of rat to human. It was discovered in Zaire and latter spread to Zambia, Congo, Sierra Leone and Nigeria. The outbreak of Ebola in some parts of African countries posed therapeutic challenges, due to lack of ideal therapeutic agent against Ebola. In view of this, molecular and cellular pathogenesis of Ebola virus, therapeutic modalit...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of acute diarrhea and associated precipitating factors among under-five children in West Guji Zone, Oromia Region, Ethiopia, 2018: Community based cross sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/D639B0C63174</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/D639B0C63174</guid><description>
	Child hood diarrhea has continued as a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in Ethiopia. In conjunction with implementing control programs, an up to-date comprehensive information on the magnitude and contributing factors among child hood diarrhea is needed to develop and design effective interventions at the district level. A community based cross sectional study was carried out among 7...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Hepatitis B vaccination and its associated factors among health care workers working in Wolayita Sodo Hospitals, Southern Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/85DED0361671</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/85DED0361671</guid><description>
	Hepatitis B is the principal public health problem among diverse segments of inhabitants. However, attention is not given on its prevention strategy, especially among health care workers. Hence, the intention of this study was to assess hepatitis B virus vaccination status and associated factors among health care workers working in Wolayita Sodo hospitals, Southern Ethiopia. An institution b...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Micafungin and caspofungin pharmacodynamics in patients with candidemia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/7EF2CA259613</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/7EF2CA259613</guid><description>
	Candidemia is an important cause of health care-associated bloodstream infections. Appropriate antifungal therapy is crucial to reduce morbidity and mortality. A previous randomized clinical trial compared the clinical effectiveness of caspofungin 50 mg, micafungin 100 mg (M100), and micafungin 150 mg (M150) in treating invasive candidiasis and candidemia. M100 treatment success was non-infe...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Typhoid fever outbreak investigation in Ofla Woreda, Southern Zone of Tigray Region, Ethiopia, 2016: An unmatched 1:2 case-control</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/63F799C57384</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/63F799C57384</guid><description>
	Typhoid fever (TF) is a systemic infection caused by the bacterium, Salmonella typhi. Globally, 22 million illnesses and 216,000 deaths occurred annually. The woreda WAS have alerted the outbreak on 27 July, 2016. The objective of this study was to investigate typhoid fever outbreak in Dera Kebele of Ofla woreda, Tigray Region, Ethiopia. Here, we defined a suspected TF case as any person wit...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Non pseudomonal Ecthyma gangrenosum: A case report of an infant seen at a tertiary hospital in Sokoto, North-Western Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/0A019FD57271</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/0A019FD57271</guid><description>
	Ecthyma gangrenosum (EG) is a cutaneous infection characterized by vesicles or blisters which rapidly evolve into necrotic ulcers with undermined tender erythematous border. It has been rarely reported from the African continent. Pseudomonas aeruginosa is the commonest isolated organism but others, including Staphylococcus aureus (S. aureus) and Escherichia coli ((E. coli) have been reported...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The curious tale of how crocodiles farmed for designer leather handbags are helping to develop human anti-arboviral vaccines</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/7539A7756864</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/7539A7756864</guid><description>
	Most residents of industrialised nations in temperate climatic zones know mosquitoes to be an irritant; those blood-sucking pests that can blight a summer barbeque or family picnic. However, for people living in tropical and subtropical regions of the world, mosquitoes carry the threat of transmission of pathogens responsible for debilitating and often life-threatening blood-borne infectious...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Seroepidemiology of Toxoplasmosis among Pregnant Women in Osogbo, Southwestern, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/AF8AEFF56862</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/AF8AEFF56862</guid><description>
	Infection with Toxoplasma gondii during pregnancy represents a risk of congenital infection. Simple hygienic practices due to adequate knowledge about the parasite is one of the major keys to avoiding this preventable infection among pregnant women and women of child bearing age. The present cross sectional study was carried out to investigate the seroprevalence of anti-Toxoplasma Immunoglob...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Immunological outcomes of neverapin (NVP) versus efafrenz (EFV) based antiretroviral therapy (ART) regimen among children on ART: A study from Black Lion Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/F7BBC0656012</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/F7BBC0656012</guid><description>
	Antiretroviral therapy has reduced HIV-related morbidity and mortality substantially. WHO recommends the use of Nevirapine or Efavirenz as first line combined with two from nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors. In this study the immunological outcomes of Neverapin versus Efafrenz based ART was assessed. Medical records of patients were retrieved and important variables were captured t...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Treatment defaulter rate and associated factors among tuberculosis patients on follow up attending justh tuberculosis clinic</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/048CE8365329</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIDI/article-abstract/048CE8365329</guid><description>
	Tuberculosis is a chronic infections disease caused by Mycobacterium tuberculosis attributable to nearly 9.3 million new cases and 2 million deaths a year, most of which occurring in developing countries. Besides its public health impact, tuberculosis continues to be a challenge for holistic development. Lack of proper knowledge regarding treatment of tuberculosis and consequences of default...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>