<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Internet and Information Systems - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Internet and Information Systems</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Performance comparison of in-memory and disk-based databases using transaction processing performance council (TPC) benchmarking</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/D74EDF358447</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/D74EDF358447</guid><description>
	Database performance throughput is one of the main measurements of the application effectiveness or a system, in terms of speed and delivery. Higher application efficiency is always a goal for any organization; therefore, finding the way to improve the database performance has priority. There are two main factors that can contribute to performance gain or slowness. Firstly, how well designed...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Information Communication and Technology (ICT) diffusion and inequality in Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/8AB838465759</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/8AB838465759</guid><description>
	This study aims to examine the link between inequality and diffusion of Information Communication and Technology (ICT). It focuses on a set of 32 African countries. ICT diffusion rate for all the countries was calculated. Two estimation techniques were used: Fractional Regression Model method and Ordinary Least Squares. The results indicate that inequality contributed to the development of I...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges to enforcement of cyber-crimes laws 
and policy
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/930ADF960210</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/930ADF960210</guid><description>
	Cybercrime, a concept which to date has defied a globally accepted definition, appears to be the latest scourge plaguing man and same has occupied the cynosure. The word cybercrime is on the lips of almost everyone involved in the use of the computer and Internet, be it individual, corporate, organization, national, multinational or international. The attention accorded cybercrimes is not fa...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cybercaf&#xE9;s operations and its incessant closure in Delta State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/D002DF750036</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/D002DF750036</guid><description>
	The general purpose of this study is to identify the reasons responsible for closure of cybercafs in Delta State, Nigeria. Questionnaire was designed in line with the objectives of the study and used to gather data for the research. The data gathered were analyzed and presented using charts. The study revealed that there was incessant closure of cybercafs in the two sites (Abraka and Asaba) ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The information management practices of Bahirdar University
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/369E8EF43621</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/369E8EF43621</guid><description>
	Recognizing the importance of information management systems, Bahirdar University introduced its student information management system in 2009. However, studies had not been conducted on the functioning of this system. This study, therefore, examined the information management practices of the University. The academic leaders, core process owners, and the system administrators were the resea...</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The magnitude of barriers facing e-commerce businesses in Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/1DA946043626</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/1DA946043626</guid><description>
	The aim of the paper was to examine comprehensively, the internal and external factors of organisations which affect the future of electronic commerce (e-commerce) and the magnitude of these constraints in Kenya, using the systems framework. The research methodology used a questionnaire survey (internet survey) to collect data from 137 e-commerce businesses out of which 74 or 54.01% usable q...</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Review on network performance: Meaning, quantification and measurement</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/0172D9840142</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/0172D9840142</guid><description>
	

	This paper surveys various literatures on network performance with main focus on three main issues: its meaning, quantification and measurement. The essence of performance in communication systems is discussed and its meaning explored. Further, we look at relationship between network performance and its characteristics. The weaknesses in literature are disclosed with respect to how perf...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Wired LAN Overall Performance Model (LOPM) </title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/371B35840147</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/371B35840147</guid><description>
	

	This paper presents development of the wired LAN overall performance model. We investigated theperformance characteristics of major LAN components, that is, media, protocols, traffic and devices;determined the main characteristics amongst them and their interrelation; and applied mathematicalprinciples to develop a model which captures the overall network performance in terms of itschar...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A survey on faculty members&#x2019; perspective on digital library plus</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/BBA9D059036</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/BBA9D059036</guid><description>
	

	The aim of this paper is to evaluate accessibility, usability, and usefulness of digital library plus (dl+) from the faculty members perspective. A questionnaire was prepared, and sent to the email address of all participants who had registered in digital library plus. Data analysis shows that only a few number of faculty members are interested to register in digital library and use it....</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An e-farming framework for sustainable agricultural development in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/535F4189011</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JIIS/article-abstract/535F4189011</guid><description>
	

	The concept of e-farming has been described as the integration and utilization of information technology (IT) in farming related operations. Farming is a traditional trade and operations involved in production have largely remained habitual in nature. Traditional methods of farming incorporated little to no use of IT, despite its potential for dramatically increasing operations efficien...</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>