<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Languages and Culture - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Languages and Culture</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Orality, performance and creativity: A descriptive perspective of the Izon Obobo bi necromancy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/EA73BA763405</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/EA73BA763405</guid><description>
	African traditional literature is fraught with songs, dances, riddles, jokes, proverbs as well as chants, incantations, invocation, rituals and musical performances. Some of these features are found in earlier poet, Christopher Okigbos Labyrinths and comparatively recent poet, Christian Otobotekeres A Sailors Son: in the wake of dance and games. Oral poetry in Iz&#x1ECD;n tradition is diverse but o...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Looking at Chinese parent-teenager conflict talks from the perspective of the rapport management theory</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/3BBD59963585</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/3BBD59963585</guid><description>
	As a common but complex linguistic phenomenon, conflict talks (CTs) frequently occur in daily communications. This study aims to carry out analyses of parent-teenager CTs in two Chinese TV series A Love for Separation and Home with Kids to reveal the three steps of CTs. From the perspective of the rapport management theory, this study mainly centers on probing into the causes as well as the ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Verbal semiotics resources employed in advertising cigarette on TV in Indonesia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/2CA772560742</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/2CA772560742</guid><description>
	This work analyzes the verbal semiotics resources used for advertising cigarette in Indonesia. Descriptive qualitative method was used in this study. The data of this study are verbal semiotics resources (oral and written) used for cigarette advertisement. From the result of this work, it is seen that in ideational function, material process was dominantly used in advertising cigarette on TV...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Insertion strategies used with lone English verbs in otherwise Igbo utterances</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/49CF93B59326</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/49CF93B59326</guid><description>
	Using examples of tape recorded conversational data from fifty educated adult Igbo-English bilinguals resident in Port Harcourt, Nigeria, this paper demonstrates that lone English verbs are typically inserted into otherwise Igbo utterances by means of Igbo verbal inflectional morphology. Other verbs are adjoined to a helping verb from Igbo, specifically involving an adapted form. Yet, a few ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Destruction of Abbay Choman Oromo indigenous practice due to Gojjame invasion, north east Wollega South of Abay River, Ethiopia (1870s - 1882)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/4DD94FC58880</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/4DD94FC58880</guid><description>
	This paper deals with the destruction of Oromo indigenous practices under Gojjame rule: the case of Abbay Choman Oromo, in the south of Abay River 1870s-1882. The year 1870s was a turning point in the history of the Oromo of Abbay Choman in particular and Horro Guduru in general because it was a period when Gadaa system with indigenous practice starts being destructed. The year 1882 was the ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges of students&#x2019; discipline in English as a Foreign Language (EFL) classes: A case of primary schools in Dembi Dollo and Nekemte towns of Oromia Region, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/F28BD6458253</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/F28BD6458253</guid><description>
	In many cultures in the world, discipline is a very important quality of students in schools. Thus, the prime objective of this study was to explore major factors contributing to students discipline problems in some primary schools of Dambi Dollo and Nekemte Towns in Ethiopia. To achieve the objective, basic research questions were developed, related literatures were reviewed and different m...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Standing straight with the title, &#x2018;As this miserable and fungus-like small plant becomes a big and favourite tree&#x2019; adapted from the Tcheonzamun poem (753rd to 768th)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/8FF3D2456007</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/8FF3D2456007</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study is to know the bi-language mask of Tcheonzamun expression; the real meaning. The researchers utilized two methods: interpretation through Korean pronunciation and utilization of Chinese character. The aim of this work is to explain in plain terms the title of this work, As the miserable and fungus-like small plant becomes a big and favourite tree. The researchers tr...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Syntactic translation and semantic implications: The case of Fulfulde and English</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/6FC9E9555693</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/6FC9E9555693</guid><description>
	It has been a general consensus that translation is an exercise of transferring a message, initially written or spoken in one language, into another language for the benefit of those who do not understand the initial language. The researchers provided some definitions of language since translation is also a language based exercise. It is also to be noted that translation can be based on vari...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Tracing the local culture in a reading book</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/4309E1B66009</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/4309E1B66009</guid><description>
	There is a strong relationship between language and culture, both carries the DNA samples of one another, which makes it hard to imagine English as a Foreign Language (EFL) in classrooms and textbooks without any reference to target culture(s). Therefore, teaching a language cannot be thought only as teaching grammatical structures of the target language, but also teaching the culture(s) of ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Language attrition in bicultural bilinguals: Evidence from Neo-Aramaic animal metaphors</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/A22389B65395</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLC/article-abstract/A22389B65395</guid><description>
	Animal-based metaphors are ubiquitous in natural languages with distinct cross-cultural implications. In this study, these conventional or dead metaphors, so to speak, are used as a tool to measure language erosion and cultural integration. We assumed that Neo-Aramaic-English bicultural bilinguals (NA-E) and Canadian-English speakers (CE) have the linguistic and cultural capacity necessary t...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>