<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Law and Conflict Resolution - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Law and Conflict Resolution</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Conspicuously absent: Women&#x2019;s role in conflict resolution and peace building in northern Uganda in the context of United Nations resolution 1325</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/C72AE9262710</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/C72AE9262710</guid><description>
	The study, Conspicuously Absent: Womens Role in Conflict Resolution and Peace Building in Northern Uganda in the Context of United Nations Resolution 1325. The research was carried out in war ravaged Acholi sub region covering the districts of Amuru, Gulu, Kitgum and Pader because they are located in the centre of Northern Uganda conflict between the Government and the rebels commonly known ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Critical appraisal of the Ethiopian Reconciliation Commission: A comparative study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/F233A4263625</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/F233A4263625</guid><description>
	This paper examined the Ethiopian Reconciliation Commission establishment proclamation with a view to assessing the Commissions probable effectiveness to attain its short, medium and long-term goals as a transitional justice accountability measure. For the purpose of critical appraisal, different factors which appear in the literature to be crucial to the effectiveness of truth commissions s...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The contentious relationship between Africa and the International Criminal Court (ICC)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/BDEC46257648</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/BDEC46257648</guid><description>
	The International Criminal Court (ICC) established in 2002 under the Rome Statute with significant support from African States, which comprise thirty percent of the ICCs total membership. After nearly two decades in operation, the ICC has issued a number of indictments to both sitting and ex-African leaders. The African Union has criticized these indictments citing that the court seems to be...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Estimating the impact of state government spending and the economy on crime rates</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/40D750956167</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/40D750956167</guid><description>
	The determinants of crime have been an area of numerous studies over time. In spite of this volume of work, interest in the causes of crime continues to persist. This paper investigates the determinants of variations in crime rates in the United States using cross-sectional state-level data. It explores the role of government spending and socio-economic variables and compares these determina...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Administration of Justice in Nigeria : Analysing the Dominant Legal Ideology
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/614930155699</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/614930155699</guid><description>
	The paper critically examined the dominant legal ideology of the Nigerian judges and their attitudes towards statutory interpretation. This was done in the light of the traditional and modern methods, and techniques of judicial reasoning and decision making. It condemned the strict constructionist legal approach which appears to be the pervading orientation of the judges and called for a tru...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Management of transboundary natural resources</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/90F760F66905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/90F760F66905</guid><description>
	Transboundary natural resources management means any process of cooperation across boundaries that facilitates or improves the management of natural resources (to the benefit of all parties in the area concerned). Because of their importance, these natural resources must be protected and managed in a way that will prevent their degradation and damage. Actual cases proved that joint managemen...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing the efficacy of alternative dispute resolution (ADR) in the settlement of environmental disputes in the Niger Delta Region of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/92A256E65636</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/92A256E65636</guid><description>
	This study presents a detailed and critical review of the Alternative Dispute Resolution as a non-judicial mechanism for the settlement of environmental disputes in the Niger Delta region of Nigeria. Ordinarily, disputes whether environmental or otherwise are resolved through court processes, but due to delays, costs, publicity and technicality associated with litigation, alternative dispute...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Trademark dispute settlement in Malaysia: A comparative analysis with the TRIPS and the Paris convention</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/DAEBDB265459</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/DAEBDB265459</guid><description>
	Trademark is a mark, name, sign, smell or a sound, which distinguishes goods and services of one undertaking, from goods and services of other undertakings. Malaysia had the trademark ordinance 1950; which is repealed by the trademark act 1976 and thereunder, the trademark regulations are made in 1997. The trademark dispute arises between the parties, at the time of the registration of the t...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Corporate responsibility for environmental crime in Indonesia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/D428B6165071</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/D428B6165071</guid><description>
	According to Indonesian law, corporations involve in environmental crime can be held accountable, and may be subject to criminal sanctions. Criminal sanctions can be imposed against those who give orders or the leaders of the corporations. They can be imposed on corporations or their leaders. Sanctions can be fines, restrictions from certain activities with strict principles.

	Key words: ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An appraisal of the regulatory framework for the protection of consumers in the communications sector in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/C78BDB261535</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLCR/article-abstract/C78BDB261535</guid><description>
	The communications sector in Nigeria has witnessed an enormous growth since 1992 when it was liberalized and deregulated. However, much more significant developments have been witnessed since 2001 when the Global System for Mobile Networks (GSM) were licensed to operate as private players in the sector. This examined the existing legal and institutional framework for the operations of these ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>