<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Land Management and Appraisal - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Land Management and Appraisal</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Comparative analysis of risks and returns on residential property sub-market in Lagos: Case study of 1004 Estate</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/0904D9260916</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/0904D9260916</guid><description>
	The study appraised the viability of investing in residential real estate submarket in Lagos State, using the apartments in 1004 Estate as case study with a view to providing a guide for investors and portfolio managers on investment decision-making in Lagos. Lagos, a mega city being a point of attraction to real estate investors makes it necessary to undertake real estate investment perform...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Utilization of valuations for secured lending in Abuja, the federal capital city of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/A6A050760443</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/A6A050760443</guid><description>
	Utilization of secured lending valuations (SLV) by deposit money banks (DMBs) has not been sufficiently investigated in Abuja, Nigeria. Adequacy of the reports, factors influencing their use and how DMBs utilized them for loans were examined. Primary data collected from Estate Valuation (ESV) firms and DMBs were analyzed. Although the study showed that substantial portions of the report were...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of exchange rate volatility on medium/high income residential real estate investment returns In NigeriaEffects of exchange rate volatility on medium/high income residential real estate investment returns In Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/45D6A1858925</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/45D6A1858925</guid><description>
	This paper investigated the effects of Naira/Dollar exchange rate volatility on medium and high income residential real estate investment returns in Nigeria using EG ARCH model. It used time series data for an 11 year period between 2000 and 2010. The findings of the study reveal that exchange rate volatility has a significant negative effect on medium income and high income residential real...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Home ownership determinants of the hausa-fulani ethnic group in Lagos, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/535D7A558931</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/535D7A558931</guid><description>
	Although many studies have been conducted in I he developed and developing world on the determinants of home ownership, very few attempts have been made to reveal these determinants in Nigeria. This study IK/.V designed to explore the determinants of home ownership among the Hausa-Fulani ethnic group lit Lagos, the most urbanized city in Nigeria, Multinomial Logit Model of three tenure choic...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Application of Quantitative Risk Assessment Techniques in Property Investment Appraisal in Enugu Urban, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/DB9D3BE58643</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/DB9D3BE58643</guid><description>
	Property investment projects are frequently subjected to unpredictable future, encompassing uncertainties and various forms of risks which impact the anticipated level of returns that should compensate for risks taken by investors. The level of sophistication in property investment risk assessment is quite elementary compared to other investment media. This state of affairs has led to projec...</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Compliant to automated approach in managing residential income properties of Enugu State Housing Development Corporation (ESHDC)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/C27D24658927</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/C27D24658927</guid><description>
	Prior to the emergence of automated management approach to real property administration, manual method of operation has been predominant in running the transactions of real property management in Nigeria, Increase in demand for quality and prompt services due to corresponding growth in housing needs are major issues facing Enugu Stale Housing Development Corporation (ESHDC). The study examin...</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effective land management as an indispensable tool for improved revenue in Enugu State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/ADF9AA458934</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JLMA/article-abstract/ADF9AA458934</guid><description>
	The collapse of the global oil prices has compelled the various States and Local Governments Of Nigeria to seek alternative sources of revenue to augment the dwindling revenue allocations from the Federal Government. Land has been identified as the alternative source of revenue. Such revenue will come as direct income or tax revenue. The fund-based taxes include among others tenement rates, ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>