<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Microbiology and Antimicrobials - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Microbiology and Antimicrobials</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Bactericidal activities of the leaf extract of Spondias mombin L. plant used for culinary and therapeutically purposes in Ivory Coast</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/0E1A2D262905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/0E1A2D262905</guid><description>
	The leaves of Spondias mombin L. consumed as infusion in Ivory Coast are used to treat gastrointestinal disorders such as diarrhea. In this study, the leaves extract, after purification by the ethyl acetate method, was evaluated for its effect on growth and cell viability of two Gram positive bacteria (Staphylococcus aureus ATCC25923 and Listeria monocytogenes ATCC25051) and four Gram negati...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of the microbial quality of seafood and effects of salt concentration and temperature on isolated microorganisms</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/D0D4A4362962</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/D0D4A4362962</guid><description>
	Seafood is part of a healthful diet, but seafood consumption is not risk-free because of sea contaminations by anthropogenic activities and environmental factors. Their microbiological quality is of major concern to the food processors, consumers and public health authorities hence the need for proper assessment of the microbial quality. This study therefore characterizes pathogenic microorg...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Occurrence and antibiotic susceptibility of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus in fresh milk and milk products in Nasarawa State, North-Central Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/EC7F32763407</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/EC7F32763407</guid><description>
	Methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) keeps emerging as a pathogen of significant public health concern. In this study, the occurrence and antibiogram of MRSA from fresh milk and milk products sold in Nasarawa State, north-central Nigeria, were determined. A total of 180 samples comprising of fresh milk, bulk milk, nono and kindirmo were collected and examined for the presence o...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antimicrobial resistance pattern in Salmonella enterica from clinical and poultry sources in Calabar, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/3B7859161641</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/3B7859161641</guid><description>
	Limited treated options to Salmonellosis exist due to the emergence of extended spectrum beta lactamases (ESBLs). This study determined the prevalence of common ESBL genes (blaSHV, blaCTX-M, blaOXA) and profiled their antimicrobial resistance drug pattern. A descriptive cross-sectional study that involved 16 Salmonella enterica isolates from diarrhoeic children at the University of Calabar T...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Detection of antibiotic resistant bacteria and sterol concentration in hand dug wells cited near pit latrine in Southwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/E339BB762046</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/E339BB762046</guid><description>
	Provision of safe water and improvement in sanitation has led to a reduction in occurrence of diseases, especially water borne diseases but citing of pit latrine near these wells can be of health concern. Assessment of microbiological quality, feacal sterol concentration and antibiotic resistant pattern of isolated bacteria from hand dug well in Oko, Nigeria were carried out during dry and r...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determinants of antimicrobial use in diarrhoea management among under-five children in Zomba, Malawi</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/6480CC162152</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/6480CC162152</guid><description>
	Diarrhoea is one of the most common infections that under-five children suffer from across the world. Antibiotics remains one of the common measures used to treat the infection, which has led to increased usage; nevertheless, the extent to which an individual is prompted to use antibiotics in managing diarrhoea in the Malawian setting is not clearly known. This study was aimed at establishin...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Plasmid curing of antibiotic resistant Escherichia coli isolates from urine and stool samples</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/8C0785D61431</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/8C0785D61431</guid><description>
	The origin of bacteria resistance to antibiotics can either be chromosomal or extra-chromosomal (plasmid mediated) and one way of determining the origin of bacterial drug resistance is by plasmid elimination. In this study, the antibiotic susceptibility of seven Escherichia coli isolates (numbered 1-7) from urine and stool samples, were assessed using the disk diffusion method. The 10 antibi...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phytochemical screening and antibacterial susceptibility of Escherichia coli O157:H7 isolates on Acacia ataxacantha leaves</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/B1C60DE57475</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/B1C60DE57475</guid><description>
	Acacia ataxacanta leaves were screened for possible constituents, and the antimicrobial properties of the leaves were tested against 18 isolates of Escherichia coli O157:H7. The leaves were aseptically collected and crude extracts were prepared by cold maceration in 98% methanol. Phytochemical analysis for bioactive constituents revealed that it contained carbohydrates, cardiac glycosides, s...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibiotic resistance patterns of bacterial isolates from hatcheries and selected fish farms in the Ashanti 
region of Ghana
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/D983F7F65898</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/D983F7F65898</guid><description>
	Antibiotic resistance has become an increasingly global health problem. This has resulted in a limited number of antibiotics being effective in the treatment of various infections. Antibiotic resistant organisms have been isolated from fish ponds in various studies in different parts of the world. This study was carried out to assess some fish farming practices among catfish and tilapia farm...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Elevated temperature induced resistance markers&#x2019; reduction of some selected clinical bacterial pathogens</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/7186ED065362</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMA/article-abstract/7186ED065362</guid><description>
	Axenic cultures of Klebsiella pneumoniae, Escherichia coli and Staphylococcus aureus obtained from the Medical Microbiology Laboratory of the Delta State University Teaching Hospital, Oghara, were inoculated into ten-fold serial dilutions of 10-1 to 10-7 in sterile Nutrient broth and incubated in water bath at 37C for 18 h initially. The turbid broth cultures of 10-5, 10-6 and 10-7 dilutions...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>