<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Media and Communication Studies - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Media and Communication Studies</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Desensitization of the Lebanese audience to the portrayal of violence on Game of Thrones and Breaking Bad: A case study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/77E642C63183</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/77E642C63183</guid><description>
	This research investigated the desensitization signs shown by the Lebanese audience to the violence portrayed on Game of Thrones and Breaking Bad. The researchs study was a qualitative case study of the theory of desensitization applied on two Lebanese participants, each watching respectively the series Breaking Bad and Game of Thrones. The participants were chosen based on the fact that one...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Literature review of sexual reproductive health campaign messages: What are the milestones and potential research topics within the Kenyan context?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/4FFA83C62185</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/4FFA83C62185</guid><description>
	This paper presents a literature review of the sexual reproductive health campaign messages and highlights the milestones in the existing literature. The review begins with definition of health campaign messages and other key concepts. The subject is then situated within the discipline of communication studies particularly within the branch of health communication. A review of relevant theor...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A study on the effect of 13 Reasons Why on young adults with low self-esteem</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/A629FE961802</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/A629FE961802</guid><description>
	The study was designed to examine the effect of 13 Reasons Why on 216 young adults with low self-esteem. Survey method was used to obtain the responses from the samples, before and after watching 13 Reasons Why. The findings of the study revealed that, 13 Reasons Why improved self-esteem in the female samples alone. No improvement in self-esteem was observed in the male samples.

	

	Key...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Facebook use among Nigerians in Houston Texas USA</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/A2A051461902</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/A2A051461902</guid><description>
	Social Media came into our world in the 21st century and changed the way things are done, knitting itself into the fabric of everyday living. It has opened the world in ways that was unimagined in previous decades, connecting people through time and space. Being one of the largest immigrant groups in Houston Texas, this study investigates how Nigerians have embraced the new medium as Diaspor...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>An exploration into the revival path of Peking Opera in the perspective of "Cooperative Communication": Discussion on the dispute between Leehom Wang and Peiyu Wang in a Chinese Talk Show</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/520881661511</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/520881661511</guid><description>
	November 4th, 2018, in the first episode of the third season of the Tucao Conference, a most popular talk show in China, pop singer Leehom Wang and Peking Opera actor Peiyu Wang debated whether pop songs should be incorporated with elements of Peking Opera. Peiyu Wang believes that young people should give themselves the opportunity to listen to Peking Opera. Pop songs should not encroach on...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The voices of culture, conservation and the media event around bullfight &#x2018;Jallikattu&#x2019; in Tamil Nadu, India</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/75BE85960500</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/75BE85960500</guid><description>
	In the Southern Indian State of Tamil Nadu, the traditional Jallikattu sport involving young men competing against bulls is described as one of the ancient living sports in the modern era. Based on petitions by animal rights groups, the Supreme Court of India banned the ancient sport of Jallikattu in 2014 on the grounds of animal cruelty. The ban of this traditional sport ignited protests cu...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparison of the effects of cognitive age and advertising credibility of the elderly on reading advertising with different information loads</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/F6D94F960501</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/F6D94F960501</guid><description>
	This study aims to find the different effects on the elderly caused by reading advertising with different information loads due to differences of cognitive age and advertising credibility. Young adults and middle-aged adults are compared with the elderly. The results reveal that different ages show differences in cognitive age but not in advertising credibility. Most of the respondents in th...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Delving into the political role of the media: An analysis of South Africa&#x2019;s mail and guardian and the online reception of its electioneering message</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/D59F3FD60309</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/D59F3FD60309</guid><description>
	Research trends illustrate that media institutions have a role in influencing the citizenry through their political communication objectives. This research paper grapples with the idea of the press as a political actor in South Africa. This has been done through the analysis of online comments responding to the Mail  Guardians editorial message/communiqu on its political position during the ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The changing nature of &#x201C;News Reporting, Story Development and Editing&#x201D;</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/E232DB059328</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/E232DB059328</guid><description>
	With advancements in technology in this age of globalization and digital media, the nature of News Reporting, Story Development and Editing across the United States have been constantly evolving. Through a systematic secondary research, the current research would examine various factors which led to the evolutionary journey of News Reporting, when there was simply a man behind a desk deliver...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Does mobile technology increase the diversity of news? A content analysis of news notifications on mobile phones</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/7CD346C59330</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMCS/article-abstract/7CD346C59330</guid><description>
	Through conducting a content analysis of news notifications on the mobile media platform, the current study mainly finds that 1) no agenda correlation exists among legacy media outlets; 2) an agenda correlation is found between non-legacy media outlets and legacy media outlets; 3) in terms of news pushing frequencies, non-legacy media outlets, and legacy media outlets share different news pu...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>