<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Music and Dance - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Music and Dance</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>The Basarwa melon throwing circle dance (Siqciru/Sigcuru): The case of Kaudwane village in Kweneng West District of Botswana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/006613B62391</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/006613B62391</guid><description>
	This paper aims at examining the practical use of the melon dance by Basarwa (San) of Kaudwane village in the Kweneng West District of Botswana. Basarwa is a group of people who originate from the Central Kgalagadi Game Reserve (CKGR). Taking into consideration the Basarwa traditional way of life, this research focuses mainly on women and girls as the main participants of the melon dance mus...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Perceiving patterns of ratios when they are converted from relative durations to melody and from cross rhythms to harmony</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/050A98255768</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/050A98255768</guid><description>
	This research aims to study the perception of relative durational and cross-rhythm patterns when they are converted into melodic or harmonic patterns. Twenty-four international students from Groningen conservatoire were given twenty- four trials; twelve deals with their melodic/harmonic perception ability and the other twelve deals with the ability to perceive the converted rhythmical patter...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Efforts to improve music education in Turkey</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/633521564834</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/633521564834</guid><description>
	It is seen how state policies are effective in education when it is thought that education is organized according to the principle of making the individual useful for the community. Given that education policies should be effective in all areas of education, music education is expected to be present in a common political attitude in the fields of general, ethical and professional music educa...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Girl child education and enrollment drive: The role of traditional music and dance</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/9BFA36261232</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/9BFA36261232</guid><description>
	The study is set out from an intervention perspective using music and dance as a vehicle for enhancing the enrollment drive and retention of girls in basic schools. It was a qualitative research under the auspices of Ghana Wins project that involved pupils, parents and teachers of New Winneba Municipal Assembly Primary and Junior High School to deepen their understanding on how Music and Dan...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Framework for music improvisation and performance: Body/instrument and body/mind connections</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/4F44E0257447</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/4F44E0257447</guid><description>
	This study elucidates connections between the body and music presenting a proposal based on workshops and a theoretical viewpoint. Firstly it describes the main principles of the workshops that have been developed to work with music improvisation and group interactions. At the workshops the study approach music improvisation based on the dialogues and transformation of musical processes and ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Expressing joy through hip-hop dance steps: Focus on new jack swing</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/F75963457217</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/F75963457217</guid><description>
	This study aimed to differentiate hip-hop dance steps based on whether joy was expressed and explained their movement features using three-dimensional motion analysis. Ten male and female participants (26.9  12.8 years old) were instructed to perform an 80-second hip-hop dance, and the step performed after 60 s (new jack swing) was analyzed. Discriminant analysis was conducted, and the diffe...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring the complexities of black male identities in South African theatre dance</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/E0D801855094</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/E0D801855094</guid><description>
	The perception of professional black male dancers in black communities in South Africa is that of a homosexual man. However, little if any systematic research has investigated the validity of this stereotype, much less the reasons why male sexual orientation would be associated with interest in dance. Many male dance figures pursuing dance as a career in Cape Town, South Africa have often be...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A synchronic study of semantics in selected Akan choral compositions in Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/2AF3FAE53593</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/2AF3FAE53593</guid><description>
	In the performance traditions of choral music in Ghanaian community, understanding the text of the music is but one facet of extremely important aspects in performance. Unfortunately, some of the texts of some recent choral music compositions lack linguistic semantic representations. Performers are only mindful of the rhythm, melody and its associated harmony without even if the meaning of t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The technical reviews of Ligeti Piano Etude No.4 Fanfares</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/1412D1052523</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/1412D1052523</guid><description>
	Ligetis etude Fanfares extends the technical skills demanded of the modern pianist and many incorporate completely new techniques. This etude, which was composed around 1985 consists of some of the most technically demanding issues composed for the piano in the last decades of the 20th century. Through the study of this work the pianist is pushed in new directions as Ligeti extends the limit...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Playing out loud: Jazz music and social protest</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/5AEAC5251488</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMD/article-abstract/5AEAC5251488</guid><description>
	This article addresses the historical relationship between jazz music and political commentary. Departing from the analysis of historical recordings and bibliography, this work will examine the circumstances in which jazz musicians assumed attitudes of political and social protest through music. These attitudes resulted in the establishment of a close bond between some jazz musicians and the...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>