<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Mechanical Engineering Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Mechanical Engineering Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Design and fabrication of a motorized rice hulling machine</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/373B41D63697</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/373B41D63697</guid><description>
	Rice is one of the most important cereal crop in the world. This paper present the design and performance evaluation of a rice hulling machine fabricated for removing chaffs from paddy rice as the consumers demand for rice requires the most hygienic, easy and less time consuming process. The design was segmented into the hopper and housing (processing) unit, the frame support and the power t...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Relevance of modeling and simulation in the management of engineering projects</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/195BD1E56772</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/195BD1E56772</guid><description>
	Project management is one of the most important and poorly understood areas of management. Delays and cost overruns are common in projects such as construction, power generation, defense, software, product development, etc. Project management is affected by problems relating to costing and scheduling. Changes in the design of customer creates costly ripple effects which in turn lead to delay...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Research on heat transfer enhancement of variable cross sectional conformal cooling of injection mold based on fluent</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/5FECA0A56729</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/5FECA0A56729</guid><description>
	The purpose of this paper is to present a technique of variable cross section conformal cooling channels (VCCC) to compare the cooling effect of moulds with equal section channel experimentally. The influence of the size structure parameters of the variable cross section conformal cooling channel on heat transfer is studied. It is found that the ratio of D/d=1.4 has the best effect of enhanc...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Vibration in systems</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/8F2C3A055679</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/8F2C3A055679</guid><description>
	The unhealthy and destructive motion exhibited in moving, operating or rotating machinery is called vibration. It is also observed as any oscillatory motion of a mechanical system about its equilibrium point. Clearly, vibration can thus be unhealthy and destructive which is the reason for its undesirability. However, it can also be good and useful as observed in some mechanical and construct...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Frictional effect on stress and displacement fields in contact region</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/4212E2966176</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/4212E2966176</guid><description>
	In this study, by applying Giannakopoulos and Pallots stress and displacement equations, and using the Goryachevas friction model, the stress and displacement equations are obtained. Finally, by applying analytical method, these equations are solved. By assuming that the roller is rigid and the substrate is almost homogeneous with constant Poisson ratio and constant elastic modulus, the resu...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Synthesis of hyperboloid gear drives: Controlling of the singularity on the active tooth surfaces</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/CDBF74165273</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/CDBF74165273</guid><description>
	The study illustrates the mathematical model, applied to the synthesis of hyperboloid gear drives with taking into account the singularity appearance on the contacting active tooth surfaces. A kinematic approach for registration of the singularity on the tooth surfaces of the synthesized spatial transmissions is shown. The analytical dependencies applicable for defining and controlling of th...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Optimization of R134a cross vane expander compressor refrigeration system oriented to COP</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/3059C8164846</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/3059C8164846</guid><description>
	Cross vane expander compressor (CVEC) is a newly invented expander-compressor combined unit, where it is introduced to replace the compressor and the expansion valve in traditional refrigeration system. The mathematical model of CVEC has been developed to examine its performance and it was found that the energy consumption of a conventional refrigeration system was reduced by as much as 18%....</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mathematical modeling, simulation and analysis of rice grain movement for design and fabrication of low-cost winnowing machine</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/0A9066362207</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/0A9066362207</guid><description>
	Winnowing called Dhan Battaune in Nepali is the process of separation of unwanted matters from paddy after threshing. In the conventional method; it requires at least four person to produce strong wind by bamboo basket (Nanglo in Nepali) to blow away straw, leaves of grasses and other unwanted matters; process starting with one of them pouring the sun dried grains from certain height. To per...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Application of augmented finite element and cohesive zone modelling to predict damage evolution in metal matrix composites and aircraft coatings</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/C7BC4E858951</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/C7BC4E858951</guid><description>
	This paper reports on the application of a special purpose finite element analysis tool that combines augmented finite element methodologies (AFEM) and cohesive zone model (CZM) methods to simulate initiation and propagation of both cohesive and adhesive cracks. The constitutive behaviour of an aluminium/silicon carbide metal matrix composite was predicted and compared with experimental data...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Investigation of compressive properties of 3D fiber reinforced polymeric (FRP) composites through combined end and shear loading</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/80B399455155</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMER/article-abstract/80B399455155</guid><description>
	The failure mechanisms and failure stress states of 2D and 3D FRP composite is investigated through experimental work, SEM, finite element analysis and failure theories. In this research work, feasibility of ASTM standard D6641 is investigated for testing of 3D FRP composite. A 3D finite element model is developed in ABAQUS with homogeneous orthotropic laminate to investigate the failure str...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>