<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Medical Genetics and Genomics - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Medical Genetics and Genomics</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>The impact of genome information on mate selection: From the African perspective</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/2DE4E6066807</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/2DE4E6066807</guid><description>
	Mate selection in humans is an important social activity which is central to every individuals life. The debate on the ethics of generating and using genetic information has been of concern to several researchers from the time of the completion of the human genome project till now. Some of the important questions to consider include whether it is ethical to generate and use genetic informati...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of BNC2 as a new candidate gene for hypospadias</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/A4532C651932</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/A4532C651932</guid><description>
	In order to evaluate the use of the BNC2 gene in clinical practice regarding hypospadias, the presence of the impact of mutations in BNC2 gene in males who had been treated surgically for hypospadias in Sweden (N=413) and controls (N=455) were evaluated. Mutational screening was performed using Sanger sequencing and genotyping by Taqman allelic discrimination, and the findings were evaluated...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Meta-analysis of methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) A1298C polymorphism and risk of orofacial cleft</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/9A932D245888</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/9A932D245888</guid><description>
	Polymorphisms in key genes involving the folate pathway have been reported to be associated with the risk of orofacial cleft (OFC) and several studies were published with conflicting results. A meta-analysis of the previous studies of allelic association between OFC with A1298C polymorphisms of the methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) gene was carried out. Odds ratios (ORs) with 95% c...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The codon 17 polymorphism of the CTLA4 gene in type 1 diabetes mellitus in the Baghdad population</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/F006C4642843</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/F006C4642843</guid><description>
	The aim of this work was to study the polymorphism in CTLA4 gene in insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus (IDDM) type I patients in Baghdad population. To achieve this goal, blood samples were collected from 80 IDDM (40 males and 40 females) and 20 samples of healthy, DNA was isolated and the CTLA4 gene (A 152 bp fragment) were amplified by using specific primers for exon1 of this gene, and th...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mutation N308T of protein tyrosine phosphatase SHP-2 in two Senegalese patients with Noonan syndrome</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/F0E6D6E42844</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/F0E6D6E42844</guid><description>
	Noonan syndrome is a genetic autosomal dominant disorder characterized by facial dysmorphy, short stature, delayed puberty and congenital heart defects. The first gene implicated in this syndrome is PTPN11, encoding protein tyrosine phosphatase SHP-2. Several studies worldwide have identified missense mutations in this gene in patients with Noonan syndrome. Our objective focused on mutations...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A study of correlation between CYP2C9 gene polymorphism and Warfarin maintenance dose in anticoagulant therapy among Han people in 
Yunnan of China
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/D4B07C242845</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/D4B07C242845</guid><description>
	In this study, we investigated the correlation between CYP2C9 gene polymorphism and maintenance dose of Warfarin in 300 patients who were the Han population derived from the Affiliated Yan An Hospital of Kunming Medical University in Yunnan Province of China, subjected to the operation of cardiac valve replacement and Warfarin oral administration post operation from 2008 to 2009 by detecting...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Association of insertion/deletion polymorphism of Alu angiotensin converting enzyme insertion/deletion genotype with type 2 diabetes mellitus and hypertension in J&amp;K population:
A case control study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/407E17A9026</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/407E17A9026</guid><description>
	The objective of the study is to know the frequencies of insertion/deletion (I/D) allele and association of angiotensin converting enzyme (ACE), I/D polymorphism in Jammu and Kashmir (JK) populations in relation to type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and hypertension (HTN). A total of 500 individuals were recruited for the present study. Out of these 500 individuals, 250 individuals had T2DM and...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Preparation and partial characterization of monoclonal antibody against human phosphdiesterase 5 (PDE5)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/CBC0F609054</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/CBC0F609054</guid><description>
	Phosphodiesterase 5 (PDE5) is a catalytic enzyme for degradation of cyclic guanosine monophosphate (cGMP) in human smooth muscle cells. Inhibition of this enzyme by certain chemicals including sildenafil, vardenafil and tadalafil, is considered a breakthrough treatment of erectile dysfunction. Unfortunately, these drugs are associated with several side effects. In this study, another strateg...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Teeth are bones: Signature genes and molecules that underwrite odontogenesis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/11E1D288995</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/11E1D288995</guid><description>
	Understanding the molecular genetics of odontogenesis (tooth development) can unlock innovative avenues to genetically engineer teeth for therapy. In this review, emerging insights into the genetic and molecular bases of tooth development are presented. Four conserved signature genes express master molecules (fibroblast growth factors, bone morphogenetic proteins, wingless integrated ligands...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase C677T gene polymorphism associated risk factor in the patients of recurrent pregnancy loss</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/4D998F69006</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMGG/article-abstract/4D998F69006</guid><description>
	The etiology of human recurrent fetal loss is associated with methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) C677T gene polymorphism. Several conflicting reports on MTHFR gene polymorphism increases the curiosity, with the aims to evaluate the prevalence of MTHFR gene in recurrent miscarriage cases using PCR-RFLP analysis. The present findings reveal that the highest (26.7%) incidence was obser...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>