<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Medical Laboratory and Diagnosis - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Medical Laboratory and Diagnosis</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Designing an expert system model for pulmonary TB disease diagnose pre-screen laboratory process</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/7E9DAEA62222</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/7E9DAEA62222</guid><description>
	Tuberculosis is a major public health problem in Ethiopia more than half a century ago. If the disease is not treated well and on time, it can lead to severe health problems like lungs, but can also affect other organs, including the central nervous system. Therefore, detecting those diseases at early stages enable us to overcome and treat them appropriately. However, among people in the dev...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The impact of needle diameter and penetration depth of safety lancets on blood volume and pain perception in 300 volunteers: A randomized controlled trial</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/62E663E59971</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/62E663E59971</guid><description>
	The aim of the study is to determine and measure the blood volume as well as level of pain of the study volunteers after being punctured with different safety lancets (varying sizes) from 20 s to 2 m. Blood sample can be used in a number of ways: for diagnosis, to determine health condition generally and for screening. 300 subjects were punctured 4 times with different safety lancets. After ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of Smear positive Pulmonary Tuberculosis (PTB) and Associated Factors among PTB Suspects Attending Harar Tuberculosis Control Center,  Harar, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/441B84457505</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/441B84457505</guid><description>
	Tuberculosis (TB) continues to be an important public health problem worldwide. It is a leading cause of disability and death in many parts of the world especially in the developing countries. Ethiopia has already a record of history of TB around greater than 58 years. The aim of the study was to determine the prevalence and associated factors of pulmonary tuberculosis (PTB) in Harar TB cont...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Health professionals&#x2019; stance towards medical laboratory technology: A cross-sectional study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/901BE9465155</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/901BE9465155</guid><description>
	The practice of modern medicine would be impossible without the tests performed in the clinical laboratory. In todays era of rapidly evolving medical research and application, medical laboratory technology plays an integral role in the health care system. In spite of this, the propensity of giving less value to the profession by certain health practitioners might reduce the health team mobil...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Seroprevalence of Rubella virus among pregnant Sudanese women with history of abortion</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/5574A1063143</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/5574A1063143</guid><description>
	Mainly, rubella infections during pregnancy are considered as serious infections worldwide. Since Rubella virus not only infects susceptible women early in pregnancy, they can also be transmitted to the fetus, and might induce birth defects. Accordingly, accurate as well as meticulous diagnosis of rubella infection is crucial during pregnancy. A descriptive, retrospective cross sectional hos...</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Quality analysis of the preanalytical phase of laboratory tests: Case of the civil hospital (Tetouan&#x2013;Morocco)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/02F8E0262296</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/02F8E0262296</guid><description>
	Several studies report that between 60 to 85% of laboratory errors are produced during the preanalytical phase. The objective of this study was to identify the factors at the origin of nonconformities during this phase at the Civil Hospital of Tetouan. A mixed preanalytical descriptive study realized between April and May 2014 was based on a questionnaire, an observation grid, focus groups a...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of antimicrobial susceptibility testing techniques in some laboratories in Cameroon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/6027A5161907</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/6027A5161907</guid><description>
	The increasing bacterial resistance to antimicrobial agents has rendered susceptibility testing an indispensable tool for appropriate antibiotic selection. This study is aimed at evaluating the technical methods of antibiogram in some medical laboratories in Cameroon. A descriptive cross-sectional study was carried out. The data collection was done with two material, the questionnaire and th...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Blood group serology analysis of one rare case of &#x3B2;-thalassemia major with cold autoantibodies and alloantibodies</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/FAFCABC60558</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/FAFCABC60558</guid><description>
	 thalassemia major is one of major public health problem in south China requiring lifelong blood transfusions for the children to stay alive. However, long-term transfusion increases the risk of the patients to produce the autoantibodies and alloantibodies due to repeated exposure to foreign antigens. In this study, we reported one rare case of -thalassemia major with cold autoantibodies and...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Teratocarcinosarcoma of the tongue with bilateral neck nodal metastases</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/6DA793860878</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/6DA793860878</guid><description>
	When confronted with a tongue and neck mass in a child, a specific diagnosis can be difficult to make with a differential diagnosis often provided. Teratocarcinosarcoma of the tongue with metastases to the neck would be considered an extremely rare specific diagnosis to correctly make prospectively. This study presents the clinical appearance, as well as the CT, MRI, PET and pathologic findi...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence and associated risk factors of Hepatitis B and Hepatitis C virus among volunteer blood donors in Arba Minch Blood Bank SNNPR, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/1E76C9558924</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMLD/article-abstract/1E76C9558924</guid><description>
	Hepatitis B virus (HBV) and Hepatitis C virus (HCV) is major public health problems that affect million people worldwide and people who are infected assumed to develop liver cirrhosis or hepatocelular carcinoma. Screening of blood donors is essential for healthy and safe donation. A cross sectional study design was conducted among volunteer blood donors in Arba Minch blood bank from March 20...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>