<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Medicinal Plants Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Medicinal Plants Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Ultrasonic assisted extraction of bioactive compounds from different parts of Hancornia Speciosa Gomes</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/55E3DD363829</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/55E3DD363829</guid><description>
	The proper use of plants and their extracts, whether for medicine or as a food additive, requires the use of extraction and characterization methods that allow the identification and quantification of the active principles in each extract, associating them with the effect produced. With this objective, the present work was developed to study the ultrasonic extracts of mangabeira (Hancornia s...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of ethanol leaf extract of Gnetum africanum on testosterone and oestradiol induced benign prostatic hyperplasia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/3BA1CF663831</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/3BA1CF663831</guid><description>
	The effect of ethanol leaf extract of Gnetum africanum was studied in albino rats induced with benign prostatic hyperplasia. The animals (36) were randomly grouped into six with six rats in each group. Testosterone and oestradiol every other day for 28 days was used to induce hyperplasia. The test groups (2 - 4) were treated with 200, 400 and 800 mg/kg body weight of extract for another 28 d...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Separation and identification of phenolics and flavonoids from wild Pistacia palaestina extract and its antioxidant activity</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5C4B54E63866</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5C4B54E63866</guid><description>
	An in-vitro evaluation of the antioxidant activities of wild Palestinian Pistacia palaestina extracts was done. In parallel, the total phenolic content (TPC) and the total flavonoids content (TFC) were measured. The antioxidant activities were determined spectrophotometrically by DPPH, FRAP, CUPRAC and the ABTS methods. The phenolic and flavonoid contents were separated and identified using ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemical composition and antioxidant activity in the essential oil of Cinnamomum zeylanicum Nees with medicinal interest</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/693E48063868</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/693E48063868</guid><description>
	Cinnamon is an evergreen tree belonging to the genus Cinnamomun; it is commonly founded in various tropical countries, consisting of more than 250 species of trees and shrubs in the Lauraceae family. This plant has had great medicinal importance in traditional medicine since ancient times. In this research, the chemical composition of the essential oil of Cinnamomum zeylanicum Nees was evalu...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Control of papaya fruits anthracnose by essential oils of medicinal plants associated to different coatings</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5BF161663528</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/5BF161663528</guid><description>
	Chemical pesticides have been commonly used for the control of various plant diseases. Although pathogens can be controlled with the application of these products, there are hazardous impacts in human health and environment. In parallel, essential oils have been shown to be effective in plant diseases management and can be safely incorporated as suitable alternatives for synthetic fungicides...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The effects of aqueous extract of Bowdichia virgilioides Kunth in the immune functions of thymocytes and B-lymphocytes</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/086CB2463536</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/086CB2463536</guid><description>
	Bowdichia virgilioides Kunth (Fabaceae) is a tree species used in folk medicine against inflammatory disorders, and it is still unclear whether consumption of the B. virgilioides stem bark extract has any effect on immune cells. Thus, this study aimed to evaluate the effects of B. virgilioides stem bark extract (AEBv) on the functions of the thymus and B lymphocytes. The AEBv was obtained by...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Hydroethanolic stem bark extract of Vernonia amygdalina Del. (Asteraceae) suppresses yeast-induced pyrexia and Plasmodium berghei malaria in murine models</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/447934F63538</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/447934F63538</guid><description>
	Vernonia amygdalina has been widely utilized in Ghana and other West African states for numerous parasitic infections, diabetes and some inflammatory conditions. In this study we evaluated the antipyretic and antimalarial properties as well as in vitro antioxidant activities of an ethanolic stem bark extract of V. amygdalina (VAE). The antipyretic effect of VAE was assessed using Bakers yeas...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibacterial, cytotoxic, and schistosomicidal activities of the methanolic extract from Cassia grandis L.f. (Fabaceae) stem bark and its fractions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/74A5BA963542</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/74A5BA963542</guid><description>
	Cassia grandis L. (Fabaceae), a native tree from Amazon Forest, has been used in folk medicine against worms and intestinal parasites, and to treat stomach and respiratory problems, blood diseases, among others uses. This study aimed to evaluate the antioxidant, cytotoxic, antimicrobial, and schistosomicidal activities of the methanolic extract from C. grandis stem bark (CgME) and to elucida...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Biological properties and therapeutic applications of cannabidiol</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/1690A3D63559</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/1690A3D63559</guid><description>
	Cannabis sp. has important pharmacological activities, so it has been the focus of attention of the scientific community. Through the search for new drugs, it was found that cannabinoids present in the plant can modulate transient potential receptors (TPR). Cannabidiol (CBD), also known as medical marijuana, represents the second most abundant phytocannabinoid of the Cannabis plant and it is...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chemical composition and biological potentials of Lebanese Cupressus sempervirens L. leaves&#x2019; extracts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/014F43E63709</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/014F43E63709</guid><description>
	The essential oils and defatted ethanolic extracts isolated from Cupressus sempervirens L. leaves collected from two geographically distinct regions in Lebanon; Beit El-Dein (mountain) and Jbeil (sea-side) were analysed for their chemical composition by GC/MS and qualitative phytochemical screening, respectively. These were then tested for their in-vitro antioxidant and antibacterial activit...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>