<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Metabolomics and Systems Biology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Metabolomics and Systems Biology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Virtual environments for mental health issues: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/73FD7F847035</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/73FD7F847035</guid><description>
	Three-dimensional (3D) environments are increasingly being used to provide therapy to those suffering from mental health problems. Virtual environments can provide a safe and realistic simulation to expose patients to the cause of their problem. This paper presents a review of the use of 3D environments to assess and treat mental health problems. Within the review applications to treat menta...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Conception of biological networks at the molecular level as orchestrated systems of oscillators representing interconnected modular molecular clocks</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/D9310D83545</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/D9310D83545</guid><description>
	Biological networks are extremely complex objects. Still representation of them remains to be very simple. Here hypothesis representing all regulatory cellular processes as cycles connected to each other is provided. Cycles were introduced as minimal parts of network containing negative feedback loop. All cycles were interconnected between each other by common members of network; it can be g...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Metabolite profiling of endophytic fungal isolates of five ethno-pharmacologically important plants of Meghalaya, India</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/15B99FD3560</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/15B99FD3560</guid><description>
	Crude metabolite extracts derived from the culture broths of endophytic fungi of five ethno-pharmacologically important plant species used by the ethnic tribes of the hill state of Meghalaya in North-East India were screened for the presence of toxins and secondary metabolites using agar plug paper chromatography, TLC (thin layer chromatography) and LC-MS (liquid chromatography-mass spectros...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Urinary metabolic profiling in rats due to heat exposure using 1H high resolution NMR spectroscopy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/D7483393507</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/D7483393507</guid><description>
	Acute heat stress may trigger systemic biochemical and physiological changes in living organisms leading to rapid loss of homeostasis. Metabolic regulatory process during heat stress has been poorly understood therefore the present study was undertaken in order to have an insight of alterations in various metabolites due to acute heat stress exposure using nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) sp...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determination and detoxification of cyanide content in sorghum for ethanol production using Saccharomyces cerevisiae strain</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/3BA8D3E39773</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/3BA8D3E39773</guid><description>
	Sorghum is a promising crop for the animal feed and fuel ethanol production. Presence of cyanide in its biomass, particularly in the tips of young leaves, carries some risk of toxicity to livestock and microbes, especially when at an immature stage of growth, its application may be restricted. The study was carried out at Indian Agricultural Research Institute, New Delhi with nine forage sor...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of (high-pathogenicity island) HPI-harboring Escherichia coli in diarrheic and healthy piglets</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/68B4BC43456</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/68B4BC43456</guid><description>
	One hundred and sixty four rectal swab samples werecollectedfrom 110 live diarrheic piglets and 54 healthy piglets during an investigation on the prevalence of HPI-harboringEscherichia coli(HPI+E. coli) infection associated with porcine diarrhea.The data of polymerase chain reaction (PCR) revealed the presence of HPI+E. coliin 58.18% of swabs taken from diarrheic piglets, while 44.44% of sam...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of dehydration on the nutritive value of drumstick leaves</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/FA626743518</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMSB/article-abstract/FA626743518</guid><description>
	Food based strategy is used as a tool for combating micronutrient deficiencies. It is also referred asdietary modification, which encompasses a wide variety of intervention that aim at increasing theproduction, availability and consumption of food products, which are rich in micronutrients. One suchfood products are green leafy vegetables. There are many varieties of green leafy vegetables w...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>