<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Neuroscience and Behavioral Health - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Neuroscience and Behavioral Health</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Predictors of stimulants use among physicians in a Nigerian tertiary health institution in Sokoto, 
Northwest Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/74BB52957549</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/74BB52957549</guid><description>
	Studies suggest that prevalence rates of stimulants use and abuse among healthcare professionalss is similar to rates in the general population. Majority of the studies on stimulants use carried out in Nigeria mainly focused on students of secondary and tertiary institutions, thus, there is the need to conduct similar study among physicians in Nigeria. This study aimed to assess the pattern ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Hormone replacement therapy and Alzheimer's disease in older women: A systematic review of literature</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/87A03CE56905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/87A03CE56905</guid><description>
	The relationships between estrogen and cognitive functions have been explored in many experimental and observational studies with rather inconsistent outcomes. This study explored the relationship between hormone replacement therapy (estrogen-based) and Alzheimers disease in postmenopausal women based on existing literature. A comprehensive search was conducted for relevant articles written ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuroprotective potential of Aframomum melegueta extracts on brain of monosodium glutamate-treated wistar albino rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/841912767178</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/841912767178</guid><description>
	The study evaluated the biochemical effects of methanolic seed extract of Aframomum melegueta (MEAM) on biochemical parameters of the brain of rats treated with monosodium glutamate (MSG) with a view to considering the possibility of using the plant as a remedy for the management of neurotoxic disorders. MEAM was prepared according to standard methods, phytochemically screened and followed b...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Auditory, visual, kinesthetic-tactile, and multi-sensory modalities: A quantitative study of how preferred modalities create more effective teaching and learning environments</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/054C36A65479</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/054C36A65479</guid><description>
	This study aims t&#x43E; examine h&#x43E;w teaching methods and learning styles of instructors play a role in how students learn, and how technology is selected. There are four type of learning styles: audit&#x43E;ry, visu&#x430;l, kin&#x435;sth&#x435;tic-t&#x430;ctil&#x435; and multi-sensory. Th&#x435; survey p&#x43E;pul&#x430;ti&#x43E;n was evenly distributed, consistening of 100 faculty members and 100 students with a response rate of 25%. The results of the ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuroprotective effect of Silibinin against middle cerebral artery occlusion induced focal cerebral ischemia and brain injury in Wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/353949A65481</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/353949A65481</guid><description>
	Silibinin (Silybin) as an active constituent derived from milk thistle (Silybum marianum) has been shown to have antioxidant and anti-apoptotic properties. In traditional system of medicine, Silybum marianum has been used for treating various kinds of ailments including liver disease and cancer; however, clinical studies are largely heterogeneous and contradictory. The present study was desi...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Vitamin B complex and homocysteine status and Cognitive impairment in the elderly among Indian population</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/33A828D61832</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/33A828D61832</guid><description>
	Vitamins B complex and homocysteine has been given much attention as preventive factors against cognitive decline and dementia. Hyper homocysteinaemia has been suggested as a cause or mechanism in the development of Alzheimers disease and other forms of dementia. The present study is designed to know the role of vitamin B complex and homocysteine and its relation with cognition, using biolog...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cigarette smoking among Jimma University Teaching and referral hospital outpatients attending services at psychiatry clinic Southwest, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/1C5F02560094</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/1C5F02560094</guid><description>
	Smoking is currently considered one of the greatest problems in public health worldwide, and it is one of the most avoidable causes of death. Cigarette consumption killed more than 6 million people, nearly 80% in low and middle income countries in 2011. The objective of the current study was to assess the prevalence of cigarette smoking and its determinant factors among psychiatric outpatien...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spinal cystic schwannoma: A rare case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/D7656F957624</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/D7656F957624</guid><description>
	A 78-year-old man was referred to our department with severe low back pain and gait disturbance. Lumbar magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) showed a large, well-circumscribed mass isointense with cerebrospinal fluid on T1- and T2-weighted imaging at the conus level. Arachnoid cyst without performing contrast-enhanced MRI was initially diagnosed. Intraoperative observation and postoperative hist...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Personality traits of in-patients with substance use disorders in a mental health facility in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/CE2111256698</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/CE2111256698</guid><description>
	Substance abuse is a multi-etiological, multi-dimensional and a worldwide problem with an alarming increase in its incidences. This study aimed to evaluate the patterns of use of psychoactive substances and to assess the predominant personality traits among the participants. This cross-sectional study used a purposive sampling technique to examined in-patients with substance abuse problem in...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The role of electroacupuncture in stroke treatment: A systematic review of the literature</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/6B2744255670</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JNBH/article-abstract/6B2744255670</guid><description>
	Stroke is a major cause of serious neurological disability, and the second leading cause of death worldwide with more than 6 million deaths each year. Although pharmaceutical treatment of stroke has advanced over the last decades, clinical treatment or prevention of motor impairment (which is the most frequent complication) is still inadequate. Therefore, it is imperative to develop new tech...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>