<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Dryland Agriculture  - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Dryland Agriculture </description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Response of cucumber (Cucumis sativus L.)  to differential pruning under greenhouse</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/42DC9DC63195</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/42DC9DC63195</guid><description>
	Sustainable cucumber production requires optimized agronomic practices that are adaptive to changing climates as well as enhanced crop yield and fruit quality. Commercial Greenhouse experiment was conducted to determine the effect of differential pruning on the growth and yield of cucumber in the Sudan Savanna of Nigeria. The treatments consisted of two hybrid cucumber varieties (Sirana F1 a...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Current status of chickpea production: Opportunities for promoting, adoption and adapting the crop in Zimbabwe: A review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/B27473A63025</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/B27473A63025</guid><description>
	Chickpea is a cool season, drought hardy grain legume crop that is grown in Asia, East Africa, United States of America and Europe. The crop has the potential to close the winter legume gap because it can adapt to cool season temperatures as compared to summer legumes grown in Zimbabwe. The aim of this paper is to unpack various opportunities for promoting chickpea in drought prone areas of ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Yield variability of Irish potato (Solanum tuberosum L.) as affected by cultivars and sowing date in the Sudan Savanna Zone of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/B9EF1FB62427</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/B9EF1FB62427</guid><description>
	Field experiments were conducted in the Sudan Savannah Zone of Nigeria during the 2015/2016 dry season. The Research Farm of Audu Bako Collage of Agriculture, Danbatta (12 44 N and 8 51 E) and Federal College of Education Technical, Bichi (1224N and 8.24E) represented the two locations. Subjects of interest were to determine the effect of variety and sowing date on yield of Irish potato. Tre...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of Daniella olivera wood biochar on the growth and biomass of maize (zea mays L.) in Lafia, North central Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/1BAEE6B61075</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/1BAEE6B61075</guid><description>
	The study aimed to evaluate the effect of Daniella wood Biochar on the growth and biomass of maize harvested 8 weeks after sowing in a pot experiment. The research was carried out in order to evaluate the effect of Daniella wood biochar on the growth and biomass of maize and the effects of Daniella wood biochar on the physiochemical properties of the soil. Pots were filled with 5 kg of norma...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Growth variability of Irish potato (Solanum tuberosum L.) as affected by cultivars and sowing date in the Sudan savannah zone of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/842972660925</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/842972660925</guid><description>
	Field experiments were conducted in the Sudan savannah zone of Nigeria during the 2015/2016 dry season. The Research Farm of Audu Bako Collage of Agriculture, Danbatta (12 44 N and 8 51 E) and Federal Collage of Education Technical, Bichi (1224N and 8.24E) represented the two locations. Subjects of interest were to determine the effect of variety and sowing date on growth of Irish potato. Tr...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of tillage and planting method under conservation farming for soil and crop productivity in the dry-land areas of Tigray, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/6709D2760929</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/6709D2760929</guid><description>
	Study on conservation farming (CF) was conducted in moisture deficit area of Tigray, Ethiopia from 2013-2014. The experiment was conducted both on station and on farmers field. The treatments were: conventional tillage with fertilizer, conventional tillage without fertilizer, sub soiling with fertilizer, sub soiling + tie ridging with fertilizer, sub soiling + tie ridging + intercropping wit...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Participatory evaluation of maize varieties for the management of maize gray leaf spot disease (Cercospora zeae maydis) at Gondar Zuria district, northwest Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/9BC82CA59763</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/9BC82CA59763</guid><description>
	Gray leaf spot is one of the major constraints of maize production in Ethiopia where warm humid environmental condition is prevailing. A field experiment was conducted in Gondar zuria district of western Ethiopia during 2016/17 and 2017/18 cropping season with the aim to evaluate effective maize varieties for the management of maize gray leaf spot disease. The experiment was laid out in Rand...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Shallow groundwater condition for irrigation along dryland river basin, northwestern Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/CA8E17C59556</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/CA8E17C59556</guid><description>
	This study investigated shallow groundwater quality and yield for irrigation along Hadejia River Basin of Jigawa State in both the dry and rainy seasons of one year. Sites in the floodplain with a history of irrigation where the use of tube wells is dominant were selected covering a transect of about 135 km. Six transects, oriented perpendicular to the river channel were established within 1...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Screening for Drought Tolerance in Maize Hybrids using Drought Indices</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/62E26DF58284</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/62E26DF58284</guid><description>
	A study was conducted to select extra-early maize hybrids for drought tolerance and investigate the efficacy of different drought indices. The material consisted of 10 single cross hybrids which were selected from 66 single cross hybrids using IITA base index. The initial experiment was conducted at Ikenne and was laid in a randomized incomplete block design with two replicates. Data collect...</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mitigation of Moisture Stress in Sweet Pepper (Capsicum annuum L.) by Foliar Application of Salicylic Acid in Sudan Savanna Agro-Ecology, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/46C4BC658286</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JODA/article-abstract/46C4BC658286</guid><description>
	Field experiment was conducted to study the influence of salicylic acid in the mitigation of moisture stress in sweet pepper. Treatments consisted of four rates (0, 0.2, 0.4 and 0.6gL-1) of salicylic acid and three moisture stress stages (vegetative, flowering and fruit setting). These were laid out in split plot design with three replications. Results of the study revealed that exogenous ap...</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>