<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Oceanography and Marine Science - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Oceanography and Marine Science</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Heavy metal concentration and public health risk in consuming Sardinella maderensis (Sardine), Sarotherodon melanotheron (Tilapia), and Liza falicipinis (Mullet) harvested from Bonny River, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/78246B863259</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/78246B863259</guid><description>
	Contamination of the river by oil spill had put the health of the people who consume fish at risk. Five fish samples each of Liza falicipinis (Mullet), Sarotherodon melanotheron (Tilapia) and Sardinella maderensis (Sardine) (n=15) were collected monthly from the Bonny Estuary from February to July 2018. The samples were oven dried at 100C and analyzed using Atomic Absorption Spectrophotomete...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Detection and spatio-temporal variation of marine heatwaves in the Gulf of Guinea, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/E00AA8662030</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/E00AA8662030</guid><description>
	Time series analyses spanning 30 years (1988 - 2017) on spatial and temporal variations in sea surface temperatures reveal the occurrence of marine heatwaves (MHWs) within the Nigerian segment of the Gulf of Guinea. For specific focus, three locations were also chosen along Nigerias coastal zone, namely Lagos lagoon (western region), the Niger Delta (Forcados/Central region) and outer Cross ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Influence of climatic factors on Sargassum arrivals to the coasts of the Dominican Republic</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/5E6723C62067</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/5E6723C62067</guid><description>
	Since 2011, the coasts of North America, Mexico, and the Caribbean have experienced an unusual increase in the arrival of Sargassum. A large amount of Sargassum has caused significant economic losses in the tourism sector of the Dominican Republic as well as the entire Caribbean region. The present article discusses the possible factors contributing toward this unusual increase. Large Sargas...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spatial variability in autumnal equatorial upwelling intensity within the Gulf of Guinea as inferred from in situ measurements</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/F3D236A60455</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/F3D236A60455</guid><description>
	In attempt to study the spatial differences in autumnal equatorial upwelling intensity relative to bio-productivity in the eastern equatorial Atlantic, oceanographic in situ data along regions 10W, 0E, 2.5E and 6E, collected in the Gulf of Guinea during autumn cruise carried out in September 2007 were analyzed. The surface mean values for temperature along 10W, 0E, 2.5E and 6E are 25.02, 26....</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evidence for enhanced chlorophyll-a levels in the Bay of Bengal during early north-east monsoon</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/D5D97F956117</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/D5D97F956117</guid><description>
	To understand the chlorophyll-a distribution in the neritic waters of the northern Indian Ocean, which comprises the Arabian Sea on the west and the Bay of Bengal on the east, seawater samples were collected during early north-east monsoon season (November, 2008). The column integrated chlorophyll-a over the Arabian Sea and the North Bay of Bengal exhibit high concentrations. However, the so...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spatial distribution and diversity of phytoplankton community in Eastern Obolo River Estuary, Niger Delta</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/C53639055697</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/C53639055697</guid><description>
	This paper reported a two season study of diversity, spatial distribution, species composition of phytoplankton and physico-chemical characteristics of the Eastern Obolo River Estuary between June and November 2015 and December and May, 2016. Water conductivity (675) showed direct relationship with phytoplankton abundance, turbidity showed strong correlation with species density as well. Spe...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Growth and exploitation parameters of Ilisha africana, by-catch of the experimental fishing for the study on selectivity of gill nets for Ethmalosa fimbriata, in the Saloum estuary and Joal (Senegal)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/D6B747164436</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/D6B747164436</guid><description>
	Growth and exploitation parameters Ilisha africana were determined from the size frequency for the first time in Senegal. The size distribution showed average sizes equal to 19.26  1.70 and 19.75  2.03 cm, respectively in the estuary and at the sea. The values of allometric rates of the length-weight relationship were, respectively equal to 2.88 and 2.93 in the estuary and at the sea indicat...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Embryonic development of anemone fishes in captivity</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/BA9A90763713</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/BA9A90763713</guid><description>
	Broodstock development, spawning, fertilization, embryonic development, fecundity, hatching rate and deformation rates of five species (Amphiprion ocellaris, A. percula, A. melanopus, A. clarkii and A. nigripes) of anemone fish were studied in captive condition. The egg diameter, parental care, fecundity rate, fertilization rate, hatching rate, deformation rates and size of eggs were quantif...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Recruitment pattern and catch per unit effort of the Black Tiger Shrimp (Penaeus monodon) in Andoni River System, Niger Delta Region of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/64A974B61871</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/64A974B61871</guid><description>
	The investigation of recruitment pattern and catch per unit effort of the black tiger shrimp (Penaeus monodon) was conducted from March 2012 to February 2013 in Andoni River System, Niger Delta region of Nigeria. Total weight and length of sampled P. monodon, number of fishers, fishing duration and temperature were sampled monthly. Total weight of P. monodon landed, number of fishers and fis...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Baseline physico-chemical and bathymetry assessment of Mahin Lake, Southwestern, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/B419F0861639</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JOMS/article-abstract/B419F0861639</guid><description>
	Assessment of baseline physico-chemical parameters and bathymetry mapping of Mahin Lake has been carried out for effective and sustainable utilization, management, conservation, and exploitation of its resources. pH, temperature, dissolved oxygen, electrical conductivity, resistivity, total dissolved solid (TDS), salinity, and surface pressure were determined in situ; while concentrations of...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>