<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Public Administration and Policy Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Public Administration and Policy Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>HIV and AIDS mainstreaming in Uganda&#x2019;s higher education sector strategic direction: A case of Uganda Management Institute</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/F21688663068</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/F21688663068</guid><description>
	HIV and AIDS mainstreaming in the development arena has been a point of emphasis globally over the years. The higher education sector has also put emphasis on the campaign to have HIV and AIDS issues mainstreamed for in all strategies and operations. The purpose of this study is to investigate how HIV and AIDS mainstreaming has been considered in Uganda Management Institute (UMI) strategic d...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>China&#x2019;s path of rural poverty alleviation through health care financing: The case of Taijiang County-Guizhou Province
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/2B4B54462052</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/2B4B54462052</guid><description>
	China has made considerable progress in economic, social, cultural and political fields since reform and opening-up started in 1978. In the last forty years the country lifted over 700 million people out of poverty by implementing large-scale, long-lasting, government-led, and very effective rural poverty alleviation and development plan. In health care financing, the country also achieved u...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Pursuing Sustainable Development Goals in Uganda: Do anti-corruption strategies of Management Development Institutes matter?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/E2512A462498</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/E2512A462498</guid><description>
	Sustainable development refers to using resources sparingly so that future generations may also use them for development. Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) are a global development agenda adopted in 2015 to end poverty, protect the planet, and ensure prosperity for all. The 15-year development agenda recognizes eradication of poverty in all its forms and dimensions, including extreme pove...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evolution of the public private partnership (ppps) and its application in down market urban housing in Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/4FAA32661222</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/4FAA32661222</guid><description>
	The State Department of Housing in Kenya puts the housing demand in the country at 250,000 housing units per year, while actual supply is 50,000 units p.a. This demand for housing has accumulated to 1.85 million units as at 2018. This has led to the growing proliferation of slums and informal settlements, with the Department showing that there are over 500 such settlements. This state of aff...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Strengthening local government through participation and leadership: Bangladesh perspective</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/B687FEE60960</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/B687FEE60960</guid><description>
	Active participation and effective leadership are two accepted substantial objects of a well-functioning local government, without those ingredients, governance of local government intuitions cannot be contented to its founding purpose. Bangladesh, an emerging South Asian economic tiger, has achieved some exemplary development within short time in many fields, is still struggling to establis...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Is it more than a trade war?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/50BE46560753</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/50BE46560753</guid><description>
	The paper examines the underlying reasons for the trade war and is mainly aimed at China. It was suggested that there is an underlying motive apart from trade imbalance or intellectual property issues as accused by the United State of America government. It examines to some extent the possible contributions of countries such as Canada, England, Australia and the European Union (EU) to isolat...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Value chain and local economic development in the shai-Osudoku district assembly of Ghana: The experience of the Asutuare rice farming project</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/D44B53159418</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/D44B53159418</guid><description>
	The article sought to discuss the impact of value chain development and local economic development among rice farmers in Asutuare in the Shai-Osudoku District Assembly of Ghana. The study specifically examined the actors in the rice value chain development process, their roles and how their roles shaped the final output for the consumer and the extent to which the value chain development and...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A comparative corporate governance mechanism</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/F5F0B7959219</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/F5F0B7959219</guid><description>
	This paper presents an analysis of the connection between management and governance. Management is a business function that has been entrusted with providing leadership support to organisations resources to realise strategic goals and objectives. In contemporary management, however, another function of leadership has been realised which is governance. Experts have identified that while the t...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The need for executive federalism in federal-provincial relations: The Canadian example</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/B5ACBA467181</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/B5ACBA467181</guid><description>
	Prime Minister Stephen Harpers championing of a new course of federal-provincial relations in Canada away from the traditional executive federalism has drawn a lot of scholarly concerns. His open federalism doctrine has been touted by many as the future of federalism in Canada as a way of ensuring popular inclusion, participation, and grass root representation. While agreeing to the need to ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Administrative impact of restructured provincial administration on selected aspects of maintenance of law and order in Kenya in 2010 to 2014: A case study of Bomet county</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/9D418C265931</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAPR/article-abstract/9D418C265931</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to investigate the administrative impact of Restructured Provincial Administration (RPA) as independent variable on maintenance of law and order as dependent variable in Bomet County, Kenya from 2010 to 2014. Based on the theory of new-institutionalism, it focused on four selected aspects of maintenance of law and order measured from 2006 to 2010 and from 2010 to 201...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>