<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Physiology and Pathophysiology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Physiology and Pathophysiology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Evaluation of ventilatory function of Senegalese patients with type 2 diabetes</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/70FE3CB62224</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/70FE3CB62224</guid><description>
	Diabetes is a common disease in sub-Saharan Africa. Complications associated with type 2 diabetes mellitus are due to macro-vascular and micro-vascular lesions. One of the less known complications of diabetes is impaired respiratory function. The objective of this study was to evaluate the ventilatory function of Senegalese type 2 diabetics. A total of Sixty-four women composed to 32 diabeti...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids confer protection against gentamicin-induced testicular injury: Novel insights into possible mechanisms</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/24EB07661865</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/24EB07661865</guid><description>
	Gentamicin (GM) is an aminoglycoside that has harmful effects on the male germ cells and sperm quality. N-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (n-3 PUFA) are natural antioxidants that influence cell signaling and inflammation. Heme-oxygenase-1 (HO-1) and heat shock proteins (HSP) aid in cellular protection against cellular insults. This study aimed to explore the potential alleviating influences of...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Carpolobia lutea methanol root extract reinstates androgenesis and testicular function in cadmium-challenged rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/C77672D60787</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/C77672D60787</guid><description>
	Cadmium produces a wide range of biological dysfunctions in human and laboratory animals where it chiefly affects the testes, whereas, Carpolobia lutea has been known to have antioxidant benefits. This study was intended to investigate the effects of Carpolobia lutea root extracts on testicular hormone function in cadmium-challenged male rats. 48 male Wistar rats (170-190 g) were divided int...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of the cytoprotective effects of anti-ulcer agents in acid-alcohol induced gastric ulceration in wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/CC0E84D61015</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/CC0E84D61015</guid><description>
	Adequate studies have been done using proton pump inhibitors and H2-receptor antagonist and only few studies for cyto-protective and gastric acid secretions have been done in Nigeria. Therefore this work studied the cyto-protective and gastric acid secretory effects of rabeprazole, ranitidine, omeprazole and cimetidine in wistar rats. 28 male wistar rats of weights 300 to 400 g were recruite...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Preliminary study of physiopathological changes associated with the ethanolic extract of the stem leaves of Phyllanthus amarus in rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/1B8262B56808</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/1B8262B56808</guid><description>
	The present work aimed to investigate physiopathological changes associated with the ethanolic extract of the stem leaves of Phyllanthus amarus (EEt(OH) P.a. Exploratory tests are performed in vivo on Wistar albino rats. Analysis of the variation in body weight at the level of the batch having received, and the control group showed a slight weight drop 7 d after treatment. This variation is ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Oxytocin ameliorates the deleterious effect of pain in adult male rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/5D782A462439</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/5D782A462439</guid><description>
	Oxytocin (OXT) is a neuropeptide with a peripheral role in reproduction, though it may have a central effect. The aim of the study is to verify its cental pathophysiological mechanisms on experimental rats. Rats were divided into control, OXT (which divided into intrathecal OXT and IV OXT subgroups), and antagonist group: OXT and l-glutamate Na+ subgroup with measuring of pain threshold, car...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Age-related effects of lead poisoning on sex hormones in adult male Wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/39671F159720</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/39671F159720</guid><description>
	The World Health Organization (WHO) estimates that, about a quarter of the diseases facing mankind today occur due to prolonged exposure to environmental pollution, and that most of these environment-related diseases are however, not easily detected and may be acquired during childhood and manifested later in adulthood. The aim of this work was to determine the sub-chronic effects of lead po...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Preliminary study on the establishment of reference intervals for serum prolactin for women in Zaria, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/47D30A959164</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/47D30A959164</guid><description>
	The interpretation of prolactin results is difficult as race related reference intervals are scarce, especially in Nigerian women. Serum prolactin reference intervals were determined from 120 subjects. Subjects were randomly selected from antenatal clinics and general outpatient clinics in one private hospital and three government hospitals in Zaria, Northern Nigeria. They consisted of six g...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative study of three methods for QT interval correction in African national level football players</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/7D0D18157876</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/7D0D18157876</guid><description>
	The aim of this study was to compare three correction methods of QT interval in African national level football players. QT interval was measured in D2 lead on resting electrocardiogram (ECG) in 216 Black male football players (age range 18 to 35 years). Corrected QT (QTc) was calculated using Bazett, Fridericia, and Framinghams formulas. Means and percentages of long QT (QTc440 ms and QTc47...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of Gmelina arborea, Roxb (Verbenaceae) aqueous extract on arterial pressure of Wistar rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/69D127356897</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPAP/article-abstract/69D127356897</guid><description>
	In this study, the effect of Gmelina arborea aqueous extract, a medicinal plant used in the treatment of hypertension, on rat blood pressure was investigated. After harvest, leaves of G. arborea were dried, reduced in powder and used for aqueous extract preparation. The aqueous extract was administrated at 500 mg/kg/day to Wistar rats, which has been made hypertensive by NG-Nitro-L-arginine ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>