<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Plant Breeding and Crop Science - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Plant Breeding and Crop Science</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Selection of drought tolerant genotypes in groundnut (Arachis hypogaea L.) using indices</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/65D45BD63825</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/65D45BD63825</guid><description>
	A study was carried out to evaluate the effect of drought stress on pod yield and other traits of groundnut genotypes to select the ten best performing genotypes using indices. Ninety six genotypes including 90 F2:3 progenies, 4 parents and 2 checks were planted under well-watered (WW) and water-stressed (WS) conditions at the International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Genetic variation among white lupin (Lupinus albus L.) landraces from Northwestern and Southern Ethiopia for agronomic traits and nutrient contents of grain</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/AA64B5A63893</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/AA64B5A63893</guid><description>
	White lupin (Lupinus albus L.) is rich in quality protein, relatively tolerant to drought, soil salinity and acidity, increase the fertility of soils and can contribute to improved agricultural sustainability, food security and reduce malnutrition which has close associations with climate change. This study was conducted to assess genetic variability of white lupin genotypes for agronomic tr...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of improved pigeon pea (Cajanus cajan) varieties for organoleptic dal quality in India</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/195B18363901</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/195B18363901</guid><description>
	Pigeon pea (Cajanus cajan L.) is an important pulse crop in the Indian diet and one of the most important sources of dietary protein for the population. Organoleptic qualities of pigeon pea dal were tested to draw conclusions on the preferred varieties. Organoleptic qualities such as taste, texture, aroma, tenderness, sweetness and overall acceptance were tested by a trained sensory panel. A...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Allelic variability of oil palm inter-population progenies based on simple sequence repeats markers</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/182971363574</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/182971363574</guid><description>
	The genetic structure and variability was described among 52 oil palm inter-population crosses after two selection cycles using simple sequence repeats markers (SRR). The 10 sets of SSR markers covering 62.5% of the oil palm genome showed a high level of polymorphism (average number of alleles per locus = 6.7; unbiased expected heterozygosity = 0.655; Gst = 0.346) across the oil palm samples...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Potential of ten wild diploid cotton species for the improvement of fiber fineness of upland cotton through interspecific hybridization</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/25008D563578</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/25008D563578</guid><description>
	Cotton is the highest source of natural fiber in textile industry worldwide. With the modern spinning technologies, the demand for cotton fiber with higher quality has increased, making the genetic improvement of fiber quality one of the main challenges for cotton breeders. In cotton breeding, wild species are important source of several desirable genes for genetic improvement of the main cu...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Establishment of an early selection method (criteria) for breeding in cowpea (Vigna unguiculata)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/723DCDE63582</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/723DCDE63582</guid><description>
	Populations with high genetic variability are targeted by breeders as they create opportunity for selection and genetic improvement. To achieve this, multiple populations are created, but resources are often scarce. This calls for identification of populations with the desired traits at early generation. The study was carried out at MUARIK in seasons 2017A and 2017B on 135 F2 and 40 F3 cowpe...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Harnessing genotype-by-environment interaction to determine adaptability of advanced cowpea lines to multiple environments in Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/159144F63682</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/159144F63682</guid><description>
	This study was conducted to determine the yield stability of advanced cowpea lines in diverse agro-ecological zones of Uganda in order to facilitate documentation requirements for national performance trials (NPT). Thirty cowpea genotypes were evaluated against six checks in three localities, over three growing seasons, making a total of 9 unique environments. The trials were laid in a 6x6 a...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Genetic variability, heritability and correlation of quantitative traits for Arabusta coffee (C. arabica L. X Tetraploid C. canephora Pierre)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/F31C83863241</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/F31C83863241</guid><description>
	The biennial bearing and the long productive nature of coffee makes it difficult to release coffee variety within a short time span. This study aimed at evaluating the yield performance of the Arabusta hybrids and its backcrosses developed by Coffee Research Institute of the Kenya Agricultural and Livestock Research Organization (KALRO-CRI) using the morphological traits. Nineteen coffee gen...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Variability, Association and Path Coefficient Analysis of Green Pod Yield and Yield Components of Hot pepper (Capsicum annuum L.) Landraces at Mereb Lehke, Northern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/2C6A83763304</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/2C6A83763304</guid><description>
	Understanding the genetic variability and diversity of crops is the basis for breeding and improving of crops. Sixty four Ethiopian hot pepper genotypes were evaluated in 88 simple lattice design for genetic variability in green fruit yield and yield related traits at Axum Agricultural Research Center during 2018/2019 under irrigation. Data were collected on green pod yield and yield related...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluating natural infection of fungal, bacterial and viral pathogens to dry bean genotypes under field conditions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/385BEEF63332</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPBCS/article-abstract/385BEEF63332</guid><description>
	Fungal, bacterial and viral diseases are economic foliar diseases that cause yield losses, between 40 and 100%, in commonly grown dry bean cultivars in the world. Development of disease resistance genotypes is a complex interaction between genetic and environmental factors. This study focused on determining the natural infection of disease-causing pathogens of angular leaf spot, powdery mild...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>