<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Philosophy and Culture - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Philosophy and Culture</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Tabooing insults: Why the ambivalence?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/DB569ED63018</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/DB569ED63018</guid><description>
	This paper examines insults, both verbal and non-verbal, on the premise that societies the world over have adopted an ambivalent attitude towards the creation and use of insult. The ambivalence argument is grounded in the sheer preponderance of both institutionalised and informal usages of verbal and non-verbal insults, through the arts mainly, as well as the tabooing regimes of insults in t...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Socio-cultural perspectives on death announcements in Ghanaian newspapers: Some sociolinguistic evidence</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/8F1C40763757</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/8F1C40763757</guid><description>
	Death announcements are presumed to provide a socio-cultural icon for examining the societys collective attitude towards death and dying. The present study attempts to investigate the death announcement genre in Ghana from a sociolinguistic viewpoint in order to highlight the underpinning sociocultural perspectives. To accomplish this task, the study deployed both qualitative and quantitativ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A Yor&#xF9;b&#xE1; reflection on the theodicy embedded in Prince&#x2019;s &#x201C;Sign O&#x2019; The Times&#x201D;: Implications for scholarship on African Theology</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/8358B1461380</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/8358B1461380</guid><description>
	Given the array of tracks inspired by various realities during Prince Roger Nelsons (popularly known as Prince) career, this study engages the philosophical problem of evil as well as the implied justification that Africans had no idea of the divine as embedded in his Sign O the Times. In this track, Prince reflects over some of the horrendous evils in the world. However, his evangelizing of...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Can there be an African logic?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/CC6DA3F60912</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/CC6DA3F60912</guid><description>
	Since the myriads of questions and keen debates concerning the existence or otherwise of African philosophy have been defused and now become obsolete, some thinkers are poised to argue for contextual or African peculiar perspective of the various branches of philosophy, including logic. The preoccupation in this study is to make an inquiry into whether logic is culture bound or contextualiza...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>African systems of thought: Whether they fit scientific knowledge
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/C5AB41060914</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/C5AB41060914</guid><description>
	This paper aims to show that in Africa there are thought systems that can have equivalent value with the scientific practices in the Western paradigmal system though it is not itself paradigmal. The Western thought system by its nature is exclusive for other traditions of scientific practice by its claim that science is deeply rational, universal and methodological. African scientific practi...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility: An old wine in a new gourd</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/3D31BCF60505</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/3D31BCF60505</guid><description>
	A corporations moral obligation is said to be sustained by two viewpoints: the narrow and broad views. The narrow view restrains a corporations moral obligation to the corporations owners and shareholders while the broad view, which is often deployed to support Corporate Social Responsibility initiatives, extends the corporations moral obligation towards others beyond the confines of the cor...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Seeing Foucault&#x2019;s theory through African lenses: The discourse on sex, gender and power</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/3AAA8DB59532</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/3AAA8DB59532</guid><description>
	The paradigm of male domination exemplified by the social relations between the sexes is structured in a way that men dominate and women submit. As such, these socio cultural relations presuppose a dyadic conception of domination in which women are subject to men. If men are domineering and women are docile, then it is contradictory to say women have power. However, in line with Foucaults id...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The feasibility of self-reliancism as a foundation for democracy
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/5160E3F59534</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/5160E3F59534</guid><description>
	In popular discourse, democracy often centres on concepts such as liberty, equality, consent, choice, rule of law, participation, accountability, transparency, etc. This popular rendition, more often than not, excludes the notion of self-reliancism. This study argues that the exclusion of this notion weakens the etymological foundation of democracy as government by the people and undermines ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>&#x2018;Mine to Win&#x2019;: a Book that Binds Aspects of Ethiopian Christianity Education and Philosophy</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/103EF9858537</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/103EF9858537</guid><description>
	The author of this book, Hiwot Teffera, is among the vibrant politers of the then generation called YaTiwulid. This period extends from 1972- 1992 , and many of them were young and involved in different political factions of the time. She and some of her friends are destined to share their experience, knowledge and reading; however, many could bear fruit because of Red and White Terrors of t...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Moderate communitarianism is different: A Response to J. O. Famakinwa and B. Matolino</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/525C35C58539</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPC/article-abstract/525C35C58539</guid><description>
	Moderate communitarianism is a thesis introduced into African philosophical literature by the Akan philosopher Kwame Gyekye. He suggests that this thesis better accounts for the Akan and, to some extent, African social set-up than what he calls radical communitarianism (a thesis which he attributes especially to John Mbiti and Ifeanyi Menkiti). However, Gyekye is criticised by J. O. Famakinw...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>