<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Physical Education and Sport Management - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Physical Education and Sport Management</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Analysis on the environmental ethics awareness of outdoor recreation leaders</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/A3136F660988</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/A3136F660988</guid><description>
	The most preliminary factor of an outdoor recreation is nature. In a state where natural resources are depleted, it is not viable to mention an outdoor recreation; hence during recreation activities it is of utmost importance to conserve and attentively consume natural resources. The aim of this study is to analyze the environmental-ethics awareness levels of recreation leaders who play a sa...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Technical problems in teaching basketball practical session: The case of Grade 11 in Alamura Preparatory School
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/BBD34D659333</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/BBD34D659333</guid><description>
	The main purpose of this study was to assess the major technical problems in teaching basketball practical session of Grade 11 in Alamura Preparatory School. To undertake this study, descriptive survey design with mixed method was employed. The sources of the data were 63 Grade 11 students, health and physical education (HPE) teachers, 3 principals, and 1 department head. Stratified random s...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The level of physical activity and the body mass index as factors that influence absenteeism and 
health behaviours
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/29F4B5057620</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/29F4B5057620</guid><description>
	Obesity and health problems have been observed to reduce productivity and increase absenteeism. Although the relationship between health and productivity is strong, few studies have examined whether the level of obesity and physical activity affect the absence from work and how the health-related habits are affected. The aim of this study was to examine the relations between Body Mass Index ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Buying in: Analyzing the first fan adopters of a new National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I Football Program</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/8E48F4757160</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/8E48F4757160</guid><description>
	Establishing a strong fan base within the inaugural year of a National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I Football Program presents many challenges. Tracking consumers and their behavior becomes imperative as sport marketers seek to better understand the first fan adopters of a new program. With new NCAA football programs being established every year, sport marketers of a new ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A content analysis of pictorial content in entertainment and sports programming networks (ESPN): The magazine&#x2019;s body issue</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/53E03E555764</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/53E03E555764</guid><description>
	The purpose of this study was to examine the pictorial content of entertainment and sports programming networks (ESPN) The Magazines Body Issue to determine the type of coverage sportswomen received in the annual special edition. The Body Issue was intended to celebrate the physical characteristics of athletes through visual representation that honored diverse human elements such as body sha...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>From virtual reality to reality: Examining the relationship between sport video gaming and sport consumption behaviors</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/DD13E3265221</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/DD13E3265221</guid><description>
	Insufficient attention has been given to the relationship between sport video games and sport consumer behaviors even though sports and sport video games are popular, multi-billion dollar industries. The purpose of this study is two-fold. First, examine the effects of sport video gamer identification on sport consumption behaviors. Second, investigate the extent which sport fan identificatio...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effectiveness of motor intervention on children with Developmental Coordination Disorder (DCD): A systematic review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/90C775765217</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/90C775765217</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to determine the quality of evidence obtainable from published clinical trials on motor interventions, and assess whether the quality, in terms of methods and results, is sufficient to enable the development of evidence-based recommendations for clinical practice on children with Developmental Coordination Disorder (DCD). Here, a systematic review was conducted, with...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Olympic and world champion judo athletes: Motivational aspects</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/F0DCF2764672</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/F0DCF2764672</guid><description>
	The objectives of this study is to identify the motivational factors which make judo athletes train for years until they finally become world and/or Olympic champion in judo. The work employed closed-ended rating values questionnaires Three Brazilian Olympic judo team members, (men and women) 41 in total were evaluated. Three professional experts of renowned and proven experience in judo com...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Children with autism spectrum disorder and physical activity: A descriptive synthesis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/7D71ACC62461</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/7D71ACC62461</guid><description>
	The purpose of this literature review was to describe research on strategies used in engaging children with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) in physical activity. Keyword searches were used to identify articles from selected electronic databases over a 25-year period from 1990 through 2015. Thirty-five articles met all inclusion criteria. These studies were retrieved, reviewed, coded, analyzed...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Study on fear of negative evaluation, and social appearance anxiety of university students engaged in futsal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/3194A4960657</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPESM/article-abstract/3194A4960657</guid><description>
	This study is conducted by using a screening model with an eye to examine the fear of negative evaluation, and social appearance anxiety of sportsmen engaged in futsal. The research was carried out on teams which participated in the Futsal Competitions organized through Turkey University Sports Federation at Physical Education and Sports College of Ahi Evran University between April 01 and 0...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>