<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Petroleum and Gas Engineering - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Petroleum and Gas Engineering</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Influence of wavelet phase rotation on post stack model based seismic inversion: A case study of X-field, 
Niger Delta, Nigeria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/8B16D9963885</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/8B16D9963885</guid><description>
	The effect of wavelet phase rotation on post inversion in X-field Niger Delta has been investigated. This paper demonstrates the influence of wavelet phase employed in model based seismic inversion. It presents the problem associated with variation in wavelet phases employed in post-stack model based seismic inversion which affect the discrimination of litho-fluid contrast from inverted seis...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of a novel ionic demulsifier in the treatment of selected Niger Delta crude oil emulsions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/01FE60463621</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/01FE60463621</guid><description>
	Emulsion treatment is one of the major challenges in crude oil production, transportation and processing. It has great impact crude oil quality, refining costs and environment. The use of chemical demulsifiers is a widely accepted procedure in the industry. However, demulsifiers used in treatment of crude oil emulsions in Nigeria industries are imported. This study was designed to evaluate t...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Predicting the compressibility factor of natural gases containing various amounts of CO2 at high temperatures and pressures</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/A4C994063491</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/A4C994063491</guid><description>
	In recent years, many natural gas reservoirs have been discovered with varying CO2 contents, many of which are at supercritical conditions. Calculation of compressibility factors for such reservoirs is important. Therefore, this research presents an extensive review of the various methods to calculate the compressibility factor for different natural gases containing CO2 at various temperatur...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Performance evaluation of Mucuna solannie as a drilling fluid additive in water-base mud at cold temperature</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/D60887562851</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/D60887562851</guid><description>
	Weighted and unweighted aqueous mud formulations from a biomaterial, at cold temperature of 5C, were tested for their rheological characteristics. Based on API guidelines and recommended equipment for drilling fluid tests, the rheological properties of the formulations were determined. The muds exhibited pseudoplastic behaviour. The fluid loss volumes of the weighted and unweighted muds are ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Application of rate transient analysis modeling in diagnosis of well abnormal flowing status in Middle East carbonate reservoir</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/504D71362919</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/504D71362919</guid><description>
	Modern Rate Transient Analysis (RTA) is the hottest technology in recent years in reservoir engineering. Its main working principle is combining production data with bottom-hole pressure data based on the assuming reservoir model and well model. It will evaluate the reserves (Oil Drainage Radius and STOIIP), reservoir properties (permeability), wellbore condition (skin) and forecast producti...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Software approach on crude oil yields prediction: A case study of Tema Oil Refinery</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/441D4BA62193</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/441D4BA62193</guid><description>
	Yield prediction is an integral part of every refinery process due to the intricacy of the process and composition of crude oil. Inability to sufficiently predict the yields before refinery process creates challenges such as inadequacy in planning the operating conditions to meet product target, product optimisation failure and inability to meet product market specification. Predicting yield...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluating the performance of ultrasound energy on improved oil recovery using MATLAB reservoir simulation toolbox (MRST)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/C6F9A2661863</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/C6F9A2661863</guid><description>
	There are many processes the oil industry used to recover more oil from the reservoir after the natural energy is depleted. In this research work, ultrasound energy has been tested as a method of improving oil recovery after waterflooding. The method used in this research work was a numerical simulation using MATLAB Reservoir Simulation Toolbox (MRST-2017a). Ultrasound energy source equation...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Probabilistic approach for shale volume estimation in Bornu Basin of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/9394BAA61661</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/9394BAA61661</guid><description>
	The gamma ray log has over the years provided the conventional means for shale volume (Vsh) estimation. Knowledge of Vsh is used in the prediction of petrophysical parameters like effective porosity and water saturation, which are the input parameters for the calculation of oil in place. Currently, many studies have been conducted on the Bornu Basin of Nigeria, to access its hydrocarbon pote...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A dry gas material balance with an infinite aquifer influence: A comparative study between the unsteady state model of van Everdingen-Hurst and analytical model</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/C2693A861743</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/C2693A861743</guid><description>
	Aquifer water influx is an important natural mechanism for primary recovery. It affects the performance of all types of reservoirs, also natural gas reservoirs. Water influx provides pressure support during reservoir depletion, resulting in slower pressure decline. Consequently, gas reservoirs associated with large aquifers show a flattening, cubic behavior of the p/z vs. Gp curve, which all...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Concept of complete CO2 capture from natural gas inside exploration wells and its storage in rock reservoirs
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/5257C6D61763</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPGE/article-abstract/5257C6D61763</guid><description>
	The innovative concept herein shown intends to present a new system of carbon capture and storage (CCS) from natural gas extracted on cement completions of gas wells by absorbent selective nanoporous materials, forming conducting channels on linked pores. CO2 fluids will be transported upwards and then injected and stored in upper nonproductive oil and gas porous rock reservoirs by the remov...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>