<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Pharmacognosy and Phytotherapy - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Pharmacognosy and Phytotherapy</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Hypoglycaemic activity of preheated (roasting) Aframomum citratum (C. Pereira) K. Schum and Tetrapleura tetraptera (Schumach &amp; Thonn.) fruits beverage on Streptozotocin-induced rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/936C25963544</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/936C25963544</guid><description>
	Tetrapleura tetraptera and Aframomum citratum fruits are used as spices and in the traditional pharmacopeia in Cameroon. They are mostly combined and preheated for many purposes while cooking. The effects of roasting on the phenolic content of spices, phenolic profile of a beverage made with the mix of roasted spices and its hypoglycaemic activity on diabetes complications were investigated....</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phytochemical profiling, body weight effect and anti-hypercholesterolemia potentials of Cnidoscolus aconitifolius leaf extracts in male albino rat</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/D534B0A63364</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/D534B0A63364</guid><description>
	The present study investigated the phytochemical constituents of Cnidoscolus aconitifolius leaves extracts and its anti-hypercholesterolemia potentials using standard analytical methods. Forty five male albino rats weighing (115-121 g), divided into nine groups of five rats were used. Group I served as the control while the other groups were administered 200, 400, 600 and 800 mg/kg body weig...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antioxidant and alpha amylase inhibitory activity of Nepalese medicinal plants from Gorkha district</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/E04F15A63437</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/E04F15A63437</guid><description>
	The aim of this study is to evaluate the antioxidant activity, -amylase inhibition activity, estimation of total phenolic and flavonoid content and the toxicity in ten medicinal plants Woodfordia fructicosa, Tectaria coadunate, Prunus cerasoides, Abrus precatorius, Eclipta prostrate, Poranopsis paniculata, Chenopodium album, Oroxylum indicum, Curcuma caesia, and Butea monosperma collected fr...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Macroscopic and microscopic features of diagnostic value for Warburgia ugandensis Sprague leaf and stem-bark herbal materials
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/488269963479</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/488269963479</guid><description>
	Warbugia ugandensis is among the ten most utilized medicinal plants in East Africa. Stem-bark and leaves are used as remedies for malaria, stomachache, coughs and several skin diseases. Consequently, the plant is endangered because of uncontrolled harvest from the wild and lack of domestication. There is therefore fear of poor quality commercialized products due to lack of quality control me...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phytochemical analysis, antioxidant and antidiarrhoeal activities of methanol extract of Fimbristylis miliacea (L.) Vahl</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/B8089FE63247</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/B8089FE63247</guid><description>
	The present study determined phytochemical content, antioxidant and antidiarrhoeal effect of methanol extract of Fimbristylis miliacea. Phytochemical screening showed the presence of flavonoids, saponins, tannins, phenols, alkaloids and cardiac glycosides. Total phenolic, flavonoids, flavonols, tannins, -carotene, lycopene, chlorophyll-, and chlorophyll- contents were found 154.13 mg GAE/g, ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Review on biological and immunomodulatory properties of Moringa oleifera in animal and human nutrition</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/052862862881</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/052862862881</guid><description>
	Moringa oleifera, also called miracle tree or tree for life is a tree native from India. Highly resistant to drought, M. oleifera grows very well in tropical regions, including Benin. It is a plant with very high nutritional values. The different parts of the plant (leaves, fruiots, seeds, roots, bark and flowers) have multiple uses, both therapeutic and nutritional, with uses in human and a...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Pharmacognostic, physicochemical and phytochemical evaluation of the leaves of Fadogia cienkowski Schweinf (Rubiaceae)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/CEB9B0C61988</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/CEB9B0C61988</guid><description>
	Fadogia cienkowskii is a shrub used in folklore medicine. Evaluations of the leaves were carried out to determine the macroscopic, microscopic, chemomicroscopic, physicochemical and phytochemical profiles using standard methods. The macroscopic examination revealed fresh leaves are green, odourless with a bitter taste. The leaf is oblong-elliptic in shape and sub-acute at apex; rounded at th...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Tea tree oil a new natural adjuvant for inhibiting glioblastoma growth</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/644F7E962032</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/644F7E962032</guid><description>
	Tea Tree oil (TTO), the essential oil from the Australian native Melaleuca alternifolia has demonstrated a variety of beneficial efficacies including antimicrobial, antifungal, antiviral and anti-inflammatory. This report discusses data obtained on the in vitro activity of TTO on human glioblastoma cells U87MG. Cell viability was examined by 2-(4,5-dimethyl-2-thiazolyl)-3,5-diphenyl-2H-tetra...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A comparative study of phytochemical profile and antioxidant activity of Sahelian plants used in the treatment of infectious diseases in northern part of Burkina Faso: Acacia seyal Delile and Acacia tortilis (Forssk.) Hayne subsp. raddiana (Savi)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/011882C62187</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/011882C62187</guid><description>
	Acacia seyal and Acacia tortilis are used in the treatment of infectious diseases in traditional medicine by population in Northern Burkina Faso. Phytochemical screening by tube test and on HPTLC plates showed the presence of important chemical compounds in these plants. Determination of total phenolic content using method of Folin-Ciocalteu Reagent (FCR) and antioxidant activity by 1, 1-dip...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Phytochemistry, acute toxicity and blood profile of albino rats treated with fruit extract of 
Solanum macrocarpon
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/E3F451161796</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPP/article-abstract/E3F451161796</guid><description>
	Phytochemical screening of the methanolic fruit extract of Solanum macrocarpon was performed using standard method. Eighteen male albino mice, assigned into six groups (n=3) were used to determine the acute toxicity (LD50) of the extract. Haematological effect of the extract was determined using forty eight adult male rats assigned into four groups (A-D; n=12). The treatment groups received ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>