<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Petroleum Technology and Alternative Fuels - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Petroleum Technology and Alternative Fuels</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Fatty acid profile and quality parameters of Ceiba pentandra (L.) seed oil: A potential source of biodiesel</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/0D465E659580</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/0D465E659580</guid><description>
	The probable depletion of fossil energy resources has led the international scientific community to direct research towards biofuels, including vegetable oils. Benin has a rich biodiversity with multiple oilseed species, potential sources of biofuels. Among these, Ceiba pentandra was identified and selected for a detailed study of its unconventional vegetable oil. In this order of idea, the ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of some citrus juice concentrates on crude 
oil emulsion
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/733780658106</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/733780658106</guid><description>
	Crude oil emulsions constitute a major challenge in oil field operations. To resolve this challenge, many researchers have studied crude oil emulsion demulsification patterns in the presence of various demulsifiers. Research is ongoing for discovery of locally sourced biodegradable and inexpensive demulsifiers. The aim of this research is to demusify heavy crude oil emulsion, using locally s...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Biodiesel potentials of two phenotypes of Cyperus esculentus unconventional oils</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/841A23356999</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/841A23356999</guid><description>
	Two varieties of Cyperus esculentus, identified by their phenotype (black or yellow) were collected from Benin. To investigate their biodiesel profiles, the roots were extracted with hexane. Physicochemical properties and fuel profiles of obtained oils (YCE and BCE, respectively Yellow C. esculentus and Black C. esculentus) were determined by following standards methods. Although the major p...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Field application of adding formate salts exertion on the water based drilling fluid properties enhancement: an experimental comparative analysis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/C48574E64634</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/C48574E64634</guid><description>
	Due to the fact that there is a wide range of drilling fluids, it is difficult to discuss drilling fluid composition that is completely accurate for all mud types in all drilling situations. The approach taken here is description of drilling fluids as two-phase systems. Formate base fluids have been utilized in a wide variety of drilling operations in terms of its applicant and lower expense...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Removal of free fatty acids in neem oil using diphenylamine functionalized magnetic mesoporous silica SBA-15 for biodiesel production</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/F2930FB58533</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/F2930FB58533</guid><description>
	Biodiesel is produced from edible/non-edible plants oil. However, alkaline transesterification of these oils makes the process challenging due to the presence of large amount of free fatty acids (FFA), which forms soap on reaction with alkali. Hence, it is necessary to reduce FFA present so that alkaline catalyzed transesterification can be carried out. In this work, biodiesel fuel was produ...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of biofuel production on selected local Communities in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/031CC8C57939</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/031CC8C57939</guid><description>
	Biofuel is gradually being adopted as alternative to fossil fuel in the use for automotive, thermal and power generation. The Nigerian Policy on biofuel introduced in 2007 expresses the national biofuel production programme. However, problems associated with production and uses arise from the effects on arable land and staple foods, which if diverted for production, have vast diverse effects...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Physico-chemical characteristics of Pakistani used engine oils</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/3740EDE57936</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/3740EDE57936</guid><description>
	In this study, physicochemical characteristics of Pakistani fresh and used monograde (SAE-40, SAE-50) and multigrade (SAE-20W/50) engine oils have been studied. The samples were analyzed for specific gravity at 60/60F, kinematic viscosity at 100 and 40C, kinematic viscosity index, pour point, flash point, total base number, copper strip corrosion and sulphur contents following the ASTM (Amer...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Temperature programme reduction (TPR) studies of cobalt phases in &#x3B3;-alumina supported cobalt catalysts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/9824F0256972</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/9824F0256972</guid><description>
	Temperature programmed reduction (TPR) is one of the techniques for obtaining information about phases or bulk species in heterogeneous catalysts. Information from TPR analysis can give insights about phase-support interaction and extent of reduction of the phases at different temperatures. TPR technique is a common tool in the characterisation of cobalt based Fischer-Tropsch (FT) catalysts....</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The effects of the volatile oil-gas ratio on reserve estimation (GMBE versus CMBE) in undersaturated volumetric reservoirs</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/867D06751942</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/867D06751942</guid><description>
	
		This work presents a general, straight-line method to estimate the original oil and gas in-place in a reservoir without restrictions on fluid composition. All past efforts are applicable to only restricted ranges of reservoir fluids. The work supersedes these and it is applicable to the full range of reservoir fluids-including volatile-oils and gas-condensates. The work is based on the n...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A review of biodiesel generation from non edible seed oils crop using non conventional heterogeneous catalysts</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/90E020F50915</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPTAF/article-abstract/90E020F50915</guid><description>
	The focus of this review is on the use of non-conventional heterogeneous catalysts for biodiesel synthesis. The review is based on published works that have utilized these non-conventional catalysts for biodiesel synthesis with very good biodiesel yield. The non-conventional catalysts under consideration in this review are those obtained majorly from egg shells. These materials are generally...</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>