<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Parasitology and Vector Biology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Parasitology and Vector Biology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Assessment of the performance of malaria rapid diagnostic test in acutely malnourished children under five years of age in Nanoro - Burkina Faso</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/B1A563063255</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/B1A563063255</guid><description>
	The interaction of malaria with malnutrition is complex. In areas where malnutrition among children is prevalent, management of malaria is not standardized. In Burkina Faso, malaria treatment is prescribed after positive malaria rapid diagnostic test (RDT) or thick blood smears confirmation regardless of the nutritional status of the child. The study aims to assess the performance of malaria...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Studies on distribution and abundance of freshwater snail intermediate hosts of schistosomiasis along Kwanar Areh Dam in Rimi L.G.A. of Katsina State</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/505AA0362572</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/505AA0362572</guid><description>
	Various species of freshwater snails act as intermediate hosts for Schistosoma species. The Bulinus and Biomphalaria snails serve as intermediate hosts for Schistosoma haematobium and Schistosoma mansoni, which are the causative agents of urinary and intestinal schistosomiasis in humans, respectively. This study aims to determine the distribution and abundance of these snail intermediate hos...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of malaria and the associated risk factors among pregnant women attending antenatal care in health institutions of Damot Woyide district,  Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/1931B3E61659</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/1931B3E61659</guid><description>
	Malaria during pregnancy is a cause of morbidity and mortality in pregnant women and their fetuses eventually the newborns and infants. Hence, this study was conducted to determine the prevalence and risk factors of malaria among pregnant women that attend antenatal clinics in health institutions found in Damote Woyide district. A health institution based cross-sectional study was conducted....</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence and intensity of urogenital and intestinal schistosomiasis among primary school children in rural districts of Senegal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/673F7E762189</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/673F7E762189</guid><description>
	Schistosomiasis is a public health problem in Senegal with unevenly distributed prevalence. The purpose of this study was to assess the prevalence and intensity of Schistosoma haematobium and Schistosoma mansoni infections among primary school children in eight districts of Senegal. A cross-sectional survey including school children aged from 7 to 13 years were included and was conducted in ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A pilot study on isolation of Asaia and detecting its co-presence with Plasmodium falciparum in two major malaria vectors in Senegal</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/69934FA59973</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/69934FA59973</guid><description>
	The declining of malaria creates the opportunity to accelerate its elimination. However, the elimination program is threatened by the spread of insecticide resistance among Anopheles (An.) mosquitoes, stressing the urgent need for new vector control strategies. Recent evidence of stable infection of anopheles symbionts that could affect the development of Plasmodium parasites within mosquito...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Community's knowledge, attitude and practices toward malaria and mosquito behavior 	in Abeshige Woreda, Gurage Zone, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/CD7F3259665</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/CD7F3259665</guid><description>
	Community Knowledge about malaria and mosquito behavior is critical for successful malaria intervention, appropriate treatment, prevention and control measures. Thus, this study aimed to assess knowledge, attitude and practices of the community towards malaria and mosquito behavior in Abeshige Woreda, South west Ethiopia. A community-based cross-sectional study was conducted in Abeshige Wore...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Vector resistance to pyrethroids and impact on the efficacy of insecticide-treated mosquito nets in Southern Benin</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/322565B59317</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/322565B59317</guid><description>
	The use of Long Lasting Insecticidal Nets (LLINs) to protect population from malaria is one of the main strategies which decline the malaria morbidity and mortality in several trials carried out in different countries. However, resistance to pyrethroids is one of some problems which compromise the LLINs effectiveness. This study compares the effectiveness of LLINs in two areas, low and high ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of indoor residual spraying on malaria incidence, parasitemia and parasite density among children less than five years of age in northern Benin</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/BE8928A59003</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/BE8928A59003</guid><description>
	The effects of indoor residual spraying (IRS) on malaria transmission have been documented. However, the impact on morbidity has not always been highlighted. The aim of this study was to evaluate the effects of IRS on malaria incidence, parasitemia and parasite density among children less than five years of age in Benin. We conducted a cohort study in sprayed and unsprayed areas during the m...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of Schistosoma mansoni infection and associated factors in irrigation workers in Gamo Gofa and South Omo Zone, 2017: A Community based parasitological survey</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/48CA70B58811</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/48CA70B58811</guid><description>
	Schistosomiasis is one of the most prevalent parasitic diseases and an important public health problem in many developing countries. In this era of global warming and climatic changes, the epidemiology of temperature-dependent infectious diseases could be changing implying the possibility of new transmission area in the world in general and in Ethiopia in particular. This study aims to asses...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Review on the epidemiological features of equine Endoparasites in Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/536035657807</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JPVB/article-abstract/536035657807</guid><description>
	Equines contributed a lot to the livelihood of Ethiopian people in terms of income generation, public transport, ploughing, threshing and ambulatory service for sick humans and animals, however various health problems hamper their contributions and of which endoparasitism is the major one. A number of epidemiological studies conducted in different part of Ethiopia point out the burden and ty...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>