<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Stored Products and Postharvest Research - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Stored Products and Postharvest Research</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Re-useable plastic crates as a veritable tool for handling of fresh fruits and vegetables: Lagos State as a case study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/98E007363481</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/98E007363481</guid><description>
	Nigerian Stored Products Research Institute (NSPRI) developed plastic packaging crates of International standard and best practices known as reusable plastic crates (RPCs) in lieu of raffia woven baskets (RWBs) for the transportation and storage of fresh fruits and vegetables in 1986. In collaboration with Lagos State Ministry of Agriculture, Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition and Postha...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of morphometric and physiological seed quality traits of improved cowpea (Vigna unguiculata L. Walp) varieties in Sierra Leone</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/7CAD42D61960</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/7CAD42D61960</guid><description>
	A study was conducted at the Seed Laboratory of the Njala Agricultural Research Centre (NARC) to evaluate the seed quality traits of five cowpea genotypes at room temperature (25  2C). The five genotypes studied were Slipeas 1, 2, 4 and 5 and local Tabe. The trial was laid out in a Completely Randomized Design (CRD) in four replicates. The results indicated that the local variety (Tabe) had ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determination of appropriate packaging materials for cowpea seed storage</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/19A3A8261245</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/19A3A8261245</guid><description>
	Quality seed is an important resource for any seed-propagated crop. Cowpea (Vigna unguiculata) seed is prone to cowpea weevil (Callosobruchus maculatus) infestation during storage. This can result in 100% seed loss when stored without treatment. Smallholder farmers in Kenya use traditional methods of storage and occasionally accompanied by pesticides treatment. Due to health concerns, pestic...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Relative susceptibilities of different populations of Sitophilus zeamais and Prostephanus truncatus to currently registered grain protectants in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/B0A26EF60327</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/B0A26EF60327</guid><description>
	Sitophilus zeamais Motschulsky and Prostephanus truncatus (Horn) are the two most destructive post-harvest insect pests of maize worldwide. Bioassays were carried out to determine the efficacy of commercially available dilute dust grain protectants (pseudonamed protectant A, B, C, D, E and F) in controlling S. zeamais and P. truncatus under laboratory conditions. The products tested were: Hu...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Degradation of postharvest applied fludioxonil in pomegranate fruit cv. &#x2018;Wonderful&#x2019; and efficacy on the gray mould</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/2AFA23060057</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/2AFA23060057</guid><description>
	Present study aimed to determine the effects of fludioxonil (FLU) against the gray mould disease development on pomegranate fruits; and the residue levels of FLU during 150 days of storage. Pomegranate (Punica granatum) fruits are very susceptible to postharvest decay (Botrytis cinerea Pers.) and very few chemicals are approved for the use in postharvest storage. Studies conducted with Wonde...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-harvest losses in maize store-time and marketing model perspectives in Sub-Saharan Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/9C2E4E759875</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/9C2E4E759875</guid><description>
	Post&#x2012;harvest losses of maize are almost half of the produced grains in Sub&#x2012;Saharan Africa. Efforts to reverse this trend are recommended. Thus, there is a prerequisite to create a post&#x2012;harvest loss resilient strategy to guide small scale maize growing farmers in Africa. In this review, critical elements underlying post&#x2012;harvest losses in Africa such as infestation by insect&#x2012;pests, microbes, r...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Postharvest loss assessment of maize (Zea mays) along its value chain in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/9D1501459877</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/9D1501459877</guid><description>
	Maize is the third most important cereal and staple globally. Poor agricultural policies and funding are the major problems of agriculture in Nigeria. This work was aimed at studying maize postharvest losses through identification of causes and sources. Data were gathered via Commodity Systems Assessment Methodology which includes 26 components, structured interviews and protocols for measur...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Selection, characterization and identification of smokes from different biomass materials as a medium for modifying the atmosphere for stored grain</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/687640559623</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/687640559623</guid><description>
	In developing countries, losses of stored grains due to insect pests are significant. Modified atmosphere (MA) storage is one of the strategies to minimize impact of the pests. This work aimed to identify a biomass material for generating smoke having high concentrations of CO and CO2 to create a MA in stored grains. Smokes from seven biomass were characterized in terms of CO, CO2, NO and O2...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of four variant diatomaceous earths and a commercial DE Insecto&#xAE; against Callosobruchus maculatus F. (Coleoptera:Chrysomelidae) on two varieties of stored cowpea in Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/BA4397F58911</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/BA4397F58911</guid><description>
	Nigerian Stored Products Research Institute (NSPRI) has patented a Diatomaceous Earth, a non-toxic pesticide NSPRIDUST Patent No. 000744 for storage of grains with Trade Marks Section of the Federal Ministry of Trade and Investment, Abuja, Nigeria. Efficacy of four Nigerian Diatomaceous Earths (DEs): Bularafa, Abakire, Share and Kwami as grain protectants of stored cowpea against cowpea bruc...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of the storage and drying processes of Melissa officinalis L. leaves</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/6D0F79459057</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSPPR/article-abstract/6D0F79459057</guid><description>
	Melissa officinalis L. (Lamiaceae), medicinal plant used as sedative commercialized in natura and as dry plant in Brazil. The aim of this study was to determine the postharvest life and drying processes of Melissa leaves in function of essential oil contents. Leaves (10 g) were stored at room temperature (RT=19.6C) and refrigeration temperature (10C, AR), measured daily loss of fresh mass. I...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>