<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Soil Science and Environmental Management - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Soil Science and Environmental Management</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Validation of blended NPSB fertilizer rates on yield, yield components of Teff [Eragrostis tef (Zuccagni) Trotter] at vertisols of Hatsebo, Central Tigray, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/4F6A1D363827</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/4F6A1D363827</guid><description>
	Application of unbalanced nutrition was the main yield limiting factor in the study area. Hence, an experiment was conducted during the 2017 cropping season on farmers fields to validate and determine optimum blended fertilizer rate for teff production. Eight levels of NPSB (0, 25, 50, 100, 150, 200, 250 and 300 kg ha-1) and recommended NP (100 kg ha-1 urea and 100 kg ha-1TSP) were used as t...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic importance of termites and integrated soil and water conservation for the rehabilitation of termite-degraded lands and termite management in Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/1AE656663763</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/1AE656663763</guid><description>
	In Ethiopia, termites pose serious threat to a variety of agricultural crops, forestry, rangelands, houses and other wooden structures. Termite problem is particularly prevalent in the western part of the country, where it has persisted for many years and has received wide publicity. Termites appeared in the region for the first time in 1904 at a specific place called Bafano Koreche around K...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Soil conservation techniques among arable crop farmers in Odo Otin local government area, Osun state: A multinomial logit approach</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/D8E61CB63611</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/D8E61CB63611</guid><description>
	The study investigated the soil conservation techniques among the arable farmers in Odo Otin local government area of Osun State. Two-stage sampling procedure was employed for the study. Primary data were collected from 120 arable crop farmers in the Local Government Area. Data collected were analysed using descriptive statistics; multinomial logit regression model. Result shows that most th...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of flooding on peatland in U Minh Thuong National Park, Vietnam</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/F71443763685</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/F71443763685</guid><description>
	U Minh Thuong National Park is one of the two significant areas of peatland swamp forest remaining in Vietnam, and is recognized as one of the three highest priority sites for wetland conservation in Mekong Delta. A large area of Melaleuca Forest in the park was destroyed and degraded by a devastating fire in 2002. Besides this, an artificial flooding technique for controlling fire applied a...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Compost biomass, pH value and C, N, K contents of some local wild plant species: Case of Panicum maximum L., Trypsa- cum laxum L. and Pueraria javanica (Benth.) Benth, in the Region of Kisangani, 
Democratic Republic of Congo
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/A8B513A63372</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/A8B513A63372</guid><description>
	Soil fertility transience and weed management are often among decried impediments undermining agricultural productivity in many tropical countries. A study aiming at transforming baffling problems of abundant weed biomasses especially that of Panicum maximum (T1), Tryps-acum laxum (T2) and Pueraria javanica (T3), often cause of crop yield loss into advantage to enhance soil fertility, increa...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Soil moisture retention and rainfed wheat yield variations by the addition of gypsum and green manure</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/7A06DC963137</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/7A06DC963137</guid><description>
	In rainfed tract, the success of agriculture depends on conservation and efficient use of soil moisture and nutrients availability that directly linked with the presence of moisture in soil. The moisture can be conserved through several means including green manures and gypsum addition. The experiment was conducted to investigate the integrated effect of green manures and gypsum for moisture...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Use of charcoal (biochar) to enhance tropical soil fertility: A case of Masako in Democratic Republic 
of Congo
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/393549D63243</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/393549D63243</guid><description>
	Soil fertility transience in the region of Masako in Democratic Republic (RD) of Congo remains a major challenge to sustainable agricultural production. Recently, biochar application as soil amendment has attracted attention of the people across the world owing to its potential to improve soil physicochemical properties, crop yield and carbon sequestration into the soil. A study was conducte...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effects of long term sugarcane production on soils physicochemical properties at Finchaa sugar Estate</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/861B73363245</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/861B73363245</guid><description>
	In Ethiopia, where sugarcane has been cultivated for over 20 years, changes in soil physicochemical properties are expected to occur albeit information on the extent of change is scanty. A study was conducted in 2015 at Finchaa Sugar Estate with the objective of assessing the status of selected soil properties under long term mechanized sugarcane cultivation. Disturbed composite and undistur...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Optimization of the analytical method for the determination of organic matter</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/241D9A762939</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/241D9A762939</guid><description>
	Soil organic matter represents the remains of roots, plant materials, dead organisms in varies stages of decomposition and synthesis and is variable in composition. Walkley-Black method for the determination of organic matter is the most common method; however, it requires a lot of reagents and chemicals including potassium dichromate which is toxic especially when it is in a hexavalent form...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of vermicompost and blended fertilizers rates on yield and yield components of Tef (Eragrostis tef (Zucc.) Trotter)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/291673562326</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JSSEM/article-abstract/291673562326</guid><description>
	Tef is a stable crop in Ethiopia in which its yield is constrained by poor soil fertility management. Therefore, a field experiment was conducted for two consecutive years during 2016 and 2017 on clayey textural soil to assess the effect of vermicompost and inorganic fertilizer rates on yield and yield components of tef. Accordingly, field experiment with four levels of vermicompost (0, 2, 4...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>