<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Toxicology and Environmental Health Sciences - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Toxicology and Environmental Health Sciences</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Heavy metal pollution status and risk assessment on area with artisanal mining activities</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/E0AE3F163601</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/E0AE3F163601</guid><description>
	This study was undertaken to re-evaluate the heavy contamination level of Bagega community which recorded acute lead poisoning in 2010 and was reclaimed between 2010 and 2012. The levels of the following heavy metals (Zn, Pb, Hg, As and Cd) was measured in sixteen sampling sites around Bagega and its environs using Varian AA240 Atomic Absorption Spectrophotometer. The assessment of pollution...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Study of pesticides use conditions in cashew production in C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/BB1AC7E62661</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/BB1AC7E62661</guid><description>
	This work aims to promote the rational use of agrochemicals in cashew cultivation by evaluating health prevention culture and environmental preservation levels in cashew producers practices in Cte dIvoire. A cross-sectional study was conducted from April 2017 to August 2018 in the 3 main cashew production areas (Mankono, Dabakala and Bondoukou). A total of 386 cashew farmers randomly selecte...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Safety assessment of Cymbopogon shoenanthus (L.) Spreng. (Poaceae) essential oils: Oral toxicity, dermal and eye irritancy investigations</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/526CAC162014</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/526CAC162014</guid><description>
	The side effects prediction is a regulatory requirement prior the effective use of a new product as drug or pesticide constituent is allowed. The handling hazards of Cymbopogon schoenanthus essential oils (CSEO) were determined by investigating their acute and subacute toxicities as well as irritancy potential for eye and skin in compliance with the Organization for Economic Cooperation and ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Effect of lead on the activity of antioxidant enzymes and male reproductive hormones</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/549260D62016</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/549260D62016</guid><description>
	Environmental exposure to heavy metals such as lead is detrimental to male reproductive system. Lead induced oxidative stress is believed to contribute immensely to male infertility. The study was designed to investigate the influence of environmental lead exposure on the activities of antioxidant enzymes and male reproductive hormones levels in male individuals of Bagega and Kawaye villages...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cellular energy budget in tropical freshwater fish following exposure to sublethal concentrations 
of cadmium
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/8BA488A61586</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/8BA488A61586</guid><description>
	Under stressful conditions (toxicity), organisms often try to detoxify by mobilizing available energy sources with costs to various metabolic functions, such as growth or reproduction. Cellular energy allocation (CEA) is a methodology used to evaluate the energetic status and which relates with organisms overall condition and response to toxic stress. It consists of the integration of the en...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Therapeutic assessment of Idebenone versus Titanium dioxide nanoparticles induced pulmonary injury in adult albino Rats: Experimental study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/3E835E161195</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/3E835E161195</guid><description>
	Titanium dioxide nanoparticles are extensively used metal in cosmetics, sunscreens, food products, paints and drugs, producing oxidative stress and deoxyribonucleic acid damage. This study aimed to improve the overall (TiO2NP) use and decrease its related health hazards through the following objective among albino rates: To assess the TiO2NPs oral administration pulmonary induced toxic effec...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Spatial distribution and operations of petrol stations in the Kassena-Nankana district (Ghana) and associated health and safety hazards</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/A72776460885</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/A72776460885</guid><description>
	This study was conducted in Paga to assess the spatial distribution and operations of petrol stations and the associated health and safety hazards. Coordinates of the stations and the distances between them and the nearest residences were elicited and analysed using a GPS and ArcGIS software. Distances between fuel stations boundaries and the middle of the N10 highway and the distances betwe...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The possible protective effect of Zingiber officinale extract on cyclophosphamide-induced cardiotoxicity in adult male albino rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/8FB7E6F60621</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/8FB7E6F60621</guid><description>
	Cyclophosphamide, a cytotoxic alkylating agent, is an extensively used antineoplastic agent. Cardio-toxicity is considered as one of the limiting side effects of its use, which is attributed to oxidative stress. Zingiber officinale is powerful antioxidants against free radicals and oxidative attacks. The aim of this study is to investigate the possible protective effects of Z. officinale aga...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Poisonings with heavy metals and neoplasms - possible correlations</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/A86A83560333</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/A86A83560333</guid><description>
	As a side effect of industrialization, some diseases have developed only recently, becoming a challenge for the medical specialists both in research and medical treatment fields. Among these, the poisoning with heavy metals occupies a certain category that must retain attention, due to since the effects of this kind of poisoning are very serious effects if these injuries poisonings are not p...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-epidemic lead exposure to animals following a decontamination exercise in gold mining village of Bagega, Zamfara State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/62F674960529</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JTEHS/article-abstract/62F674960529</guid><description>
	This study focused on the evaluation of environmental lead contamination due to artisanal gold mining at a Nigerian village of Bagega one year after a clean-up exercise was carried out. Water samples were collected from earthen dams, faucets and wells, while plant and soil samples from grazing fields, residential areas and sites within the vicinity of the gold mine. The collected samples wer...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>