<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Health - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Health</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Efficacy of Newcastle disease vaccines and vaccination protocols commonly used in Mali, West Africa</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/DDD000B63850</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/DDD000B63850</guid><description>
	Newcastle disease, caused by Avian paramyxovirus -1 (APMV-1), is a devastating disease of poultry that is endemic in many countries worldwide. Several commercial vaccines and protocols are available against the disease and in most cases, they provide good clinical protection. However, despite vaccination, cases of Newcastle disease are often seen in some countries, including Mali in West Afr...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Clinicians&#x2019; perception and assessment of risk factors for surgical site infections in small animal practice in South-West, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/4EC016063852</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/4EC016063852</guid><description>
	This study evaluated the prevalence of Surgical Site Infections (SSIs), the enhancing risk factors in small animal hospitals and clinics, and clinicians perception of SSIs in South-west, Nigeria. Ten years (2007-2017) surgical patients case records from four government veterinary hospitals were initially studied. Fifty-seven copies of structured pre-tested questionnaires were further adminis...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Causes of organ condemnations in cattle at slaughter and associated financial losses in Siaya County, Kenya</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/E2EEFBF63595</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/E2EEFBF63595</guid><description>
	Cattle production is an important economic activity worldwide. Its potential, however, is not fully maximized owing to disease conditions, some causing condemnation and wastage of edible organs at slaughter and a threat of zoonoses. This work aimed at establishing definitive causes of organ condemnation and financial losses in cattle from three slaughterhouses (Kaumara, Siaya, and Ugunja) in...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of operational facilities and sanitary practices in Zangon Shanu abattoir, Sabon Gari Local Government Area, Kaduna State, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/95C428163666</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/95C428163666</guid><description>
	A descriptive cross-sectional study was conducted to assess the operational facilities and sanitary practices in Zangon Shanu abattoir, Kaduna State, Nigeria. Semi structured questionnaires were administered to the workers and also observational studies on facilities and sanitary practices in the abattoir were conducted. The results showed that 75.00% of the abattoir workers were between the...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Determination of some heavy metals residues in slaughtered cattle at Sokoto and Gusau modern abattoirs, Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/B2E894163692</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/B2E894163692</guid><description>
	Some heavy metals are classified under environmental pollutant due to their toxic effects on animals, human and plants. These metals are not biodegradable in environment and find their way into the food chain. Concentrations of lead (Pb), cadmium (Cd), and chromium (Cr) were determined in some selected organs and tissues (kidney, liver, muscle, hide and blood) of slaughtered cattle at Sokoto...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Molecular characterization and phylogenetic analysis of Newcastle disease virus isolated from poultry in North Central States of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/2DBAB7763449</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/2DBAB7763449</guid><description>
	Newcastle disease (ND) is a highly contagious viral disease constituting a continuous threat to the poultry industry worldwide. This study evaluated the genetic characteristics of Newcastle disease viruses (NDVs) obtained from backyard commercial poultry farms and live bird markets during active and passive surveillance in different regions of Plateau and Nasarawa States of Nigeria between 2...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Identification of small ruminant external parasite species in Tanqua Abergelle and Kola Tembien districts of Tigray region, Northern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/FF5BAB063249</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/FF5BAB063249</guid><description>
	Ectoparasites are a major concern in sheep and goat flocks, wherever sheep and goat are kept. A cross-sectional study was carried out in the districts of Kola Tembien and Tanqua Abergelle from September 2014 to June 2017 with the objectives of identifying external parasites to their species level. Randomly selected sheep and goats were clinically examined for the presence of ectoparasites or...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Ovopet&#xAE; a new and effective treatment to decrease inflammation, pain and lameness in competing trotters</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/81E433F62761</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/81E433F62761</guid><description>
	The use of nutritional supplements for joint problems has received much attention in recent years. At this sight, Ovopet, an innovative ingredient from eggshell membrane that ensures the supply of nutrients necessary for the repair of joints together with anti-inflammatory compounds of natural origin, appears as a natural alternative supplementation for the treatment of joint problems in hor...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Aerobic bacterial isolates, incidence rate and associated risk factors of heifer and cow mastitis in and around Debre-Libanos district, Oromia, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/67A870162763</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/67A870162763</guid><description>
	The investigation was led from February-November 2014 longitudinally to recognize aerobic bacterial isolates, estimate incidence rate, identify the associated risk factors and antimicrobial sensitivity patterns of heifer and cow mastitis in and around Debre-Libanos district. An aggregate of 31 Jersey and Holstein-Fresian cross heifers that were left for less than a month to calve were sample...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessing the impact of Trypanosoma spp. in cattle and its vector infestation in controlled and uncontrolled Kebeles in Kucha Wereda, Southern Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/EAB00E361982</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JVMAH/article-abstract/EAB00E361982</guid><description>
	This study was undertaken in Kucha Woreda to assess the impact of Trypanosoma spp. on cattle and its vector infestation rate using cross-sectional study design. The study was done from November 2016 to June 2017 on 384 local cattle using buffy coat method and tsetse fly density was seen in intervention area with non-controlled area. The overall infection rate 4.17% (N=16) showed an insignifi...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>