<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Journal of Yeast and Fungal Research  - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Journal of Yeast and Fungal Research </description><language>en-us</language><item><title>The potential use of Lentinus edodes to manage and control water hyacinth in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/1332ADC62907</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/1332ADC62907</guid><description>
	The rapid expansion and reproduction of certain plant species represents one of the biggest problems in aquatic environments, ranging from eutrophication to the limited availability of water for human consumption. Among these plants is water hyacinth (Eichhornia crassipes), a herbaceous hydrophyte often branded the worlds worst aquatic weed due to its invasive aggression, negative impact on ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Selection of appropriate substrate for production of oyster mushroom (Pleurotus ostreatus)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/5CE639762968</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/5CE639762968</guid><description>
	Mushroom production is an economically viable biotechnology process for conversion of various agro-industrial wastes into food. Mushroom, a fruiting body of macrofungi has been valued throughout the world as either food or medicine for more than three thousand years ago. The mushroom grows on a vast number of substrate and environment. Substrate compromises different agro-industrial residues...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of yield loss due to northern leaf blight in five maize varieties grown in Tanzania</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/94B5E0363433</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/94B5E0363433</guid><description>
	Field experiments were conducted in the Agricultural Research Institute, Uyole, using five susceptible maize varieties during 2013 and 2014 growing seasons. The varieties were used to determine yield losses due to northern leaf blight disease in Mbeya Region of Tanzania. The trials were laid out in two blocks of E. turcicum inoculated and Mancozeb treatment arranged in randomized complete bl...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Diversity of cellulase- and xylanase-producing filamentous fungi from termite mounds</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/E5D541B61397</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/E5D541B61397</guid><description>
	Cellulases and xylanases are enzymes of industrial significance, particularly in the pulp, paper, textile, and animal feed industries. Moreover, their utilization in the food industry, among them, bakery, brewery, winery and fruit and vegetable juice production, cannot be underestimated. One of the potential sources of enzymes is the filamentous fungi, and hence bio-prospecting of this speci...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Fungal and yeast carotenoids</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/206083662198</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/206083662198</guid><description>
	This review reports and discusses all available information about the fungal carotenoids such general characters, derivatives, common names, chemical structure, molecular formula, color, bioactivity, and industrial applications in medicine, pharmacology, food processing, cosmetics, dyeing and others. It also reviews the classification of the fungal carotenoids, biosynthetic pathway, distribu...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxonomical study of the genus Amanita from Western Burkina Faso</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/9B00E2262306</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/9B00E2262306</guid><description>
	Burkina Faso has abundant wild mushrooms, but very few inventories have been carried out to record these species. The shortage of taxonomic studies in Burkina Faso on wild mushroom species limits their knowledge. Three species of the genus Amanita from Burkina Faso are reported and fully described in this paper. They are Amanita pulverulenta Beeli, Amanita citrina (Schaeffer) Persoon and Ama...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring for the possibility of utilizing Pleurotus ostreatus to manage Eichhornia crassipes in Zimbabwe</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/63CC3D261173</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/63CC3D261173</guid><description>
	The versatile nature of the commercial mushroom, Pleurotus ostreatus (Jacq.: Fr.) Kumm., provides basis for continued exploration of its biochemical processes during solid state fermentation on various lignocellulosic biomass as potential substrates. As a fungal organism, P. ostreatus feeds on lignocellulose by secreting various extracellular enzymes responsible for breaking down this organi...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Anticandidosic activity of selected medicinal plants from C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/F885CA559343</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/F885CA559343</guid><description>
	Superficial candidiasis is a real public health problem, especially in immunocompromised people and HIV-infected patients. Due to the toxic handicap and the high cost of antifungal drug treatment, people use medicinal plants, which are relatively more accessible. Medicinal plants are an important source of novel antimicrobial agents.This study aims to determine thein vitroantimicrobial activ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Susceptibility of Candida species isolated from recurrent vulvovaginal candidiasis to antifungal agents among women at Institut Pasteur of C&#xF4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/6C6A9D358978</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/6C6A9D358978</guid><description>
	Recurrent vulvo-vaginal candidiasis is a major issue in pubescent females because of the fact that it is a source of health discomfort. For a better medical treatment, an analysis of susceptibility of Candida species to antifungal agents is fundamental. Therefore, this study aims to determine the susceptibility of Candida spp. to antifungal agents isolated in recurrent vulvo-vaginal candidia...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Optimization of nutritional and environmental conditions for biomass production and sporulation of entomogenous fungus Lecanicillium lecanii CA-1-G using two-stage cultivation system</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/D710CD658589</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/JYFR/article-abstract/D710CD658589</guid><description>
	Some factors on sporulation of Lecanicillium lecanii CA-1-G by one-time-at-a-factor have been studied. These factors include carbon and nitrogen sources, carbon-to-nitrogen ratios, mineral elements and vitamins together with water potentials, temperatures, dark/light cycles and pHs. On the basis of these results, together with two-step cultivation and orthogonal method, we optimized the cult...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>