<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Medical Case Studies - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS</link><description>view the most recent articles from Medical Case Studies</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Interventions in women with one blocked oviduct, lessons learnt and recommendations: A case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/C9D6F0660934</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/C9D6F0660934</guid><description>
	Women can still conceive naturally or through in vitro fertilization (IVF) with the one oviduct that is properly functioning if only one oviduct is blocked, however, the chances are decreased particularly if the blockage is close to the ovary (hydrosalpinx) because of wash out phenomena and toxic fluid produced by the fallopian tube that is blocked. In situations where only a single tube has...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The great mimicker: A rare case of Iliopsoas abscess associated with vertebral and sacroiliac osteomyelitis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/DEDE73260198</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/DEDE73260198</guid><description>
	A 21-year-old, recent Indian migrant to Australia, presented to the Emergency Department with a 3-week history of worsening right buttock and thigh pain and weakness, associated with fever of up to 39C and weight loss of 3 kg. On examination, the patient demonstrated a right-sided antalgic gait with a limp and weakness of right hip flexion. The patient was tachycardic with a heart rate of 14...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Case report: Challenges in diagnosis and treatment of Small bowel diverticulitis presenting with 
acute abdomen
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/E3F987858483</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/E3F987858483</guid><description>
	Small bowel diverticulitis is a rare condition that is often excluded in the differential diagnosis of acute abdomen. We herein present two cases of patients with small bowel diverticulitis who presented with acute abdomen. First case was a 72-year-old lady who presented to emergency with 2 days of sudden-onset worsening generalized abdominal pain. The computed tomography (CT) revealed a seg...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Blind nasal intubation in temporomandibular joint ankylosis: A case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/33D851A56481</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/33D851A56481</guid><description>
	Temperomandibular joint (TMJ) ankylosis is loss of joint movement that results from a union of the mandibular condyle to the base of the skull. Managing airway is considered to be one of the most difficult and challenging procedures when there is a diseased temperomandibular joint as a result of inadequate mouth opening. Although TMJ ankylosis is well known risk factors of difficult airway m...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Percutaneous drainage management of an abscess developed from conservatively treated retroperitoneal haematoma caused by acupuncture</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/52CA52261826</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/52CA52261826</guid><description>
	With acupuncture treatment becoming a widely used technique in medicine to control chronic pain, there have been increasing reports on its associated complications. Although pneumothorax is the most frequently reported, infectious complications may not be uncommon. However, retroperitoneal or intraabdominal abscess caused by acupuncture may be much more serious conditions than pneumothorax. ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Epidural abscess in a diabetic patient with complicated pyelonephritis: Case report and literature review</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/8C15A2759608</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/8C15A2759608</guid><description>
	Epidural abscess is a rare condition, with increasing incidence, but still underdiagnosed. Clinical set is often confused with common diseases, which delays the diagnosis and may progress to irreversible neurological sequelae or death, if no early intervention is taken. We have reported a case of a patient immunosuppressed by diabetes who developed an epidural abscess due to a complicated py...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Legacy of mental Illness: A family with unusual genetic penetration</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/F1B958855530</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/F1B958855530</guid><description>
	Mental illnesses are multifactorial disorders caused by the interaction of genetic and environmental factors. Multiple lines of evidence suggest that the roles of genetic and environmental factors depend on each other. The aim of the report is to share the presentation of different psychiatric illnesses in generations of a family. A 31 year old male, unmarried, studied up to class eight, une...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Corticotrophin deficiency in end-stage renal failure led to recurrent hypoglycemia: A case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/35986D354099</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/35986D354099</guid><description>
	Reactive hypoglycemia caused by an insulinoma, pre-diabetic metabolic state, fluctuations in diabetic metabolic situation and antidiabetic medication is commonly known. We report on the case of an unusual multi-factorial occurrence of a woman with recurrent hypoglycemia, which cannot be explained adequately by a single commonly known cause. We refer to a cachectic non-diabetic 52-year-old Ge...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus prostatic abscess in an American soldier</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/B5A135746907</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/B5A135746907</guid><description>
	Prostatic abscess caused by methicillin resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) is rare with few previously reported cases. This appears to be the first identifiable report of a healthy, immunocompetent individual developing a community acquired prostatic abscess. A 35 year old male soldier presented to the emergency room complaining of chills, malaise, pelvic pain, tenesmus, dysuria and bloo...</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Huge retroperitoneal liposarcom: Case report</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/741D74E45803</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MCS/article-abstract/741D74E45803</guid><description>
	Liposarcoma is the most common tumor type of retroperitoneal soft tissue sarcomas. Liposarcoma is a malignant tumor of mesenchymal origin in which the bulk of tumor differentiates into adipose tissue. A 50 year old male patient was presented at our clinic with abdominal mass and pain. Abdominal ultrasonography, computed tomography (CT) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) showed a huge retro...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>