<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Medical Practice and Reviews - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Medical Practice and Reviews</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Maternity waiting homes and skilled delivery in Ethiopia: Review of strategy and implementation to drive sustainable development goals</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/92A625156886</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/92A625156886</guid><description>
	Improving maternal and child health is foundation for every nations, communities and families. Millennium Development Goals had applied various strategies to overcome the gaps resulted in maternal and child health morbidity and mortality from global to local levels. Among the strategies is maternity waiting home, an important tool-had been addressed those in need of access and hard/difficult...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Predictors of institutional delivery service utilization, among women of reproductive age group in Dima District, Agnua zone, Gambella, Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/3683F0C56127</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/3683F0C56127</guid><description>
	Institutional delivery reduces the risk of complications and infections of the mother and newborn baby. There was inadequate information in the study area that this study intended to provide. The study assessed institutional delivery and predictors in Gambella, Ethiopia. A community-based cross-sectional study was conducted on 798 subjects from February 1 to June 15, 2017 among reproductive ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A three-year study on childhood intussusception in Jimma University Medical Center</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/07AA54655853</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/07AA54655853</guid><description>
	Intussusception is the leading cause of intestinal obstruction in the young child and refers to the condition whereby a segment of intestine becomes drawn into the lumen of the more proximal bowel. The process usually begins in the region of the terminal ileum, and extends distally into colon. Rarely, an intussusception may prolapse through the rectum. Although it is a common entity, no rese...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevention of mother to child transmission of HIV/AIDS: Service utilization and associated factors among selected public health facilities in Ethiopia</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/3FDCBA365848</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/3FDCBA365848</guid><description>
	Mother-to-child transmission (MTCT) of human immune virus/acquired immune deficiency syndrome (HIV/AIDS) is the largest mode of HIV transmission among children. This study assesses the prevention of mother to child transmission (PMTCT) of HIV/AIDS service utilization and associated factors among mothers attending antenatal care (ANC) in selected public health facilities of Horo Guduru Wolleg...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of ovarian torsion in postmenopausal women in a Nigerian community</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/6F302FB58499</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/6F302FB58499</guid><description>
	This study aimed at determining the prevalence of ovarian torsion in postmenopausal women in Nigeria. For this purpose, a histopathology data pool was maintained for 30 years among the Igbos, a large ethnic group in Nigeria from where postmenopausal women diagnosed with ovarian torsion were extracted for classification. The data concerned 69 cases. All were presented with acute abdominal pai...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The challenges of qualitative research: Can it be used to strengthen decision making for health care in Uganda?</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/300BC8252626</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/300BC8252626</guid><description>
	The growing need to integrate qualitative research findings in health care is a result of its ability to provide more credence to empirical data from the Uganda Health Management Information System (HMIS) in Uganda. This paper based on literature review identifies some of the main challenges encountered in use of qualitative research findings to inform the policy decision making process. Whi...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Retention challenges of human resources for health: What are the alternatives incentives for retention of skilled health workers in Uganda health sector?
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/A82BFC951813</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/A82BFC951813</guid><description>
	Available literature shows that retention of human resources for health is underpinned by a number of factors in Motivation-Hygiene Theory key which include human resource development, financial incentives, and personal and professional support mechanisms. These are all linked to motivation and productivity. There is convergence of opinion that staff retentions required packaging different b...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Computerized tomography scan and head injury: The experience in a tertiary hospital in Nigeria:
 A cross sectional study
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/352D4EB50440</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/352D4EB50440</guid><description>
	Trauma is the leading cause of death in all age groups, and head trauma is the cause of death in more than 50% of cases. Head injury reduces the level of physical and mental health of a community, ultimately increasing the socioeconomic burden. In our resource limited country, skull x ray was the main mode of investigating head trauma until recently when computerized tomography (CT) scans be...</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Medical students&#x2019; reflections on first clinical experience
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/15AD22649218</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/15AD22649218</guid><description>
	
		Reflection is an important skill, as it supports both individual and lifelong learning. It can be used as a learning method in medical education for professional development at all stages. This study aims to evaluate reflective skills of third-year medical students in primary care experience. Physicians from affiliated primary health care centers supervised students during their clinical...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of computer technology on health: Computer Vision Syndrome (CVS)</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/0905F9948599</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/MPR/article-abstract/0905F9948599</guid><description>
	In todays society, the use of computer as a tool at workplaces, academic institutions, recreation facilities and homes has become very common. It is estimated that globally, about 45 to 70 million people spend hours staring into a video display terminal, popularly known as computer screen. Several studies, mainly in developed countries, have shown an association between computer use and visu...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>