<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Philosophical Papers and Review - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR</link><description>view the most recent articles from Philosophical Papers and Review</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Big bang: The apologetic of Quran and the Will of God</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/C1A6B0061476</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/C1A6B0061476</guid><description>
	Muslims believe Quran as the word of God (Allah), sent as verbal revelation to Prophet Mohammad S.A.W. through the angel Gabriel. In the paper from segregate verses of Quran, the main events taking part in the time-line of one of the most widely accepted theories Lambda-Cold Dark Matter model which is the current standard model of Big Bang cosmology is derived. The six long periods that took...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Existential phenomenology of religious liberty and security in religion and politics: A case study of Nigeria</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/720592E61187</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/720592E61187</guid><description>
	That peace and justice is the solution to the flux and insecurity in the church and in the state cannot be denied. In fact, it is exigent to ask this question thus: can there be peace and justice in the religious institution in the first instance, without religious liberty and of course, civil liberty untwisted? There is no gain-saying the fact that sacred and secular histories have tended t...</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>A review on normative and other factors contributing to Africa&#x2019;s adolescent development crisis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/A26549960184</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/A26549960184</guid><description>
	The objective of this review is to examine factors influencing African adolescents identity development. The review begins with defining identity and discuses major theories of identity development. Moreover, this review focuses on colonialism, globalization, media and other factors which are considered to influence youth identity development. The author has used the terms adolescence and yo...</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Decentralisation and constitutionalism in Africa: A theoretical exploration for sustainable 
distributive justice
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/F134CDF56760</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/F134CDF56760</guid><description>
	Central to the problem of most of the states in Africa as a whole and Nigeria in particular is the excessive centralization of the federal system. The centralized federalism denied the opportunity for self-expression, autonomy and by extension prevented avenues for negotiations towards attaining equity and justice. Similar to this is the defect on the constitution which is meant to define wh...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The philosophy behind some Adinkra symbols and their communicative values in Akan</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/A5A4C6E58407</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/A5A4C6E58407</guid><description>
	This paper represents selected Adinkra symbols of the Akan and brings out the philosophical, educational, historical and moral values inherent in them. It seeks to encourage the understanding and usage of the Adinkra symbols in a more meaningful way by Ghanaians and foreigners, contemporary artists, designers, craftsmen, teachers, and all who appreciate the traditional symbols. It discusses ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Philosophical paradigm of Islamic cosmology</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/E1A8ABA57874</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/E1A8ABA57874</guid><description>
	Humans have been examining the cosmic bodies for many millennia, but scientific discoveries and ideas about the origin of the universe have changed the religious discourse and rely completely on empiricism. Many theories were put forth by the physicists, philosophers and even religions at large but Islam has its prime source of information Quran upon which Muslim cosmologists builds their th...</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Hayek&#x2019;s concept of orders in relation to technicism and neo-liberalism</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/764B63056846</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/764B63056846</guid><description>
	Since the 1970s, neo-liberalism has become a key ideology driving the global economy. It originates in the liberalism of enlightenment thinkers, neo-classical economics (marginal utility) and a resistance to totalitarianism. In 1938 a colloquium of prominent economists/philosophers, discussed how 19th century liberalism could be renewed without a naturalistic laissez-faire approach. From 194...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>On Western and Chinese conception of time: A comparative study</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/7C0C79A55304</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/7C0C79A55304</guid><description>
	While Western thinking considers change within a unique process stretching ad infinitum, Eastern thinking conceives change within a process that hold together repetition and transformation. Making sense to this is to simply recognize that the issues regarding time understanding in ontological and metaphysical terms, serve to support the idea that how we consider the nature of history it will...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Culture in society, society in culture: Understanding threads of cultural-social dialectic</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/D3AA6A251495</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/D3AA6A251495</guid><description>
	This paper aims at exploring the provinces of social and cultural dialectical threads. In doing so, it offers an account of (1) why it is quite often confusingly believed that there is a methodological and epistemological difference between social and cultural ones[i], and (2) how this belief cloaks some inherent weaknesses and obstacles to change. It is, therefore, within this rationale tha...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Foundational myths of Zionism: An inquiry into the light of sacred text</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/E739FE151408</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/PPR/article-abstract/E739FE151408</guid><description>
	Zionist movement is based on some historical and religious myths. They propagate that Palestine is their ancestors home and the entire Holy Land was promised to them as a covenant between Abraham and God and they are the sole legitimate heirs of Abraham. They say that this covenant was unconditional and the Holy Land would be given to them whatever they may do. But when we examine their clai...</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>