<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Research in Pharmaceutical Biotechnology - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB</link><description>view the most recent articles from Research in Pharmaceutical Biotechnology</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Antimicrobial activity and phytochemical fingerprints of five crude extracts obtained from indigenous medicinal plants of Uganda</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/D292C7167116</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/D292C7167116</guid><description>
	Five crude extracts from four Ugandan plants were screened in vitro for their antimicrobial activity and phytochemical composition. They included the chloroform extracts of Bothliocline longipes, Maesa lanceolata, Trimeria bakeri, Rhus natalensis and the petroleum ether extract of T. bakeri. The plant crude extracts were tested against Staphylococcus aureus (ATCC 25923), Escherichia coli (AT...</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of the in vivo anti malarial activity of the methanolic leaf extract of Nepata cateria
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/B06AC9955427</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/B06AC9955427</guid><description>
	Nepata cateria (Labiatae) growing widely in northern Nigeria is used by most indigenes for the treatment of malaria and other related diseases. The in vivo anti-malarial activity of the methanol leaf extract was evaluated in mice infected with the chloroquine sensitive Plasmodium berghei berghei NK65 strain. Oral acute toxicity of the methanol leaf extract with modified Lorke`s method was ev...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Protective effect of HAMI 3379 against high glucose-induced PC12 cell injury</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/56BA97955013</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/56BA97955013</guid><description>
	Diabetic neuropathy is one of the most common diabetic complications, associated with long time exposure to high glucose. Hyperglycemia induces the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and reactive nitrogen species contributing to neuronal damage. We have previously reported that HAMI 3379, a selective antagonist of CysLT2 receptor, is involved in neuron injury after ischemia. In this...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibacterial activity of alkaloidal compound isolated from leaves of Catharanthus roseaus (L.) against 
multi-drug resistant strains
</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/24CC1CE49464</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/24CC1CE49464</guid><description>
	The following alkaloids were isolated from Catharanthus roseus L. leaves from the yellow crystal as white powder at (38C). The chemical and physical properties were studied by thin layer chromatography (TLC), IR-spectrum (IR), Ultraviolet - visible spectrum (UV) and melting point (mp). Standard strains of bacteria: Staphylococcus aureus NCTC 6571, Escherichia coli NCTC 5933 and the clinical ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Synthesis, characterization and biological activity of 2-Aryl -2, 3-dihydro-1H-perimidine</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/C078BF743689</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/C078BF743689</guid><description>
	A series of new 2-Aryl-2,3-dihydro-1H-perimidine, derivatives (3a - j) were synthesized under reflux and at room temperature by condensation reaction of 1,8-diaminonaphthalene (2) with various substituted benzaldehyde using glacial acetic acid a catalyst. The synthesized compounds were characterized by spectroscopic methods, infrared (IR), proton nuclear magnetic resonance (1H-NMR), carbon n...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Instrumental and chemical characterization of Moringa oleifera Lam root starch as an industrial biomaterial</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/394F56643954</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/394F56643954</guid><description>
	Moringa oleifera Lam. (Moringaceae family) is a deciduous plant with tuber-like root at the earlier stage. Starch was isolated from the young tuber of the plant and examined instrumentally for its functional groups, X-ray diffractometer (XRD) profile, elemental analysis and antioxidant activities. The Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy analysis shows that peaks at 3465.23 to 3577.11 cm1...</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Comparative phytochemical screening and biological evaluation of n-hexane and water extracts of Acacia tortilis</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/EB53987496</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/EB53987496</guid><description>
	

	N-Hexane and water extracts of the leaves, stem-bark and roots of the indigenous plantAcacia tortilislocally reputed for the treatment of cough, malaria, asthma and stomach pain in Girei Local Government Area (LGA), Adamawa State were phytochemically screened and biologically tested againstEscherichia coli, Shigellasp.,Pseudomonas aeruginosa, Staphylococcus aureus, Streptococcus pyogene...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Antioxidant activity of n-butanol extract of celery (Apium graveolens) seed in streptozotocin-induced diabetic male rats</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/264C36F498</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/264C36F498</guid><description>
	

	The potent of n-butanol extract of celery (Apium graveolens) seed in ameliorating the lipid peroxidation and antioxidant status was investigated in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Thirty two mature male rats were assigned to four groups, non-diabetic control and three diabetic groups. Diabetes was induced by single injection with streptozotocin (60 mg/kg b.w.,i.p.). Rats  200 mg/d...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaluation of Sesamum indicum gum as a binder in the formulation of paracetamol granules and tablets</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/D29FAE0493</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/D29FAE0493</guid><description>
	

	Comparative evaluation ofSesamum indicumgum as a binder in the formulation of paracetamol (PCM) granules and tablets was performed using acacia, gelatin, and Sodium carboxyl methylcellulose (SCMC) as standard binders for comparison. The properties of granules and tablets such as; flow rate, angle of repose, density, weight uniformity, crushing strength, friability, disintegration rate a...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosiglitazone protection against experimentally-induced intestinal ischemia/re-perfusion</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/27F0633494</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/RPB/article-abstract/27F0633494</guid><description>
	

	Several studies have shown that peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-g(PPARg) agonists protect against ischemia/re-perfusion (I/R) damage in different organs. This study was carried out to assess the possible role of PPARgon intestinal I/R-mediated tissue injury. This was achieved by evaluating the effects of the PPARgagonist rosiglitazone and the PPARgantagonist bisphenol A digly...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>