<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Scientific Research and Essays - Most Recent Articles</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE</link><description>view the most recent articles from Scientific Research and Essays</description><language>en-us</language><item><title>Impact of some heavy metals on bacterial utilization of kerosene in liquid medium</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/83857B563833</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/83857B563833</guid><description>
	Potential petroleum degrading bacteria, Pseudomonas aerogenosa and Micrococcus sp. was isolated from petroleum contaminated soil in petroleum microbiology laboratory, Department of Microbiology University of Nigeria, Nsukka. Hydrocarbon utilization in liquid media was assessed through time  course optical density measurement. Concentrations of the heavy metals ranging from 50 to 200 mg/L wer...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Knowledge and understanding of energy efficiency in air-conditioning: Exploring perceptions from the manufacturing sector in Ghana</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B98B52E63874</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B98B52E63874</guid><description>
	The study investigated Energy Efficiency (EE) measures and practices from the perspectives of Ghanas manufacturing sector. A mixed methods approach that applied both qualitative and quantitative methodologies guided the study. The quantitative approach was relevant to establish statistical inferences and the qualitative methods used to provide further in-depth understanding to statistic(s) p...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Mitigating the spread of COVID-19 in low-income countries</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/392B15563903</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/392B15563903</guid><description>
	Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has become an increasing concern to global health organizations, and may pose major challenges to health care systems in the low-income countries due to the absence of equipment, lack of funding, and insufficient training of healthcare workers. Thus, mitigation measures that involve social distances and personal hygiene may be prioritized. The main objecti...</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevalence of hepatitis B virus and HIV infections among pregnant women visiting healthcare institutions in Ebonyi State, Nigeria.</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/5C1E7DA63435</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/5C1E7DA63435</guid><description>
	This study aims to determine the prevalence of hepatitis B virus (HBV) and HIV infections among pregnant women visiting Healthcare Institutions within Ebonyi State, Nigeria. Blood samples were collected from 100 pregnant women who visited Rural Improvement Missionary Hospital (RIMH) and General Hospital (GHE) within Ebonyi State. The presence of hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) in serum w...</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Surfactants of microbial origin and its application  in foods</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B30FBF162921</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/B30FBF162921</guid><description>
	Surfactants are petroleum-derived compounds widely used globally in industrial areas such as pharmaceuticals, cosmetics, textile, among others. The synthesis and use of these compounds has generated environmental pollution, putting public health at risk. For several years, the synthesis of surfactants has been reported by various microorganisms called biosurfactants. Biosurfactants have been...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Preparation of Laundry Soap from Used Cooking Oils: Getting value out of waste</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/FEC1AE762643</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/FEC1AE762643</guid><description>
	Palm oil is commonly used to prepare laundry soap by treating it with alkaline solutions. However, using it for this purpose is becoming expensive as palm oil is imported from few major exerting countries. Moreover, it is used for biodiesel production. Therefore, looking for alternative raw material that substitutes palm oil for soap production is imperative. Used cooking oils (UCOs) are goo...</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Positioning smallholder farming in the agricultural productivity and food security in resource limited Sierra Leone</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/67BF42E61771</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/67BF42E61771</guid><description>
	Agriculture is dominated by smallholder farmers who occupy the majority of land, and produce most of the crop and livestock products in Sierra Leone. Nonetheless, the key long-standing challenge of the smallholder farmers is low productivity that stems from the lack of access to markets, credit and technology, and in recent years these are compounded by the volatile food and energy prices an...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Structural plasticity and species distribution in a peri-urban mangrove of Southeastern Brazil</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/00991D361958</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/00991D361958</guid><description>
	The goal of this study was to evaluate the structural plasticity and distribution of mangrove species in the Estuarine System of Greater Vitria (ESGV). Four areas distributed along the estuary were analyzed. Fringe and basin forests were sampled in each station. Concomitantly to the forest sampling, interstitial salinity was measured in the field, and sediment was collected for analysis of o...</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Assessment of ecosystem services in the Wildlife Reserve of Togodo (South East of Togo, West Africa) and vulnerability-adaptation of surrounding communities to climate variability and change effects

</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/33741B061376</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/33741B061376</guid><description>
	This study aims at contributing to the vulnerability and adaptation to climate changes (CC) analysis of bordering communities of Togodo Reserve, in order to enhance their resilience. Specifically, the present study attempted to (i) identify the climatic hazards of the WRT; (ii) determine the impacts of climate variability and change on their livelihoods; (iii) assess the socio-economic vulne...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>The importance of undergraduate coursework in student success at South Carolina medical institutions</title><link>https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/80C208261481</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://academicjournals.org/journal/SRE/article-abstract/80C208261481</guid><description>
	The importance of undergraduate coursework in determining medical school student readiness reaches far beyond preparation to take the standardized Medical College Admissions Test (MCAT). Since medical schools employ a rigorous and fast-paced learning system to instruct prospective medical students on (A) didactic information in the basic sciences and (B) the critical methodology of clinical ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>